import{_ as g,o as i,c as t,a as n,m as h,t as l,C as y,M as b,U as c,F as w,p,e as f,f as j,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},A={class:"poem-container"},z={class:"review"},T={class:"review-title"},N={class:"review-content"};function C(e,a,s,m,o,r){return i(),t("div",A,[n("div",z,[n("div",T,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),h(l(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",N,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),h(l(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const S=g(q,[["render",C],["__scopeId","data-v-407aa75a"]]),M=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"வினா:கைபிடி, கைப்பிடி – சொற்களின் பொருள் வேறுபாடுகளையும் அவற்றின் புணர்ச்சி வகைகளையும் எழுதுக.","answer":"விடை:“கை பிடி” – கையைப் பிடித்துக் கொள் என்று பொருள்.“கைப்பிடி” – கைப்பிடி அளவைக் குறிப்பது. (ஒரு கைப்பிடி பருப்பு கொடு)கை + பிடி → கைபிடி – இயல்புப் புணர்ச்சி ஆகும்.கை + பிடி → கைப்பிடி (தோன்றல்) – விகாரப்புணர்ச்சி ஆகும்."},{"question":" O que é um ecossistema?","answer":"Um ecossistema é um sistema complexo composto por comunidades de organismos vivos interagindo com seu ambiente físico. Isso inclui todos os seres vivos, seus habitats e os fatores ambientais que os afetam."},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Meesha Lagu Aasay Rasuulka (NNKH) ?","answer":"Jawaab: Waxa Lagu Aasay Rasuulka (NNKH) Gurigiisa Oo Ku Yiilay Masjidka Madiina."},{"question":"தொடரமைப்பு மாறினால் பொருளும் மாறிவிடும் என்பதற்குச் சான்று தருக. தொடரமைப்பு மாறினால் பொருள் மாறிவிடும்.","answer":"சான்று : ஆண்டு தோறும் மறைந்த தி.ஜானகி ராமன் நினைவாகக் கூட்டம் நடைபெறும். இத்தொடர் தி.ஜானகி ராமன் ஆண்டுதோறும் மறைந்தார் என்னும் தவறான பொருளைத் தருகின்றது.சரியான தொடரமைப்பு :“மறைந்த தி.ஜானகிராமன் நினைவாக ஆண்டுதோறும் கூட்டம் நடைபெறும்” என்பதேயாகும்."},{"question":"ما هي أصغر وﻻية في الولايات المتحدة الأمريكية؟","answer":"ولاية هاواي في المحيط الهادي أصغر الولايات مساحة في أمريكا."},{"question":"सारस - नेपाली कथा |","answer":"एक ग्रामीण युक्रेनी गाउँमा १९ अप्रिल २०१४ को राति, ठूलो आवाजले ओक्सानालाई मध्यरातमा ब्यूँझाइयो। “के यो इस्टरको आतिशबाजी हो ?” उनले आश्चर्य व्यक्त गरिन्। इस्टर आइतबार उनको लागि सबैभन्दा खुशीको उज्यालो बिदाको दिन थियो।तर यो आतिशबाजी थिएन; यो युद्ध थियो। स्वचालित बन्दुक, ग्रेनेड र विष्फोटकको आवाजले उनको मुटु धड्कन थाल्यो । के यो वास्तविक थियो? उनी चर्चमा गएर प्रार्थना गरिन्। उनले अगाडिको पीडाको कल्पना पनि गर्न सकिनन् ।एक तोपको गोला आफ्नै बगैंचामा खस्यो । डरले पेट भरियो । उनले आफ्ना छोरीहरूलाई भेटिन र धेरै बेरसम्म अँगालो हालेर रोइन्।वर्षाले मानिसहरूलाई यति खुसी बनाएको थियो कि भनेर उनी सम्झन सक्दिनन्, तर पानी परेपछि सुटिङ रोकियो। र त्यो पर्याप्त थियो।छोराछोरीको सुरक्षाको लागि, तिनीहरूले घर छोड्ने निर्णय गरे। तर यात्राको लागि कसरी प्याक गर्ने? उनीहरूलाई कागजपत्र, पैसा र लुगा चाहियो। र पुस्तै पुस्ताहरूबाट सङ्कलन गरिएका पुस्तकहरूको पुस्तकालय, पारिवारिक फोटो एल्बमहरू र उनकी हजुरआमाका आइकनहरू, जसमा उनले आफ्नो काकाबाट विरासतमा पाएका थिए। तिनीहरू झोलामा अटाउदैनन् । उनी रोइन्। उनी बगैँचामा गइन् र हरेक झाडी, रूख र फूलको फोटो खिचिन् । कमसेकम उसले सम्झनाहरू राख्छ।“आमा,” उनले आफ्नी सासूलाई भनिन्, “हामी भोलि जाँदैछौं। के तपाईंले प्याक गर्नुभयो?”“म जाँदै छैन। मेरो जीवन, मेरो घर, मेरो श्रीमानको चिहान सबै यही गाउँमा छ। म गएँ भने तिनीहरूको हेरचाह कसले गर्ने? म यहीं जन्मिएँ र यहीं मर्नेछु। तिमी जाउ । मेरा नातिनीहरूलाई शान्ति, शान्त र खुशीमा लैजाउ। तिम्रो सारा जीवन तिम्रो अगाडि छ।”उनीहरूले उनलाई छोड्न सकेनन्। त्यसैले, तिनीहरू बसे!जब उनीहरूले बस्ने निर्णय गरे, ओक्सानाको संसारको सम्पूर्ण दृष्टिकोण परिवर्तन भयो। उनीहरुको समस्याले उनीहरुलाई छिमेकीहरुसँग जोडेको छ । उनीहरुले एकअर्कालाई साथ दिए । चालीस दिन बिजुली गएपछि उनका श्रीमान् र उनका साथीहरूले जेनेरेटर फेला पारे, मर्मत गरे र इन्धन फेला पारे। बेलुका सबैजना आआफ्नो घरमा ब्याट्री चार्ज गर्न आउने गर्दथे । मानिसहरूले खाना बाडेर खाए । साँझ गाउँका गाईहरूबाट बाल्टिनमा दूध लिएर सडकमा जान्थे। बच्चाहरू, वयस्कहरू र बिरालाहरू र कुकुरहरूले पनि उनीहरूले चाहेको जति दूध पिए।त्यसअघि उनीहरू साँझ टिभी वा कम्प्युटरको अगाडि बिताउने गर्थे। अहिले उनीहरु सडकमा बसेर कुराकानी र सल्लाह आदानप्रदान गर्छन् । तिनीहरूले एक अर्कालाई कसरी इनार सफा गर्न मद्दत गर्ने भनेर पत्ता लगाए। उनीहरूले वृद्धवृद्धाहरूलाई पानी वितरणको व्यवस्था गरे। उनीहरूले खाँचोमा परेका मानिसहरूका लागि औषधि फेला पारे।एक जोडी सारस पनि गाउँमा बस्थे । मानिसहरूले राम्रो भाग्य ल्याउँछन् भन्छन्। तर ओक्सानामा तिनीहरूले आनन्द ल्याए। चर्को गर्मीको बावजुद सारसले पाँचवटा चल्ला पाले । उनीहरू बन्दुकबाट डराउँदैनथे। तिनीहरूले आफ्नो गुँड छोडेनन्, तिनीहरू गाउँका मानिसहरू जस्तै बसे र बाँचे। शरद ऋतुमा, सारसहरू गाउँ छाडे … तर के तपाइँ यसलाई विश्वास गर्न सक्नुहुन्छ? तिनीहरू अर्को वसन्तमा फर्किए !"},{"question":"தமிழரின் வாழ்வியல் கருவலமாகக் கருதப்படுவது………………….அ) அகநானூறுஆ) புறநானூறுஇ) பதிற்றுப்பத்துஈ) கலித்தொகை","answer":"ஆ) புறநானூறுபுறநானூறு என்னும் தொகைநூல் நானூறு பாடல்களைக் கொண்ட புறத்திணை சார்ந்த ஒரு சங்கத் தமிழ் நூலாகும். புறம், புறப்பாட்டு, நந்தா விளக்கம் என்றும் வழங்கப்படும். இது சங்க காலத் தமிழ் நூல் தொகுப்பான எட்டுத்தொகை நூல்களில் புறநூல்களுள் ஒன்று. இந்நூலைத் தொகுத்தவர் பெயரும், தொகுப்பித்தவர் பெயரும் தெரியவில்லை. இந்நூலின் பாக்கள் 4 அடி முதல் 40 அடி வரையிலான ஆசிரியப்பாவால் அமைந்து உள்ளன. சிறுபான்மையாக வஞ்சி அடிகளும் விரவி வரும். புறநானூற்றின் பாடல்கள் சங்ககாலத்தில் ஆண்ட அரசர்களைப் பற்றியும் மக்களின் சமூக வாழ்க்கை பற்றியும் எடுத்துரைக்கின்றன. இதனை ஜி. யு. போப் ஆங்கிலத்தில் மொழிபெயர்த்துள்ளார்.பாடியவர்கள்:இந் நூலில் அடங்கியுள்ள பாடல்கள் பல்வேறு புலவர்களால் பல்வேறு காலங்களில் பாடப்பட்டவை. அகவற்பா வகையைச் சேர்ந்த இப்பாடல்கள், 150க்கும் மேற்பட்ட புலவர்களால் எழுதப்பட்டவை. இந்நூலில் அதிக பாடல்களைப் பாடியவர் ஔவையார் (33 பாடல்கள்) ஆவார். அவரை அடுத்து அதிக பாடலைப் பாடியவர் கபிலர் (28 பாடல்கள்) ஆவார். இந்நூலில் இடம்பெறும் புலவர்கள் அனைவரும் ஒரே சமூகத்தையோ நாட்டையோ சார்ந்தவர்கள் அல்லர்,அரசன் முதல் எளிய குயவன்மகள் வரை பல்வேறு நிலைகளில் இருந்த ஆடவரும் பெண்டிருமான புலவர்கள் பாடியுள்ளனர். நூல் அமைப்பு:இந்நூலில் பாடல்கள் தொகுக்கப்படும்போது ஒருவகை இயைபு கருதி, முதலில் முடிமன்னர் மூவர், அடுத்து குறுநில மன்னர், வேளிர் ஆகியோரைப் பற்றிய பாடல்களும் அதனை அடுத்துப் போர்ப் பற்றிய பாடல்களும் கையறுநிலைப்பாடல், நடுகல், மகளிர் தீப்பாய்தல் என்று தொகுத்துள்ளனர். புறப்பொருள் கருத்துகளைத் தழுவிப் பாடப்பட்ட இந்நூலில் ஒவ்வொரு பாடலின் இறுதியிலும் திணை, துறை, பாடினோர், பாடப்பட்டோர், பாடப்பட்ட சூழல் போன்ற குறிப்புகள் உள்ளன.புறநானூறு வழி அறியலாகும் செய்திகள்:   அக்காலத் தமிழ் மக்களின் அரசியல், சமூகம், பொருளாதாரம், கல்வி, நாகரிகம், கலை வளர்ச்சி, வீரம், கொடை, ஆடை, அணிகலன், பழக்க வழக்கங்கள், வாணிபம் போன்ற பல செய்திகளைப் புறநானூறு வழி அறியலாம்."},{"question":"Oviana ny andro maneran-tany ho an’ity planeta misy antsika ity ary inona ny anarana hafa azo hiantsoana azy?","answer":" 22 Aprily ny andro maneran-tany ho an'ity planeta misy antsika ity.  \\"Planète bleue\\" na planeta manga no fomba fiantso azy hafa."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Tysklands herrjuniorlandslag i ishockey representerar Tyskland i ishockey för herrjuniorer. Laget spelade","answer":", som Västtyskland, sin första landskamp den 23 december 1976 i Zvolen under juniorvärldsmästerskapet, och besegrade med 4-3."},{"question":"दूषित पानीले हाम्रो स्वास्थ्यलाई कसरी असर गर्छ?","answer":"दूषित पानीको उपभोगले भाइरस र ब्याक्टेरियाबाट हुने रोगहरू निम्त्याएर हाम्रो स्वास्थ्यमा खतरनाक असर पार्न सक्छ। स्वास्थ्य जोखिमहरू कम गर्न र जीवन शक्ति सुनिश्चित गर्न सफा पानी पिउनु महत्त्वपूर्ण छ।"},{"question":"س137 - ما هي صلة القرابة بين الرسول صلى الله عليهوسلم وعدوه اللدود أبو لهب ؟","answer":"ج138 - عمه"},{"question":"Ngiyogiya ngiqephuze,Ngihay' izibongo.Ngingqabashiye ngihalalise ngokuqhashambulaSengiphumelel' ukufez' ezeminyak' izifisoNezinhloso zami ngelokujaja ilanga.Senginqwanjiswe umnqwamb' oqavile.Sengiyikazel' iminyezane yakomfundo.Ngiyogiya ngiqephuze.Ngigiye ngiqephuze ngiqeketh' izindabaNgigiye ngilokoth' amagam' angalokothwayoAlab' abayibekil' induk' ebandla.Abachathazil' emagulen' abo ezangqondo'Ze ngiqwal' eqonsayo imimango.Ngiyogiya ngiqephuze.Ngigiye kuyiyize omame nezalukazi.Besho bempongoloza ngamaphimbo emizwilili.Usho mfo kaShandu ukuth' uyalazi leliBhobhodleyana lakoMshibe.Usho liphekwe kweyakh' imbizaUgiye kanye nalo ngaphimbo linyeNingqabashiye ze nakwabezay' ixoxw' indaba.Bhala uhlobo lomsebenzi owenziwa ngumfokaShandu.","answer":"Unguthisha / Uyafundisa. "},{"question":"கெட்டுப்போன காய்க்கும் கனிக்கும் தாவரத்திற்கேற்ப வழங்கப்படும் சொற்கள் யாவை?","answer":"சூம்பல், சிவியல், சொத்தை, வெம்பல், அளியல், அழுகல், சொண்டு, தேரைக்காய், அல்லிக்காய், ஒல்லிக்காய், கோட்டான்காய் (அ) கூகைக்காய்."},{"question":"Ambil jawaban dari pertanyaan berikut dalam kutipan: Kapankah Pesawat Ulang-Alik Challenger pertama diciptakan ?Kutipan terkait: Pesawat ulang-alik: Pesawat ulang-alik yang pertama adalah Enterprise, yang sebenarnya merupakan wahana uji terbang. Pesawat berikutnya adalah Columbia, Challenger, Discovery dan Atlantis. Challenger telah hancur ketika proses peluncuran pada tahun 1986, dan akhirnya dibuat Endeavour sebagai penggantinya. Sedangkan Columbia hancur ketika proses memasuki atmosfer bumi pada tahun 2003.","answer":"1986"},{"question":"Namakan pantai-pantai di Pulau Pinang. ","answer":"Batu Feringgi, Pantai Monyet, Pantai Kerachut dan Tanjong Bungah"},{"question":"आपूर्ति श्रृंखला व्यवस्थापनलाई अनुकूलन गर्न औद्योगिक इन्जिनियरहरूको भूमिका के हो?","answer":"औद्योगिक इन्जिनियरहरूले प्रक्रियाहरू विश्लेषण गरेर, दक्षता सुधार गरेर, र लागत घटाएर आपूर्ति श्रृंखला व्यवस्थापनलाई अनुकूलन गर्छन्। तिनीहरू आपूर्ति श्रृंखला प्रणालीहरूको समग्र प्रदर्शन बढाउन रसद, सूची व्यवस्थापन, र उत्पादन योजनामा ​​​​फोकस गर्छन्।"},{"question":"Zer da musikan serialismoa, eta nola eragiten du tonuen eta soinuen antolaketa?","answer":"Serialismoa da musikaren teknika non tonuak, erritmoak eta dinamikak serie batzuen arabera antolatzen diren. Hau musikaren egitura matematiko eta abstraktua sortzen du, tradizio harmonikoak desafiatuz."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk \\"Kelebihan Gotong-Royong dalam Masyarakat\\".","answer":"Gotong-royong merupakan tradisi turun-temurun yang diamalkan oleh masyarakat terdahulu. Amalan ini lazimnya dibuat untuk menjalankan majlis seperti kenduri perkahwinan atau majlis keramaian yang melibatkan komuniti setempat. Namun, dalam meniti arus kemodenan hari ini, amalan gotong royong semakin dilupakan oleh masyarakat konvensional di mana pelbagai manfaat yang mampu diperoleh menjadi kerugian. Tidak dinafikan, perkembangan corak kehidupan masyarakat masa kini lebih ke arah menjana pendapatan tetapi ia tidak menghalang kita untuk tetap mengamalkan gotong-royong di peringkat kecil seperti di taman perumahan dan blok pangsapuri yang kita huni. Peribahasa Melayu berkata, tak basah dek hujan, tak lekang dek panas yang bermaksud warisan tradisi kita seharusnya sentiasa relevan dan diingati oleh masyarakat kita. Oleh hal yang demikian, penting untuk kita mengenali kelebihan amalan bergotong-royong dalam masyarakat.Antara manfaat prima yang akan diperoleh apabila kita bergotong-royong adalah ia dapat memupuk semangat perpaduan antara satu sama lain. Umum sedia maklum, Malaysia merupakan negara yang unik di mana pelbagai kaum, bangsa dan agama duduk di bawah satu negara sejak mencapai kemerdekaan. Kemajmukan masyarakat ini perlu diperkukuh dari semasa ke semasa kerana terdapat segelintir daripadanya yang cuba menjadikan perbezaan perkauman dan sebagainya sebagai satu isu tetapi disebaliknya hanya ingin mendapatkan kepentingan diri. Dengan melibatkan diri dalam aktiviti gotong-royong, kita dapat mengenali jiran tetangga kita dengan lebih baik. Hubungan silaturahim akan terjalin di samping bersama-sama menyiapkan tugasan yang telah diberikan. Persis lagu nukilan artis tempatan, ikan di laut, asam di darat, dalam periuk bikin muafakat. Intihannya, bergotong-royong dapat mengukuhkan nilai perpaduan antara masyarakat supaya kesejahteraan dan keamanan yang kita kecapi hari ini berkekalan sampai bila-bila.Di samping itu, amalan bergotong-royong memberikan kelebihan kepada setiap ahli masyarakat kerana ia akan memudahkan tugasan atau objektif yang ingin dicapai. Sebagai contoh, aktiviti gotong-royong dianjurkan oleh Pihak Berkuasa Tempatan untuk membersihkan kawasan persekitaran dewan serbaguna komuniti setempat. Jika setiap diantara ahli komuniti terbabit melibatkan diri bersama-sama melakukan aktiviti pembersihan seperti mengutip sampah dan menyapu dedaun kering, ia pasti dapat diselesaikan dalam masa yang singkat. Maka, secara tidak langsung kita dapat meluangkan masa yang lebih untuk melakukan aktiviti bermanfaat yang lain. Jika dipandang daripada sudut yang lain, kita juga dapat menjimatkan kos perbelanjaan yang digunakan untuk menyelenggara kebersihan kemudahan awam. Ibarat sambil menyelam minum air. Peruntukan yang dijimatkan dapat disalurkan ke arah yang lebih baik seperti pembinaan lorong berbasikal di kawasan tertentu dan juga kemudahan gimnasium di pasang di taman rekreasi untuk penggunaan awam. Kesannya, pelbagai kerja dan manfaat lain yang akan kita peroleh sekiranya sentiasa mengamalkan aktiviti bergotong-royong. Pada masa yang sama, kebersihan kawasan persekitaran dapat dijamin jika kita kerap menjalankan aktiviti gotong-royong. Endemik denggi semakin hari semakin merunsing fikiran dan ketenteraman masyarakat kita. Nyamuk aedes yang membawa penyakit denggi lazimnya membiak di kawasan takungan air yang lama dan tidak terusik. Dengan adanya aktiviti bergotong-royong, kita dapat bersama-sama pihak berkuasa dalam membanteras pembiakan nyamuk-nyamuk yang menyebabkan berlakunya penularan wabak denggi. Setiap di antara kita perlu sedar bahawa tanggungjawab menjaga kebersihan adalah tanggungjawab bersama. Janganlah kita bersikap seperti sudah terhantuk baru terngadah di mana apabila sesuatu perkara itu menimpa kita barulah timbul kesedaran untuk melakukan sesuatu tindakan. Justeru, setiap komuniti atau organisasi seperti Rukun Tetangga seharusnya menganjurkan aktiviti gotong-royong di kawasan masing-masing sebagai langkah mengawal dan membanteras segala bentuk ancaman kesihatan kepada masyarakat. Sesungguhnya, mencegah sesuatu perkara adalah lebih baik daripada merawat perkara tersebut.Melalui kegiatan yang mulia ini, kita juga dapat mewujudkan kawasan persekitaran yang indah, kemas dan teratur. Rumahku syurgaku merupakan satu perumpamaan yang menunjukkan bahawa rumah adalah tempat dimana segala perkara yang bermakna berlaku dan memberi memori yang indah buat kita yang mendiaminya. Sejajar dengan itu, kita seharusnya berusaha sebaik mungkin untuk memelihara kebersihan dan keindahan kawasan persekitarannya dengan mengajak jiran tetangga untuk bergotong-royong. Rumah merupakan keperluan asas setiap manusia dan sudah pasti bagi menjamin keindahan dalam hidup yang kita jalani setiap hari hendaklah bermula daripada rumah kita. Kaajian menyatakan bahawa kejiranan yang berada dalam keadaan bersih, kemas dan teratur melahirkan komuniti yang bahagia dan sejahtera. Tambahan pula, kita sebagai penghuni kediaman akan berasa lebih selamat untuk kekal menetap di kawasan tersebut kerana jiran tetangga kita mempunyai kesedaran atas tanggungjawab yang sama iaitu menjamin kesejahteraan semua. Natijahnya, bergotong-royong dapat memperindahkan lagi kawasan persekitaran kita kerana pemandangan yang indah melahirkan sifat bahagia dan tenteram.Secara tuntas, amalan bergotong-royong sudah semsetinya akan memberikan pelbagai kelebihan kepada masyarakat yang menyertainya dengan aktif. Amalan tradisi nenek dan moyang kita pastinya memeberi seribu satu manfaat kepada kita secara umumnya. Kalau tidak, mengapa mereka mengamalkan pada ketika dahulu. Kini ia terletak kepada kesedaran setiap individu sama ada untuk melibatkan diri dalam aktiviti komuniti atau bersikap endah tak endah. Kita telah simpulkan bahawa dengan aktiviti bergotong-royong yang melibatkan setiap ahli komuniti dapat menjadi agen penyatu antara satu sama lain di samping faedah-faedah lain. Saranan dan galakan daripada pihak seperti Kementerian Wanita, Keluarga dan Masyarakat seharusnya lebih giat dan menggunakan semua media yang menjadi sasluran informasi masyarakat masa kini. Semoga Masayarakat yang madani dan inteligensia dapat dilahirkan hasil daripada penglibatan dalam aktiviti gotong royong dalam membantu meringankan ujian atau musibah yang melanda negara kita. Bak kata pepatah ke bukit sama didaki, ke lurah sama dituruni."},{"question":"Iza no filozofa grika mpialoha lalana ny hevitra tandrefana?","answer":"Ny filozofa grika teo amin'ny eritreritra tandrefana dia i Socrates. Izy no malaza indrindra amin'ny fomba fampianarana mifototra amin'ny fanontaniana, antsoina hoe fomba Socratic."},{"question":"ഈ വാചകം ഏത് പ്രധാന സംഭവത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്: മാത്തുണ്ണി മാത്യൂസ്  (2017 മെയ് 20-ന് അന്തരിച്ചു) ഒരു ഇന്ത്യനും, കുവൈറ്റ് റെസിഡന്റുമായിരുന്നു. 1990 -ലെ ഇറാഖ് കുവൈറ്റ് യുദ്ധത്തിലകപ്പെട്ട 170,000 ഇന്ത്യക്കാരെ സുരക്ഷിതമായി നാട്ടിലെത്തിച്ച എയർലിഫ്റ്റ് ഇവാക്കുവേഷൻ നടത്തിയത് ഇദ്ദേഹമാണ്. ലോകത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും വലിയ സിവിലിയൻ ഇവാക്കുവേഷനായി ഇതറിയപ്പെടുന്നു. 2016 ൽ ഈ സംഭവുമായി ബന്ധപ്പെട്ടു അക്ഷയ് കുമാർ നായകനായ \\"എയർലിഫ്റ്റ്\\" എന്ന ചലച്ചിത്രം പുറത്തിറങ്ങി.","answer":"1990 -ലെ ഇറാഖ് കുവൈറ്റ്"},{"question":"Madaxa Labaad: Xuquuqda, Xorriyaadka Aasaasiga Ah Ee Qofka Iyo Xaddidaadooda.","answer":"Qodobka 39aad. Sixidda Ku-xadgudubka (1) Xuquuqda Aadanaha Sharcigu waa in uu qeexaa habraac habboon oo lagu saxayo xadgudubyada xaquuqda Aadanaha. (2) Sixidda xadgudubyadaas waa in lagu helaa maxkamad ay dadku si fudud dacwad uga furan karaan. Qof ama urur kastaa wuu tegi karaa maxkamad, si uu u difaaco xuquuqda dadka kale ee aan awoodin in ay iskood isu difaacaan."},{"question":"Biorąc pod uwagę następujące zdanie, nazwij części mowy:\\"Lubię jabłka\\".","answer":"Lubię - czasownikjabłka - rzeczownik"},{"question":"Blessing pa iya rẹ sinu oko n’Ilẹ-Oluji, o ni ọrọ pasitọ ṣọọsi awọn loun tẹle","answer":"Ọwọ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ondo ti tẹ obinrin ẹni ọgbọn ọdun kan, Blessing Jimoh, lori ẹsun pipa iya rẹ, Abilekọ Njeoma Odo, sinu oko n’Ilẹ-Oluji, nijọba ibilẹ Ilẹ-Oliji /Oke-Igbo.Iya ọlọmọ mẹrin ọhun ni wọn lo sa mama agbalagba naa ladaa pa mọ inu oko lasiko ti wọn n ṣiṣẹ lọwọ l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ to kọja.Afurasi naa ni wọn ṣafihan rẹ ni olu ileesẹ wọn to wa lagbegbe Alagbaka, niluu Akurẹ, lọsan-an ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ ta a wa yii.Nigba ta a si n fọrọ wa Blessing lẹnu wo, oun funra rẹ jẹwọ pe loootọ loun pa iya oun nibi tawọn ti jọ n ṣiṣẹ, ada lo ni oun fi dumbu obinrin to wa lati ipinlẹ Enugu ọhun bii ẹran bo tilẹ jẹ pe oun ti ṣe kinni ọhun tán ki oju oun too walẹ.Lati bii ọdun diẹ sẹyin lo ni arun ọpọlọ ti n yọ oun lẹnu, ó ni ṣọọsi kan ti oun ti lọọ gbadura ni pasitọ ti jẹ ko ye oun pe ajẹ ni iya ọhun.O ni ọpọ igba loun ti gbe igbesẹ ati bẹ ẹ, ṣugbọn ti ko si ayipada rara lori ọrọ aisan naa.Kọmisanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ, Bọlaji Salami, ti ni o di dandan ki ọdaran ọhun foju bale-ẹjọ lẹyin ti iwadii awọn ba ti pari lori ẹsun ti wọn fi kan an."},{"question":"Hatagi ko ug mga lugar na pwede bisitahan sa usa ka 8 year old na bata","answer":"Niay listahan sa mga lugar pwede bisitahan sa usa ka 8 year old na bata:ZoosParksBeachesAquariumMuseumsShort hiking trailsAmusement parksTrampoline parksRestaurants nga naay indoor play areaArcadeLazer tagLibraryBowlingPaint ball"},{"question":"கேள்வி: சிற்றிலக்கியம் தோற்றம் வளர்ச்சி குறித்து எழுதுக.","answer":"பதில் :சிற்றிலக்கியம் முன்னுரைதமிழ் மொழியில் அமைந்த இலக்கிய செல்வங்களுள் ஒன்றாக திகழ்வது தான் சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் ஆகும். தமிழில் நெடும் பாடல்களாக அமைந்த பிரபந்த வகைகளைச் சிற்றிலக்கியம் என்பர்.இதன் வித்தும் வளர்ச்சியும் சங்ககாலத்தில் உள்ளது. ஆற்றுப்படை ஒரு துறையாகவும், தனிப்பெரும் பாடல்களாகவும் அன்றே வளர்ச்சி பெற்றன.தொல்காப்பியம், பாட்டு தொகை, பதினெண் கீழ்க்கணக்கு, ஐம்பெருங்காப்பியங்கள், ஐஞ்சிறு காப்பியம், பக்தி பாடல்கள், இசை நாடக இலக்கியங்கள் இதற்கு சான்றாகின்றன.இத்தகைய சிற்றிலக்கியங்களின் தோற்றமும் வளர்ச்சியும் பற்றி இக்கட்டுரையில் காண்போம்.சிற்றிலக்கியம்குறைந்த எண்ணிக்கையுடைய பாடல்களைக் கொண்டு படைக்கப்படும் இலக்கிய வகைகளை சிற்றிலக்கியம் என்பர். அகப்பொருள் அல்லது புறப்பொருளில் ஏதேனும் ஒரு துறையைப் பற்றியதாக அமையும்.அறம், பொருள், இன்பம், வீடு ஆகியவற்றில் ஒன்றோ பலவோ குறைந்துவரின் இவை சிற்றிலக்கியம் எனவும் விளக்கம் கொடுக்கலாம்.வடமொழியில் பிரபந்தம் என்று அழைக்கப்படுவதை நாம் சிற்றிலக்கியங்களாகக் கொள்கின்றோம்.பிரபந்தம்சிற்றிலக்கியங்களை வடமொழியில் பிரபந்தங்கள் என அழைக்கிறார்கள். பிரபந்தம் என்பதனை தமிழில் யாப்பு என்ற சொல்லோடு ஒப்பிடலாம். இரண்டும் கட்டுதல் என்ற பொருளிலேயே வழங்கப்படுகின்றன.பாட்டியல் நூல்களின் படி 96 வகைப் பிரபந்தங்களில் காப்படி புராணம், சிறு நூல்கள் என அனைத்தும் இடம்பெற்றமை அறியலாம்.காலம்ஆற்றுப்படை இலக்கியங்கள் தோன்றிய சங்க காலத்திலிருந்தே சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் தோற்றம் பெற்றாலும் சிற்றிலக்கியம் உச்ச நிலையில் இருந்த காலத்தை நாம் கணக்கில் கொள்ள வேண்டியுள்ளது.பல்லவர் காலத்தை காப்பிய காலம் என்றும் இடைக்காலச் சோழர் காலத்தை காப்பியக் காலம் என்றும் அதன்மேலோங்கிய தன்மையால் கூறுகிறோம். அதுபோல நாயக்கர் காலத்தைச் சிற்றிலக்கிய காலம் என்று அழைக்கலாம் என்கிறார் டாக்டர் தமிழண்ணல்.அவ்வகையில் கி.பி 15, கி.பி 16, மற்றும் 17 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டுகளை நாம் சிற்றிலக்கிய காலமெனக் கூறலாம்.அமைப்புசிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் அளவில் சிறியதாக அமைகின்ற பல் துறை சார்ந்த பெரிய நூல்கள் போல் அமையாமல் ஒரு சில துறைகளை ஆழமாக பார்ப்பவையாக அவை அமைகின்றன.அறம், பொருள், இன்பம், வீடு என்னும் நான்கு உறுதிப் பொருள்களுள் ஏதேனும் ஒன்றை தருவதாக அமைவது சிற்றிலக்கியம்.பாடப்பெறும் கடவுள் அல்லது மன்னன் அல்லது வள்ளல் ஆகியோரை சிறப்பிக்கும். உதாரணம் உலா – இதில் தலைவன் உலாவரும் காட்சியை மட்டுமே சிறப்பித்துப் பாடப்படும்.முடிவுரைசிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் மூலம் ஓரளவு தமிழ்ப் பண்பாட்டினை தமிழக வரலாற்றையும் அறிய முடிகின்றது. கற்பனை ஆற்றலைப் பெருக்குவதில் சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் பேருதவியாக அமைகின்றன.அளவில் சிறியதாயினும் பெரும் சுவையைத் தருவனவாக சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் காணப்படுகின்றன. பள்ளு போன்ற சிற்றிலக்கியங்களின் மூலம் அக்கால மக்களின் சமூக வாழ்வியலை நம்மால் அறியமுடிகின்றது.தெய்வங்கள் மீது அமைந்துள்ள சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் மூலம் ஊர், வரலாறு, புராணக்கதைகள், மக்களின் வழிபாட்டு முறைகள் ஆகியவற்றை நாம் அறிந்துகொள்ள முடிகின்றமை சிறப்பிற்குரியதாகும்."},{"question":"የቢል ክሊንተን አባት ስም ማነው?","answer":"ዊሊያም ጄፈርሰን ብላይዝ ጁኚየር"},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa Venezuela na da arzikin mai?","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"Dañu maa gaañoon.","answer":"I’ve been injured."},{"question":"అడిదము సూరకవి చాటుపద్యాన్ని వివరించండి.","answer":"కొన్ని కొన్ని చాటుపద్యాలు వెలలేని చారిత్రక సత్యాలకు నిలువుటద్దాల్లాగా నిలిచిపోయినవి. అడిదము సూరకవి చెప్పిన ఈ క్రింది పద్యం అందుకు ఒక ఉదాహరణ.“మెత్తనైయున్న అరటాకు మీదగాకమంటమీదను చెల్లునే ముంటివాడిబీదలైయున్న మా బోంట్ల మీదగాకకలదె క్రొవ్వాడి బాదుల్ల’ ఖాను మీద”అడిదము సూరకవి పూసపాటి విజయరామరాజు యొక్క ఆస్థానకవి. ఆ రాజు సూరకవిపై ఆగ్రహించి ఆస్థానం నుండి సూరకవిని తొలగించాడు. ఆ రాజుగారు ఒకసారి మహమ్మదీయ రాజైన బాదుల్లాఖానుతో యుద్ధము చేసి ఓడిపోయాడు. తన మనస్సులోని కోపాన్ని సూరకవి ఈ చాటుపద్యం ద్వారా విజయరామరాజుకు చురకలంటించాడు.ఈ చారిత్రక వృత్తం ఈ చాటుపద్యం ద్వారా లోకానికి తెలిసింది. అంతకు పూర్వం విజయరామరాజు బాదుల్లాఖానును యుద్ధంలో ఓడించిన వృత్తాంతాన్ని కూడా సూరకవిని “ఢిల్లీ లోపల గోలకొండ పురినిండన్ నీ ప్రశంసల్” అను పద్యం ద్వారా కీర్తించటం కూడా జరిగింది. ఇలా చాటుపద్యాలు చారిత్రక సత్యాలను ప్రపంచానికి చాటుతున్నాయి."},{"question":"Làm một bài văn tả về một người bạn thân của em","answer":"Em có một người bạn thân, chơi với em từ bé. Ngoài những người bạn trong lớp, có lẽ bạn ấy là một người mà em yêu quý nhất. Bạn là Ngọc Duy ở lớp kế bên.Em quen bạn Duy trong một lần tình cờ gặp nhau trên sân trường. Chúng em nhanh chóng làm quen với nhau, chơi với nhau rồi thân nhau lúc nào không biết. Năm nay, Duy tròn mười một tuổi. Bạn có dáng người vừa phải, không cao cũng không thấp, chỉ cao hơn em nửa cái đầu. Làn da hơi ngăm ngăm trông rất rắn chắc. Mái tóc bạn đen nhánh, lúc nào cũng gọn gàng. Gương mặt đầy đặn và hay tươi cười. Đôi mắt sáng tinh anh làm bạn có vẻ rất thông minh. Bạn làm gì cũng nhanh nhẹn, chỉ nhoáng cái là xong.Tính Duy rất hiền lành, hay nhường nhịn bạn. Mỗi khi rảnh rỗi, bạn ấy thường rủ em học chung hoặc chơi cờ. Mỗi khi chơi trò gì đó, nó thường nhường bạn chơi trước. Dù chơi có thua hay thắng, nét mặt bạn ấy vẫn luôn tươi cười. Bạn ấy học rất giỏi, thường được cô giáo khen. Năm nào bạn ấy cũng được nhận phần thưởng của trường và của lớp.Chơi với nhau gần năm năm, chúng em đã có rất nhiều kỉ niệm. Có lần, chúng em chơi đuổi bắt, Duy bị vấp cục đá, té trầy hết cả chân tay. Hai đứa sợ bố mẹ xanh cả mặt mày. Rất may là không có chuyện gì xảy ra. Hôm sau gặp nhau lại cười toe toét.Năm năm học trôi qua thật nhanh. Sang năm đã chuyển trường mới chắc là không còn học chung với nhau nữa. Dù thế nào đi nữa, chúng em vẫn sẽ giữ bao kỉ niệm đẹp về nhau"},{"question":"ජංගම සන්නිවේදනය (Mobile Communication) ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"රැහැන් භාවිතයෙන් තොරව දුරස්ථව සිට තොරතුරු සන්නිවේදනය කිරීමයි. මුල් අවධියේ දී දෙදෙනෙකු අතර පමණක් (ඒකපථ) ජංගම සන්නිවේදනය සිදු වුවද, මෙහි දියුණුවත් සමඟ බොහෝ දෙනෙකු අතර ජංගම සන්නිවේදනය සිදු කිරීමට හැකියාව ලැබී ඇත. මේ සඳහා බහුපථ ක්‍රමය උපයෝගී කරගෙන ඇත.බහුපථ ක්‍රමය,කාලය බෙදීමේ බහු ප්‍රවේශය (Time Division Multiple Access –TDMA)කේත බෙදීමේ බහු ප්‍රවේශය(Code Division Multiple Access –CDMA)සංඛ්‍යාතය බෙදීමේ බහු ප්‍රවේශය(Frequency Division Multiple Access –FDMA)"},{"question":"Qual é a diferença entre carvão antracito e carvão betuminoso?","answer":"O carvão antracito é um tipo de carvão com classificação superior devido à sua maior percentagem de carbono (87%) e menores impurezas. O antracito processa uma quantidade maior de calor por unidade de massa do que os outros tipos de carvão. Ele não acende facilmente e queima de forma limpa. O antracito é mais duro do que outros tipos de carvão; portanto, é conhecido como carvão duro. O antracito é formado quando outros tipos de carvão de classificação inferior são submetidos a temperaturas mais altas por um longo período de tempo. "},{"question":"Explica la complejidad temporal en el contexto de la programación competitiva de una manera informal.","answer":"El análisis de la complejidad temporal de un algoritmo es una técnica que permite entender qué tan rápido un algoritmo es sin necesidad de tener que implementarlo ni ejecturar dicho programa.La idea es la siguiente: bajo los modelos computacionales estándar (por ejemplo, Random Access Machine), se pueden definir ciertas operaciones atómicas, como suma, restar, multiplicar y dividir dos números, también modificar un byte o acceder a una posición en memoria. Entonces, podemos definir la complejidad de un programa de acuerdo a la cantidad de operaciones atómicas realizadas con respecto al tamaño de la entrada.Cabe mencionar que aunque consideramos todas las operaciones atómicas igual de baratas, en realidad no lo son; por ejemplo, la multiplicación es más cara que la adición. Debido a eso, obviamos las constantes en nuestro análisis, y nos preocupamos más por el crecimiento de la cantidad de operaciones.Por ejemplo, los siguientes bucles en Python tienen la misma complejidad computacional, aunque uno hace n iteraciones, otro hace 3*n + 2 iteraciones, y el otro hace n/2 iteraciones.sum = 0for i in range(n):     sum += ifor i in range(3*n + 2):      sum += ifor i in range(n//2):      sum += iLas complejidades computacionales más populares son:- logarítmica: O(log n), es cuando la cantidad de operaciones crece de manera lineal cuando n crece exponencialmente. Un ejemplo es la búsqueda binaria.- lineal: O(n), cuando la cantidad de operaciones es proporcional a n, por ejemplo, la búsqueda lineal.- O(n log n), por ejemplo ordenar una lista de n elementos con el algoritmo de merge sort.- O(n^2), por ejemplo ordenar una lista de n elementos con el algoritmo de bubble sort.- O(2^n), exponencial, por ejemplo extraer todos los subconjuntos de un conjunto de tamaño n."},{"question":"Di manakah terletaknya Hokkaido? ","answer":"Hokkaidō (bahasa Jepun: 北海道) adalah pulau kedua terbesar di Jepun dan suatu prefektur yang terletak di bahagian paling utara negara tersebut dibahagikan kepada 47 peringkat subwilayah. Selat Tsugaru yang memisahkan Hokkaidō daripada Honshū walaupun kedua-dua buah pulau dihubungkan melalui terowong bawah laut iaitu Terowong Seikan. Bandar terbesar di Hokkaidō ialah pusat bandarnya, Sapporo dimana ia juga merupakan bandar terancang ordinan."},{"question":"ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ‘ਤੇ ਸੰਖੇਪ ਨੋਟ ਲਿਖੋ ।","answer":"ਜਦੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਹੀ ਔਰਤ ਨਾਲ ਇੱਕ ਹੀ ਆਦਮੀ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਵਿਆਹ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਜਦੋਂ ਤੱਕ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਜਿਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਾਂ ਇੱਕ ਦੂਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਤਲਾਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੈ ਲੈਂਦੇ, ਉਹ ਦੂਜਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਵਾ ਸਕਦੇ ।"},{"question":"Ырыскелди Осмонкуловдун аткаруусундагы Энекебай обонду ырынын сөзү кайсы?","answer":"Энекебай, о ыйыгым ыйыгым,Энекебай, о кутманым уюгум.Алып келип тамырыңдан алтымыш,Алтын өмүр бешигиңе уюдум.Сен көз жумсаң унутармын жыл чыдап,Мен көз жумсам көз өткөнчө буркурап.Апакебай кара чачың куу болоор,Кош эмчегиң алмак-салмак зыркырап.Энекебай, билем туям эмгегиң,Энекебай өмүр жашың мен жедим.Кантип мени карыш жолго узатсын,Кактап күн-түн ак сүтүңдү эмгенмин.Кактап күн-түн ак сүтүңдү эмгенмин,Кирпик какпай канча жолу термедиң.Татыбайт го минуталык толгооңо,Менин күндү алып келип бергеним."},{"question":"Суроо: Жердин атмосферасында озон катмарынын ролу кандай?","answer":"Жооп: Озон катмары күндөн келген зыяндуу ультрафиолет (УК) нурланууну сиңирип, бөгөттөп, Жердеги жашоону ашыкча УК таасиринен коргойт."},{"question":"வினா:   நாகசாகி தினம் எப்போது அனுசரிக்கப்படுகின்றது?","answer":"விடை:  நாகசாகி தினம் ஆகஸ்ட் 9  -ல் அனுசரிக்கப்படுகின்றது.1.  நாகசாகி ஜப்பானில் உள்ள ஒரு பெருநகரம் ஆகும். 2.  இந்நகரத்தின் மீது இரண்டாம் உலகப்போரின் போது ஹிரோஷிமா நகரத்திற்கு அடுத்து கொழுத்த மனிதன் என்னும் அணுகுண்டு, ஆகத்து 9ஆம் நாளன்று அமெரிக்கா வீசியது."},{"question":"Eeyan mẹẹẹdọgbọn ku ninu ija awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun l’Ogun","answer":"Pẹlu bi ija agba ṣe n waye lemọlemọ laarin awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun oriṣiiriṣii kaakiri ipinlẹ Ogun, ti wọn si n pa ara wọn, Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa nipinlẹ yii, Edward Awolọwọ Ajogun, ti sọ pe ko din leeyan mẹẹẹdọgbọn (25) to ti padanu ẹmi wọn ninu awọn ija agba ọhun.Ọjọ Iṣẹgun, ọjọ kejila, oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun 2021, ni Ajogun sọrọ yii ni Kọmanmdi ọlọpaa to wa ni Igbẹba, n’Ijẹbu-Ode, lasiko to ba awọn olori agbegbe, awọn ọdọ atawọn alẹnulọrọ lori ohun to n ṣẹlẹ naa pade, to si tun foju awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun mọkanla han fawọn akọroyin.Ṣe lẹnu ọjọ mẹta yii, Ijẹbu-Ode ko sinmi lọwọ awọn ọmọkunrin ti wọn n ṣe ẹgbẹ okunkun Ẹiyẹ, Aiye ati Aake Dudu, pẹlu bi wọn ṣe n ko idaamu ba awọn araalu ti ọrọ ko kan lasiko ti wọn ba bẹrẹ wahala wọn.Kọmiṣanna sọ pe ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun mẹrindinlogun lọwọ awọn ti ba laarin oṣu kan si asiko yii, bẹẹ ni ọpọlọpọ nnkan ija pẹlu oogun abẹnugọngọ lawọn ọlọpaa ri gba lọwọ wọn. O fi kun un pe lọjọ kọkandinlọgbọn, oṣu kejila, ọdun to kọja, ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun naa padanu ẹmi ẹ lasiko tawọn ọlọpaa koju wọn.Bo ṣe waa jẹ pe awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ Aiye, Aake Dudu ati Ẹiye ko fẹẹ gba alaafia laaye yii, Ajogun ni awọn agbofinro naa ko ni i pada lẹyin wọn nipinlẹ Ogun yii. O lawọn yoo maa wa wọn jade nibi yoowu ki wọn sa gba ni, wọn yoo si maa jiya to yẹ wọn labẹ ofin.Lọjọ kẹsan-an, oṣu kin-in-ni yii, ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun Aake Dudu (Black Axe), Micheal Jayeọla, padanu ẹmi ẹ nigba ti wọn yinbọn pa a, bẹẹ ni wọn tun ge apa rẹ paapaa lọja Ijẹbu-Imushin. CP Ajogun lo fidi eyi mulẹ, bẹẹ lo ni bawọn ọlọpaa yoo ṣe maa ṣigun lọọ ba awọn ọmọ to n da alaafia Ijẹbu-Ode ati ipinlẹ Ogun lapapọ ru naa ni yii.Ọga ọlọpaa yii ko ṣai de awọn orita ti wọn ni ibẹ lawọn ọmọ Aiye, Ẹiye ati Aake Dudu fi n ṣe ibuba n’Ijẹbu-Ode. O kilọ fawọn ọdọ ibẹ pe ki wọn jawọ bi wọn ko ba fẹẹ bọ sọwọ ofin, bẹẹ lo kilọ fawọn obi paapaa pe ki wọn fa awọn ọmọ wọn leti, kawọn olori adugbo naa ba awọn eeyan wọn sọrọ, nitori ẹni tọwọ ba tẹ pẹlu bi nnkan ṣe n lọ yii, tọhun ko ni i le royin tan nigba tọwọ ọlọpaa ba tẹ ẹ. Awọn mi-in ti wa ni kootu ninu wọn ti wọn n jẹjọ apaayan ati iṣeeṣipaniyan gẹgẹ bi Ajogun ṣe wi."},{"question":"Sence dunyanin en guzel ilk 10 sehri hangileridir?","answer":"Binden fazla seyahat yazarı ve acentasıyla anket yapan seyahat sitesi Flight Network'e gore ilk 10'daki sehirler sunlar:1. Paris, Fransa2. New York, ABD3. Londra, İngiltere4. Venedik, İtalya5. Vancouver, Kanada6. Barselona, ​​İspanya7. Cape Town, Güney Afrika Cumhuriyeti8. San Francisco, ABD9. Sidney, Avustralya10. Roma, İtalya"},{"question":"Complete a frase: \\"Com a crescente conscientização sobre a saúde mental, as empresas...\\"","answer":"Com a crescente conscientização sobre a saúde mental, as empresas estão implementando programas de apoio aos funcionários para reduzir o estresse no trabalho."},{"question":"ਆਪਣੇ ਸਕੂਲ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਅਧਿਆਪਕ ਨੂੰ ਬਿਮਾਰੀ ਦੀ ਛੁੱਟੀ ਲੈਣ ਲਈ ਬਿਨੈ-ਪੱਤਰ ਲਿਖੋ ।","answer":"ਸੇਵਾ ਵਿਖੇ                                                                                                                                                     ਮੁੱਖ ਅਧਿਆਪਕ ਸਾਹਿਬ,                                                                                                                                              ਰਿਆਨ ਇੰਟਰਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਸਕੂਲ,                                                                                                                                                                      ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਸਰ ।ਸ਼੍ਰੀਮਾਨ ਜੀ,ਬੇਨਤੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਸਕੂਲ ਤੋਂ ਘਰ ਜਾਂਦਿਆਂ ਰਸਤੇ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਬੁਖ਼ਾਰ ਚੜ੍ਹ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ । ਇਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਅੱਜ ਮੈਂ ਸਕੂਲ ਵਿਚ ਹਾਜ਼ਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ । ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਅੱਜ ਦੀ ਛੁੱਟੀ ਦੇ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਜਾਵੇ । ਮੈਂ ਆਪ ਜੀ ਦਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਧੰਨਵਾਦੀ ਹੋਵਾਂਗਾ ।ਆਪ ਜੀ ਦਾ ਆਗਿਆਕਾਰ,ਅਜੀਤ ਕੁਮਾਰ,ਰੋਲ ਨੰ: 12ਮਿਤੀ : 10 ਦਸੰਬਰ, 20 ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀ ਚੌਥੀ ਏ ।"},{"question":"Eni kan fara pa lasiko ija awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ PDP l’Ekiti","answer":"Arabinrin kan, Bola Owolabi, to jẹ olori awọn obinrin ninu ẹgbẹ PDP ni wọọdu kẹsan-an, nijọba ibilẹ Ado, ti wa ni ileewosan bayii. Eyi waye nitori ifarapa to ni ninu ija awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ PDP to ṣẹlẹ niluu Ado-Ekiti l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii.Ija ajaku akata yii waye nigba ti awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ naa n ṣepade ọlọsọọsẹ wọn laduugbo Odo-Ado, niluu Ado-Ekiti. Lasiko ija naa to gba bii ọgbọn iṣẹju ni Arabinrin Owolabi ti fara pa pẹlu bo ṣe foju gba igi ti ọkan lara awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ ju,  ti won si gbe e digba digba lọ sileewosan nibi to ti n gba itọju lọwọlọwọ.Ọkan lara ọmọ ẹgbẹ PDP ti iṣẹlẹ naa ṣojú rẹ ṣo pe awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ PDP ti wọọdu kẹsan-an lo ko ara wọn jọ lati bẹrẹ ipade wọn,ti olori awọn obinrin ni wọọdu naa, Arabinrin Bọla Owolabi, si dide lati sọrọ iṣaaju. Bayii ni awuyewuye kan sadeede waye, eyi to ja si ariyanjiyan laarin Arabinrin Owolabi yii ati Ọgbẹni Tosin Adebayọ, to jẹ amugbalẹgbẹẹ fun alaga ijọba ibile Ado-Ekiti tẹlẹ Ọnarebu, Ayọdeji Ogunṣakin.Lẹyin iṣẹju diẹ ti wọn ti bẹrẹ ija naa ni ẹjẹ bẹrẹ si i jade loju ati ni gbogbo ara Arabinrin Owolabi, eyi to jẹ ki awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ yooku gbe e lọ si ileewosan lati gba itọju.Lara awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ naa to ba ALAROYE sọrọ sọ pe Ọgbẹni Adebayọ, yii lo la igi nla kan mọ oju Arabinrin Owolabi nigba ti awuyewuye naa n lọ lọwọ.Wọn sọ pe Ọgbẹni Adebayọ lo n ja fun Oloye Bisi Kọlawọle to fẹe ̣dije fun ipo gomina ipinlẹ Ekiti ninu eto idibo ọdun to n bọ ni ipinlẹ oun. Bisi Kọlawọle yii jẹ ọkan lara ọmọlẹyin Ayọ Fayoṣe to jẹ gomina ipinlẹ Ekiti tẹlẹri, ti gbogbo awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ to jẹ ti Fayoṣe si n tẹle.Nigba ti Arabinrin Owolabi n ja fun Igbakeji Gomina ipinlẹ ọhun tẹlẹ, Ọjọgbọn Oluṣọla Eleka, ti oun naa tun fẹe ̣dije fun ipo gomina, ṣugbọn ti ọga rẹ tẹlẹ yii ko fara mọ ọn.Wọn ti fi ọrọ ija naa to awọn ọlọpaa to wa ni Okesa, niluu Ado-Ekiti, ati awọn ajọ obinrin agbẹjọro (FIDA)  nipinlẹ Ekiti leti ki wọn le bẹrẹ igbesẹ ati iwadii lori ọrọ naa.Gbogbo akitiyan ti ALAROYE sa lati ba olori awọn obinrin ninu ẹgbẹ PDP, naa sọrọ lo ja si pabo, pẹlu bo ṣe n gba itọju lọwọ nileewosan kan to jẹ ti aladaani niluu Ado-Ekiti ati pe oun ko fẹe ̣sọrọ lori ọrọ naa, ayafi ti awọn agba inu ẹgbẹ naa ba gbọ ọrọ naa."},{"question":"නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගය ජයග්‍රහණය කළ පළමු කාන්තාව කවුද?","answer":"නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගයක් දිනූ පළමු කාන්තාව වූයේ 1903 දී භෞතික විද්‍යාව සඳහා  නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගයෙන් පිදුම් ලැබූ මාරි කියුරි ය. විකිරණශීලිත්වය පිළිබඳ ඔවුන්ගේ වැඩකටයුතු වෙනුවෙන් ඇය සිය සැමියා වන පියරේ කියුරි සහ හෙන්රි බෙකරල් සමඟ එක්ව ත්‍යාගය ලබා ගත්තාය. මාරි කියුරිගේ ජයග්‍රහණ එතැනින් නතර වූයේ නැත. ඇය 1911 දී දෙවන නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගය (රසායන විද්‍යාව සඳහා) දිනා ගත්තාය. ඒ ඇය රේඩියම් සහ පොලෝනියම් මූලද්‍රව්‍ය සොයා ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන්ය. විවිධ විද්‍යාත්මක ක්ෂේත්‍ර දෙකක නොබෙල් ත්‍යාග දිනාගත් එකම පුද්ගලයා  ඇයයි."},{"question":"Inona no atao tsiny ?","answer":"  Ny tsiny dia hery manimba mitambesatra amin’ny olona nandika fady ka mahavoa azy eo amin’ny fiainany manontolo: ny fahasalamana, ny fananany ary ny taranany.Ny tsiny dia fahadisoana na fahotana noho ny fanaovana zavatra tsy tokony ho natao na amin’Andriamanitra na amin’ny Razana na amin’olombelona na zavatra hafa.Ny tsiny izany dia fanamelohana ataon’ny mpiara-belona amin’ny olona iray noho ny fahadisoana nataony na tandrina na tsy tandrina izany. Mety tsy fahafaham-po na tsy fahafenoana na kilema ihany koa ny tsiny, araka ny fitenenana hoe: “Indrokelin’ny mpandrafitra” sy ny hoe “tovovavy tsara tarehy petak’orona ka voatandro iray no tsininy.”Ny tsiny dia enti-milaza ny tsy fahalavorariana eo amin’ny olona na zavatra iray.Eo amin’ny fiaraha-miaina, ny tsiny dia ny tsy fanajana ny lamina misy eo amin’ny fiarahamonina.Ny tsiny dia ilazana ny fahavoazana mitranga eo amin’ny olona."},{"question":"Me kalmar Aqua take nufi a hausa?","answer":"Yana nufin ruwa"},{"question":"In a society where everyone has a miniature elephant as a pet, what are some unique challenges and benefits?","answer":"In this society, having a miniature elephant as a pet brings both unique challenges and benefits. One challenge is space management, as even miniature elephants require a significant amount of room to roam and play. Apartment dwellers often have community elephant parks. On the benefit side, these elephants are highly intelligent and empathetic, providing emotional support and companionship. They are trained to assist in household tasks, and their trunks are perfect for reaching high shelves or picking up small items. The bond between humans and their elephant pets is deep, fostering a community centered around care and mutual respect."},{"question":"ਨਿਸ਼ੇਚਨ ਕਿਰਿਆ ਦਾ ਵਰਣਨ ਕਰੋ ।","answer":"ਨਿਸ਼ੇਚਨ ਕਿਰਿਆ-ਪਰਾਗਕਣਗਾਹੀ ‘ਤੇ ਪੁੱਜਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਧੁਰੀ ਕੇਂਦਰਕ ਪਰਾਗਕਣ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਛੋਟੀ ਜਿਹੀ ਟਿਊਬ ਨਿਕਲਦੀ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸਨੂੰ ਪਰਾਗਨਲੀ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਹ ਇਸਤਰੀ ਕੇਸਰ ਦੀ ਪਰਾਗ ਵਹਿਣੀ ਜਾਂ ਵਰਤੀਕਾਗਰ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਅੰਡਕੋਸ਼ ਤੱਕ ਪੁੱਜਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਫਿਰ ਗੈਮੀਟੋਫਾਈਟ – ਅੰਡਾਣੁ (Ovule) ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇੱਥੇ ਨਰ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਦਾ ਯੁਗਮ ਦਾ ਮੇਲ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਨਰ ਯੁਗਮਕ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਦਾ ਯੁਗਮਕ ਦੇ । ਸ਼ੁਕਰਾਣੂ ਸੁਮੇਲ ਨੂੰ ਨਿਸ਼ਚਨ ਕਿਰਿਆ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਨਿਸ਼ੇਚਨ ਦੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਫੁੱਲ ਦੀਆਂ ਪੰਖੜੀਆਂ, ਪੁੰਕੇਸਰ, ਸਟਾਇਲ ਅਤੇ ਸਟਿਗਮਾ ਡਿਗ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਬਾਹਰੀ ਦਲ ਸੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਅੰਡਕੋਸ਼ ਤੇ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਅੰਡਕੋਸ਼ ਤੇਜ਼ੀ ਨਾਲ ਵਾਧਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਸੈੱਲ ਵਿਭਾਜਿਤ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਵਾਧਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਬੀਜ ਦਾ ਬਣਨਾ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਬੀਜ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਭਰੂਣ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਭਰੂਣ ਵਿਚ ਇੱਕ ਛੋਟੀ ਜੜ੍ਹ (ਮੂਲ ਜੜ੍ਹ), ਇੱਕ ਛੋਟਾ ਪ੍ਰੋਹ (ਕੁਰ) ਅਤੇ ਬੀਜ ਪੱਤਰ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਬੀਜ ਪੱਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਭੋਜਨ ਸੰਚਿਤ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਸਮੇਂ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਬੀਜ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਸੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਹ ਬੀਜ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਕੂਲ ਹਾਲਤਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੀਵਤ ਰਹਿ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ । ਅੰਡਕੋਸ਼ ਦੀ ਦੀਵਾਰ ਵੀ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਕ ਫਲੀ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਨਿਸ਼ੇਚਨ ਦੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਸਾਰੇ ਅੰਡਕੋਸ਼ ਨੂੰ ਫਲ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"Maseru mooy gëblag man réew?","answer":"Maseru mooy gëblag réewum Lesotho."},{"question":"मिझोराम राज्याची राजधानी कोणती आहे?(A) कोहिमा(B) इटानगर(C) गंगटोक(D) ऐझवाल=> ","answer":"(D) ऐझवाल"},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?[Neel: ] \\"Ku weddi Yàlla ba noonu ko ak i Malaakaam ak i Yonentam ak Jibriil ak Miikaayil... Yàlla it di ab noonam rekk\\".","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:[Neel:] \\"Ku weddi Yàlla ba noonoo ko ak i Malaakaam ak i Yonentam ak Jibriil ak Miikaayil... Yàlla ìt di ab noonam rekk\\"."},{"question":"كنت أقرأ في مراجعة ووجدت الجملة التالية 'تصميم جميل ولكن ملاحظه بسيطة لا يوجد في الغرفة طاوله صغيره للأكل كما لا يوجد سرير صغير للأطفال ولكن رغم ذلك سأعود مره أخرى'. هل المراجعة السابقة إيجابية سلبية او محايدة؟","answer":"المراجعة السابقة تعبر عن مشاعر إيجابية."},{"question":"س300- وحده من البنات ديال الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم وكتلقب بالزهراء ؟","answer":"ج300- السيدة فاطمة"},{"question":"\\"Para bom entendedor, meia palavra basta.\\" O que a expressão acima significa?","answer":"A expressão significa que pessoas inteligentes e perspicazes são potencialmente capazes de entender o que está implícito ou sugerido, mesmo que apenas uma parte da informação seja fornecida explicitamente."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'jika pandai menggunting, hendaklah pandai menjahitnya'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sesuatu pekerjaan yang sudah dimulai janganlah dibiarkan terbengkalai"},{"question":"Manana teny mikotorana ianaokandrimeOmeo ary teny marina :","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"mendrika\\""},{"question":"ما هي السورة الوحيدة التي تنتهي بـ “والله أعلم”؟ |  |","answer":"| سورة الأنفال"},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"மதக்குறி என்பது மாட்டு மந்தைக்காரன் தனது மாடுகளுக்குப் போடும் அடையாளம் போன்றதே."},{"question":"Imagine a futuristic society where robots and humans coexist. Write a scene depicting their interactions.","answer":" एक भविष्यवाणी भविष्यवाणी करें जहां रोबोट और मानव सहजीवन हैं। उनके बीच इंटरएक्शन को दर्शाता सीन लिखें।"},{"question":"ਲੇਖਿਕਾ ਆਪਣੀ ਡਰਾਫਟ ਜਮ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਰਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਡੈੱਡਲਾਈਨ ਤੋਂ ਖੁੰਝ ਗਈ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਲੱਗ ਰਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਕੀ ਲਿਖੇ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਨੇ ਡਰਾਫਟ ਸੋਧਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਲੱਗ ਰਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਕੀ ਲਿਖੇ।"},{"question":"රත්රන් සඳහා රසායනික සංකේතය කුමක්ද?","answer":"රත්රන් සඳහා රසායනික සංකේතය වන්නේ 'Au'ය"},{"question":"பிடல் காஸ்ட்ரோவின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"அவர்கள் சோஷலிசத்தின் தோல்வி பற்றி பேசுகின்றனர், ஆனால் ஆப்பிரிக்கா, ஆசியா மற்றும் லத்தீன் அமெரிக்காவில் எங்கே முதலாளித்துவம் வெற்றி பெற்றுள்ளது?"},{"question":"It is six o’clock in the afternoon and Mary starts to prepare dinner for us. In front of Mary, there is a table placed with different small-sized bottles of salt, sugar and pepper; different sizes of knives, long, short, big and small; a silver-colored tap and sink; a wooden round chopping board; some washing-up liquid. Putting the vegetables on the chopping board, Mary begins to cook! Sizzling, she turns on the stove and pours some oil together with garlic into the wok and starts to fry the vegetables. Smoke is coming out with a bit oily but tasty smell. Where does Mary prepare the dinner based on the above paragraph?A.\\tKitchenB.\\tLivingroomC.\\tBedroomD.\\tBathroomAnswer:","answer":"Correct option is (A). Mary prepares the dinner in the kitchen."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Ada leher, kepalanya dipasangkan, sentiasa diambil dan diletak balik oleh manusia, apakah itu?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah botol."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Trong lịch sử, chiến lược Inkspot gắn liền với tình trạng Tình trạng khẩn cấp Malaya","answer":"và chiến tranh Việt Nam.Gần đây, thuật ngữ này đã được sử dụng để chỉ chiến dịch của NATO ở Afghanistan và các chiến dịch do Mỹ đứng đầu chống lại quân nổi dậy ở Iraq."},{"question":"inona no atao hoe riorio?","answer":"ny riorio dia tady ampifamatorana iarovana ny voly amin'ny vorna; toy izany koa ny kiady, na ny horohoro,  na ny kalo, iarovana ny vary amin'ny fody"},{"question":"O ṣoju mi koro (Apa Keji)","answer":"Ṣe bi ẹ oo ṣe maa wo ọkunrin Fulani ilẹ Yoruba yii reeKo too di pe ijọba Buhari yii de, a ko gbọ ariwo tabi orukọ Ọba Fulani nibi kankan nilẹ Yoruba, bo tilẹ jẹ pe a maa n gbọ awọn ọba Hausa laarin wa. Ṣugbọn ọba Hausa yii naa ki i ṣe ọba bẹẹ, olori awọn Hausa adugbo kan lasan ni, aarin Saabo ni yoo si wa, ko si si ẹni ti yoo gbọ ariwo rẹ nibi kankan. Ṣugbọn nnkan ko ri bẹẹ mọ bayii, nitori nigba ti Gomina Babajide Sanwo-Olu Eko yii fẹẹ du ipo, Ọlọrun nikan lo mọ bo ṣe mọ aafin olori awọn Fulani to sọ ara rẹ di Ọba Fulani, Muhammed Abubakar Bambado. Araalu ko gbọ pupọ nipa rẹ ri, afi nigba idibo naa. Awọn Sanwo-Olu lọ si aafin ọba yii, nigba naa ni awọn eeyan ri ohun to wa nibẹ, ati bi aafin naa ṣe fẹrẹ ju ti Ọba Eko lọ. Ki i waa ṣe iyẹn ni, bi ko ṣe agbara ti ọkunrin naa ni, debii pe a ko gbọ Seriki Hausa mọ, ọkunrin naa lo ku to da bii olori fun ọba Hausa ati Fulani ni gbogbo ilẹ Yoruba yikayika, nitori o loun ki i ṣe olori Fulani ipinlẹ Eko nikan, pe ti gbogbo ilẹ Yoruba ni. Ko si ohun to buru bi awọn alejo kan ba ko ara wọn jọ nibi kan, ti wọn si yan olori tiwọn, ṣugbọn nigba ti olori naa ba n ta kan-n-gbọn pẹlu awọn oniluu ni wahala yoo bẹrẹ. O daju pe ko si ibikibi nilẹ Hausa ti wọn yoo ti gba iru iyẹn. Ko si ara ti ọkunrin to n pe ara rẹ ni Ọba Fulani ilẹ Yoruba yii ki i da o: aafin nla bii ti ọba gidi, awọn iranṣẹ loriṣiiriṣii ti wọn yoo maa jokoo yi i ka, awọn ẹṣọ pẹlu ohun ija lọwọ wọn, bẹẹ si ni bo ba n lọ pẹlu ẹṣin, tabi to ba n lọ si ode pẹlu ọpọlọpọ mọto, o loju ọba Yoruba ti yoo duro lẹgbẹẹ rẹ bo ba de ibi ayẹyẹ kan. Gẹgẹ bi awọn Fulani ti i maa i ṣe, bii ere ni kinni yii bẹrẹ, pẹlu ọgbọn ati ẹtan, ṣugbọn ni bayii, o ti di nla, awọn oloṣẹlu wa lo si tubọ ba nnkan jẹ fun wa. Awọn oloṣelu wa lo n paara ọdọ olori awọn Fulani yii, nitori wọn yoo ni ki wọn dibo fawọn. Nidii eyi, ọkunrin Bambado yii sọ lọsẹ to kọja pe ati oun o, atawọn ọmọ oun o, ko si ipo kankan ti awọn ko le du ni Eko yii, nitori Eko ni wọn bi oun si, Eko yii si loun bi awọn ọmọ oun naa si, ko si si ipo oṣelu kan ti yoo yọju ti wọn yoo ni oun ko le du u, tabi pe ko tọ si ọmọ oun. Itumọ eyi ni pe laipẹ lai jinna, ọmọ olori awọn Fulani yii yoo du ipo gomina Eko niyẹn o. Bo ba jẹ gbogbo ẹni ti wọn ba bi sibi kan ni i jọba nibẹ, Ọmọ Abẹokuta iba jọba Kano, ṣugbọn o daju pe awọn ara Kano ko ni i gba iyẹn. Yoruba nikan ni ki i ka iru eleyii si tẹlẹ, nitori Yoruba ko alejo mọra gan-an. Ṣugbọn awọn to ku ko ri wa bẹẹ, bi ija ba ti de kẹrẹ nilẹ Hausa, ile awọn Yoruba ati awọn ajoji mi-in lawọn ọmọ ibẹ maa n wa kiri, ti wọn yoo si maa pa wọn lai fi ti pe wọn ti wa nibẹ tipẹ ṣe. Gbogbo raurau tawọn n dan wo yii, ko si ẹni ti yoo lọ siluu wọn lọọ dan an wo, wọn yoo juwe ile baba tọhun fun un. Nigba ti ọkunrin yii ti waa jokoo si arin wa yii, to si sọ ara rẹ di olori, igba meloo lawọn Fulani yoo fi rọ kun ilẹ yii, ati awọn Fulani to jẹ ọmọ Naijiria ati awọn ti wọn jẹ ara orilẹ-ede mi-in. Ijọba atawọn oloye Eko gbọdọ fi opin si iwa ta-ni-yoo-mu-mi to fẹẹ di iwa awọn ajoji laarin wa yii o. Awọn ijoye Eko gbọdọ dide, ko gbọdọ si ọba Fulani nibi kan l’Ekoo, nitori ko si oye bẹẹ ninu ilana wa. Bi olori Fulani ba wa ni agbegbe kan, labẹ ọba agbegbe naa ni yoo wa, ki i ṣe ki olori Fulani kan sọ ara rẹ di ọba nla kan laarin wa. Ẹ kilọ fawọn oloṣelu aarin wa ki wọn ma ta Yoruba soko ẹru pata, ki wọn ma faaye gba awọn Fulani ki wọn ko ogun ja wa niluu yii lọjọ kan. Ẹ tete ṣe ohun to ba yẹ kẹ ẹ ṣe ki nnkan too bajẹ, giragira olori awọn Fulani Eko yii ṣẹẹ n pọ ju o.Ẹ gbọ, ta la ri ba wi bi ko ṣe Ọba Akiolu, ElekooNigba ti ọba kan ba wa ti ko fi ti awọn eeyan rẹ ṣe, tabi ti ko ka awọn eeyan rẹ si kinni kan, araata ni yoo gba ipo apọnle to wa lọwọ rẹ, yoo si di eeyan yẹpẹrẹ. Wahala to ṣẹlẹ si ọba Eko ṣoju wa lasiko iwọde SARS, o si fi han bi ọba naa ko ṣe niyi kan laarin awọn eeyan rẹ, koda, nitosi aafin rẹ gan-an. Ohun ti ko si jẹ ki Ọba Rilwanu Akiolu niyi bayii, ẹni to ba wo fidio kan to ṣe jade lọsẹ to kọja yoo ri i. Ninu fidio naa, Akiolu ni oun ni ọba Eko, boya awọn kan fẹ o, boya wọn ko fẹ o, oun ni Ọba le gbogbo wọn lori, ko si sohun tẹnikan ninu wọn le ṣe. Lo ba bẹrẹ si i sọ oyinbo lọ bii ilẹ bii ẹni, lo kewu lọ rai, bii ẹni pe ọba ilu oyinbo ni, ki i ṣe ọba Yoruba, tabi pe oun lọba wọn nilẹ Larubawa ti kewu dun mọ ọn lẹnu. Ọrọ ti Akiolu sọ ki i ṣe ọrọ agba to fẹẹ pari ija, ọrọ agbalagba to mura ija pẹlu awọn to n ṣẹjọba le lori ni. Ko si bi eeyan yoo ṣe maa ṣe bẹẹ ti yoo niyi loju awọn araalu rẹ, bi wọn ṣe ṣe fun un lọjọsi yii naa ni wọn yoo maa ṣe fun un. Inu buruku ni agba n ni, agbalagba ki i lọrọ buruku lẹnu; bẹẹ lo jẹ pe agba to ba wẹwu aṣeju, ẹtẹ ni yoo fi ri. Bi Akiolu ba n binu, ki i ṣe gbangba bẹẹ ni yoo ti maa fa ibinu rẹ yọ, nitori o ni iwa ti ọba gbọdọ hu lawujọ. Paripari rẹ ni pe awọn wo ni Ọba Akiolu n ba sọrọ gan-an. Ṣe awọn ọmọ Yoruba Eko lo n sọ ede oyinbo ati kewu si. Aṣe pe ede Yoruba n dojuti i ni gbangba niyẹn o, tabi pe to ba sọ Yoruba, awọn ọmọ Yoruba to fẹẹ sọ ọ fun ko ni i gbọ. Boya to ba si fi ede Yoruba ṣadura, adura naa ko ni i de ọdọ Ọlọrun ni. Nigba ti a ba pe eeyan ni ọba Yoruba, to fẹẹ ba Yoruba sọrọ, to da oyinbo palẹ, to fẹẹ ṣadura, to mu kewu ke bii Lemọọmu ayelujara. Ṣe iru ọba bẹẹ ko mọ pe oun n ta Yoruba lọpọ ni, ko mọ pe oun n fabuku kan iran oun ni, ko mọ pe oun n sọ pe ede ati aṣa awọn baba oun ko jẹ kinni kan ni, ati pe ede ti oun n sọ yii ni olori fun ede toun, ati aṣa awọn baba toun. Bẹẹ bi wọn ba fẹẹ jọba, wọn yoo maa sare kiri, wọn yoo maa bẹbẹ, wọn yoo ni Yoruba lawọn fẹẹ wa gbe ga. Awọn ọba aferugbabukun wọnyi, nigba wo ni awọn alalẹ Yoruba ko ni i binu si wọn. Iru wọn si pọ nilẹ Yoruba. Ṣugbọn ipo pataki ni Akiolu di mu, ko yee soyinbo sara Eko mọ, ko sọ Yoruba to tori ẹ gba ipo ọba, ko ma si laju silẹ ki awọn alejo gba Eko lọwọ ẹ, ko ma di ohun ti Fulani yoo le e danu nipo ọba lọjọ kan. Ẹ foṣelu silẹ, ọba to ba n ṣoṣelu ki i niyi lawujọ.Ni ti yunifasiti LAUTECH, o yẹ ki oju ti awọn agbalagba yii niO dun-un-yan pe Bọọda Isiaka Ajimọbi ti ku, ṣugbọn nibikibi to ba wa naa, alaye ọrọ yii yoo maa ba a. Raufu Arẹgbẹṣọla wa ni Abuja, ko maa gbọ. Alao Akala wa ni Ogbomọṣọ, koun naa gbọ nibẹ, bẹẹ naa si ni Ọlagunsoye Oyinlọla niluu Okuku. Gbogbo awọn wọnyi ni wọn ṣe gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ ati ti Ọṣun. Ṣugbọn  gbogbo wọn naa ni wọn yanju ọrọ LAUTECH, yunifasiti nla to jẹ ti awọn ipinlẹ mejeeji. Asiko kan naa ni Alao Akala ati Oyinlọla ṣe gomina l’Ọyọọ ati l’Ọṣun, ọrẹ si ni wọn, ṣugbọn wọn yanju ọrọ LAUTECH yii ti, bẹẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP lawọn mejeeji yii o. Ni gbogbo asiko ti awọn yii fi n ṣe gomina, awọn APC fẹrẹ bu wọn pa, wọn ni to ba jẹ awọn ni, awọn yoo yanju ọrọ naa kia. Nigba ti Ọlọrun yoo ṣe e, Arẹgbẹ ati Ajimọbi di gomina, ACN ni wọn jọ n ṣe ki wọn too di APC, aṣaaju ẹgbẹ wọn si ni Bọla Tinubu i ṣe. Bọla Tinubu yii, awọn yii naa ni wọn fi ṣe baba isalẹ fun yunifasiti naa, wọn ni yoo mu daadaa ba wọn. Ṣugbọn ati Arẹgbẹ, ati Ajimọbi, ati Tinubu funra ẹ, wọn yanju ọrọ naa ti: igberaga, emi-ni-mo-jaja-to-bayii ati imọtara-wọn-nikan ko jẹ ki wọn le ba ara wọn sododo, ki wọn si yanju ọrọ lori ohun ini awa ọmọ Yoruba. Tabi ki lo na wọn? Ki ọkunrin ri ejo, ki obinrin pa a, ṣebi ki ejo ma ti lọ ni. Bi LAUTECH ba wa ni Ọyọ, ṣe ki i ṣe ilẹ Yoruba ni. Tabi to jẹ Ọṣun naa lo wa, ṣe ki i ṣe ilẹ Yoruba ni. Ọlọrun nikan lo mọ bi awọn agbalagba wọnyi ti ṣe ronu, ti ironu naa si dorikodo pata, nitori ironu ti ko mu anfaani kankan fun wa nilẹ Yoruba ni, ijiya to si ti idi iwa wọn yii wa fun awọn oṣiṣẹ ati akẹkọọ yunifasiti yii, eeyan ko gbọdọ ṣadura pe ki Ọlọrun san awọn oloṣelu wọnyi lẹsan to ba tọ si wọn ni. Ẹ waa wo awọn gomina tuntun meji yii, Ṣeyi Makinde ati Gboyega Oyetọla. Ọna yoowu ti awọn gba ti wọn fi yanju ẹ, ko sẹni to fẹẹ beere, ohun ti inu gbogbo eeyan dun si ni pe wọn yanju ọrọ naa laarin ara wọn, ijọba si ba wọn fọwọ si i. Ohun ti wọn n pe ni ijọba ati agbọye niyi. Makinde ki i ṣe ọmọ APC, bẹẹ ni Adegboyega ki i ṣe ọmọ  PDP, ṣugbọn wọn ri ọrọ yii bii ọrọ to kan gbogbo Yoruba, wọn si ṣe ohun to yẹ ki wọn ṣe. Ọrọ oṣelu yatọ si idagbasoke ilu ati agbegbe ẹni, ẹni to ba fi idagbasoke awọn ẹya rẹ silẹ to gba oṣelu mu, yoo jẹbi gbẹyin ni. Oṣelu lawọn Arẹgbẹ waa ṣe, ati Oyinlọla pẹlu Alao Akala, ṣugbọn loju wọn, lai ti i ku, Ọlọrun ti ba Yoruba ṣe ohun to ṣoroo ṣe loju wọn. O yẹ koju ti wọn ni. Ṣugbọn oloṣelu ko lojuti, bẹ ẹ ba ri wọn lode, wọn yoo bẹrẹ si i ko agbada iranu kiri, wọn yoo ni ko si bi awọn ko ti jẹ. Oṣelu nikan ni wọn waye wọn waa ṣe. Ẹ wo o, ẹ sun mẹyin o jare!Fayoṣe ati Tinubu, Ọlọrun ma jẹ ẹ tanra yin pa!Ọrọ ti Peter Ayọdele Fayoṣe n sọ ko le tete yeeyan, nitori ọrọ oloṣelu ki i yeeyan daadaa, afi ti eeyan ba mọ iru ohun ti oloṣelu bẹẹ n fẹ. Iroyin ti awọn kan gbe jade ni pe Fayoṣe sọ pe Aṣiwaju Bọla Tunubu ni aṣiwaju iran Yoruba patapata, pe ba a fẹ, ba a kọ. Awọn mi-in si gbe e jade pe ọkan ninu awọn aṣaaju ilẹ Yoruba ni Bọla Tinubu, wọn ni ohun ti Fayoṣe sọ niyẹn. Dajudaju, bi oloṣelu ba ti n sọrọ oloṣelu ẹgbẹ rẹ bayii, o ni kinni kan to n wa. Ọjọ kan n bọ ti gbogbo ilu yoo mọ ohun ti Fayoṣe n wa gan-an. Ṣugbọn ni ti ọrọ to sọ yii, keeyan ma lọ jinna lori ẹ, yoo ṣoro ki Yoruba too gba pe Tinubu ni aṣaaju awọn. Bo ba ṣe pe ọkan ninu awọn aṣaaju Yoruba ni, ko si ohun to buru ninu iyẹn, nitori aṣiwaju pọ nilẹ Yoruba, beeyan ba pe e ni ọkan ninu awọn aṣaaju wa, tọhun ko jẹ ayo pa. Ṣugbọn ẹni ba pe Tinubu ni olori ọmọ Yoruba pata nikan lo fẹẹ gbọ ọrọ mi-in lẹnu awọn eeyan, nitori ni tootọ, Tinubu ki i ṣe olori ọmọ Yoruba pata, oloṣelu lasan loun, oloṣelu ko si le jẹ olori iran kan, paapaa, bo ba jẹ iru oṣelu ti awọn n ṣe laye ode oni ni. Ẹni ti yoo jẹ olori awọn ẹya kan, yoo ran iru ẹya bẹẹ lọwọ, yoo ṣe oore ti wọn ko ni i le gbagbe laye fun wọn. Awolọwọ lo fun Yoruba ni ẹkọ-ọfẹ nigba ti oju dudu gan-an, ẹkọ-ọfẹ yii si ni Yoruba fi ta gbogbo ẹya to ku ni Naijiria yọ titi doni. Ta ni yoo waa sọ pe Awolọwọ ki i ṣe aṣaaju wa, bẹẹ ọdun marun-un pere lo fi ṣe olori ijọba ilẹ Yoruba naa. Ṣugbọn Tinubu lo ọdun mẹjọ, igba kan si wa to jẹ oun naa ni olori awọn gomina gbogbo to jẹ nilẹ Yoruba pata, oun lo n fi wọn sipo naa pẹlu owo rẹpẹtẹ. Ṣugbọn ki gan-an ni a oo tọka si pe Tinubu ṣe fun Yoruba o. Ṣebi loju Tinubu lawọn Fulani ṣe n fiya jẹ wa, loju ẹ ni ijọba Buhari yii ṣe n gba ohun gbogbo to tọ si ọmọ Yoruba to n gbe e fun ẹya mi-in, bẹẹ Tinubu yii lo gbe Buhari waa ba wọn. Loju Tinubu yii, ati lasiko ti oun n ṣe olori oloṣelu adugbo wa yii, ina Yoruba ko jo siwaju, ajorẹyin ni, ohun gbogbo ti ko si ṣẹlẹ ri bẹrẹ si i ṣẹlẹ laarin wa. Bi gbogbo rẹ ba si ṣẹlẹ, bi wọn n pa ọmọ Yoruba, ti wọn n ji ọmọ Yoruba gbe, Tinubu yii ko ni i sọ pe oun ri wa, bẹẹ okoowo ati awọn ibi ti oun ti n ri owo wa nibẹ ti ko bajẹ, o tubọ n le si i ni. Eyi ni pe bi Tinubu ba jẹ ọmọ Yoruba, to si n ṣe oṣelu nilẹ Yoruba, oun kan n fi oṣelu ilẹ Yoruba naa tun aye ara tirẹ ati ti awọn ọmọ rẹ ṣe ni, iyẹn ni pe o n fi orukọ Yoruba jẹun lasan. Iru ẹni bẹẹ ko le jẹ aṣiwaju iran kankan, ka ma ti i sọ ti Yoruba to jẹ iran awọn ọlaju pata. Nitori bẹẹ, ẹ sọ fun Fayoṣe ko wa ọrọ mi-in sọ jare, Tinubu ko le jẹ Aṣiwaju ọmọ Yoruba afi ti wọn ba jọ n tan ara wọn jẹ nikan. Bo a si jẹ wọn n tan ara wọn jẹ naa ni, afi ka gbadura fun wọn pe, “Ọlọrun ma jẹ ẹ tanra yin pa!’"},{"question":"Tunis mooy péeyu man réew ?","answer":"Tunis mooy péeyu réewum Tunisie"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਇਕੁ ਪਛਾਣੂ ਜੀਅ ਕਾ ਇਕੋ ਰਖਣਹਾਰੁ ॥ਇਕਸ ਕਾ ਮਨਿ ਆਸਰਾ ਇਕੋ ਪ੍ਰਾਣ ਅਧਾਰੁ ॥ਤਿਸੁ ਸਰਣਾਈ ਸਦਾ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮੁ ਕਰਤਾਰੁ ॥੧॥ਮਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਗਲ ਉਪਾਵ ਤਿਆਗੁ ॥ਗੁਰੁ ਪੂਰਾ ਆਰਾਧਿ ਨਿਤ ਇਕਸੁ ਕੀ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਗੁ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਇਕੋ ਭਾਈ ਮਿਤੁ ਇਕੁ ਇਕੋ ਮਾਤ ਪਿਤਾ ॥ਇਕਸ ਕੀ ਮਨਿ ਟੇਕ ਹੈ ਜਿਨਿ ਜੀਉ ਪਿੰਡੁ ਦਿਤਾ ॥ਸੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਮਨਹੁ ਨ ਵਿਸਰੈ ਜਿਨਿ ਸਭੁ ਕਿਛੁ ਵਸਿ ਕੀਤਾ ॥੨॥ਘਰਿ ਇਕੋ ਬਾਹਰਿ ਇਕੋ ਥਾਨ ਥਨੰਤਰਿ ਆਪਿ ॥ਜੀਅ ਜੰਤ ਸਭਿ ਜਿਨਿ ਕੀਏ ਆਠ ਪਹਰ ਤਿਸੁ ਜਾਪਿ ॥ਇਕਸੁ ਸੇਤੀ ਰਤਿਆ ਨ ਹੋਵੀ ਸੋਗ ਸੰਤਾਪੁ ॥੩॥ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮੁ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਏਕੁ ਹੈ ਦੂਜਾ ਨਾਹੀ ਕੋਇ ॥ਜੀਉ ਪਿੰਡੁ ਸਭੁ ਤਿਸ ਕਾ ਜੋ ਤਿਸੁ ਭਾਵੈ ਸੁ ਹੋਇ ॥ਗੁਰਿ ਪੂਰੈ ਪੂਰਾ ਭਇਆ ਜਪਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਸਚਾ ਸੋਇ ॥੪॥੯॥੭੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 45 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਜਿੰਦ ਦਾ ਮਿੱਤਰ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ ਜਿੰਦ ਨੂੰ (ਵਿਕਾਰ ਆਦਿਕਾਂ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚਾਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ (ਇਸ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਰੱਖ, ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ ਜਿੰਦ ਦਾ ਸਹਾਰਾ ਹੈ  ਉਹ ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮ ਕਰਤਾਰ (ਹੀ ਸਹਾਰਾ ਹੈ) ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ ਸਦਾ ਸੁਖ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧। ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਹੀਲੇ ਛੱਡ ਦੇ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਚੇਤੇ ਰੱਖ (ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਲੈ, ਤੇ) ਇਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ) ਦੀ ਲਗਨ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਲਾਈ ਰੱਖ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। (ਹੇ ਮਨ !) ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ (ਅਸਲ) ਭਰਾ ਹੈ ਮਿੱਤਰ ਹੈ, ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ (ਅਸਲ) ਮਾਂ ਪਿਉ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਮਾਪਿਆਂ ਵਾਂਗ ਪਾਲਣਹਾਰ ਹੈ) (ਮੈਨੂੰ ਤਾਂ) ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਸਹਾਰਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਜਿੰਦ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਸਰੀਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ (ਮੇਰੀ ਸਦਾ ਇਹੀ ਅਰਦਾਸ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਜਿਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਆਪਣੇ ਵੱਸ ਵਿਚ ਰਖਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਕਦੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਤੋਂ ਨਾਹ ਭੁੱਲੇ ।੨। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਤੇਰੇ) ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਤੇ ਬਾਹਰ ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਭੀ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ ਵੱਸ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਅੱਠੇ ਪਹਿਰ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਅ ਜੰਤ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਨ  ਜੇ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ (ਪਿਆਰ-ਰੰਗ) ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਰਹੀਏ, ਤਾਂ ਕਦੇ ਕੋਈ ਦੁੱਖ ਕਲੇਸ਼ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੋਂਹਦਾ ।੩। ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ (ਸਾਰੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ) ਹੈ, ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ (ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦਾ) ਸਰੀਰ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ, (ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਉਹੀ ਕੁਝ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਚੰਗਾ ਲਗਦਾ ਹੈ। ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਉਸ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ (ਸਭ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਨਾਲ) ਮੁਕੰਮਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੯।੭੯।\\""},{"question":"ਵਾਰਾਂ ਭਾਈ ਗੁਰਦਾਸ : ਵਾਰ ੧ ਪਉੜੀ ੪ ਪੰ. ੧ਜਗਤ ਕਾਰਣਓਅੰਕਾਰੁ ਆਕਾਰ ਕਰਿ ਏਕ ਕਵਾਉ ਪਸਾਉ ਪਸਾਰਾ।ਪੰਜ ਤਤ ਪਰਵਾਣੁ ਕਰਿ ਘਟਿ ਘਟਿ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਤ੍ਰਿਭਵਣੁ ਸਾਰਾ।ਕਾਦਰੁ ਕਿਨੇ ਨ ਲਖਿਆ ਕੁਦਰਤਿ ਸਾਜਿ ਕੀਆ ਅਵਤਾਰਾ।ਇਕ ਦੂ ਕੁਦਰਤਿ ਲਖ ਕਰਿ ਲਖ ਬਿਅੰਤ ਅਸੰਖ ਅਪਾਰਾ।ਰੋਮ ਰੋਮ ਵਿਚ ਰਖਿਓਨ ਕਰਿ ਬ੍ਰਹਮੰਡਿ ਕਰੋੜਿ ਸੁਮਾਰਾ।ਇਕਸ ਇਕਸ ਬ੍ਰਹਿਮੰਡਿ ਵਿਚਿ ਦਸ ਦਸ ਕਰਿ ਅਵਤਾਰ ਉਤਾਰਾ।ਕੇਤੇ ਬੇਦ ਬਿਆਸ ਕਰਿ ਕਈ ਕਤੇਬ ਮੁਹੰਮਦ ਯਾਰਾ।ਕੁਦਰਤਿ ਇਕੁ ਏਤਾ ਪਾਸਾਰਾ ॥੪॥","answer":"(ਓਅੰਕਾਰ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਬਚਨ ਥੋਂ ਆਕਾਰ ਰਚਕੇ (ਸਾਰਾ) ਪਸਾਰਾ ਪਸਾਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਪਹਿਲ ਇਕ ਵਾਹਿਗੁਰੂ ਹੀ ਸੀ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਬਚਨ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਰਾ ਪਸਾਰਾ ਕੀਤਾ)।(ਫੇਰ) ਪੰਜ ਤੱਤਾਂ ਥੋਂ ਬ੍ਰਹਿਮਾਂਡ ਰਚਕੇ ਆਪ (ਘਟ ਘਟ ਕਹੀਏ) ਹਰੇਕ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਖੇ (ਪਰਵੇਸ਼ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਆਪ, ਜੋ) ਤਿੰਨਾਂ ਭਵਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਾਰ ਰੂਪ (ਹੈ, ਸੱਤਾ ਦੇ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ)। (ਪੰਜ ਤੱਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਪਰਵਾਣ=ਤੋਲ, ਯਾ ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ਾ ਇਕੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਰੱਖਣ ਦਾ ਭਾਵ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕੋਈ ਤੱਤ ਕਿਸੇ ਤੇ ਬਲੀ ਨਾ ਪਵੇ, ਇਕ ਸਾਰਖੇ ਰਹਿਣ। ਪਰਵਾਣ ਦਾ ਅਰਥ(ਕਾਦਰ) ਕੁਦਰਤ ਦਾ ਕਰਤਾ ਕਿਸੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਡਿੱਠਾ,ਇਕ ਮਾਯਾ ਥੋਂ ਲੱਖਾਂ (ਬ੍ਰਹਿਮਾਂਡ) ਰਚਦਾ ਹੈ (ਫੇਰ) ਲੱਖਾਂ ਬਿਅੰਤ ਅਸੰਖ ਅਪਾਰ (ਰਚਨਾਂ ਸਾਜਦਾ ਹੈ)। (ਇਥੇ ਚਾਰ ਵਾਰ ਕਹਿਣ ਦਾ ਭਾਵ ਚਾਰ ਜੁਗਾਂ ਵਿਖੇ ਅਸੰਖ ਤੇ ਅਪਾਰ ਰਚਨਾ ਸਿਰਜਣ ਦਾ ਹੈ)। (ਉਸੇ ਨੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ) ਮਾਯਾ ਬਣਾ ਕੇ ਅਵਤਾਰ (ਬ੍ਰਹਮਾਦਿਕ) ਕੀਤੇ ਹਨ।ਆਪਣੇ ਇਕ ਇਕ ਰੋਮ ਵਿਖੇ ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਦੀ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਬ੍ਰਹਿਮੰਡ (ਉਸ ਨੇ) ਰੱਖੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ।ਹਰ ਬ੍ਰਹਮਾਂਡ ਵਿਖੇ ਦਸ ਦਸ ਔਤਾਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਸਾਜੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ (ਭਾਵ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਬ੍ਰਹਮੰਡ ਤੇ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹੀ ਅਵਤਾਰ ਹਨ)।ਕਈ ਬੇਦਾਂ (ਦੇ ਵਕਤਾ) ਬਿਆਸ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੇ, ਕਈ ਕਿਤਾਬਾਂ (ਕਈ) ਮੁਹੰਮਦ (ਅਰ ਕਈ ਉਸ ਦੇ) ਯਾਰ ਬਣਾ ਦਿੱਤੇ।(ਪ੍ਰੰਤੂ) ਕੁਦਰਤ ਇਕ ਹੈ, (ਜਿਸ ਦਾ) ਇੰਨਾ ਪਸਾਰਾ (ਪਸਰਿਆ) ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Trình bày tín ngưỡng tôn giáo của các dân tộc trên đất nước Việt nam.","answer":"Tín ngưỡng tôn giáo của các dân tộc trên đất nước Việt Nam là rất đa dạng và phong phú. Người Kinh, dân tộc chủ đạo của Việt Nam, có tín ngưỡng thờ cúng tổ tiên, thờ những người có công với công đồng, thờ Mẫu, Thành hoàng làng và còn tiếp thu nhiều tôn giáo lớn trên thế giới như Phật giáo, Công giáo, Tin Lành. Họ xây dựng nhiều công trình kiến trúc như đình, đền, chùa, tháp, nhà thờ và tổ chức nhiều nghi lễ liên quan đến các tôn giáo như lễ Phật đản, lễ Giáng sinh.Các dân tộc thiểu số Việt Nam cũng duy trì nhiều tín ngưỡng đa thần, vạn vật hữu linh, tô tem giáo ở các mức độ đậm, nhạt khác nhau. Họ cũng đã và đang tiếp thu, chịu ảnh hưởng của nhiều tôn giáo lớn trên thế giới như Phật giáo, Công giáo, Hồi giáo.Ngoài ra, cả người Kinh và các dân tộc thiểu số Việt Nam đều thực hành nhiều phong tục, tập quán, lễ hội liên quan đến chu kỳ vòng đời, chu kỳ canh tác và chu kỳ thời gian/thời tiết. Họ duy trì và phát triển hệ thống lễ hội đa dạng và phong phú, gồm lễ hội liên quan đến các tín ngưỡng dân gian, tôn giáo, tưởng nhớ các anh hùng dân tộc.Đời sống tín ngưỡng và tôn giáo của các dân tộc trên đất nước Việt Nam đang ngày càng đa dạng và phong phú. Bên cạnh việc giữ gìn và phát huy những nét đẹp văn hóa truyền thống, người Kinh và các dân tộc thiểu số cũng không ngừng giao lưu, tiếp thu và phát triển những giá trị, thành tố văn hóa tiên tiến từ bên ngoài."},{"question":"الطاقة اللازمة لإلنتزاع إلكترون من ذرة في حالتها الغازية تعريف لـ:(أ) طاقة الوضع(ب) طاقة التأين(ج) طاقة الحركة(د) طاقة الرابطة","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة هي: (ب) طاقة التأين"},{"question":"Hiran'iza no ahitana ity andalana ity: \\"Etsy ho fafako ny ranomasonao, tsapako izay tsapanao\\"","answer":"Hira mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Mitonia\\"  no ahitana io andalana io, izay ny tarika Reko Band no namorona azy."},{"question":"Jelaskan ciri-ciri pemimpin yang mampu melonjakkan kecemerlangan negara ke persada dunia. ","answer":"Seorang pemimpin yang cemerlang perlulah mempunyai wawasan yang jelas. Dia patut mampu berfikir dalam pelbagai pendekatan bagi mencari cara alternatif supaya dapat menyelesaikan setiap permasalahan dengan berkesan. Contohnya, pemimpin yang mempunyai cita-cita untuk memajukan negara dan berwawasan akan sentiasa memastikan cara terbaik untuk mencapai apa yang diingini.Pemimpin juga perlulah bertanggungjawab dan memikul tanggungjawab yang perlu dilaksanakan demi kesejahteraan rakyat. Contohnya, dia mengutamakan kebajikan rakyat supaya rakyat dapat hidup dengan aman dan sejahtera. Pemimpin mempunyai tanggungjawab yang besar untuk memastikan kemakmuran negara."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada jalan\\"?","answer":"Ada cara untuk menyelesaikan sesuatu perkara."},{"question":"Differentiate between supervised and unsupervised learning in the context of deep learning.","answer":"In supervised learning, the model is trained on labeled data, while unsupervised learning involves learning patterns from unlabeled data without explicit target labels."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Shin yaya za a rubuta ɗari uku da goma sha-uku a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 313"},{"question":"Supposons qu'il est vrai que \\"Henry Charles Tonking (né à Camborne, Cornouailles, le 17 janvier 1863 et décédé à Glasgow, le 7 juin 1926) est un organiste britannique. Il est organiste au Royal Aquarium de Westminster (1886), à l’église Saint-Luc de Norwood (1887) et, à partir de 1888, au Convent Garden Opera. Il donne également des récitals au Crystal Palace, à l’Institut Bow and Bromley et au Royal Albert Hall Sunday Concerts (1895-1905).\\". Alors, est-ce que \\"Henry Charles Tonking est mort de la grippe.\\" ? \\"vrai\\", \\"faux\\", ou \\"incertain\\" ?\\"","answer":"Ceci est incertain, car nous ne possédons pas de preuves historiques précises sur la cause de son décès. "},{"question":"රජයේ වියදම බෙදෙන ප්‍රධාන කොටස් දෙක මොනවද?","answer":"පුනරා වර්තන  හා  ප්‍රාග්ධන වියදම් "},{"question":"請例出北美五大湖？","answer":"北美五大湖是指：蘇必利爾湖、休倫湖、密歇根湖、安大略湖和伊利湖，一些湖泊由美國和加拿大共享的。"},{"question":"নিচের অনুচ্ছেদের বিষয় কি?বাংলাদেশ ফিল্ড হাসপাতাল হলো অস্থায়ী বাংলাদেশ সরকারের সরাসরি ব্যবস্থাপনায় পরিচালিত একটি এবং একমাত্র স্বাস্থ্য সেবা প্রদানকারী প্রতিষ্ঠান। এটি ১৯৭১ সালে বাংলাদেশের স্বাধীনতা যুদ্ধ চলাকালীন ভারতের ত্রিপুরা রাজ্যের মেলাঘরে প্রতিষ্ঠা করা হয়।","answer":"বাংলাদেশের স্বাধীনতা যুদ্ধ |"},{"question":"Dapọ Abiọdun ṣedaro Kaṣimawo Laloko, akọni-mọ-ọn-gba bọọlu to ku","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ogun, Ọmọọba Dapọ Abiọdun, ti ranṣẹ ibanikẹdun si awọn ẹbi, awujọ bọọlu ati gbogbo ẹni to mọ Oloogbe Kaṣimawo Laloko to figba kan jẹ akọni-mọ-ọn-gba agbabọọlu NFF nilẹ yii, to si tun jẹ olori Parakoyi ilẹ Ẹgba lapapọ.Satide, ọjọ kẹtadinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹta yii, ni Oloye Kaṣimawo Laloko dagbere faye nileewosan Sacred Hearts to wa l’Abẹokuta, ẹni ọdun mẹrindinlọgọrin( 76) ni.Ninu atẹjade to ti ọfiisi Akọwe iroyin gomina, Ọgbẹni Kunle Ṣomọrin, jade lọjọ Aje ọsẹ yii ni Dapọ Abiọdun ti ṣalaye pe adanu nla ni iku Laloko lẹka awọn agbabọọlu nipinlẹ Ogun, nilẹ Naijiria ati ni gbogbo agbaye pata.Gomina tẹsiwaju pe yatọ si ẹka agbabọọlu ti oloogbe yii ti ṣiṣẹ takuntakun, o ni Kaṣimawo ko fi ọrọ okoowo naa ṣere. Eyi naa lo fa a ti wọn fi fi i jẹ oye olori Parakoyi gbogbo ilẹ Ẹgba pata.Oloogbe Kaṣimawo Laloko da ileewe nipa ere bọọlu silẹ l’Orile-Imọ, eyi ti Pepsi Football Academy ti ara ẹ dide, to si jẹ pe ọpọ awọn agbabọọlu ọjẹ wẹwẹ lo ti ibẹ dide ti wọn di ẹni nla.Ọkan ninu awọn eeyan to nigbagbọ ninu gbigba akọni-mọ-ọn-gba ilẹ wa lati kọ awọn eeyan ni bọọlu ni baba to doloogbe yii, oun ko fara mọ ka maa kowo foyinbo ti yoo waa kọ awọn eeyan ilẹ yii ni bọọlu gbigba, nitori ẹnikan to nigbagbọ ninu gbigbe nnkan Naijiria larugẹ ni."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Gene Roddenberry? ","answer":"Drámadóir, scríbhneoir ficsin eolaíochta agus léiritheoir teilifíse ab ea Eugene Wesley \\"Gene\\" Roddenberry (19 Lúnasa 1921 – 24 Deireadh Fómhair 1991).Rugadh Roddenberry sa bhliain 1921 in El Paso, Texas, agus d'fhás sé suas i Los Angeles.Tá clú agus cáil air mar gheall ar an tsraith theilifíse Star Trek a scríobh sé.Fuair sé bás i Santa Monica, California sa bhliain 1991."},{"question":" கேள்வி: தேசிய கீதம் முதன் முதலாக எப்போது பாடப்பட்டது?  1.நவம்பர் 27 - 1882  2.ஆகஸ்ட் 2 - 1948  3.ஜனவரி 26 - 1917  4.டிசம்பர் 27 - 1911","answer":"பதில்:4.டிசம்பர் 27 - 1911"},{"question":"வினா:காவிரி நதி தமிழ் நாட்டில் நுழையும் இடம் எது ? ","answer":"விடை: ஒக்கேனக்கல்"},{"question":"لومړۍ جمله: په راډیر کې د تریاسک ډبرې کارول شوې یوه ډبره د \\" راډیر ډبره \\" ده ، چې لکه څنګه چې نوم یې وړاندیز کوي ، د کارډیف په ولسوالۍ کې کان کیندل کیږي. دویمه جمله: په رادیر کې د تریاسک ډبرې څخه یوه د رادیر ډبره ده ، یوه ازاده ډبره چې لکه څنګه چې نوم یې وړاندیز کوي ، د کارډیف په ولسوالۍ کې کان کیندل کیږي. پوښتنه: ایا لومړۍ او دویمه جمله یو شان معنی لري؟ هو یا نه؟","answer":"هو"},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Tsy zakako ireo mpiaro ny tontolo iainana ireo fa tia sehoseho fotsiny izy ireo.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Eny, kabary fankahalana ity fanambarana ity satria tsy ara-drariny no iantsoana ireo mpiaro ny tontolo iainana ho tia sehoseho."},{"question":"Тыйын дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Тыйын – жүгүртүү жана тейлөө каражаты катары колдонулуучу металлдан жасалган акча белгиси. Биринчи тыйындар биздин заманга чейинки 7-кылымдан баштап белгилүү. Бир эле мезгилде тарыхый, жазма жана буюм эстелиги катары маалымат берет. Тарыхый изилдөөдө эстеликтин мезгилин аныктайт; тыйындын салмагы, номиналы (баасы) өлчөм-чен тууралуу маалымат берет.Жасалган материалына жараша коомдун өнүгүш деңгээлин аныктоого мүмкүндүк берет; тыйындагы жазуу аркылуу палеографияга, лингвистикага байланыштуу маалыматтарды алууга болот; тыйындагы сүрөттөр археологдор, этнографтар, искусство таануучулар үчүн табылгыс булак; тыйындагы өзгөрүүлөр (бузулушу, типтеринин өзгөрүшү, кошумча белгилердин коюлушу) акча реформалары, саясий-экономикалык баш аламандыктар жөнүндө кабар бериши мүмкүн.Тыйын картографиясын түзүү, тыйын казналарын анализдөө – айрым аймактардагы соода байланыштарын билүүгө жол ачат. Тарых илиминин бир бөлүгү болгон нумизматика илими. тыйындын тарыхын изилдейт. Тыйынды окуп үйрөнүү геральдика, сфрагистика менен тыгыз байланыштуу."},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Emmy Noether para a matemática?","answer":"Emmy Noether teve um impacto significativo na álgebra abstrata e na teoria dos invariantes. Suas contribuições incluem o teorema de Noether, que estabelece a relação entre simetria e leis de conservação na física. Ela também desempenhou um papel crucial na fundação da álgebra comutativa e na teoria dos grupos."},{"question":"Суроо: Асман менен жер канча кабат?","answer":"Жооп: Асман менен жер 7 (жети) кабат."},{"question":"TIROS I හා  සම්බන්ධ පුරාවස්තුවක් අමුත්තන්ට දැකිය හැක්කේ කොතැනින්ද, එය එම ස්ථානයට මාරු කළේ කවදාද?","answer":"ප්‍රථම සාර්ථක කාලගුණ චන්ද්‍රිකාව වන TIROS I (රූපවාහිනී අධෝරක්ත නිරීක්ෂණ චන්ද්‍රිකාව) හා සම්බන්ධ පුරාවස්තුවක් වොෂින්ටන්, ඩීසී හි Smithsonian ජාතික ගුවන් හා  අභ්‍යවකාශ කෞතුකාගාරයේ ප්‍රදර්ශනය කෙරේ. ගුවන් හා  අභ්‍යවකාශ කෞතුක වස්තු එකතුවක් සඳහා  ප්‍රසිද්ධ මෙම කෞතුකාගාරය කෞතුක වස්තු රැසකට නිවහනක් සපයයි. අභ්‍යවකාශ ගවේෂණ සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා තාක්‍ෂණයට සම්බන්ධ ඒවා  ඇතුළුව ඓතිහාසික වශයෙන් වැදගත් අයිතම රාශියක්. නාසා ආයතනය 1965 දී මෙම පුරාවස්තුව කෞතුකාගාරයට මාරු කළේය."},{"question":"Quem é coroado rei de Gondor após a Guerra do Anel, em Senhor dos Aneis?","answer":"Aragorn, também conhecido por Elessar, é coroado rei de Gondor após a Guerra do Anel."},{"question":"Waa kuma goat-kaga?","answer":"Wa Ronaldo. "},{"question":"السؤال: من هي ذات النطاقين؟","answer":"الإجابة: أسماء بنت أبي بكر"},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: An san Beljiyam don kyawawan cakulan da waffles. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"Qual a personagem mais famosa de Maurício de Sousa?","answer":"A personagem mais famosa de Maurício de Sousa é a Mônica."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو المقصود في قوله تعالى: ” ولقد رآه بالأفق المبين”؟","answer":"الإجابة: أي أن الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم رأى جبريل في صورته"},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Kết quả điều tra cho thấy, từ tháng 1-2020 đến tháng 10-2021, Sở Y tế, CDC Cà Mau và Bệnh viện đa khoa tỉnh thực hiện 11 gói thầu mua sinh phẩm xét nghiệm Covid-19, máy tách chiết DNA/RNA tự động, hóa chất, sinh phẩm và thiết bị phục vụ công tác phòng chống dịch Covid-19 của Công ty Việt Á, với số tiền trên 49,4 tỷ đồng. Chưa dừng lại ở đó, Sở Y tế mua sinh phẩm xét nghiệm Covid-19 của Công ty Việt Á cao hơn so với chi phí sản xuất (đã bao gồm 5% lợi nhuận và chi phí khác), dẫn đến thiệt hại trên 9,1 tỷ đồng. Còn lại gói thầu 40.000 sinh phẩm xét nghiệm chưa thanh quyết toán. CDC Cà Mau mua sinh phẩm xét nghiệm Covid-19 của Công ty Việt Á cao hơn so với giá của chi phí sản xuất (đã bao gồm 5% lợi nhuận và chi phí khác), dẫn đến thiệt hại trên 3 tỷ đồng. Quá trình thực hiện hồ sơ đấu thầu mua sinh phẩm xét nghiệm Covid-19 của Công ty Việt Á, Lê Ngọc Định, Đặng Hải Đăng và Hồ Quang Nhu thực hiện không đúng quy định về đấu thầu, \\"không bảo đảm công bằng, minh bạch\\", vi phạm các hành vi bị cấm trong đấu thầu quy định tại khoản 6 Điều 89 Luật Đấu thầu; gây thiệt hại cho ngân sách nhà nước trên 12,2 tỷ đồng. Hành vi của 3 đối tượng nêu trên đủ yếu tố cấu thành tội \\"Vi phạm quy định về đấu thầu gây hậu quả nghiêm trọng\\" quy định tại khoản 3 Điều 222 Bộ luật Hình sự năm 2015 (sửa đổi năm 2017). Hiện Cơ quan Cảnh sát điều tra Công an tỉnh Cà Mau tiếp tục điều tra làm rõ vụ việc để xử lý theo đúng pháp luật. Trước đó, ngày 18-4, Cơ quan Cảnh sát điều tra Công an tỉnh Cà Mau ra Quyết định khởi tố vụ án hình sự số 17/CSKT, về tội \\"Vi phạm quy định về đấu thầu gây hậu quả nghiêm trọng\\" xảy ra tại Sở Y tế và CDC Cà Mau. TTXVN ","answer":"Bắt tạm giam Giám đốc CDC Cà Mau liên quan đến mua sinh phẩm xét nghiệm của Công ty Việt Á"},{"question":"다음 단락을 완성시켜주세요.1759년 1월 그는 함대를 이끌고, 퀘벡에서 제임스 울프를 호송하는 임무를 맡았다. 2월 14일에는 부제목으로 승진했다. 그는 1759년 9월에 벌어진 아브라함 평원 전투","answer":"이후에 남아 있는 영국군을 수습하고, 당시 조지 타운센드 대령의 휘하에 보급을 충실히 함으로써 죽은 장군의 승리를 공고히 했다. 손더스와 타운센드는 프랑스 수비대가 항복한 후 영국측 서명자로 합류했다."},{"question":"Rahoviana no atao ny fisoratam-panambadiana?","answer":"Ny fisoratam-panambadiana dia atao rehefa samy vonona izy roa, ary hatao any amin'ny firaisana any amin'ny kaominina."},{"question":"Razaq Okoya","answer":"Rasaki Akanni Okoya ni wọ́n bí ní ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó ni ọjọ́ Kejìlá Oṣù Kìíní, ọdún 1940 (12 January 1940). Ó jẹ́ gbajúgbajà ìlúmọ̀ọ́kà oníṣòwò, olówó tabua tí ó ní ilé iṣẹ́ púpọ̀.Aáyan ìkẹ́kọ̀ọ́ rẹ̀Razaq Ọkọ́ya kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ àkóbẹ̀rẹ̀ rẹ̀ nílé ẹ̀kọ́ alákọ̀ọ́bẹ̀rẹ̀ tí Ansar-un-deen, Òkè pòpó, ní ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó. Òun ni Aláṣẹ àti olùdásílẹ̀ ilé-iṣẹ́ Eleganza Group, tí ó n ta ọjà jákèjádò ilẹ̀ Adúláwò (Western Africa).Oloye Razak Okoya je omo  Yoruba lati ariwa iwo Oorun (south-western)  Naijiria. Won bi ni ididle ogbeni  Tiamiyu Ayinde Okoya ni ilu Eko . O sise pelu baba re gege bi aranso ti baba re je, ti won si tun n ta awon ohun elo iranso pelu.   Imo ti o ni lo fun ni igboya lati da duro funra re gege bi oga. O tu owo jo ti o fi pe ogun Poun (20 Pounds), ti iya re naa si raan lowo pelu aadota Poun (50 Pounds), lati fi bere owo tita ati rira lati ile Japan.Ile ise Razak Okoya gbooro kia, o si n serin ajo kaakiri lati mo nipa bi won se n pese nkan ti o nigbagbo wipe won yoo se se ni orile ede Naijiria bi tawon toku . Iyawo re akoko ti oruko re n je  Kuburat Okoya, ni o feran ki o ma ra awon ohun oso ara jewellery pamo ti Razak si ma n semo nipa bi won se won to. O mo wipe iye owo awon oso ara wonyi ko kere, atipe oun le ma se won nile Naijiria igba ti owo ohun ipese re ko won ni ile Naijiria. Okoya tun rin iri ajo lo si ile okere lati ra ero ti o le pese awon ohun oso ara naa. Nigba ti o bere si ni pese re ni ona ara ti o si n taa ni owo pooku, awon eniyan boo apa re ko si fe ka bi awon eniyan se n beere fun oja re mo. Eyi ni o bere ile ipese ile ise ohun oso ara re.  O bere kiko awon bata gidi lopo yanturu, lai moye igba ni awon oja re kii tete de pelu bi o se n tete san owo asan sile. O serin ajo lo ile Italy lati ri awon ti won n se bata naa, iyalenu lo je fun wipe won ti fi owo oja re san gbese tiwon. Bayi ni o se pinu lati da ile ise bata tire naa sile. O ra awon ero to lagbara lati sise naa ti o si gba awon akose-mose lati ko awon osise re ni ile Naijiria bi won se n pese bata. Loni, labe akoso re,ile ise Eleganza ti n pese orisirisi ohun elo ile. Awon ile ise re wa ni: 'Oregun-Ikeja, Isolo, Alaba and Iganmu' ti o ti gba o le ni egberun marun osise ti o je omo orile ede Naijiria ati awon ajoji. Ile ise akojopo Eleganza je okan lara awon ile ise to laami laka jake jado ile Naijiria , ti o si tun ni o kere tan mefa kaakiri awon orile ede to sunmo ile Naijiria.  O ti gba ami eye idani-lola fun idi aseyori okowo re gege bi Oludasile ise ara-eni asiko tiwa (Business Entrepreneur of Our Time) lati owo iwe iroyin Thisday Newspapers.\\"Nile iwe, mo ni anfani lati sesa ise okowo nigba ti mo ri awon oluko mi ninu awon aso to ti gbo; ti mo si ri onise okowo to n wo aso pataki laarin oja Dosumu ti o je oju oja lEko nigba naa.\\"\\"Mo ma n sora mi. Mi o si ki n wo aago alaago sise. Mo si ma n je ki ohun ti mo bani o temi lorun. Mi o si ki n wa owo ofe. Bakan naa ni mi o ki n je ki oselu o wo mi loju. \\"\\"A o ki n fi igberaga se owo. Ohun ti a ma n wo ni pipese ohun ti awon eniyan le ra lowo pooku.Eyi je okan lara asiri mi.\\"\\"\\"Ohun ti o je iwuri fun mi ni wipe mo fe je olola, mo si mo wipe mo ti sise gidigidi lati de ipo naa.\\"\\"Mi o ni ero kero si kikekoo. Sugbon nigba miran, iwe kika ma n se awon eniyan ni akin ti kii se ooto. O ma n je ki won fokan bale lori iwe eri won laisakitiyan lati ni ola.\\"Oloye Razak Okoya bi omo maruun. Awon omo naa ni: Sade Okoya, Olamide Okoya, Subomi Okoya, Oyinlola Okoya, ati Wahab Okoya.Oloye Razak Okoya ni awon iyawo to po seyin. Sugbon, eyi ti o wa loju opon lowo ni iya Afin Folasade Okoya ti Oloye Razak Okoya so wipe o ma sise kara kara. Oun naa lo bi awon (Olamide, Oyinlola, Subomi and Wahab) fun. Sade paa paa ti gba opo ami eye idani-lola gege bi eni to mo araamu julo ti awon eiyan si n kose re."},{"question":"એક ફૂલની આત્મકથા નિબંધ.","answer":"છાતી કાઢીને , આકાશ તરફ જોઈને ચાલવાને બદલે જરા ધરતીની ધૂળ તરફ પણ નજર નાખો. જુઓ ! તમે કચડો છો મને ! મારી વેદનાના સ્વરો તરફ તમે ધ્યાન પણ આપ્યું નહિ ! હા, એ તરફ તમારું ધ્યાન કેવી રીતે જઈ શકે ? હું તો નકામું ગણી, ફેંકી દેવાયેલું એક કરમાયેલું ફૂલ છું. થોડી વારમાં તો હું માટીમાં મળી ગયું હોઈશ !તમે ક્યાંક જવાની ઉતાવળમાં હશો, પણ જતાં પહેલાં મારી વાત જરા સાંભળતા જાઓ. ત્રણ દિવસ પહેલાં જ એક છોડની ટોચે ઊગેલી કળીના રૂપમાં મારો જન્મ થયો હતો. મારી સાથે બીજી અનેક કળીઓ પણ એ છોડ પર ઊગી હતી. એ સમયે આખા બગીચામાં સુગંધનું સામ્રાજ્ય છવાયું હતું. ભમરાનું એક ઝુંડ મધુર સ્વરે ગુંજારવ કરતું કરતું ચારે તરફ ઘૂમી રહ્યું હતું. પવનની મંદ મંદ શીતળ લહેરોથી હું આમતેમ ડોલી રહ્યું હતું. ઊગતા સૂર્યનાં સોનેરી કિરણો મારામાં નવી ચેતનાનો સંચાર કરી રહ્યાં હતાં. બગીચાના એક વૃક્ષની ડાળી પર બેઠેલી બુલબુલ મધુર ગીતો ગાઈ રહી હતી. હું આસમાન સાથે વાતો કરતું હતુંમેં જોયું તો એક સુંદર હારમાં મારી શોભા અનેક ગણી વધી ગઈ હતી.હારમાં સ્થાન મળવાથી મને ખૂબ આનંદ થયો. એક સભામાં પ્રમુખસ્થાન શોભાવવા માટે પધારેલા નેતાજીને એ હાર પહેરાવવામાં આવ્યો. એમણે તરત જ ગળામાંથી હાર ઉતારીને પોતાની સાથે આવેલા પટાવાળાને સોંપી દીધો. પટાવાળાએ એ હાર બાજુ પર મૂક્યો. અંતે એ હાર એક છોકરાએ ત્યાંથી ઉપાડી લીધો. સમય જતાં હારમાં ગૂંથેલાં લગભગ બધાં ફૂલો કરમાવા લાગ્યાં. સદ્નસીબે હું હજુ થોડું તાજું રહ્યું હતું. પેલા છોકરાએ હળવેકથી મને હારમાંથી અલગ કર્યું અને હારને કચરાપેટીમાં નાખી દીધો. થોડી વાર સુધી છોકરો મને સૂંઘતો રહ્યો. છેવટે તેણે પણ મને જમીન પર ફેંકી દીધું. ધીમે ધીમે હું કરમાવા લાગ્યું. થોડી વાર પહેલાં જે લોકો મને અહોભાવથી જોઈ રહ્યા હતા, એ જ લોકો હવે મને પગ નીચે કચડીને જઈ રહ્યા છે !મેં મારા અલ્પકાળમાં જીવનનાં અનેક રૂપો જોયાં છે. મને લાગે છે કે જીવનમાં ભલે સંઘર્ષ આવે એવી સ્થિતિમાં પણ વ્યક્તિએ શાંત અને સ્વસ્થ રહેવું જોઈએ. સુખ અને દુઃખ તો આવતાં - જતાં રહેવાનાં જ.મને બિલકુલ અસોસ નથી. ઊગે તે આથમે એવા તત્ત્વજ્ઞાનમાં મને રસ નથી. મારું લક્ષ્ય હતું – પૂર્ણપણે વિકસવું . એ સિદ્ધ કરીને આનંદની પ્રાપ્તિ મેં માણી લીધી. રૂપ - રંગ બીજાને માટે ધરી દીધાં.મારા જીવનની સાર્થકતા જ અન્યના જીવનને પણ ધન્યતા આપી રહેશે."},{"question":"Ai là tác giả truyện \\"Lục Vân Tiên\\"?","answer":"đây là tác phẩm của Nguyễn Đình ChiểuLục Vân Tiên là truyện thơ Nôm, thể lục bát, chưa rõ thời điểm sáng tác. Tiểu dẫn của sách giáo khoa Ngữ văn lớp 11 (tập 1, Nhà xuất bản Giáo dục Việt Nam) nêu, tác phẩm có lẽ được Nguyễn Đình Chiểu sáng tác vào khoảng đầu năm 50 của thế kỷ 19. Lúc này, ông đã bị mù, đang dạy học và chữa bệnh cho người dân ở Gia Định."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe joro ary inona no atao mandritra ny joro?","answer":"Ny joro dia fomba Malagasy iray avy any amin'ny faritra avaratry ny nosy. Amin'ny finoana Malagasy, ny joro dia fipetrahan'ny fanahin'ny mpanjaka iray efa maty, anaty vatan'olombelona mba hahafahany mandray anjara amin'ny asa-piarahamonina. Mandritra io dia misy ny famonoana omby ho fangataham-pitahiana amin'ny razana, na ho sorona amin'ny zanahary. Izay no atao mandritra ny joro."},{"question":"Awọn ajinigbe wọle lọọ ji ọba alaye gbe laafin rẹ l’Ekiti","answer":"Awọn ajinigbe to n ṣọṣẹ nipinlẹ Ekiti lọwọlọwọ ti gba ọna mi-in yọ bayii pẹlu bi wọn ṣe kọ lu aafin Ọbadu tilu Ilẹmẹṣọ-Ekiti, Ọba David Oyewumi, ti wọn si ji kabiyesi naa gbe.Ni nnkan bii aago mẹjọ aabọ Ọjọru, Tọsidee, niṣẹlẹ naa waye niluu naa to wa nijọba ibilẹ Ọyẹ.Gẹgẹ bi a ṣe gbọ, niṣe lawọn agbebọn naa fo fẹnsi aafin wọle lẹyin tawọn oloye ti wọn waa ṣepade ti lọ sile, bẹẹ ni wọn da ibọn bolẹ lati ko awọn ti wọn ba nibẹ ni papamọra. Lẹyin eyi ni wọn bẹrẹ si i beere ọba alaye naa, ti wọn si n fiya jẹ awọn ti wọn ri, eyi to tumọ si pe oun gan-an ni wọn n wa.Bi wọn ṣe ri kabiyesi la gbọ pe wọn gbe e, wọn si wọ ọ kuro laafin lọ sibi ti ẹnikẹni ko mọ di akoko yii.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, ASP Sunday Abutu to jẹ Alukoro ọlọpaa Ekiti sọ pe nnkan to ba ni lọkan jẹ gbaa ni, ati pe ibọn tawọn eeyan ọhun fi waa ṣọṣẹ lagbara pupọ.O waa ni iwadii ti bẹrẹ, ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa yoo si wa gbogbo ọna lati gba Ọba Oyewumi silẹ lọwọ awọn ajinigbe, ati lati mu awọn ọdaran naa.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ko ti i pe ọsẹ kan tawọn agbebọn kọ lu Elewu tilu Ewu-Ekiti, Ọba Adetutu Ajayi, lasiko to n lọ si Ayetoro-Ekiti lati ilu ẹ, ṣe ni wọn si yinbọn fun un lọwọ, ẹsẹ ati ikun lasiko to n gbiyanju lati sa fun wọn, eyi to sọ ọ dero ileewosan."},{"question":"नमस्कार। आज म सामाजिक शिक्षाको विषयमा कक्षा लिन जाँदैछु। सामाजिक अध्ययनले भूगोल, मानवविज्ञान, अर्थशास्त्र, इतिहास, समाजशास्त्र, राजनीति विज्ञान र नागरिकशास्त्र सहित समाजका विभिन्न पक्षहरूलाई समेट्छ। सामाजिक शिक्षा सिकाउने मुख्य लक्ष्य विद्यार्थीहरूलाई असल नागरिक बन्न सिकाउनु हो। हामी एक विविध समाजमा बाँचिरहेका छौं - जसलाई सफल हुनको लागि सामाजिक शिक्षाको ज्ञान चाहिन्छ। सामाजिक शिक्षाको ज्ञान भएका बच्चाहरु ठुला भएर हाम्रो समाजमा सामाजिक, सभ्य र मानवीय ढंगले भाग लिन सक्छन्।माथिको अन्नुक्चेदहरुलाई हिन्दी भाषामा लेख्नुहोस् । ","answer":"नमस्कार। आज मैं सामाजिक अध्ययन पर एक कक्षा लेने जा रहा हूँ।सामाजिक अध्ययन भूगोल, मानव विज्ञान, अर्थशास्त्र, इतिहास, समाजशास्त्र, राजनीति विज्ञान और नागरिक शास्त्र सहित समाज के विभिन्न पहलुओं को शामिल करता है। सामाजिक अध्ययन पढ़ाने का मुख्य लक्ष्य छात्रों को अच्छा नागरिक बनना सिखाना है। हम एक विविध समाज में रहते हैं - जिसमें सफल होने के लिए सामाजिक शिक्षा के ज्ञान की आवश्यकता होती है। सामाजिक शिक्षा का ज्ञान रखने वाले बच्चे बड़े होकर हमारे समाज में सामाजिक, सभ्य और मानवीय तरीके से भाग ले सकते हैं।"},{"question":"Напиши продовження тексту: Ці дані оприлюднила українська компанія «Research & Branding Group». Соціологи дізнавалися про ставлення українців до незалежності України, а також щодо подій серпня 1991 року","answer":"в різних регіонах. Так, кожний п'ятий українець визначив серпневий путч як «епізод боротьби за владу серед найвищого керівництва країни». На заході ж більшість українців охарактеризувала путч як «перемогу демократичної революції, яка покінчила із владою КПРС»."},{"question":"Kí ni àpẹẹrẹ àwon ẹ̀yà ara tí a fi ń pe ìró ní ède Yorùbá?","answer":"Àwọn nìwọ̀nyí:imú;èrìgì;kàá imú;ahọ́n;kàá ẹnu ;eyín òkè; àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ."},{"question":"Tukarkan ayat aktif berikut kepada ayat pasif. Ayat aktif:  Baginda meminta rakyat supaya bersabar.","answer":"Ayat pasif yang betul ialah 'Rakyat diminta oleh baginda supaya bersabar.'"},{"question":"Schrijf een voortzetting van de paragraaf - Het station is vernoemd naar de dichtbijgelegen \\"rue Vaneau\\". Louis Vaneau was een polytechnicus,","answer":".die sneuvelde bij de inneming van de kazerne Babylone tijdens de revolutie van juli 1830."},{"question":"විශිෂ්ඨ තාප ධාරිතාව (c) යනු කුමක්ද ?         ","answer":"යම්කිසි ද්‍රව්‍යයක ඒකක ස්කන්ධයක උෂ්ණත්වය ඒකකයකින් වැඩි කිරීම සඳහා සපයා දිය යුතු තාප ප්‍රමාණය එම ද්‍රව්‍යයේ විශිෂ්ඨ තාප ධාරිතාව යි. (J oC -1kg-1)විශිෂ්ඨ තාප ධාරිතාවයේ අගය දී ඇති ද්‍රව්‍යයට ආවේණික වේ. දී ඇති ප්‍රමාණය මත රඳා නො පවතී.m ස්කන්ධයක θ උෂ්ණත්වයකින් වැඩි කිරීම සඳහා ලබා දිය යුතු තාප ප්‍රමාණය Q නම්,                Q =mcθ"},{"question":"நாட்டுப்புறக் கதை வகைகள் யாவை?","answer":"நாட்டுப்புற இலக்கியத்தின் பல்வேறு கூறுகளில் ஒன்று நாட்டுப்புறக்கதைகளாகும். நாட்டுப்புறக்கதை என்பது வாய்வழியாகப் பரவுவதாகும். நாட்டுப்புற இலக்கியத்திற்கேயுரிய தனிச்சிறப்பைப் போன்றே இதற்குத் தனி ஆசிரியர் கிடையாது. வாய்வழியாகப் பரவி வந்துள்ளதே இதன் தனி இயல்பாகும். ஒரு நிகழ்ச்சியை விளக்கிக் கொள்ள மனிதன் கற்பனையுடன், தன் அனுபவத்தையும் இணைத்து ஏற்படுத்திக் கொண்டதே கதைகள் தோன்றக் காரணமாகும். மனிதன் தோன்றிய போது கதைகளும் தோன்றிவிட்டன எனக் கூறலாம். தனது அனுபவங்களை மற்றவர்களுக்குச் சொல்லத் தொடங்கியபொழுதே கதைகள் தோன்றிவிட்டன. மக்கள் கூட்டங்கூட்டமாக ஓரிடத்திலிருந்து மற்றோர் இடத்திற்குச் சென்றபோதும் கால்நடை மேய்ச்சலுக்காக அலைந்து திரிந்த போதும் தாம் கண்டவற்றையும், அனுபவித்தவற்றையும் கதையாகச் சொல்லத் தொடங்கினான். இவை வாய்மொழியாகப் பலருக்கும் கூறப்பட்டன. கதைகள் உருவாகத் தொடங்கிற்று.தமிழில் கதைகளைப் பற்றிய ஆய்வு அண்மைக்காலத்தில் தான் முக்கியத்துவம் பெற்று வருகிறது. நாட்டுப்புறக் கதைகளைப் பற்றிய பாகுபாடுகள் பின்வருமாறு.1. விசித்திரக் கதை 2. நாள் வாழ்வுக் கதை3. விலங்குக்கதை என பொதுவாக நாட்டுப்புறக் கதைகளை மூவகையாகப் பாகுபாடு செய்துள்ளனர்.தெலுங்கு மொழியில் நாட்டுப்புறக் கதைகளை,1. வீரகாவியம் 2. இதிகாசம் 3. அற்புதக் கதை 4. நீதிக் கதை5. புராணக்கதை என ஐவகையாகப் பாகுபாடு செய்கின்றனர்.மேலும் நாட்டுப்புறக் கதைகளை நாட்டுப்புறவியல் அறிஞர்கள் நான்கு பெரும் பிரிவுகளாக பிரித்துள்ளனர். அவை,1. மனிதக் கதைகள் 2. மிருகக் கதைகள்3. மந்திரக் கதைகள் 4. தெய்வக் கதைகள் என்பன மனிதர்களைப் பற்றியும், மனித உணர்வுகளைப் பற்றியும் கூறப்படும் கதைகள் மனிதக் கதைகள் என்ற வகையில் அடங்குவனவாகும். அரசர்கள் பற்றிய கதைகளும் இவ்வகையில் அடங்கும். காதல், உல்லாசம், பிரயாணம், நீதி முதலியனவும் இவ்வகையில் அடங்கும்."},{"question":"Wane abinci ne ake magana a kai a matsayin mafi mahimmancin rana?","answer":"Abincin karin kumallo"},{"question":"Iza no heverina ho mpanoratra ny bokin’ny Genesisy ao amin’ny Testamenta Taloha?","answer":"Ny bokin'ny Genesisy dia nosoratan'i Mosesy."},{"question":"Từ các chi tiết “tự hoạ” về bản thân và lời lẽ, cách xưng hô, điệu bộ, giọng điệu, thái độ của Dế Mèn đối với Dế Choắt, chị Cốc, trong Bài học đường đời đầu tiên của tác giả Tô Hoài em có nhận xét gì về tính cách của nhân vật này?","answer":"- Dế Mèn “tự họa” bản thân: tự hào, kiêu căng.- Lời lẽ, cách xưng hô, điệu bộ, giọng điệu, thái độ của Dế Mèn đối với Dế Choắt, chị Cốc: chế giễu, coi thường.→ Tính cách của Dế Mèn hống hách, nghịch ngợm, ích kỉ, chỉ biết đến bản thân mình."},{"question":"చిట్టీ, సూఫీ బోధకుల విజయాలను చర్చించండి.","answer":"భారతదేశంలోని చిట్టీ, సూఫీ బోధకుల్లో ఖ్వాజా మొయినుద్దీన్ శిష్యులైన షేక్ హమీదుద్దీన్, షేక్ కుతుబుద్దీన్ భక్తియార్ కాకిలు ప్రధానమైనవారు. వారు సమానత్వాన్ని బోధిస్తూ సామాన్య జీవితాన్ని గడిపారు. శాకాహారులైన వారు స్థానిక హిందువులతో సన్నిహితంగా మెలిగారు. రాజపోషణ, దానాలు తీసుకోవడాన్ని వారు వ్యతిరేకించారు. గాత్ర, వాయిద్య సంగీతాలలో గొప్ప ఆధ్యాత్మికత ఉన్నట్లువారు పేర్కొన్నారు. భక్తియార్ కాకికి ఆధ్యాత్మిక సంగీతం అంటే ఇష్టం. సూఫీ బోధకులు తమ ఆశ్రమాల్లో ఏర్పాటు చేసిన హిందూ, ముస్లిం సంగీత విభావరులు అశేష ప్రజానీకాన్ని ఆకట్టుకొన్నాయి.షేక్ ఫరీద్ లేదా బబాఫరీద్ ఢిల్లీ సుల్తానుల కాలానికి చెందిన మరొక సూఫీ బోధకుడు. అతడు అతి సామాన్య జీవితాన్ని గడిపాడు. భక్తి బోధకుల సంగీతాన్ని ఇష్టపడేవాడు. ఆయన శిష్యుల్లో నిజాముద్దీన్ అలియా ముఖ్యుడు. ఢిల్లీలోని ఘజియాపూర్లో తన కేంద్రాన్ని ఏర్పాటు చేశాడు.హజరత్ నిజాముద్దీన్ వినయశీలి. ఇతడు అత్యంత సామాన్య జీవితాన్ని గడిపాడు. పేదవారిని ప్రేమించాడు. ఢిల్లీ సుల్తానుల బహుమానాలను ఆయన తిరస్కరించాడు. నసీరుద్దీన్ చిరాగ్, షేక్ సలీం చిష్టిలు ఆయన ప్రధాన శిష్యులు. షేక్ సలీమ్ చిష్టీ అక్బర్ సమకాలీకుడు. ఇతని సిద్ధాంతాలు, జీవనవిధానం అక్బర్ను తీవ్రంగా ప్రభావితం చేశాయి. అక్బర్ స్వయంగా ఫతేపూర్ సిక్రిని సందర్శించి చిష్టీ ఆశీస్సులను పొందాడు. తనకు కుమారుడు జన్మించాక అతనికి సలీమ్ అని అక్బర్ నామకరణం చేశాడు. చిష్తీ సమాధిపై అక్బర్ నిర్మించిన దర్గా ఉరుసు సందర్భంగా అన్ని ప్రాంతాల, అన్ని మతాల ప్రజలను విశేషంగా ఆకర్షిస్తూ ఉంది."},{"question":"Manana teny mikotorana ianaoLAOLAOmeo ary teny marina :","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"LALAO\\""},{"question":"ජංගම පරිගණනය (Mobile Computing) යනු කුමක්ද ? ","answer":"භෞතික සම්බන්ධයකින් තොරව පරිගණක හෝ වෙනත් රැහැන් රහික  උපක්‍රම භාවිතයෙන් ශ්‍රව්‍ය. දෘශ්‍ය දත්ත හුවමාරු කිරීමයි."},{"question":"你爸爸和你妈妈生了个儿子,他既不是你哥哥又不是你弟弟,他是谁","answer":"答案：是你自己呀"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe Trinite ao amin'ny Kristianisma?","answer":"Ny Trinite dia ny fampianarana fa iray ihany Andriamanitra, saingy ao amin'ny persona telo: ny Ray, ny Zanaka ary ny Fanahy Masina."},{"question":"\\"හදන්නට වැහි බිංදුවක්\\" ගීතයේ ඉතිරි පද සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.","answer":"හදන්නට වැහි බිංදුවක්පොළොව ගහකොළ විඳි දුකක්දන්නවා නම් තෙමෙනවා ඔබමහා වැස්සේ කල්පයක්ඔබ සොයා ගෙන ආ දුරක්වින්ද අපමණ දුක් කඳක්දන්නවා නම් යන්නෙ නෑ ඔබමා දමා මේ හැටි දුරක්නෙතට නිදි නැති රැය දුකක්ඉසිඹුවක් නොලදිමි පැයක්ඔබව හිත ළඟ බලා ගත් හැටිදන්නෙ නෑ ලොව කවුරුවත්කරුණාරත්න දිවුල්ගනේනාරද විජේසූරියරෝහණ ධර්මකීර්ති"},{"question":"Iza no oniversite be mpianatra indrindra maneran-tany?","answer":"\\"Indira Gandhi National Open University \\"(IGNOU) any India no oniversite be mpianatra indrindra maneran-tany, manolotra fampiofanana tsy mivivanta amin'ny alalan'ny serasera ho an'ny mpianatra an-tapitrisany."},{"question":"What is the highest mountain in the world?","answer":"The highest mountain in the world is Mount Everest. It reaches approximately 8,848.86 meters (29,031.7 feet) above sea level, according to a 2020 revision of its height by China and Nepal. It is located in the Himalayas on the border between Nepal and the Tibet Autonomous Region of China.Other mountains have claimed to be the tallest when measured from points other than sea level. For example, the top of Mount Chimborazo is farther from the Earth's center than Mount Everest. Ojos del Salado has the greatest rise on Earth, at 13,420 meters (44,029 feet) vertically to the summit from the bottom of the Atacama Trench. "},{"question":"வினா: ஜாலியன் வாலாபாக் படுகொலை எந்த ஆண்டு நடந்தது?1) 16192) 17193) 18194) 1919","answer":"விடை: 1919"},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Jawa yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia.Bareng wis suwe, Razia weruh luwih akeh kewan nglangi. Dheweke sinau solahe kewan kang anyar. Razia nendhang. Dheweke ngambang. Dheweke lumenggang. Dheweke nyilem. Dheweke ngampet ambegan suwe lan saya suwe. Dheweke nglangi cepet.Terjemahan:","answer":"Hari-hari berlalu. Rasya mengamati cara beraneka ragam hewan berenang. Ia mempelajari banyak gerakan baru. Rasya menendang. Ia mengapung. Ia bergoyang- goyang. Ia menyelam. Ia menahan napasnya makin lama dan lama. Ia berenang makin cepat."},{"question":"Mene ne huɗa?","answer":"Shine rarraba ƙasa, sassauta/tuna ƙasa, da jujjuya ƙasar don tumɓuke ciyayi da jika ƙasar."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và trả lời câu hỏi: thời gian cho sinh viên nghỉ Tết dài nhất là bao nhiêu?Đoạn văn: Gần 40 trường đại học công bố lịch nghỉ Tết Nguyên đán 2024, phần lớn trong 2-3 tuần, có trường gần một tháng.Thời gian cho sinh viên nghỉ Tết dài nhất hiện thuộc về trường Đại học Công thương TP HCM, với 28 ngày nghỉ, từ 29/1/2024 đến 25/2.Lý giải, thạc sĩ Phạm Thái Sơn, Giám đốc Trung tâm tuyển sinh và Truyền thông, cho biết nhà trường mong sinh viên, giảng viên có thời gian nghỉ ngơi, tái tạo sức lao động. Sinh viên xa quê có thể giảm chi phí đi lại đắt đỏ dịp Tết nhờ tránh được những ngày cao điểm.\\"Khung thời gian năm học bao gồm lịch nghỉ Tết đã được sắp xếp từ đầu năm nên không ảnh hưởng đến chương trình dạy học\\", ông Sơn nói.Ở khu vực phía bắc, trường Đại học Kinh tế, Đại học Quốc gia Hà Nội; trường Đại học Tài nguyên và Môi trường Hà Nội, Sư phạm Hà Nội 2 (Vĩnh Phúc) thuộc nhóm cho sinh viên nghỉ sớm và dài nhất, kéo dài 21 ngày, từ 21/1 đến 18/2 (tức 19 tháng chạp đến mùng 9 tháng giêng).","answer":"Thời gian cho sinh viên nghỉ Tết dài nhất là 28 ngày và thuộc về trường Đại học Công thương TP HCM, từ ngày 29/1/2024 đến ngày 25/2/2024 với 28 ngày nghỉ."},{"question":" காளமேகப் புலவரின் இயற்பெயர் என்ன?","answer":" காளமேகப் புலவரின் இயற்பெயர் வரதன் ஆகும்.காளமேகம் 15 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் வாழ்ந்த ஒரு தமிழ்ப் புலவர் ஆவார். வைணவ சமயத்தில் பிறந்த இவர், திருவானைக்கா கோவிலைச் சேர்ந்த மோகனாங்கி என்பவளிடம் ஆசை கொண்டார். இதனால் தனது சமயத்தை விட்டு மோகனாங்கி சார்ந்திருந்த சைவ சமயத்துக்கு மாறினார். இவர் சைவப் பாடல்கள் பாடுவதில் வல்லவர் என்று கூறப்படுகின்றது. ஆனாலும் இவர் பல சிறந்த நயம் மிகுந்த பாடல்களையும் பாடியுள்ளார். இவர் பாடிய சிலேடைப் பாடல்களும், நகைச் சுவைப் பாடல்களும் பல உள்ளன. சமயம் சார்ந்த நூல்களையும் இவர் இயற்றியுள்ளார். இவர் ஒரு ஆசு கவி ஆவார்."},{"question":"சிரிக்கும் வாயு என்றும் அழைக்கப்படும் வாயு எது?","answer":"விடை: நைட்ரஸ் ஆக்சைடு"},{"question":"-النحلة ترفرف بجناحيها في الثانية الواحدة بمعدل….؟","answer":"(350 مرة)"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai langau mengerumuni bangkai\\"?","answer":"Peribahasa ini menghuraikan keadaan yang riuh-rendah."},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, akẹkọọ UNIOSUN para ẹ, majele lo gbe jẹ","answer":"Akẹkọọ kan to wa nipele akọkọ ni ẹka ileewe UNIOSUN to wa niluu Ikire, Juba Babatunde Philips, lo ti gbẹmi ara rẹ bayii.Oogun ti wọn fi n pa kokoro (snipper), la gbọ pe Babatunde, ẹni to wa ni ẹka ti wọn ti n kọ nipa ere itage, Theatre Art. lawọn ọrẹ rẹ ba oku ẹ ninu yara rẹ nirọlẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun,Tusidee, ọsẹ yii.Gẹgẹ bi iwadii ṣe fi han oniruuru ọrọ nipa igbẹmi ara ẹni ni ọmọdekunrin naa ti n kọ sori ikanni ayelujara rẹ lẹnu lọọlọ yii.Agbẹnusọ ileewe UNIOSUN, Adesọji Ademọla, fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ, o ṣalaye pe ko ti i si ẹnikẹni to le sọ ni pato nnkan to mu ki oloogbe gbe igbesẹ naa.Bakan naa ni Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, Yẹmisi Ọpalọla, ṣalaye pe olori ẹṣọ alaabo ileewe naa, Akintibubọ Rahman, lo lọọ fi iṣẹlẹ naa to awọn ọlọpaa leti, wọn si ba agolo oogun to lo ọhun lẹgbẹẹ rẹ.Ọpalọla ni wọn ti gbe oku rẹ lọ sile igbokuu-si ti ileewosan Catholic Hospital, Oluyoro, Apomu fun ayẹwo to peye."},{"question":"வினா:தொல்லை வினைதரு தொல்லை அகன்று சுடர்க ……………………அ) ஆந்திராஆ) கர்நாடகாஇ) கேரளம்ஈ) தமிழ்நாடு","answer":"விடை: ஈ) தமிழ்நாடு"},{"question":"Qual a resposta correta para a pergunta a seguir: Qual rainha Britânica nunca teve um filho?","answer":"A resposta correta é Elizabeth I"},{"question":"ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਕਿਹੜੇ ਭਾਗ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸਦੀ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਬਾਹਰੀ ਭਾਗ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"ابحث عن البلدان المقابلة لقائمة العملات التالية.","answer":"\\"- اليورو:تستخدم اليورو كعملة رسمية في الدول الأعضاء في الاتحاد الأوروبي، وهي 19 دولة تشمل:النمسا، بلجيكا، قبرص، إستونيا، فنلندا، فرنسا، ألمانيا، اليونان، إيرلندا، إيطاليا، لاتفيا، ليتوانيا، لوكسمبورغ، مالطا، هولندا، البرتغال، سلوفاكيا، سلوفينيا، إسبانيا.- الين الياباني:تستخدم الين الياباني كعملة رسمية في اليابان فقط.- الدولار الأسترالي:تستخدم الدولار الأسترالي كعملة رسمية في أستراليا، وكذلك، في جزر كوك، توفالو، نوي، كيريباتي، ناورو، جزر سليمان، جزيرة نورفولك، وفانواتو. علاوة على ذلك، تستخدم الدولار الأسترالي أيضًا كعملة غير رسمية في كل من كرايستشيرش وغرب وايتراب في نيوزيلندا.\\""},{"question":"ગુજરાતની પ્રખ્યાત મહિલાઓ વિષે કહો","answer":"ગુજરાત રાજ્ય વિવિધ ક્ષેત્રોમાં નોંધપાત્ર યોગદાન આપતી મહિલાઓનો સમૃદ્ધ ઇતિહાસ ધરાવે છે. સામાજિક સક્રિયતા અને શિક્ષણથી લઈને વ્યવસાય અને રાજકારણ સુધી, ગુજરાતી મહિલાઓએ રાજ્યની પ્રગતિ અને વિકાસને આકાર આપવામાં મુખ્ય ભૂમિકા ભજવી છે. અહીં ગુજરાતની કેટલીક નોંધપાત્ર મહિલાઓ છે જેમણે વિવિધ ક્ષેત્રોમાં પોતાની ઓળખ બનાવી છે:ડૉ. ઇલાબેન મહેતા (1938-2009): ડૉ. ઇલાબેન મહેતા એક પ્રખ્યાત બાળરોગ અને સામાજિક કાર્યકર હતા જેમણે ગ્રામીણ ગુજરાતમાં બાળ આરોગ્ય અને શિક્ષણને સુધારવા માટે પોતાનું જીવન સમર્પિત કર્યું હતું. તેણીએ અમદાવાદમાં શ્રી આસ્થા ચિલ્ડ્રન હોસ્પિટલની સ્થાપના કરી, જે વંચિત બાળકો માટે આશાનું કિરણ બની. તેણીના અથાક પ્રયત્નો અને દયાળુ સંભાળે તેણીને બાળરોગ અને સામાજિક કાર્યના ક્ષેત્રમાં એક આઇકોન બનાવી.મીરા સોમાણી (1962-2018): મીરા સોમાણી એક અગ્રણી ઉદ્યોગસાહસિક અને પરોપકારી હતા જેમણે ગુજરાતના કાપડ ઉદ્યોગમાં પરિવર્તન લાવ્યું હતું. તેણીએ કાપડ કંપની, કલાપારીની સ્થાપના કરી, જે તેની ઉત્કૃષ્ટ હસ્તકલા અને ટકાઉ પ્રથાઓ માટે જાણીતી વૈશ્વિક બ્રાન્ડ બની. મહિલા કારીગરોને સશક્ત બનાવવા અને પરંપરાગત કાપડ તકનીકોને સાચવવા માટેના તેણીના સમર્પણે તેણીને મહત્વાકાંક્ષી ઉદ્યોગસાહસિકો માટે રોલ મોડેલ બનાવ્યા.આનંદીબાઈ જોશી (1865-1887): આનંદીબાઈ જોશી ભારતની પ્રથમ મહિલા ચિકિત્સક હતી. ગુજરાતના કલ્યાણમાં જન્મેલી, તેણીએ સામાજિક અવરોધોને પાર કર્યા અને મુંબઈમાં તબીબી શિક્ષણ મેળવ્યું. તેણીનો અભ્યાસ પૂર્ણ કર્યા પછી, તેણીએ સુરતમાં દવાની પ્રેક્ટિસ કરી અને મહિલા સશક્તિકરણ અને શિક્ષણનું પ્રતીક બની. તેણીનો વારસો મહિલાઓને તેમના સપનાઓને અનુસરવા અને લિંગ સ્ટીરિયોટાઇપ્સને તોડવા માટે પ્રેરણા આપવાનું ચાલુ રાખે છે.મલ્લિકા સારાભાઈ (1952-): મલ્લિકા સારાભાઈ એક પ્રખ્યાત ડાન્સર, કોરિયોગ્રાફર અને સામાજિક કાર્યકર્તા છે. તેણીએ અમદાવાદમાં દર્પણ એકેડેમી ઓફ પર્ફોર્મિંગ આર્ટ્સની સ્થાપના કરી, જે શાસ્ત્રીય ભારતીય નૃત્ય માટે એક અગ્રણી સંસ્થા બની ગઈ છે. તેમનું કાર્ય ભારતીય નૃત્ય પરંપરાઓને જાળવવા અને પ્રોત્સાહન આપવામાં મહત્ત્વપૂર્ણ રહ્યું છે, અને તેમની સક્રિયતાએ મહિલાઓના અધિકારો અને પર્યાવરણીય સંરક્ષણ જેવા મુદ્દાઓ પર ધ્યાન કેન્દ્રિત કર્યું છે.સ્મિતા પાટીલ (1955-1986): સ્મિતા પાટીલ એક પ્રખ્યાત ભારતીય અભિનેત્રી હતી જેણે હિન્દી સિનેમા પર નોંધપાત્ર અસર કરી હતી. પુણે, ગુજરાતમાં જન્મેલી, તેણીએ 1980 ના દાયકામાં સ્ટારડમમાં વધારો કર્યો, વિવિધ ભૂમિકાઓમાં તેણીની વૈવિધ્યતા અને પ્રતિભા દર્શાવી. તેણીની ફિલ્મોમાં ઘણીવાર સામાજિક મુદ્દાઓની શોધ કરવામાં આવી હતી અને પરંપરાગત ધોરણોને પડકારવામાં આવી હતી, જે તેણીને મહિલાઓ અને હાંસિયામાં ધકેલાઈ ગયેલા જૂથો માટે એક શક્તિશાળી અવાજ બનાવે છે.લીલાવતી મુનિ (1946-2022): લીલાવતી મુનિ એક પ્રખ્યાત ગુજરાતી લોકગાયિકા હતા જેમણે પોતાના ભાવપૂર્ણ અવાજ અને મનમોહક વાર્તા કહેવાથી શ્રોતાઓને મંત્રમુગ્ધ કર્યા હતા. ગુજરાતી લોકસંગીતને વિશાળ શ્રોતાઓ સુધી પહોંચાડવામાં તેણી અગ્રણી હતી અને ગુજરાતી સાંસ્કૃતિક વારસાને જાળવવામાં મહત્વની ભૂમિકા ભજવી હતી. તેના ગીતો પેઢી દર પેઢી લોકોમાં ગુંજતા રહે છે.દુલારી દેવી (1924-2012): દુલારી દેવી ગુજરાતના પ્રખ્યાત લોક કલાકાર અને વાર્તાકાર હતા. તેણી તેના જટિલ મધુબની ચિત્રો માટે જાણીતી હતી, જેમાં પૌરાણિક કથાઓ અને લોકકથાઓનું નિરૂપણ કરવામાં આવ્યું હતું. તેણીના કાર્યને 2005 માં પ્રતિષ્ઠિત પદ્મશ્રી પુરસ્કારથી માન્યતા આપવામાં આવી હતી, અને તેણીનો વારસો કલાકારો અને વાર્તાકારોને પ્રેરણા આપતો રહે છે.મણિબેન પટેલ (1903-1994): મણિબેન પટેલ એક પ્રખ્યાત સામાજિક કાર્યકર અને શિક્ષણવિદ હતા જેમણે ગ્રામીણ ગુજરાતમાં મહિલાઓ અને બાળકોના સશક્તિકરણ માટે પોતાનું જીવન સમર્પિત કર્યું હતું. તેણીએ ગૂજરાત વિદ્યાપીઠની સ્થાપના કરી, જે એક અગ્રણી સંસ્થા છે જેણે મહિલાઓને શિક્ષણ અને વ્યાવસાયિક તાલીમ પૂરી પાડી હતી. તેણીના કામે ગુજરાતમાં મહિલાઓના અધિકારો અને શિક્ષણને આગળ વધારવામાં મુખ્ય ભૂમિકા ભજવી હતી.આશા પારેખ (1942-): આશા પારેખ એક પ્રખ્યાત ભારતીય અભિનેત્રી છે જેણે 1960 અને 1970 ના દાયકા દરમિયાન હિન્દી સિનેમામાં સર્વોચ્ચ શાસન કર્યું હતું. ગુજરાતમાં જન્મેલી, તેણીએ પોતાની જાતને તેના સમયની સૌથી સફળ અભિનેત્રીઓમાંની એક તરીકે સ્થાપિત કરી, જે તેણીની ગ્રેસ, લાવણ્ય અને વર્સેટિલિટી માટે જાણીતી છે. ભારતીય સિનેમામાં તેમના યોગદાનને 1997માં પદ્મશ્રી સહિત અસંખ્ય પુરસ્કારોથી માન્યતા આપવામાં આવી છે.ગુજરાતની આ મહિલાઓએ પોતપોતાના ક્ષેત્રોમાં અવરોધોને તોડીને આવનારી પેઢીઓને પ્રેરણા આપતાં મહત્ત્વપૂર્ણ યોગદાન આપ્યું છે. તેમની સિદ્ધિઓએ માત્ર રાજ્યની પ્રગતિને આકાર આપ્યો નથી પરંતુ ભારતના સાંસ્કૃતિક, સામાજિક અને બૌદ્ધિક લેન્ડસ્કેપ પર પણ અમીટ છાપ છોડી છે."},{"question":"在加拿大，雙形道上轉左，應行駛在哪條行車道？","answer":"靠近分界線（黃線）右邊行車"},{"question":"Ile-ẹjọ ni ki ọlọpaa san owo itanran fun Agboọla, igbakeji gomina Ondo tẹlẹ","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ giga kan to fikalẹ siluu Akurẹ ti pasẹ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa orilẹ-ede yii lati san ọgọrun-un miliọnu fun igbakeji gomina ana nipinlẹ Ondo, Ọnarebu Agboọla Ajayi, lori bi wọn ko ṣe fun un laaye lati tete kẹru rẹ kuro nile ijọba.Onidaajọ F. A. Olubanjọ to gbe idajọ ọhun kalẹ lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ to kọja yii, ni ṣe lawọn ẹsọ alaabo tẹ ẹtọ igbakeji gomina tẹlẹ ọhun mọlẹ pẹlu bi wọn ṣe fipa da a duro sile ijọba laarin aago mẹsan-an aarọ ogunjọ, oṣu kẹfa, ọdun 2020.Adajọ ni iwa tawọn agbofinro ọhun hu ko bojumu rara, nitori pe ti wọn ba le fi iru iya bẹẹ jẹ Agboọla pẹlu gbogbo anfaani ofin asẹmalu to rọ mọ ipo igbakeji gomina to wa nigba naa, ọjọ n bọ ti wọn yoo fipa gbe odidi aarẹ orilẹ-ede lori awawi pe awọn fẹẹ ṣe iwadii rẹ.Onidaajọ Olubanjọ ni awọn ọlọpaa gbọdọ san ọgọrun-un miliọnu naira fun Agboọla gẹgẹ bii owo ‘gba ma binu’ lori ẹtọ rẹ ti wọn fi du u labẹ ofin dipo biliọnu kan naira ti olupẹjọ n beere fun."},{"question":"Qual a resposta da piada a seguir: Como um homem sedentário queima três mil calorias de uma só vez?","answer":"Deixando queimar um bolo inteiro."},{"question":"ලක්ශපාන විදුලි බලාගාරය පිහිටා  ඇත්තේ මොන පළාතේද?","answer":"ලක්ශපාන විදුලි බලාගාරය පිහිටා  ඇත්තේ මධ්‍යම පළාතේ ලක්ශපාන විදුලි බලාගාරය පිහිටා   ඇත"},{"question":"ما هي الدولة التي عاصمتها برلين؟","answer":"ألمانيا."},{"question":"Awọn obi ati olukọ ta ko bijọba ṣe kọ lati ṣi ileewe ni Kwara","answer":"Nitori bijọba ṣe kọ lati ṣi awọn ileewe pada nipinlẹ Kwara, awọn obi ati olukọ ileewe aladaani ni igbesẹ naa ko bojumu rara.Ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ yii, lawọn eeyan ọhun fẹhonu niluu Ilọrin. Wọn ni ebi ti fẹẹ lu awọn pa bawọn ṣe n jokoo sile, nitori idi eyi, kijọba ṣaanu awọn, ki wọn ṣi awọn ileewe ni kiakia.Alaga ẹgbẹ awọn oludasilẹ ileewe aladaani ni Kwara, National Association of Proprietors of Private Schools, Dokita Rahaman Adetunji, ṣalaye pe jijokoo sile lai ṣe nnkan kan ti su awọn akẹkọọ atawọn olukọ.O ni pẹlu bi ijọba ṣe ṣi ileewe fun idanwo aṣekagba, WASCE, o fi han pe awọn ileewe ti ṣee ṣi, nitori pe ko si akẹkọọ kankan to jokoo ṣedanwo to lugbadi arun Korona laarin asiko ti idanwo naa fi waye.Adetunji ni, “Awọn ileejọsin, ọja atawọn mi-in to jẹ pe o rọrun lati ko arun Korona nitori ero rẹpẹtẹ to maa n wa nibẹ gan-an ti di ṣiṣi, ki waa lo fa a ti ileewe ṣe maa wa ni titi.”O ni o kere tan, bii ida marundinlọgọrun-un awọn ileewe aladaani to wa ni Kwara lo ti ṣeto ilana ti wọn yoo fi daabo bo awọn akẹkọọ ati olukọ lọwọ lilugbadi arun naa.O rọ ijọba Kwara lati gbe igbesẹ kia, ko si kede asiko ati ilana iwọle awọn akẹkọọ"},{"question":"युनिभर्सल बेसिक इनकम (UBI) को अवधारणा समाजमा पैसाको वितरणसँग कसरी सम्बन्धित छ?","answer":"UBI ले सबै नागरिकहरूलाई नियमित, बिना शर्त आम्दानी, सम्पत्ति वितरण, गरिबी निवारण, सामाजिक कल्याण इत्यादी कुराहरु समावेश गर्दछ।"},{"question":"වගවීම යන්න පහදාන්න.","answer":"වගවීම කියන්නෙ යම් කටයුත්තක් ඉටු කැරෙන බවට බැඳී සිටීමයි."},{"question":"හිරු උදා වන්නේ කුමන දිශාවෙන්ද ?","answer":"නැගෙනහිර දිශාවෙන්ද හිරු උදා  වේ."},{"question":"kukuthini ukuthi b'uu ngengubo in isixhosa?","answer":"Kubeka ingubo ngaphezulu."},{"question":"ਗਰਮੀ ਰੁੱਤ ਵਿਚ ਉਗਾਈ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਖੁੰਬਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਤੇ ਉਸਦੀਆਂ ਕਿੰਨੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਸਲਾਂ ਲਈਆਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ?","answer":"ਗਰਮੀ ਰੁੱਤ ਵਿਚ ਉਗਾਈ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਪਰਾਲੀ ਵਾਲੀ ਖੁੰਬ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਤੋਂ 4 ਫ਼ਸਲਾਂ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"Wọn ti mu awọn Fulani ajinigbe to pa Olori-Ọdọ n’Ibadan","answer":"Lẹyin bii oṣu kan ti wọn yinbọn pa Olori-Ọdọ lagbegbe Akinyẹle, n’Ibadan, ọwọ ọlọpaa ti tẹ awọn Fulani darandaran to huwa ọdaran naa.Ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọjọ keji, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun 2021 yii, ni wọn ṣafihan awọn afurasi apaayan naa ti wọn n jẹ Usman Mohammed, ẹni ọdun mẹtadinlọgbọn, ati Umaru Mohammed toun jẹ ẹni ọdun mẹrindinlogun.Gẹgẹ b’ALAROYE ṣe gbọ, ijinigbe ni wọn fi bẹrẹ ipaniyan ọhun pẹlu bi wọn ṣe tan awọn ọmọ Yoruba kan lọ sinu igbo, ti wọn si ji wọn gbe. Awọn ọdọ agbegbe ọhun to tun fi ara wọn ji lati gba awọn to wa ni igbekun wọn silẹ lawọn ọdaju eeyan yii yinbọn pa ọga wọn ti wọn n pe l’Olori-Ọdọ.Nigba to n ṣafihan awọn afurasi ọdaran naa, Ọga agba ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ, CP Ngozi Onadeko, sọ pe eyi to n jẹ Umaru Muhammed ninu awọn Fulani wọnyi lo pe ọmọ Yoruba kan to n jẹ Taofeek pe maaluu to fẹẹ ra lọwọ oun ti wa nilẹ, ko tete maa bọ waa ba oun ni Kaara l’Akinyẹle lati waa gbe e.O ni, “Bi Taofeek ṣe n gba ipe ọhun tan loun pẹlu aburo ẹ to n jẹ Yusuf Taiwo gun ọkada lọọ pade ọkunrin onimaalu naa laimọ pe iyẹn ti ṣeto awọn to maa ji wọn gbe soju ọna ibi ti wọn maa gba kọja lọ si Aba Onidundu ti wọn ni maaluu ọhun wa gan-an.“Bi wọn ṣe de oju-ọlọmọ-o-to-o lawọn ajinigbe naa yọ si wọn tibọntibọn, ti wọn si ji Taiwo gbe nigba ti Ọlaide ribi ba sa mọ wọn lọwọ.“Bi wọn ṣe fiṣẹlẹ yii to wa leti lawọn eeyan mi to n gbogun ti ijinigbe (Anti Kidnapping Squard, AKA) ti ya bo inu igbo gbogbo to wa lagbegbe yẹn, ti wọn si fin awọn afurasi ọdaran naa jade nibuba wọn.“Bẹẹ la ri ẹni to wa ni igbekun wọn tu silẹ. Ibọn awọn afurasi ajinigbebyen ti ba a n’itan, nibi ti wọn ti n gbiyanju lati gbe e lọjọsi.“Ṣugbọn o ṣe ni laaanu pe bi awọn afurasi ọdaran yii ṣe n sa lọ ki awọn olopaa ma baa ri wọn mu, wọn pade awọn ọdọ adugbo yẹn kan loju ọna, wọn si yinbọn pa ọkan ninu wọn ti wọn n pe ni Olori-Ọdọ.“Ninu itẹsiwaju iwadii ta a ṣe lori iṣẹlẹ bayii la ti ri Usman ati Umaru mu. Iwadii ṣi n lọ lọwọ lati ri awọn yooku wọn ti wọn jọ lẹdi àpò pọ lati huwa ọdaran yẹn mu.”Eyi to n jẹ Umaru Muhammed ninu awọn Fulani naa sọ pe loootọ lawọn tan Taiwo ati Ọlaide lọ sọdọ awọn ajinigbe ki awọn le rowo gba lọwọ awọn ẹbi wọn leyin ti awọn ba ji wọn gbe tan. Ṣugbọn awọn ọdọ kan di awọn lọwọ, wọnyi ko jẹ ki awọn fara balẹ ṣiṣẹ naa plu bi wọn ṣe wa awọn wa sinu igbo. Eyi lo si mu ki awọn yinbọn fun wọn, ti ọkan ninu wọn fi jẹ Ọlọrun nipe."},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn kọ lu ileeṣẹ ologun ni Kaduna, wọn paayan meji, wọn tun ji ṣọja kan gbe sa lọ","answer":"Iyalẹnu lo ṣi n jẹ fun gbogbo awọn ti wọn gbọ pe awọn agbebọn ya wọn ileeṣẹ ologun, (Nigerian Defence Academy), to wa niluu Kaduna, ti wọn si ṣakọlu si wọn, nibi ti wọn ti pa ṣọja meji, ti wọn si ji ẹni kan gbe sa lọ laaarọ kutukutu ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe aṣọ ologun ni awọn eeyan naa wọ, ti wọn si dibọn bii pe ṣọja ni wọn, eyi lo fun wọn ni anfaani lati kọja lọdọ awọn ẹṣọ to yẹ ki wọn yẹ wọn wo.Bi wọn ṣe kuro nibẹ ileegbee awọn ọmọ ogun ni wọn kọri si, bi wọn si ti de itosi ibẹ ni wọn da ibọn bolẹ, ti wọn bẹrẹ si i yin in lakọ lakọ. Lasiko yii ni wọn yinbọ pa ọga ṣọja meji, ti wọn si tun ji ẹni kan ti wọn pe ni mejọ lẹnu iṣẹ ologun gbe lọ.Ariwo ibọn yii lo ta awọn ikọ ayaraṣaṣa awọn ṣọja lolobo ti wọn fi sare bọ sita. Ṣugbọn ẹpa ko boro mọ, awọn agbebọn naa ti sa lọ pẹlu ọkan ninu awọn ṣọja ti wọn ji, awọn ẹṣọ alaabo ayaraṣaṣa awọn ṣọja yii ko ri i gba pada.A gbọ pe ikọ awọn ologun naa ti bẹrẹ si i wa gbogbo inu igbo, bẹẹ ni wọn gbe baalu to maa n ṣawari awọn inu igbo ati ibi kọlọfin gbogbo jade lati le ṣawari awọn to ṣiṣẹ ibi naa.Niṣe lẹru bẹrẹ si i ba gbogbo awọn to gbọ nipa iṣẹlẹ naa, ohun ti wọn si n sọ ni pe bi awọn agbebọn ba le wọ ileewe awọn ṣọja lọ, nibo lo ku ti aabo tun waa wa lorileede yii."},{"question":"नेपालको जैविक विविधता संरक्षणमा \\"राष्ट्रिय निकुञ्ज\\" र \\"संरक्षण क्षेत्रहरू\\" को महत्त्व व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"नेपालका राष्ट्रिय निकुञ्ज र संरक्षण क्षेत्रहरू विविध पारिस्थितिक प्रणाली, वन्यजन्तु र जैविक विविधताको संरक्षणका लागि महत्वपूर्ण छन्।"},{"question":"මනෝ විද්‍යාවේ පියා කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"සිග්මන් ප්‍රොයිඩ්"},{"question":"Sheeg ubadka aan Aabe Mooye, Awoowe aanan laheyn?","answer":"Waa ilma Aadam CS."},{"question":"W ilu stopniach woda zaczyna wrzeć?","answer":"Przy normalnym ciśnieniu, woda wrze w 100 stopniach."},{"question":"ඩිමෙන්ශියාවට වඩාත් පොදු හේතුව වන රෝගය පිළිබඳ සොයාගැනීම්","answer":"නව ඖෂධයක්, රුධිර පරීක්ෂණ සහ රෝගීන් සඳහා වූ සුවිශේෂී ගම්මානයක් යන කරුණු පසුගිය වසර හතර තුළ ඇල්සයිමර් රෝගීන් සඳහා නව බලාපොරොත්තු ලබා දුන් කරුණු ඇතුලත් වේ. ඩිමෙන්ශියා රෝගීන් සිටින පවුල්වල තරුණ හා මහලු සැමට උපකාර කිරීමට තවත් බොහෝ දේ තිබේ. අදාළ පර්යේෂණ වලින් මෑත වසරවල සැළකිය යුතු වර්ධනයන් සනිටුහන් වී ඇති අතර, ගෙවුණු සැප්තැම්බර් 21 වන දින ලෝක ඇල්සයිමර් දිනය සැමරුණු අතර එය නිමිති කොට ගෙන අපි සොයා ගත් කරුණු හතරක් ගැන ඔබ වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කරන්නෙමු."},{"question":"\\"ویبینار \\"کس طرح اپنے سوشل میڈیا کے لئے مفت مواد تخلیق کریں\\" کی خلاصہ تیار کریں اور شامل کریں کہ ویبینار میں مواد تخلیق کرنے کے لئے آپ کو استعمال کرنے والی ایپلیکیشنز کا عملی استعمال شامل ہوگا جیسے کہ \\"کینوا\\"۔\\"","answer":"سیشن کا خاکہ: \\"سوشل میڈیا کے لئے مفت مواد تخلیق کرنے کا طریقہ\\"I. مقدمہ   A. سوشل میڈیا پلیٹ فارمز پر مشغول کنندہ مواد کی اہمیت   B. سیشن کے اہداف کا جائزہII. مواد تخلیق کو سمجھنا   A. مواد کی تخلیق کی تعریف اور اس کی اہمیت کا تشریح   B. مختلف قسم کے مواد (تصاویر، ویڈیوز، مواد)   C. تخلیقیت اور انوکھا پن کی کردارIII. مفت مواد تخلیق کے لئے استریٹیجیاں   A. اپنے ذاتی تجربات اور دلچسپیوں کا استعمال کرنا   B. موجودہ مواد کو نئے نظریے سے دوبارہ تخلیق کرنا   C. مخاطبین کے لئے قیمتی معلومات شامل کرناIV. آپ کے مواد کی منظمی اور منصوبہ بندی   A. ایک مواد کی تقویم تخلیق کرنا   B. مسلسل پوسٹ کرنے کا منظم گرداب ترتیب کرنا   C. مواد کو موجودہ موضوعات یا واقعات کے ساتھ موافقت دیناV. مواد تخلیق کے اوزار کا عملی استعمال   A. مختلف مفت مواد تخلیق کے اوزار کی تعارف   B. \\"کینوا\\" ایپ کا تفصیلی پیش کش کرنا   C. مختلف مواد کے لئے خصوصیت اور ڈیزائن کی خصوصیات کی کوشش کرناVI. دلفریب دیداری مواد تخلیق کرنا   A. دیکھنے میں دلچسپ پوسٹ کے لئے ڈیزائن اصول   B. تصاویر، گرافکس، اور تشکیلیں مؤثر طریقے سے استعمال کرنا   C. کیپشنز، کوٹس، یا مختصر تشریحات شامل کرناVII. دلفریب ویڈیو مواد تخلیق کرنا   A. اسمارٹ فون کا استعمال کرکے معیاری ویڈیوز کی تخلیق کے لئے مشورے   B. ویڈیو مواد کو بہتر بنانے والے اوزار   C. کہانی سنانے اور موزوں تصاویر کا استعمال کرناVIII. دلفریب مواد کی تخلیق کرنے کے لئے مضامین   A. دھان انگیز عناوین اور ابتدائی مصدر بنانے کے مشورے   B. پیغام کو مختصر اور مؤثر طریقے سے پیش کرنا   C. موزوں ہیشٹیگز اور کلمات کا استعمال کرناIX. صارفین کے مواد کا فائدہ اٹھانا   A. پیروکاروں کو مواد میں شامل ہونے کی تشویق دینا   B. صارفین کے تاثرات اور جائزے کی تشہیر کرنا   C. مشترکہ مواد کے ذریعے ایک بنیادی جماعت کی تخلیق کرناX. مخاطبین کے ساتھ مشغول ہونا   A. تبصرے اور پیغامات کا جواب جلدی دینا   B. گفتگو اور مباحثوں کو بڑھانے کی تشویق دینا   C. رائے اور سفارشات کو مستقبل کے مواد میں شامل کرناXI. کامیابی کی پیمائش اور تجدید   A. سوشل میڈیا کے اندازے اور مواد کی میٹرکس کا تجزیہ کرنا   B. کامیاب مواد کی"},{"question":"Inona ary izany: mihiratra tsy mahita azy, mikipy vao mahita azy?","answer":"nofy"},{"question":"Дүйнөдө кайсыл өлкөнүн 3 борбор шаары бар?","answer":"Түштүк Африка Республикасынын 3 борбор шаары бар. Алар:1. Мыйзам чыгаруу бийлик борбор шаары - Кейптаун2. Өлкөнүн соттук борбору - Блумфонтейн 3. Расмий борбор шаары - Претория"},{"question":"Schrijf een voortzetting van de paragraaf: Na de dood van koning George II van Groot-Brittannië-Hannover in 1760 tijdens de Zevenjarige Oorlog (1756-1763) werd onder zijn opvolger koning George III het fort Hamelen versterkt door de vestingwerken op de Klüt. Tijdens deze oorlog had op grondgebied van de huidige gemeente Hamelen op 26 juli 1757 de Slag bij Hastenbeck","answer":"plaatsgevonden, waarbij het dorp van die naam geheel was verwoest. Fort I (Fort George) werd gebouwd van 1760 tot 1763 op de berg Klüt. Van 1774 tot 1784 werden hier nog twee forten aangelegd: fort II (fort Wilhelm) en fort III. Hamelen werd het \\"onneembare Gibraltar van het noorden\\", het sterkste fort van het toenmalige keurvorstendom van Hannover. Tijdens het Napoleontische tijdperk, onder wisselende Franse en Pruisische bezettingen werd in de jaren tot 1806 gebouwd aan Fort IV (Fort Luise), aan de voet van de heuvel Klüt."},{"question":"তিনি একজন গণিতবিদ ছিলেন যার ধারণা তার সময়ের চেয়ে অনেক এগিয়ে ছিল। তিনি এনিগমা মেশিনের এনক্রিপ্ট করা কোডের পাঠোদ্ধার করতে সক্ষম হন। বিশ্বযুদ্ধের সময় জার্মান বাহিনীর প্রতিরোধকে শক্তিশালী করতে একটি গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ভূমিকা পালন করেছিলেন। সেই গণিতবিদের নাম কি?","answer":"অ্যালান টুরিং"},{"question":"Résumez l'article:  Un ami du célèbre gangster Curtis Warren aurait affirmé que des espions du MI5 avaient placé des microphones secrets dans sa maison et avaient entraîné des oiseaux à frapper à ses fenêtres pour tenter de l'effrayer. L'homme d'affaires Philip Kerr cherche à obtenir une injonction de la Haute Cour contre les agents du renseignement, qui selon lui l'ont pris pour cible parce qu'il a refusé de coopérer avec le service de sécurité. L'homme de 53 ans dit qu'il a été soumis à une \\"campagne de harcèlement\\" au cours des 11 dernières années, affirmant que des agents ont rempli ses maisons à Wirral, Merseyside et en Thaïlande de caméras cachées et de microphones. Faites défiler vers le bas pour la vidéo. Philip Kerr, un ami du célèbre gangster Curtis Warren (photo), aurait affirmé que des espions du MI5 avaient placé des microphones secrets dans sa maison et entraîné des oiseaux à frapper à ses fenêtres pour tenter de l'effrayer. Il prétend aussi que les cornes ont été entraînées à voler dans sa fenêtre. Selon le Mirror, il dit aussi dans des documents juridiques que des espions ont interféré avec son téléphone, sa télévision et sa radio, et qu'il est prêt à payer 500 000 £ pour financer sa bataille juridique. \\"Mon cas est simplement que je suis harcelé illégalement par les services de sécurité et je souhaite que ce harcèlement cesse\\", a-t-il déclaré au journal. M. Kerr affirme que le MI5, dont le siège est à Millbank, à Londres (photo), a mis des micros dans ses maisons à Wirral, dans le Merseyside et en Thaïlande. M. Kerr dit qu'il a été approché par le MI5 en 2003 lorsque les agents enquêtaient sur le baron de la drogue Warren, qui a fait plus de 200 millions de livres sterling grâce à son empire criminel et est le seul trafiquant de drogue à figurer sur la liste des riches du Sunday Times. Cependant, il a refusé de fournir des informations sur Warren et d'autres criminels, y compris Colin \\"Smigger\\" Smith, le soi-disant roi de la cocaïne britannique, qui a été abattu à Liverpool en 2007. Selon M. Kerr, cela a incité le MI5 à commencer à le suivre. M. Kerr a reçu des conseils de l'ancienne agent de renseignement du MI5 et lanceuse d'alerte Annie Machon (photo) Ses documents juridiques ont été déposés à la Haute Cour le mois dernier, et il a engagé un avocat et...","answer":"Philip Kerr demande une injonction de la Haute Cour contre des agents du MI5. Il dit qu' il a été pris pour cible parce qu' il n' a pas coopéré avec les espions. M. Kerr, 53 ans, affirme avoir été victime de harcèlement pendant 11 ans. Il dit que des agents ont mis des micros chez lui à Wirral et en Thaïlande. Il prétend aussi qu' on a formé des cornes à voler dans ses fenêtres pour l' intimider.Commentaire: Ceci est un résumé soit, mais un peu incomplet. "},{"question":"问题：最常见的图书馆是什么类型","answer":"答案：公共图书馆"},{"question":"من هو أول من استخدم الشوكة أثناء تناول الطعام؟","answer":"الملك هنري حاكم فرنسا."},{"question":" Sheeg garoonka Kubada Cagta ee Stadium Moqdisho dalkii Dishay?","answer":"Garoonka Kubada Cagta Ee Stadium Moqdisho Waxa Dhisay Dalka Shiinaha (China) ."},{"question":"Madaxa Lalbaad: Xuquuqda, Xorriyaadka Aasaasiga Ah Ee Qofka Iyo Xaddidaadooda.Qodobka 17aad. Xorriyadda Diinta iyo Caqiiddada. ","answer":"Qodobka 17aad. Xorriyadda Diinta iyo Caqiiddada. (1) Qof kastaa wuxuu xor u yahay in uu ku dhaqmo dantiisa.(2) Diin aan ahayn Islaamka laguma faain karo Jamhuuriyadda Federaalka Soomaaliya."},{"question":"యువతపై సామాజిక మాధ్యమాల ప్రభావం గురించి వ్యాసం రాయండి.","answer":"శ్రీకృష్ణుడు ఒకప్పుడు తన నోట్లో విశ్వరూప సందర్శనం చేయిస్తే ఇప్పుడు నట్టింట్లో ‘నెట్’ తిష్ఠ వేసుక్కూచున్నది. ‘ఇంటర్ నెట్ ఇవాళ మనుషులు పనిలో భారాన్ని తగ్గించి మనసుల మధ్య దూరాన్ని పెంచుతున్నది. ఒకప్పుడు ‘లేఖ’లు, టెలిగ్రామ్ లు, టెలిఫోన్లు మనుషుల మధ్య ఇంత సమాచార వేగాన్ని పెంచకపోయినా ఒత్తిడి లేని జీవనం ఉండేది.ఇప్పుడు ‘సెల్ ఫోన్’ శరీరభాగాల్లో ఒకటిగా మారిపోగా, టీవీ ఇంట్లోని వస్తువుల్లో ఒకటిగా మారింది. ఫోను సంభాషణలు, వీడియోకాల్స్ మనిషికి మనిషికి మధ్య దూరాన్ని తగ్గించడంతో పాటు ఆత్మీయతానుబంధాలను మాయం చేశాయి.వేగవంతమైన ఇంటర్నెట్ సమాచార వ్యవస్థలు ఆత్మీయత, అనుబంధాలను పెంచుతున్నాయో, తుంచుతున్నాయో అర్థం కానంత సంఘర్షణలో సమాజం జీవిస్తున్నది. మనలాంటి అత్యధిక జనాభా ఉన్న దేశంలో ఆధునిక సమాచార వ్యవస్థ వల్ల లాభనష్టాలు రెండూ కలగలిసి ఉన్నాయి. పూర్వం ప్రతివారూ బాల్యంలో రెండు అగ్గిపెట్టెల్లోని బాక్స్ లకు దారం కట్టి ఒకరు చెవికి పెట్టుకొంటే ఇంకొకరు మాట్లాడేవారు.ఇదే పెద్ద ఆనందం..! మరిప్పుడు వాట్సాప్, ఫేస్ బుక్, యూట్యూబ్, ట్విట్టర్ వంటి మాధ్యమాలు, అనేక ‘యాప్స్’ అపరిమిత జ్ఞానంతో పాటు అనవసర విషయాలకు ప్రాధాన్యం ఎక్కువగా ఇస్తున్నాయి. ‘అరచేతిలో వైకుంఠం’ లాగా ఇప్పుడు అన్నీ మనచేతి ఫోన్ లో తెలుసుకొనే సౌకర్యం కలిగింది. ‘అన్నీ’ ఉన్నప్పుడు అందులో మంచీ చెడూ రెండూ ఉన్నాయి.1857లో స్కాట్లాండ్ దేశానికి చెందిన అలెగ్జాండర్ గ్రాహంబెల్ అనే శాస్త్రవేత్త ఫోన్ ను కనుగొని 1892లో ప్రథమంగా న్యూయార్క్ నుండి షికాగో మాట్లాడాడు. దాని అంచెలంచెల పరిణామాల అవతారాలు ఈ రోజు మన చేతిలో విన్యాసం చేస్తున్న కర్ణపిశాచి అవతారం వరకు రూపాంతరం చెందింది. 1973లో మార్టిన్ కూపర్ అనే అమెరికా దేశస్తుడు ‘మొబైల్ ఫోను’ అందుబాటులోకి తెచ్చారు. అలాగే 1857లో చార్లెస్ బాబేజ్ కంప్యూటరకు రూపకల్పన చేయగా 1936లో దానికి ఓ సాంకేతిక రూపం వచ్చింది. . పర్సనల్ కంప్యూటర్ను 1977లో రూపొందిస్తే 1983లో ఐ.బి.ఎం. అనే సంస్థ అందరికి అందుబాటులోకి వచ్చేట్లు చేసింది.ఇది మనదేశంలోకి ఇంకో రూపంలో ప్రవేశించేసరికి మరో ఇరవై ఏళ్లు పట్టింది. పాటలు వినడం, అలారం, సమాచారం, సమయం మాత్రమే తెలుసుకొనే అవకాశం ఉన్న ఈ మొబైల్ ఫోన్లు 21వ శతాబ్దంలోకి అడుగు పెట్టగానే అనేక కొత్త ఫీచర్స్ తో అందుబాటులోకి వచ్చాయి.ఈ ఇరవై ఏళ్లలో మొబైల్ ఫోను నేటి నిత్యావసర సరుకుగా మారిపోయింది. ఈ ఫోన్లకు ఇప్పుడు ఇంటర్నెట్ తోడవడంతో ప్రపంచం ఫోన్లోకి వచ్చి కూర్చొంది. సినిమాలు, డిక్షనరీలు, ఆటలు, లైవ్ ప్రోగ్రాంలు, టైపింగ్, విజ్ఞానం, సౌందర్యం వంటి మార్పులు, మత విజ్ఞానం, భాషలు, సైన్సు, విస్తృత సమాచారం, లలితకళలు, యోగవిజ్ఞానం, 24 గంటలు వార్తలు, ఇలా సమస్త ప్రపంచం ఇందులోకి చేరి ‘ఇందులో లేనిది ప్రపంచంలో లేదు. ప్రపంచంలో లేనిది ఇందులో లేదు’ అన్న స్థితికి చేరాం. ఇక్కడే అసలు సమస్య మొదలైంది.అవసరమైన అనవసరమైన సమాచారం ఒకచోట కలగాపులగంగా ఉండడం వలన సమాజంలో దుష్ప్రభావాలకు దారి సులభంగా ఏర్పడింది. ప్రతాపరుద్రుడు, స్వామి వివేకానంద, భగత్ సింగ్, ఝాన్సీ లక్ష్మీబాయి వంటి స్ఫూర్తిమూర్తుల చరిత్రలుకూడా నెట్లో దొరుకుతున్నాయి. మనుషులు ఎప్పుడైనా చెడువైపు త్వరగా ఆకర్షితులవుతారు. సమాచారం ఉప్పెనలా మనమీద పడిన తర్వాత మనుషులు సెల్ ఫోన్ లోని సోషల్ మీడియా అనే అష్టదిగ్బంధనంలో చిక్కుకపోయారు. తనతోపాటు తన చుట్టుప్రక్కల వ్యక్తులతో, ప్రకృతితో సంబంధం కోల్పోయారు.ఇటీవల కాలంలో మనం రైలు, బస్సు ఎక్కి కూర్చొంటే ప్రక్కనున్న సీట్లోని మనిషి ఎక్కడికి వెళ్తున్నారని వారి యోగక్షేమాలను పూర్వంలా ఎవరూ అడగడం లేదు. ఎవరి ఫోన్లో వారు తలదూర్చే దృశ్యం చూస్తున్నాం. మానవసంబంధాల యాంత్రికతకు ఇదో నిదర్శనం. అలాగే కొందరు ఇళ్లలో అస్తమానం కంప్యూటర్ లోనో, ఫోన్లోనో తలపెట్టి పక్కకు చూడడం లేదు.సుదీర్ఘంగా ఒకే స్థితిలో కూర్చోవడం వల్ల మెడ, వెన్ను నొప్పి వంటి దేహబాధలు తప్పడం లేదు. అలాగే కదలకుండా కూర్చొని ఊబకాయం, చక్కెర వ్యాధి వంటి వ్యాధులు కొని తెచ్చుకొంటున్నారు. మైదానాల్లో ఆడాల్సిన కబడ్డీ, క్రికెట్ వంటి ఆటలు ఫోన్లోనే ఆడడం వల్ల శారీరక వ్యాయామం జరగడం లేదు. కాలాన్ని ఎక్కువగా వాటిలోనే దుర్వినియోగం చేస్తున్నారు.తోటివారితోనే కాకుండా తనకుతానే సంబంధం కోల్పోతున్నాడు. తననుతానే వదిలి పెట్టినవాడు సమాజంతో ఎలా సంబంధం నెరపగలడు! అందుకే ఇటీవల ‘వర్చువల్ మీటింగ్స్’ తో పెళ్లిళ్లు, ఆఖరుకు అంత్యక్రియలు కూడా ఇంటర్నెట్లో చూసే దుస్థితికి దిగజారాయి. అలాగే గుడ్ మార్నింగ్ గుడ్ నైట్ తో, అప్లోడ్ డౌన్లోడ్ లతో జీవితం దుర్భరం చేసుకొంటు న్నారు.అనవసరమైన ‘చెత్త సమాచారం’ ఫార్వార్డ్ చేస్తూ అనవసర భారం ఇతరుల తలల్లోకి చొప్పిస్తున్నారు. కొన్నిసార్లు విశ్వసనీయత లేని సమాచారం ఫార్వార్డ్ చేసి సామాజిక అశాంతికి కారణం అవుతున్నారు. అసత్యాలతో కథనాలు, వీడియోలు రూపొందించి సంచలనం చేసే సంస్థలు, వ్యవస్థలు, వ్యక్తులు ఎక్కువైపోయి సోషల్ మీడియా విశ్వసనీయత దెబ్బతింటున్నది. అసత్య కథనాలతో సంచలనాలతో డబ్బు సంపాదించే వ్యక్తులు సోషల్ మీడియాలో ఉండటం వల్ల భావోద్వేగాలకు సంబంధించిన కుల, ప్రాంత, మత విద్వేషాలు రెచ్చగొట్టే సమాచారం ఇతరులకు పంపించి వాళ్లలో లేనిపోని ఉద్రిక్తతలు కలిగిస్తున్నారు.ఒకప్పుడు గొప్ప అవధానంతో ఎన్నో శ్లోకాలు, పద్యాలు మనవాళ్లు ధారణ చేసేవారు. పల్లెటూళ్లలో జానపదులు సైతం ఎన్నో సామెతలు, జానపద గీతాలు, కథలు నోటికి చెప్పేంత ధారణ ఉండేది. విద్యార్థులు ఎక్కాలు’ శతక పద్యాలు వల్లెవేసి ఎక్కడ అవసరం వస్తే అక్కడ ధారాళంగా చదివేవారు. ఇపుడు ప్రతీది ‘ఇంటర్నెట్ సమాచారం తప్ప ‘స్వీయశక్తి’తో జ్ఞాపకాన్ని జ్ఞానంగా మార్చుకోవడం లేదు.తమ తమ స్వీయ జ్ఞానాన్ని’ వీడియోలుగా మార్చి సమాజానికి అందిస్తున్నారు. ఇందులో గుణదోషాలు రెండూ ఉన్నాయి. అలాగే అశ్లీల వెబ్ సైట్లు సమాజంలో అత్యాచారాలకు ప్రధాన కారణం అవుతున్నాయి. ఆటల్లో గడపాల్సిన యువత ఎక్కువగా ఫోన్లకు, కంప్యూటర్లకు అతుక్కుపోతున్నారు. దీనివల్ల శారీరక శ్రమ తగ్గి, అనవసర మానసికఒత్తిడి పెరిగి మెదడు మొద్దుబారే స్థితి వచ్చింది. చదువుకోసం విస్తృత సమాచారం ఇవాళ నెట్టింట్లో దొరుకుతుంది. అంతవరకు యువత స్వీకరిస్తే వారి జీవితం పూలబాటగా మారుతుంది.బియ్యంలోని రాళ్లు తొలగించుకొన్నట్లు అనవసర సమాచారం తొలగించి సదసద్వివేకంతో ఈ మాధ్యమాలను తమ జ్ఞానానికి అనుకూలంగా మార్చుకోవడమే నేటి యువతరానికి ఉండవలసిన వివేకం. అదేవిధంగా ‘పిచ్చోడిచేతి’లో రాయిగా మారిన ‘సామాజిక మాధ్యమాలు’ ఇపుడు కొందరికి వ్యాపారవనరుగా మారడం మరో కోణం. యువతరం మాదకద్రవ్యాల మత్తులో పడకుండా ఎంత జాగ్రత్తగా మెలగాలో అలాగే ఈ మాధ్యమాల వలలో పడకుండా చైతన్యంతో ఉత్తమ భవిష్యత్తుకోసం ఆదర్శమార్గంలో నడవాలి."},{"question":"Fintino ity lahatsoratra ity:Nanomboka hampita ireny hevitra ireny Randria tany am-panangonam-bokatra tany. Saika tsy nino izy nony afaka volana vitsivitsy taty aoriana, betsaka no tsy nino toa azy tamin'ireo olona nitantarany fa misy toerana maromaro ahitana ny fiaraha-miasan'ny tambanivohitra, mampitatra ny valin-tanana, manova ny endriky ny dinam-pokonolona mba hampitodika bebe kokoa ny saina ho amin'ny fiaraha-mamokatra tsy ho an'ny tombontsoan' ny fianakaviana fosiny ihany fa ho an'ny faritany manontolo mihitsy.Koa tanana vitsitvitsy mifanakaiky mihitsy aza no indreo mfaninana sy mifarimbona,mifampitarika sy mifanentana ho amin'ny fiaraha-miasa vaovao. Azo tsapain-tanana ny vokatr'izany, na dia miadana dia miadana aza ny fisehony. Nitatra tsikelikely ny lalana azon'ny saretin'omby naleha na dia sarotra aza ny fanatanterahana zany noho ny tsy fananana fitaovana ara-dalana. Nifanentana ny mponina mba hiaro ny vokatry ny taniny tsy hanjakan' ny mpijirika sy ny mpanambaka azy harizay, ary indrindra nataony tsy nahita hirika hidirana intsony ire vahiny. mpitratrevatreva nanaraotra ny tsy fahalalany sy ny fahasahiranany amin' ny fikarakarany ny vokatra isan-taona. Tsaroany kokoa ankehitriny fa eo am-pelatanany ny her hiadiana amin'ny hanoanana sy ny tsy fisiana mifamotoana amin' ny fahavaratra.","answer":"Ity manaraka ity ny famintinana ny lahatsoratra:Tsy napoizin-dRandria ny fiparitahan' ny fiaraha-miasan'ny tambanivohitra haingana. Tsapa miharihary ny fitiavan'izy ireo izany. Nitatra araka izany ny toe-tsainy ka sarotra be tamin' ny mpanambaka ny namitaka azy ireo."},{"question":"जेलको सजाय निश्चयनै मान्छेलाई दिइने ठूलो यातनामध्येको एक हो। सिर्फ चार दिवारको घेराभित्र आफूलाई खुम्च्याएर मात्र होइन, अरू पनि धेरै कुराहरूबाट वञ्चित भएर, धेरै कुरालाई गुमाएर मान्छेले एक्लो, असहाय र तप्त अवस्थामा पाउँछ आफुलाई - जेलभित्र।माथिको अनुच्छेदले जेलको बारेमा के भनेको छ?","answer":"माथिको अनुच्छेदले जेलले मानिसलाई चार दिवारमा सिमित राखेर र उसलाई एक्लो बनाएर असह्य पिढा दिन्छ भनेको छ।"},{"question":"Inona avy ireo fisorohana azo atao amin'ny fijanonan’ny fo tampoka ?","answer":"Mba hisorohana ny arrêt cardiaque dia mila arahina maso ny fahasalaman’ny fo sy ny lalan-drà. Tsara raha manao fitiliana ny fo sy lalan-drà mba ahitana raha sanatria misy tsy fahatomombanana mampiahiahy ao amin’izy ireo.Mila kolokoloina ihany koa ny fo sy ny lalan-drà amin’ny alalan’ny fihinanana sakafo ara-pahasalamana, ny fanaovana fanatanjahantena (tsy mafy loatra), ny fanarahana tsara ny fitsaboana raha efa manana aretin’ny fo. Ajanona ny fifohana sigara, ahena na ajanona ny fisotroana toaka, miezaka ny manena vatana raha toa ka vaventy loatra, tandremana ny tahan’ny cholestérol, … Tsy adino ny fialana amin'ny fahakizitinana."},{"question":"வினா: எந்த வெப்பநிலையில் நீரின் அடர்த்தி அதிகபட்சமாக இருக்கும்?","answer":"விடை: 4 டிகிரி செல்சியஸ்"},{"question":"నక్షత్రాలు మిణుకు మిణుకుమనడానికి కారణం ……………..A) సంపూర్ణాంతర పరావర్తనంB) పరిక్షేపణంC) విక్షేపణంD) వాతావరణంలో కాంతి వక్రీభవనం","answer":"D) వాతావరణంలో కాంతి వక్రీభవనం"},{"question":"‘’Ọta Naijiria ni ẹnikẹni tabi ẹya to ba foju abuku wo iwọde tawọn ọdọ ṣe ta ko SARS’’","answer":"Ẹgbẹ ẹya Ibo kan ti wọn n pe ni Ohaneze ti sọ pe ẹnikẹni tabi ẹya kan ni Naijiria yii, to ba foju abuku wo iwọde tawọn ọdọ ṣe ta ko SARS, ọta ilọsiwaju Naijiria ni iru ẹni bẹẹ.Akọwe ẹgbẹ Ohaneze-Ndigbo, Ọmọọba Uche Achi-Okpaga, sọ pe gbogbo awọn ti wọn n gbiyanju lati sọ pe iwọde tawọn ọdọ ṣe ta ko awọn SARS, wọn fẹẹ fi da nnkan ru fun Buhari ni, ni  yoo kuna patapata.O ni iwọde tawọn ọdọ ṣe kaakiri orilẹ-ede yii ti fi han pe ayipada nla ti bẹrẹ si i ṣẹlẹ ni Naijiria bayii, ati pe ẹya kan abi awọn eeyan kan ti wọn ba ṣi n wo o pe bi a ṣe n ba a bọ tẹlẹ lohun gbogbo yoo maa lọ, niṣe niru wọn n tan ara wọn jẹ.Ọkunrin yii ni wọn ṣẹṣẹ bẹrẹ ni o, wọn ko ti i ri nnkan kan, ati pe ọrọ iwọde ta ko SARS yii, bii ẹni ṣẹṣẹ n mu ẹyẹ bọ lapo ni. O fi kun un pe kariaye ni ọrọ ẹrọ ayelujara ti tan de bayii, ti ẹya kan ba wa n sọ pe oun ko ni i lo o, tabi ṣamulo ẹ, niṣe ni omi ilọsiwaju maa gbe iru wọn lọ.Awọn ipinlẹ ti wọn pe ara wọn ni Aarin-Gbungbun, iyẹn Middle Belt, ni tiwọn sọ pe ọrọ ti awọn Gomina ilẹ Hausa yii atawọn ọba alaye wọn sọ ko ba laakaye kankan mu, ati pe ero tiwọn ni wọn sọ yẹn.Dokita Bitrus Porgu, ẹni ti i ṣe olori awọn eeyan agbegbe yii sọ ninu ifọrọwerọ kan pe ipade ti awọn gomina atawọn ọba alaye ọhun lọọ ṣe ni Kaduna fihan pe awọn to lọ si ipade naa ati Aarẹ Muhammed Buhari jọ n da Naijiria ru ni. O ni ṣe wọn fẹẹ sọ pe awọn nifẹẹ si bi orilẹ-ede yii ṣe ri, ti nnkan n daru si i lojoojumọ ni.Bẹẹ lo ke si awọn ti wọn ṣepade ọhun lati tun inu wọn ro daadaa, nitori nnkan ko lọ deede ni Naijiria lasiko yii, bẹẹ lohun ti wọn sọ, ero inu wọn ni, ki i ṣe ti gbogbo ọmọ Naijiria, abi awọn eeyan agbegbe tawọn.Ni ti Afẹnifẹre, akọwe ipolongo ẹgbẹ naa, Yinka Odumakin, sọ pe nibi ta a ba de yii, niṣe lo yẹ ki anfaani wa fun awọn eeyan, boya ki Naijiria ṣi wa lọkan ṣoṣo tabi ki kaluku di agbegbe ẹ mu, ti a ba fẹẹ ni orile-ede to duro daadaa.O ni, “Ohun ti ko ye wọn ni pe ariwo titako SARS tawọn ọdọ n pa kiri nigba yẹn, ki i ṣe pe wọn fẹẹ fi doju ijọba kankan bolẹ, bi ko ṣe lati fi wa ojuutu si bi ọjọ ọla Naijiria yoo ṣe dara ni.Odumakin ni ti a ba waa ri awọn kan ti wọn n gbe e kiri pe wọn fẹẹ fi wo ijọba Buhari lulẹ ni, a jẹ pe ohun kan soso to wa lọkan tiwọn ko ju bi wọn yoo ṣe maa dari orilẹ-ede yii lọ."},{"question":"p(x) బహుపది యొక్క పరిమాణం n అయిన p(x) లోని పదాల సంఖ్య గరిష్ఠంగా …………(A) n – 1(B) n(C) n + 1(D) 2n","answer":"(C) n + 1"},{"question":"निम्नलिखित प्रश्न का दिए गए विकल्पों में से उत्तर चुनें:प्रकृति में हर क्रिया (शक्ति) की एक बराबर और विपरीत विरुद्ध क्रिया होती है - यह न्यूटन का कौनसा नियम है?१) पहला नियम २) दूसरा नियम ३) तीसरा नियम ","answer":"विकल्प ३ - न्यूटन का तीसरा नियम कहता है कि हर क्रिया की एक बराबर और विरुद्ध क्रिया होती है। "},{"question":"Andininy voalohany: Miposaka any atsinanana ny masoandro ary milentika any andrefana.Andininy faharoa: Mihodina manodidina ny masoandro ny planeta.","answer":"Ireo fehezanteny roa ireo dia miresaka trangan-javatra astronomika samihafa. Ny fehezan-teny voalohany dia momba ny fihetsehan'ny masoandro manerana ny lanitra, raha ny fehezanteny faharoa kosa dia momba ny fihodin'ny planeta manodidina ny masoandro. Tsy misy fifandraisana mivantana ireo fanambarana roa ireo."},{"question":"A qual categoria pertence essa pergunta: Quais eleições presidenciais Ross Perot concorreu mas não venceu?.","answer":"Política."},{"question":"Quantas obras tem Agatha Christie?","answer":"Agatha Christie, conhecida como a maior escritora policial de todos os tempos, escreveu 93 livros e 17 peças teatrais. "},{"question":"Lanjutkan penggalan teks berikut sehingga menjadi sebuah paragraf utuh dan runtun dari cerita pendek anak-anak.Judul: Si Tukang Bohong.Ada seorang laki-laki sedang menggembalakan domba. Lalu, ia berpura-pura melihat serigala dan ...Jawaban:","answer":"berteriak minta tolong. \\"Tolong, tolong! Ada serigala!\\" Para petani yang berada di sekitar kejadian pun berdatangan. Namun, mereka dibuat kecewa karena itu adalah keusilan sang anak. Tak hanya sekali, anak gembala itu berbohong hingga tiga kali. Semua orang yang memiliki niat baik pun merasa dipermainkan. Suatu ketika, seekor serigala benar-benar datang. Anak itu kembali berteriak. \\"Tolong, tolong! Ada serigala!\\" Para petani sudah tidak percaya dan memutuskan untuk mengacuhkan sang anak. Akhirnya, serigala memangsa domba-domba milik anak tersebut."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Dalam banyak-banyak bunga-bunga apa yang berwarna hitam?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah bunga tayar. Ia bukan sejenis bunga, tetapi terdiri dapada pelbagai lapisan getah tayar yang bersentuhan pada permukaan jalan."},{"question":"مااسم الملكه الاسبانيه التي ساعدت كولمبس على اكتشاف أمريكا ؟","answer":"اسم الملكة الإسبانية التي ساعدت كولومبوس على اكتشاف أمريكا هو إيزابيلا الأولى، ملكة قشتالة. كانت إيزابيلا حاكمة حكيمة وطموحة، وكانت تسعى إلى توسيع أراضيها ونفوذها. كانت مهتمة بتمويل رحلات الاستكشاف إلى العالم الجديد، ووافقت على تمويل رحلات كولومبوس الأربعة إلى أمريكا."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਲੋਕੁ ॥ਦੇਨਹਾਰੁ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਛੋਡਿ ਕੈ ਲਾਗਹਿ ਆਨ ਸੁਆਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਕਹੂ ਨ ਸੀਝਈ ਬਿਨੁ ਨਾਵੈ ਪਤਿ ਜਾਇ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 268 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਦਾਤਾਂ) ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ (ਜੀਵ) ਹੋਰ ਸੁਆਦ ਵਿਚ ਲੱਗਦੇ ਹਨ; ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ) ਕਦੇ (ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜੀਵਨ-ਯਾਤ੍ਰਾ ਵਿਚ) ਕਾਮਯਾਬ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ) ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ।੧।\\""},{"question":" Qual artista pintou o famoso quadro","answer":"Plataforma 9 ¾, da estação Estação Kings Cross."},{"question":"Кыргыз тилинде омонимдердин түрлөрү тууралуу айтып берчи?","answer":"Жарайт! Сиз берген суроого төмөндөгүдөй жооп берейин. Кыргыз тилинде омонимдер 3 топко бөлүнөт:1)\\tОмофон; Айтылышы бирдей, бирок жазууда өзгөчөлөнгөн сөздөр: пуд-бут, парад-барад  2)\\tОмограф; Жазылышы бирдей, айтылышы башка болгон сөздөр: бак (малды багуу)-бак (темир идиш), кулак (орган)-кулак(эзүүчү таптын бир түрү)  3)\\tОмоформа; Кандайдыр бир уңгу же туунду сөзгө экинчи бир сөз белгилүү грамматикалык мүчө менен өзгөргөндөн кийин окшошуп калган сөздөр: тердик (токулга)-тер+-дик  "},{"question":"TEİAŞ kura çekimi ne zaman 2023?","answer":"Kura çekimi sonucunda belirlenen ve başvuru şartlarını taşıyan adaylar sözlü sınava alınacaktır. İŞKUR tarafından gönderilen listede yer alan adayların kura çekimi 27 Temmuz 2023 saat 15:00'de TÜSEB İstanbul Yerleşkesinde noter huzurunda gerçekleştirilecek."},{"question":"\\"Nifampizara hafanana tamin'ny namako iray tamin'izay tsy hitako ela:\\"A. Ny namako dia tsy nahatsiaro ahy mihitsy.B. Niresaka sy nifaly ho an'ny adiny faha-dimy.","answer":"B no fiafaran'ny tantara mitombona indrindra."},{"question":"મને ગુજરાતી ભાષાના કવિ \\"રઘુનાથદાસ\\" ઇતિહાસ કહો. ","answer":"કવિ અમદાવાદ પાસે ગોમતીપુરમાં થઈ ગયો. નાતે લેઊઆ કણબી હતો અને સંવત ૧૮૩૬માં હયાત હતો. તે વિષ્ણુ ભક્ત હતો. તેણે શ્રીમદ્ભાગવત ગુજરાતીમાં રચેલું છે; તથા રામાયણ, ધ્રુવાખ્યાન અને છુટક છપા સવૈયા, પદ, ગરબિયો વગેરે રચેલાં છે. એની કવિતામાં ઘણી મીઠાશ છે. તેના વંશના કણબી ગોમતીપુરમાં હાલ છે, તેની પાસે રઘુનાથદાસનાં રચેલાં તમામ પુસ્તકો છે. પણે તે એવા વેંહેમી છે કે કોઈને છાપવા આપતા નથી. રઘુનાથદાસે ઉધવજીના સંદેશાની ગરબિયો રચેલી છે તેની મતલબથી એવું જણાય છે, કે સંસાર તજીને જોગી થવાની વાત તેને ગમતી નોહોતી. અને જેમ બને તેમ પરમેશ્વર ઊપર પ્રેમ ઘણો રાખ્યાથી કલ્યાણ થાય છે. પણ તપ કરવા વગેરેથી કલ્યાણ થતું નથી; એવો તેનો અભિપ્રાય હતો. એ કવિ પેહેલા વર્ગમાં ગણાય છે. એની કવિતા સઊથી સમજી શકાય એવી સહેલી છે."},{"question":"පැහැසර ඔබෙ ආදරේ ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න ","answer":"මන්දාරම් වැහිපොද හිරිකඩමගෙ සියොළඟ රන්දාලාඋන් අප ආ ගිය මග වග තොටමතක අගුළු හැර දාලාවාවන්නට බැරි තැන දුක් කඳදෙනෙත් පියන් කවුළු කඩාදෝරෙ ගලා ගිය උණු කඳුලැලිවියලි දෙතොල් මත වැටුණාපැහැසර ඔබෙ ආදරේමන්දාරම් අඳුරේ වෙලීසැඟවී ගිය ඔබෙ සෙනෙහේහද රිද්දනවා රහසේමැලවුණු මගෙ දෙතොලෙහි රැඳි තතුසැමගෙන් සඟවා ඉන්නඔබ නොමැතිව සිනහ නගන’යුරුමට කියා දී යන්නඋමතුව හඳ විලාප දෙනහඬ අහගෙන ඉන්නබිඳකට ඇවිදින් මගෙ ලයමත ඔය සවන තියන්නසෙන්ටිග්‍රේඩ්ස්"},{"question":"Sobre qual evento importante este texto trata: Durante a invasão alemã em junho de 1941, a SVT-40 já estava sendo utilizada pelo Exército Vermelho. Numa divisão de infantaria soviética TO&amp;E, um terço das espingardas eram supostamente SVTs, embora na prática isto era raramente conseguido. Os primeiros meses da guerra foram desastrosos para a União Soviética, e milhares destas espingardas foram perdidas. Para compensar pelo enorme número de armamento perdido, a produção das velhas espingardas Mosin-Nagant foi reiniciada. Em contraste, a SVT era mais difícil de fabricar, e tropas com apenas treino rudimentar tinham dificuldade em as manter. Em adição, as pistolas-metralhadoras como a PPSh-41 tinham provado o seu valor como armas simples e baratas, mas eficazes para suplementar o poder de fogo da infantaria. Tudo isto conduziu a uma declinação na produção da SVT. Contudo, se os soldados alemães, com a sua inicial falta de espingardas semi-automáticas amigáveis, capturassem esta arma, prefeririam utilizar esta em vez das suas próprias armas. Em 1941, mais de um milhão de SVTs foram produzidas, mas em 1942 o arsenal de Ishevsk parou a produção da SVT para trocar novamente para a produção da Mosin-Nagant 91/30.","answer":"invasão alemã"},{"question":"Fale sobre o movimento diurno dos astros.","answer":"Ao longo do dia, todos os astros percorrem no céu arcos paralelos ao Equador em torno do eixo terrestre, no sentido leste-oeste (oposto ao da rotação da Terra). Note como os arcos mudam bastante de acordo com a latitude do observador no planeta."},{"question":"Awakọ pa ọlọkada sori afara niluu Ilọrin","answer":"Ọlọkada kan ti ko ti i sẹni to mọ orukọ rẹ pade iku ojiji lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, lẹyin ti awakọ ayọkẹlẹ kan kọ lu u lori afara to wa ni Post Office, niluu Ilọrin, to si sa lọ.Ijamba ọhun to ṣẹlẹ ni nnkan bii aago mẹrin irọlẹ lawọn to ṣoju wọn ni ere asapajude lo fa a.Ọlọkada ọhun to gbe ero sẹyin ni wọn loun pẹlu ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ naa fori sọ ara wọn, loju ẹsẹ ni ọkunrin naa si ku, ṣugbọn ẹni to gbe sẹyin farapa yannayanna.Awọn oṣiṣẹ ajọ to n mojuto irinna ọkọ nipinlẹ Kwara, KWARTMA, lo lọọ gbe oku ọlọkada naa ati ẹni to farapa lọ sileewosan ẹkọṣẹ Fasiti Ilọrin, UITH, nibi to ti n gba itọju."},{"question":"Đặt tiêu đề cho đoạn văn sau: Tổng thống Ba Lan Duda tuyên bố bình luận của Thủ tướng Morawiecki về ngừng chuyển vũ trang cho Ukraine đã bị hiểu sai, khi quan hệ hai nước căng thẳng.\\"Lời nói của Thủ tướng Mateusz Morawiecki đã bị hiểu theo cách tồi tệ nhất có thể. Theo tôi, Thủ tướng muốn nói rằng chúng tôi sẽ không chuyển giao cho Ukraine những loại vũ khí mới mà chúng tôi đang mua để hiện đại hóa quân đội Ba Lan\\", Tổng thống Ba Lan Andrzej Duda hôm 21/9 cho hay.Ba Lan là một trong những quốc gia ủng hộ Ukraine nhiệt thành nhất từ khi chiến sự bùng phát tháng 2/2022 và là một trong những nhà cung cấp vũ khí chính cho Kiev. Ba Lan đã cung cấp xe tăng T-72, xe bọc thép, pháo và nhiều vũ khí khác cho Ukraine.Thủ tướng Mateusz Morawiecki hôm 20/9 cho biết sẽ ngừng viện trợ vũ khí cho Ukraine để tập trung xây dựng nền quốc phòng, giữa lúc căng thẳng hai nước leo thang về vấn đề xuất khẩu nông sản. Người phát ngôn chính phủ Ba Lan Piotr Muller sau đó nói rằng Ba Lan vẫn sẽ chuyển giao các lô vũ khí và đạn dược theo thỏa thuận đã đạt được, trong đó có những hợp đồng đã ký với Ukraine.Ba Lan đã ký nhiều thỏa thuận vũ khí, bao gồm cả với Mỹ và Hàn Quốc, những nước mà họ đặt mua xe tăng K2 \\"Black Panther\\" và pháo K9 để hiện đại hóa quân đội.\\"Khi chúng tôi nhận được vũ khí mới từ Mỹ và Hàn Quốc, chúng tôi sẽ chuyển giao loại vũ khí đang được quân đội Ba Lan sử dụng. Có lẽ chúng tôi sẽ chuyển nó sang Ukraine\\", Tổng thống Duda nhấn mạnh.","answer":"Tổng thống Ba Lan: Tuyên bố ngừng cấp vũ khí cho Ukraine bị hiểu sai"},{"question":"I wonder పెద్దకాల్వ గ్రామ విస్తీర్ణం ఎంత?Can you get me some context to answer this (in the same language as my question)?","answer":"పెద్దకాల్వ, చిత్తూరు జిల్లా, గంగాధర నెల్లూరు మండలానికి చెందిన గ్రామము.[1] . పిన్ కోడ్: 517125. గణాంకాలుజనాభా (2011) - మొత్తం \\t2,673 - పురుషుల \\t1,347 - స్త్రీల \\t1,326 - గృహాల సంఖ్య \\t660జనాభా (2001) 2463 పురుషులు 1298 స్త్రీలు 1165 గృహాలు 561 విస్తీర్ణము 490 హెక్టార్లు. ప్రజల భాష. తెలుగు.పెద్దకాల్వ చిత్తూరు జిల్లా, గంగాధర నెల్లూరు మండలంలోని గ్రామం. ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన గంగాధర నెల్లూరు నుండి 4 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన చిత్తూరు నుండి 10 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 660 ఇళ్లతో, 2673 జనాభాతో 490 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 1347, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 1326. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 582 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 23. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 596666[2].పిన్ కోడ్: 517125.విద్యా సౌకర్యాలుగ్రామంలో ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమిక పాఠశాలలు ఐదు, ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమికోన్నత పాఠశాల ఒకటి , ప్రైవేటు ప్రాథమికోన్నత పాఠశాల ఒకటి ఉన్నాయి. బాలబడి, మాధ్యమిక పాఠశాల‌లు, సమీప జూనియర్ కళాశాల, అనియత విద్యా కేంద్రం గంగాధర నెల్లూరులోను, ప్రభుత్వ ఆర్ట్స్/ సైన్స్ డిగ్రీ కళాశాల వేల్కూరులోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వైద్య కళాశాల, మేనేజిమెంటు కళాశాల, దివ్యాంగుల ప్రత్యేక పాఠశాల తిరుపతి లోనూ ఉన్నాయి. పాలీటెక్నిక్,  సమీప వృత్తి విద్యా శిక్షణ పాఠశాల చిత్తూరులోను ఉన్నాయివైద్య సౌకర్యంప్రభుత్వ వైద్య సౌకర్యంఒక సంచార వైద్య శాలలో డాక్టర్లు లేరు. ముగ్గురు పారామెడికల్ సిబ్బంది ఉన్నారు. సమీప ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం, ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య ఉప కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 కి.మీ. లోపు దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. సమీప సామాజిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం, మాతా శిశు సంరక్షణ కేంద్రం, టి. బి వైద్యశాల గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. అలోపతి ఆసుపత్రి, ప్రత్యామ్నాయ ఔషధ ఆసుపత్రి, డిస్పెన్సరీ, పశు వైద్యశాల, కుటుంబ సంక్షేమ కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. తాగు నీరుగ్రామంలో కుళాయిల ద్వారా శుద్ధి చేయని నీరు సరఫరా అవుతోంది. గ్రామంలో ఏడాది పొడుగునా చేతిపంపుల ద్వారా నీరు అందుతుంది. బోరుబావుల ద్వారా కూడా ఏడాది పొడుగునా నీరు అందుతుంది. పారిశుధ్యంగ్రామంలో మురుగునీటి పారుదల వ్యవస్థ లేదు. మురుగునీటిని నేరుగా జలవనరుల్లోకి వదులుతున్నారు. గ్రామంలో సంపూర్ణ పారిశుధ్య పథకం అమలవుతోంది. సామాజిక మరుగుదొడ్డి సౌకర్యం లేదు."},{"question":"Maxa la oran jiray ninki dilay cali bin abii daalib?","answer":"Waxaa la Oran jiray c/raxmaan binu muljin."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਕੇਤਿਆ ਗਣਤ ਨਹੀ ਵੀਚਾਰੁ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 5 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਬੇਅੰਤ ਸੂਰਮੇ ਅਤੇ ਕਈ ਹੋਰ ਅਜਿਹੇ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਗਿਣਤੀ ’ਤੇ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ, \\""},{"question":"شحال درجه خط الطول الاساسي غرينتش ؟","answer":"صفر درجة"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"கடவுள் இல்லை, கடவுள் இல்லை; கடவுள் இல்லவே இல்லை; கடவுளைக் கற்பித்தவன் முட்டாள்; பரப்பியவன் அயோக்கியன்; வணக்குகிறவன் காட்டுமிராண்டி."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: \\"Nhiều trường ĐH tốp trên công bố mức điểm chuẩn cao.\\"","answer":"Trường ĐH Y Dược - ĐHQG Hà Nội vừa công bố điểm chuẩn trúng tuyển vào các ngành của trường theo kết quả bài thi đánh giá năng lực (HSA). Năm nay, y khoa là ngành có điểm chuẩn cao nhất với 22,7 điểm, ngành thấp nhất là điều dưỡng với 17,9 điểm. Điểm trúng tuyển được công bố theo thang điểm 30, đã bao gồm điểm ưu tiên theo đối tượng, khu vực tuyển sinh và chỉ xét nguyện vọng 1 của thí sinh, trường hợp thiếu chỉ tiêu mới xét đến nguyện vọng 2. Cách tính điểm xét tuyển theo kết quả thi đánh giá năng lực do ĐHQG Hà Nội tổ chức năm 2022 bằng công thức: Điểm xét tuyển = Điểm đánh giá năng lực x 30/150 + điểm ưu tiên (đối tượng, khu vực). Trong khi đó, theo thông báo của Trường ĐH Kinh tế Quốc dân, điểm chuẩn xét tuyển kết hợp với 3 nhóm thí sinh 4, 5 và 6 của trường rất cao. Cụ thể, nhóm 4 là những thí sinh có chứng chỉ tiếng Anh quốc tế kết hợp với điểm 2 môn thi tốt nghiệp THPT; nhóm 5 áp dụng với thí sinh là học sinh trường THPT chuyên và nhóm 6 dành cho thí sinh đã tham gia vòng thi tuần của chương trình \\"Đường lên đỉnh Olympia\\" hoặc đoạt giải trong kỳ thi học sinh giỏi cấp tỉnh, thành phố, quốc gia. Điểm chuẩn ngành cao nhất là 38, ngành thấp nhất là 25,5. Trường lưu ý thí sinh cần đăng ký trực tuyến nguyện vọng trúng tuyển trên hệ thống cổng thông tin tuyển sinh của Bộ Giáo dục và Đào tạo từ nay đến trước 17 giờ ngày 20/8. Trường ĐH Khoa học Xã hội và Nhân văn - ĐHQG Hà Nội cũng đã thông báo điểm chuẩn cho 4 phương thức tuyển sinh 301, 303, 401, 409 của trường. Về phương thức xét tuyển dựa trên kết quả tốt nghiệp THPT, nhiều chuyên gia tuyển sinh cho hay với phổ điểm năm nay, điểm chuẩn khối kinh tế sẽ ở mức cao. Theo PGS-TS Vũ Thị Hiền, Trưởng Phòng Đào tạo - Trường ĐH Ngoại thương, dựa trên phân tích phổ điểm, số thí sinh có mức điểm thông thường trúng tuyển vào trường này là khoảng từ 26-27 trở lên, tùy từng ngành. Tuy nhiên, bà Hiền lưu ý năm nay, phương thức xét tuyển có nhiều thay đổi. Các trường giảm số chỉ tiêu ở phương thức xét điểm thi tốt nghiệp THPT, tăng chỉ tiêu theo các phương thức xét tuyển khác. PGS-TS Nguyễn Viết Thái, Trưởng Phòng Đối ngoại và Truyền thông - Trường ĐH Thương mại, nhận định năm nay, phổ điểm các tổ hợp xét tuyển ĐH theo điểm thi tốt nghiệp THPT phần lớn ở ngưỡng 21-26. Dự kiến điểm chuẩn của trường tương đương năm ngoái. Trong mùa tuyển sinh năm 2021, Trường ĐH Thương mại có mức điểm chuẩn dao động từ 26,2 - 27,45. Bà Nguyễn Thu Thủy, Vụ trưởng Vụ Giáo dục ĐH - Bộ GD&ĐT, cho hay từ nay đến ngày 20/8, thí sinh đăng ký, điều chỉnh, bổ sung nguyện vọng xét tuyển ĐH bằng hình thức trực tuyến với số lần không giới hạn. Theo Yến Anh - Hải Yến - Minh Khuê "},{"question":"Ниагара шаркыратмасы жөнүндө кыскача эмне айта аласың ?","answer":"Ниагара шаркыратмасы 💦Америка менен Канаданын чек арасында, Нью-Йорк штаты менен Онтарио провинциясынын ортосундагы шаркыратмалар каскады.Бул шаркыратма Түндүк Американын эң таң калыштуу жаратылыш керемети болуп эсептелет.АКШ 🇺🇸"},{"question":"Cad é poll dubh? ","answer":"Is é is poll dubh nó dúpholl ann ná réigiún sa spás-am a bhfuil a réimse imtharraingthe chomh láidir is nach féidir don tsolas féin éalú as. Go bunúsach, is toradh matamaiticiúil do theoiric na coibhneasachta ginearálta é an dúpholl, ach tá na réalteolaithe i ndiaidh sonrú a chur i gcuid mhaith réadanna aisteacha sa spás a d'fhéadfadh a bheith ina ndúphoill."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Jaki napastnik w 2022 roku był reprezentantem Polski w piłce nożnej, oraz graczem Juventusu Turyn?","answer":"Odpowiedź to: Arkadiusz Milik."},{"question":"මේ ප්‍රශ්නයට උත්තර දෙන්න: ගිනි ගල් පරිණාමීය ගල් බවට පරිවර්තනය වෙනකොට, මේ ක්‍රියා වලිය මොන ආකාරයේ ශක්තියක්ද? (A) තාපය (B) රසායනික (C) චුම්බක; ආලෝකය පිළිතුර:","answer":"(B) රසායනික "},{"question":"Рио Сукури дарыясы жөнүндө кыскача эмне билесиң ?","answer":"Биздин планетадагы эң тунук жана таза жазгы дарыялардын бири.Рио Сукуридеги суу ушунчалык тунук болгондуктан, аны көрүү абдан кыйын. Анда сүзүү менен сиз абада калкып жүргөндөй элес аласыз. Дарыя суучулдар жана сноркельдер менен абдан популярдуу.Рио Сукури дарыясы, Бразилия 🇧🇷"},{"question":"First held in 1907, in which sport is the Waterloo Cup contested?","answer":" Crown Green Bowls is contested in 1907."},{"question":"தமிழ் மொழிப்பண்டாரம் என்று அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார்?","answer":"ஒப்பிலாமணிப் புலவர்."},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Etats-Unis nékk","answer":"Réwum Etats-Unis mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Amerique"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. එන්න මදනලේ ගොස් පවසන්න දුක මගේයන්නට හැකි ඔබට පමණි සිර ගෙයට ඇගේදිවා රැයේ වැලපිලා දෑස ඈගෙ රතු වෙලාකියන්නකෝ මගෙ දුක ඇගෙ කණට ළං වෙලාකියන්නකෝ මගෙ දුක ඇගෙ කණට ළං වෙලාඑන්න මදනලේ….. එන්න මදනලේ…..","answer":"එන්න මදනලේ ගොස් පවසන්න දුක මගේයන්නට හැකි ඔබට පමණි සිර ගෙයට ඇගේදිවා රැයේ වැලපිලා දෑස ඈගෙ රතු වෙලාකියන්නකෝ මගෙ දුක ඇගෙ කණට ළං වෙලාකියන්නකෝ මගෙ දුක ඇගෙ කණට ළං වෙලාඑන්න මදනලේ….. එන්න මදනලේ…..ශෝක පණිවුඩය යවන්න ආදරිය බලාකාලිදාස කිවිඳු මේඝ දූතයා කළාමට කොයින්ද එම වළා ආමි සුළඟෙ ඔබ බලාකියන්නකෝ මගෙ දුක ඇගෙ කණට ළං වෙලාඑන්න මදනලේ ගොස් පවසන්න දුක මගේයන්නට හැකි ඔබට පමණි සිර ගෙයට ඇගේදිවා රැයේ වැලපිලා දෑස ඈගෙ රතු වෙලාකියන්නකෝ මගෙ දුක ඇගෙ කණට ළං වෙලාකියන්නකෝ මගෙ දුක ඇගෙ කණට ළං වෙලාඑන්න මදනලේ….. එන්න මදනලේ…..සංදේශයකින් යවන්න මෙදුක උන් අතේආ….. ආ….. ආ…..සංදේශයකින් යවන්න මෙදුක උන් අතේහංස ගිරා ළිහිණි කොවුල් කුරුල්ලන් නැතේසුළඟේ මා අසරණයි මට ඇති වස්තුව ඇයයිකීවොත් මගෙ දුක සදහට ඔබට මා ණයයිකීවොත් මගෙ දුක සදහට ඔබට මා ණයයිඑන්න මදනලේ ගොස් පවසන්න දුක මගේයන්නට හැකි ඔබට පමණි සිර ගෙයට ඇගේඑන්න මදනලේ….. එන්න මදනලේ….."},{"question":"Fakirliğe sebep olan şeyler nelerdir?","answer":"Yoksulluk sorunu ülkeden ülkeye farklılık gösterse de yoksulluğun nedenleri olarak; işsizliğin artması, enflasyon, gelir dağılımındaki eşitsizlikler, savaşlar, iç ve dış göçler, ülkede yaşanan sosyo-ekonomik krizler sayılabilir."},{"question":"ಈ ಪ್ಯಾರಾಗ್ರಾಫ್ಗೆ ಮುಂದುವರಿಕೆ ಬರೆಯಿರಿ - \\"ದಿ ಅಪೋಥಿಯೋಸಿಸ್ ಆಫ್ ವಾರ್\\" ಅನ್ನು 1871 ರಲ್ಲಿ ವೆರೆಷ್ಚಾಗಿನ್ ಚಿತ್ರಿಸಿದರು. ಆ ಸಮಯದಲ್ಲಿ, ವೆರೆಷ್ಚಾಗಿನ್ ಜರ್ಮನಿಯ ಮ್ಯೂನಿಚ್ನಲ್ಲಿ ವಾಸಿಸುತ್ತಿದ್ದರು, ಅಲ್ಲಿ ಅವರು 13 ಕೃತಿಗಳನ್ನು (\\"ಅಪೋಥಿಯೋಸಿಸ್\\" ಸೇರಿದಂತೆ) ರಷ್ಯಾದ ಸಾಮ್ರಾಜ್ಯಶಾಹಿ ಸೈನ್ಯದೊಂದಿಗೆ ತಮ್ಮ ಹಿಂದಿನ ಪ್ರಯಾಣವನ್ನು ಚಿತ್ರಿಸಿದ್ದಾರೆ, ಏಕೆಂದರೆ ಇದು ಮಧ್ಯ ಏಷ್ಯಾದಾದ್ಯಂತ ಚಲಿಸುತ್ತಿತ್ತು, ವಿವಿಧ ಬಣಗಳ ವಿರುದ್ಧ ಹೋರಾಡಿತು ಮತ್ತು ವಶಪಡಿಸಿಕೊಂಡಿತು","answer":"ರಷ್ಯಾದ ತುರ್ಕಿಸ್ತಾನವಾಯಿತು. ಶಾಸ್ತ್ರೀಯವಾಗಿ ತರಬೇತಿ ಪಡೆದ ಯುದ್ಧ ಕಲಾವಿದನಾಗಿ, ವೆರೆಷ್ಚಗಿನ್ ಅವರ ಅನೇಕ ಕೃತಿಗಳು ರಷ್ಯದ ಸೈನ್ಯ, ಖೈವಾ ಮತ್ತು ಕೊಕಾಂಡ್ ನ ಖಾನೇಟ್ಗಳ ಪಡೆಗಳ ನಡುವಿನ ಯುದ್ಧದ ದೃಶ್ಯಗಳ ಸುತ್ತಲೂ ಕೇಂದ್ರೀಕೃತವಾಗಿವೆ"},{"question":"Phân tích ý nghĩa lịch sử thắng lợi đưa tới sự ra đời nhà nước dân chủ Cộng Hòa đầu tiên ở Đông Nam Á năm 1945","answer":"Đối với phong trào giải phóng dân tộc trên thế giới. Cách mạng tháng Tám năm 1945 thắng lợi là tấm gương, là nguồn cổ vũ cho các quốc gia - dân tộc đang mất độc lập tự do ở châu Á, châu Phi và Mỹ La-tinh, nhất là các nước láng giềng noi theo. Khẳng định vị thế, giá trị thời đại của  thắng lợi này, Chủ tich Hồ Chí Minh viết: “Cách mạng Tháng Tám thắng lợi đã làm cho chúng ta trở nên một bộ phận trong đại gia đình dân chủ thế giới. Cách mạng Tháng Tám có ảnh hưởng trực tiếp và rất to đến hai dân tộc bạn là Miên và Lào. Cách mạng Tháng Tám thành công, nhân dân hai nước Miên, Lào cùng nổi lên chống đế quốc và đòi độc lập”Cách mạng tháng Tám năm 1945 thắng lợi đã chứng minh một chân lý của thời đại: các dân tộc bị áp bức, bị xâm lược nếu có ý chí kiên cường và đường lối đúng đắn, sáng tạo, biết đoàn kết đấu tranh vì độc lập, tự do; đứng vững trên lập trường của giai cấp công nhân và biết tranh thủ sức mạnh của thời đại thì dân tộc đó nhất định thắng lợi. Vì thế, trong diễn văn kỷ niệm Cách mạng tháng Tám, Người khẳng định: “Suốt trong 80 năm nước ta bị Pháp chiếm, nhân dân ta từ Nam đến Bắc đã nhiều lần nổi dậy chống giặc ngoại xâm. Nhưng vì bọn vua quan hèn mạt, câu kết với địch, phản nước hại dân, cho nên các cuộc khởi nghĩa đều thất bại. Cách mạng Nga thành công đã thức tỉnh các dân tộc bị áp bức, dạy cho họ cách tổ chức, đấu tranh và giành thắng lợi. Nhờ vậy mà ta có Đảng tiên phong, có Mặt trận dân tộc thống nhất, đoàn kết và lãnh đạo toàn dân, kiên quyết đấu tranh cho độc lập tự do, làm Cách mạng Tháng Tám thắng lợi. Lần đầu tiên trong lịch sử nhân dân ta được hoàn toàn giải phóng: Đã phá tan cái xiềng xích nô lệ thực dân, đã đập đổ cái chế độ thối nát của vua quan phong kiến, đã lập nên nước Việt Nam Dân chủ Cộng hoà. Từ đó dân ta làm chủ nước ta”Đối với phong trào cộng sản và công nhân quốc tế.Thắng lợi của Cách mạng tháng Tám năm 1945 mang tầm vóc thời đại, góp phần to lớn vào phong trào đấu tranh vì hòa bình, tiến bộ của nhân loại; giáng một đòn chí mạng vào nền móng của chủ nghĩa thực dân cũ ở vị trí xung yếu nhất; cùng với Liên Xô, các lực lượng tiến bộ trên thế giới và quân đồng minh đánh đổ chủ nghĩa thực phát xít, giữ vững hòa bình cho khu vực và trên thế giới. Tinh thần của chiến thắng lịch sử. Do đó, cũng là chiến thắng chung của các nước trên bán đảo Đông Dương, chiến thắng của phong trào cộng sản và công nhân quốc tế, của phong trào đấu tranh vì hòa bình, tiến bộ xã hội trên toàn thế giới. Về vấn đề này, Người dẫn lại đánh giá của Báo Nhân dân Inđônêxia: “Chúng ta chỉ có thể bày tỏ sự kính trọng và lòng khâm phục cao nhất đối với nhân dân Việt Nam anh hùng... Với sự chiến đấu anh dũng của họ, nhân dân Việt Nam đã tự đặt mình lên vị trí vẻ vang nhất trên thế giới...”Thắng của Cách mạng Tháng Tám năm 1945, đã chứng minh tính cách mạng, khoa học của học thuyết Mác - Lênin về vấn đề dân tộc và thuộc địa; là sự tiếp nối và là thắng lợi tất yếu sau thắng lợi của Cách mạng xã hội chủ nghĩa Tháng Mười vĩ đại năm 1917: “Thắng lợi của Cách mạng Tháng Tám đã chứng minh sự đúng đắn của học thuyết Mác - Lênin về vấn đề dân tộc thuộc địa, đã chứng minh sự đúng đắn của con đường của Cách mạng xã hội chủ nghĩa Tháng Mười vĩ đại đã vạch ra”(10). Về vấn đề này, trong bài viết Cách mạng tháng Mười Nga mở đường giải phóng cho các dân tộc trên thế giới, Chủ tịch Hồ Chí Minh đã khẳng định: “Thực tiễn ở Việt Nam đã chứng tỏ rằng nhờ có sự lãnh đạo của đảng Mác - Lênin mà cách mạng đã thu được thắng lợi vẻ vang trong sự nghiệp giải phóng dân tộc, tiến lên xây dựng chủ nghĩa xã hội”Thời gian đã lùi xa nhưng tầm vóc ý nghĩa thắng lợi, bài học kinh nghiệm của Cách mạng Tháng Tám vẫn còn nguyên giá trị và ngày càng tỏa sáng. Đó là một trong những trang chói lọi nhất trong lịch sử của dân tộc ta, một dấu mốc lớn trên con đường phát triển trong suốt chiều dài mấy nghìn năm dựng nước và giữ nước của dân tộc Việt Nam. Đúng như Chủ tịch Hồ Chí Minh viết: “Chẳng những giai cấp lao động và nhân dân Việt Nam ta có thể tự hào, mà giai cấp lao động và những dân tộc bị áp bức nơi khác cũng có thể tự hào rằng lần này là lần đầu tiên trong lịch sử cách mạng của các dân tộc thuộc địa và nửa thuộc địa, một Đảng mới 15 tuổi đã lãnh đạo cách mạng thành công, đã nắm chính quyền toàn quốc”"},{"question":"Inona ny fanalavana ny SIMO?","answer":"Ny fanalavana ny SIMO dia: SInga MOana."},{"question":"ما هي أول شخصية عربية حصلت علي جائزة نوبل في السلام ؟","answer":"الإجابة هي : الرئيس المصري الراحل محمد أنور السادات ."},{"question":"O que a sigla \\"PDF\\" significa?","answer":"O PDF (Portable Document Format) é um formato de arquivo desenvolvido pela Adobe Systems para representar documentos de maneira independente do aplicativo, hardware, e sistema operacional usados para criá-los."},{"question":"1 metrekareye kaç tane briket gider?","answer":"TSE standartlarına uygun olarak üretilmiş briket yada bimslerden 1 (bir) m2 ye 10 ila 12,5 arası bims ya da briket gider."},{"question":"پیاز کے چند فوائد بتایں. اس میں مزید معلومات شامل کریں","answer":"پیاز کے اہم فوائد کی فہرست میں شامل کی گئی وضاحت کے ساتھ کچھ اور فوائد مندرجہ ذیل ہیں:- پیاز میں پائے جانے والے کوآئیسیٹن کانجیوگیں کو سالم رکھتے ہیں جو عموماً زیرِ جلد چمڑے کی مسائل کو روکتی ہیں۔ اس سے جلد کی صحت بہتر رہتی ہے۔- پیاز کے مصالحے میں ایک طبی قدرتی تمیز کار بھی شامل ہوتی ہے جو جلد کے مسائل کو دور کرتی ہے۔- پیاز میں موجود ثانیوں کی مقدار جلد کو نرم اور چکنا بناتی ہے اور جلد کو خشکی سے بچاتی ہے۔- پیاز کو خارش اور کھوجلی کے خلاف بھی استعمال کیا جاتا ہے۔ اس کے طبی خصوصیات ان سمسر کرنے میں مدد فراہم کرتی ہیں۔- پیاز کا رس اس کو ایک موثر گھریلو دوائی بناتا ہے جو سر درد اور جسم کی تھکاوٹ کو کم کرنے میں مدد فراہم کرتی ہے۔- پیاز کا استعمال خون کو صاف کرنے اور گندگی کو دور کرنے میں بھی مدد فراہم کرتا ہے۔پیاز کی خواص اور فوائد کی مدد سے اسے ایک اہم طبی طریقہ کار بناتے ہیں جو علاج کی ایک مخصوص ترتیب دیتا ہے۔ اگر آپ کسی بھی طبی مسئلے سے متعلق ہیں، تو آپ کے معالج سے راہنمائی حاصل کریں اور پیاز کا استعمال صرف ان کی مشورے کے مطابق کریں۔"},{"question":"Manomeza ohabolana maro  momba ny asa.","answer":"Ireto ny ohabolana momba ny asa:- “Tsy misy  mafy tsy laitry ny zoto.”- “Ny asa atao an-kira toa vita tsy natao.”- “Zararao ny raharaha: ny tapa-tanana miandry ondry, ny tapa-tongotra mitoto vary.”- “Ny valala tsy azo raha tsy handriana ilika.”- “Vavolombelon’ny mpiasa ny bainga.”- “Asa vadi-drano tsy vita raha tsy ifanakonana.”- “Samy zanaky ny mpanefy ka tsy mifampidera taim-by.”- “Mindram-pangady lohataona ka maniraka ny tompony hiasa”- “Mipetra-potsiny ohatra ny lamban’ny mpiasa”- “Milaza ho be raharaha ka ny voly vary indray no tsy efa”- “Izay miaraka amin’ny mpiasa dia mpiasa”- “Ganagana mitety asa, ny hanina tsy azo, ny tratra mangana”- “Androngo anaty asa, ka samy miaro ny rambony tsy ho tapaka”"},{"question":"રમેશ પારેખ ની \\"કવિતાએ શું કરવાનું હોય?\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"કવિતાશિયાળું રાત્રિએ તાપણું પેટાવે,ઝાડને ગળચટ્ટી છાંયડી પાડતાંશીખવે ઉનાળામાં,ચોમાસામાં કહે વરસાદને –ખાબકી પડ!શું શું બનવાનું હોય કવિતાએ?કાચ સાંધવાનું રેણ?ભૂખ્યાનું અન્ન?અનિદ્રાના દરદીની ઊંઘ?સૈનિકના ઘાવ પર પાટો?હા!શિશુના કલશોરનો ઉત્સવ ઉજવવાનો હોય,ચુંબનતરસ્યાં ફૂલો માટે પતંગિયા બનવાનું હોય,માતાના સ્તનમાં દૂધ બનવાનું હોય,શયનખંડના શુષ્ક એકાંતમાંમધુર ઐક્ય રચવાનું હોય કવિતાએ.કવિતાએ શું કરવાનું હોય?જ્યાં ઈશ્વરનાં હાથ ન પહોંચેત્યાં પંહોચવાનું હોય કવિતાએ.– એ બધું તો ખરું જ,પણ સૌથી મોટું કામ એ કેતેણે આખું ગામ ઊંઘતું હોય ત્યારેજગાડવાનો હોય કવિને.."},{"question":"Annie Macaulay-Idibia","answer":"Annie Macaulay-Idibia (tí a bí ní 13 Oṣù kọkànlá ọdún 1984) jẹ́ afẹwàṣiṣẹ́ àti òṣèré ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Wọ́n yàán fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ti òṣèré amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ tí ó dára jù níbi ayẹyẹ Best of Nollywood Awards ti ọdún 2009.A bí Annie ní Ìbàdàn ṣùgbọ́n ó wá láti Ìlú Eket ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Akwa Ibom. Ó kó lọ sí Ìlú Èkó pẹ̀lú ìyá rẹ̀ lẹ́hìn ìpínyà láàrin àwọn òbí rẹ̀. Ó ní oyè-ẹ̀kọ́ nínu ìmò kọ̀mpútá sayẹnsì àti eré tíátà, èyí tí ó gbà láti ilé-ìwé gíga Yunifásítì Ìpínlẹ̀ Èko àti Yunifásítì ìlú Èkó.Ṣáaj́u kí Annie Macaulay-Idibia tó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ òṣèré rẹ̀, ó ti díje níbi Queen of All Nations Beauty Pageant níbití ó ti ṣe ipò kejì, ó sì tún ti hàn nínu orin kan ti 2face Idibia tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ African Queen.Ó di gbajúmọ nídi iṣẹ́ òṣèré rẹ̀ ní Nollywood lẹ́yìn kíkópa nínu àwọn sinimá táa pè àkọ́lé wọn ní Pleasure and Crime àti Blackberry Babes.Annie Macaulay – Idibia ti ṣe ìgbeyàwó pẹ̀lú 2face Idibia tó sì ti bí ọmọ méjì fun. Ó bí ọmọ àkọ́kọ́ rẹ̀, ọmọbìnrin tí orúkọ rẹ̀ jẹ́ Isabella Idibia, ní Oṣù kejìlá Ọdún 2008 àti ọmọ èkejì tí orúkọ ti òun n ṣe Olivia Idibia ní Oṣù Kíní, Ọdún 2014. Ó ní ilé ìṣọ̀ṣọ́ kan ní ìlú Atlanta tí orúkọ rẹ̀ jẹ́ \\"BeOlive Hair Studio\\"."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"இராவணனது அரசு முறை மிகுதியும் நாகரிகம் உடையதாகவே இருந்திருக்கிறது என்பதற்கு அவனது மந்திராலோசனை சபையும் அங்கு நடந்ததாகச் சொல்லும் வாதப் பிரதிவாதங்களுமே சான்றாகும்."},{"question":"ඛේදජනක වසර ලෙසද හැඳින්වෙන 1930 දී ඇමරිකානුවන් කී දෙනෙක් රැකියා විරහිතව සිටියාද?","answer":" මිලියන 7කට වඩා වැඩියි"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"Boka maika anambady ka _ \\" ","answer":"Toy izao ny  tohin'ny ohabolana:\\"Boka maika anambady ka tsy mahandry ny andro zoma.\\" "},{"question":"شكون هو اول رئيس الوزراء فباكستان؟","answer":"محمد بن جناح عام 1941م."},{"question":"ਵਿਲੂਪੁਰਮ (ਤਾਮਿਲ ਨਾਡੂ): ਇੱਥੇ ਟਿੰਡੀਵਨਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੋਏ ਇਕ ਕਾਰ ਹਾਦਸੇ ’ਚ ਅੰਨਾਡੀਐਮਕੇ ਦੇ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਐਸ ਰਾਜੇਂਦਰਨ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ। 62 ਸਾਲਾ ਐਮਪੀ ਦੇ ਸਿਰ ਵਿਚ ਗਹਿਰੀ ਸੱਟ ਵੱਜੀ ਜਿਸ ਕਾਰਨ ਮੌਕੇ ’ਤੇ ਹੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ਕਾਰ ਚਾਲਕ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਇਕ ਸਹਾਇਕ ਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਖ਼ਮੀ ਹਾਲਤ ਵਿਚ ਮੁੰਡੀਯਾਕੱਪਮ ਦੇ ਗੌਰਮਿੰਟ ਮੈਡੀਕਲ ਕਾਲਜ ਹਸਪਤਾਲ ਲਿਜਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ।ਸ਼੍ਰੀ ਐਸ ਰਾਜੇਂਦਰਨ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਹੋਈ?","answer":"ਸੰਸਦ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਸ਼੍ਰੀ ਐਸ ਰਾਜੇਂਦਰਨ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਕਾਰ ਹਾਦਸੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ।"},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: W 2009 wygrała juniorskie mistrzostwa Ameryki Południowej oraz czempionat panamerykański juniorów. Złota medalistka mistrzostw kontynentu południowoamerykańskiego młodzieżowców (2010). W tym samym sezonie tuż za podium – na czwartym miejscu – zakończyła start w mistrzostwach świata juniorów w Moncton. Największym sukcesem zawodniczki w gronie seniorów jest zdobycie złotego medalu mistrzostw Ameryki Południowej","answer":"w czerwcu 2011. Stawała na podium mistrzostw Kolumbii oraz cztery razy poprawiała rekord swojego kraju w kategorii juniorów."},{"question":"When do we use spatial data analysis?","answer":"Spatial data analysis is involved when the data are spatially located and explicit consideration is given to possible importance of their spatial agreement or in the interpretation of results. "},{"question":"Ijọba lawọn o fowo kun owo epo, wọn tọrọ aforiji lọwọ araalu","answer":"Pẹlu bi aroye ati ariwo ṣe gba igboro kan lẹyin ti ajọ to n ri si ẹkunwo ati adinku owo-epo rọbi atawọn eroja nilẹ wa (Petroleum Products Pricing Agency, PPPRA) sọ lalẹ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee yii, pe awọn ti sun owo tawọn araalu maa maa ra lita epo bẹntiroolu kan si igba ati mejila naira (#212.60), ijọba apapọ ti sọ pe awọn o fọwọ si ẹkunwo naa, wọn si tọrọ aforiji lọwọ araalu. Naira mẹrin din lọgọsan-an (#176) lọpọ ileepo n ta epo naa tẹlẹ.Minisita fọrọ epo rọbi nilẹ wa, Timipre Sylva, lo kede lọsan-an ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, pe oun ati Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari ko mọ ohunkohun nipa ẹkunwo ti wọn kede naa, bẹẹ lawọn o fọwọ si i.Bakan naa ni ajọ to n bojuto igboke-gbodo epo rọbi, Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation, NNPC, sọ pe ko si idi lati fowo kun owo-epo lọwọ yii, wọn niye tawọn ileepo n ta epo tẹlẹ ni ki wọn ṣi maa ta a, ko si pẹ ti ajọ NNPC ṣe kede ọrọ yii tan ni ajọ PPPRA lọọ pa ikede ẹkunwo ti wọn lawọn ṣe naa rẹ lori ikanni wọn.Timipre Sylva sọ pe “ijọba o le maa purọ faraalu, ikede ti wọn ṣe lati fi kun owo epo yii ko lọwọ ijọba ninu, ko si si ootọ ninu ọrọ naa.“A mọ pe ikede ti wọn ṣe yii ti maa ko yin lọkan soke, o si ti maa fa aifararọ fawọn kan. A tọrọ aforiji fun ọrọ to ṣẹlẹ yii, a o fi kun owo epo o, ẹ jọọ, ẹ ma binu”, awọn ọrọ ẹbẹ yii ni minisita naa fi kadii ikede rẹ."},{"question":"السؤال: من أول من استلم الحجر الأسود من الأئمة ؟","answer":"الإجابة : عبد الله بن الزبير ."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Setiap manusia pun ada, anda juga mesti ada, tetapi orang lain yang lebih banyak gunakan benda anda, apa benda ini?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah nama"},{"question":"Het volgende is te lezen in hun folder: Wij zijn bewust niet-beursgenoteerd. Zo is er minder druk om kortetermijnwinsten te realiseren.Wij financieren met je spaargeld enkel bedrijven die ondernemen met respect voor mens en milieu. Zo groeit je geld. En zo groeit de samenleving. Blablabla Ps: Zij waren vorig jaar de eerste bank die zomaar eventjes 0 procent spaarrente gaven ..Welke Nederlandse bank stelt zich als doel om duurzaam, ethisch en transparant te bankieren? ","answer":"Er zijn meedere banken in Nederland die als doel hebben om duurzaam, ethisch en transparant te bankieren. Voorbeelden hiervan zijn Triodos en ASN bank. "},{"question":"O que é uma equação na matemática?","answer":"Uma equação é uma expressão matemática que afirma que duas quantidades são iguais. Ela é frequentemente escrita com um sinal de igual (=). Por exemplo, 2x + 3 = 7 é uma equação."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca saddexan ee halgame Xalane, meesha uu ku geeriyooday iyo            sanadkii  uu geeriyooday? ","answer":" Waxaa curiyey Raage Ugaasheeg maalintii, bishii iyo  sanadkii ay Soomaaliya ku biirtay Jaamacadda Carabta? "},{"question":"آرٽيڪل جو خلاصو: روسي صدر ولاديمير پوتن وٽ پروفيشنل ٽولن جي فوج آهي جيڪا انٽرنيٽ تي روسي پروپيگنڊا سان سيلاب ڪري رهي آهي. ولاديمير پوتن وٽ پروفيشنل ٽولن جي هڪ فوج آهي جيڪا هزارين جعلي ٽوئيٽر ۽ فيس بڪ اڪائونٽس هلائي رهي آهي ته جيئن سوشل ميڊيا کي روس جي پروپيگنڊا سان ٻوڏايو وڃي. سوين ڪارڪنن کي هر مهيني £ 500 ادا ڪيو ويندو آهي سخت 12 ڪلاڪ شفٽ ڪم ڪرڻ لاءِ انٽرنيٽ تي تبصرن سان بمباري ڪئي وئي جيڪا پوتن کي وڌيڪ سازگار روشني ۾ اڇلائي ٿي. ٽوليون سخت حالتن ۾ ڪم ڪن ٿيون جيڪي انهن کي ڳالهائڻ کان منع ڪن ٿيون ۽ هڪ ٻئي کي به منع ڪن ٿيون. انٽرنيٽ ريسرچ سينٽر ۾ هڪ اڳوڻو ڪم ڪندڙ - ڊب ٽريول فيڪٽري - اهو لائن ورتو آهي ته ملازمن کي هڪ شفٽ ۾ 130 کان وڌيڪ آن لائن پوسٽون لکڻيون آهن يا برطرفي کي منهن ڏيڻو پوندو. مارات برخارڊ وضاحت ڪئي ته ڪيئن آپريشن، سينٽ پيٽرسبرگ ۾ هڪ جديد عمارت ۾، هڪ ڏينهن ۾ 24 ڪلاڪ کليل آهي ۽ ملازم اڪثر ڪري ٽن ٽيمن ۾ ڪم ڪن ٿا. \\"اسان مان هڪ 'بدمعاش' هوندو، هڪ شخص جيڪو فورم سان اختلاف ڪري ٿو ۽ اختيارين تي تنقيد ڪري ٿو، انهي جي صداقت جو احساس ڏيارڻ لاءِ جيڪو اسان ڪري رهيا آهيون ،\\" هن ريڊيو فري يورپ / ريڊيو لبرٽي کي ٻڌايو. “ ٻئي هن سان بحث ۾ داخل ٿيا – ”نه، تون صحيح نه آهين. هتي هر شيء بلڪل صحيح آهي. 'اسان انهن فورمن تي حقيقي سرگرمي جو برم ٺاهيندا آهيون. مسٽر برڪ هارڊ انڪشاف ڪيو ته ڪيئن هن ۽ هن جا ساٿي ٽريول آمريڪي صدر بارڪ اوباما جي هندستان ۾ پنهنجي چمي پوکڻ جي ڪهاڻي جي پٺيان ڪم ڪرڻ لڳا. \\"توهان کي ان بابت 135 رايا لکڻ جي ضرورت آهي، ۽ شرم نه ٿيو ته توهان ڪيئن پنهنجو اظهار ڪيو،\\" مسٽر برخارڊ کيس ٻڌايو. ”جيڪو به توهان چاهيو لکو، رڳو لفظ اوباما کي اتي رکو ۽ پوءِ ان کي مٽيءَ سان ڍڪيو. هڪ ٻئي موقعي تي هن کي بار بار ويب سائيٽن تي پوسٽ ڪرڻ لاءِ چيو ويو ته جرمنن جي اڪثريت پوتن ۽ سندس پاليسين جي حمايت ڪئي ۽ ميرکل کان ناخوش هئي. ڪارخاني جي اندر، ٽرالون نه رڳو روسي سائيٽن کي نشانو بڻائي رهيا آهن، پر سڄي دنيا ۾ سائيٽون، برطانيه سميت. Trolls کي اڪثر پنج اهم لفظ ڏنا ويندا آهن جيڪي انهن کي انهن جي هر پوسٽ سان شامل ڪرڻ جي پڪ ڪرڻ گهرجي.","answer":"پروفيشنل ٽرولن جو لشڪر ولاديمير پوتن لاءِ جعلي اڪائونٽس هلائي رهيو آهي. مزدورن کي 12 ڪلاڪن جي ٿڪائيندڙ شفٽن لاءِ هر مهيني 500 پائونڊ ادا ڪيا ويندا آهن. انهن کي چيو ويو آهي ته اهي سائيٽون هڪ ڏينهن ۾ 130 کان وڌيڪ تبصرن سان بمباري ڪن ٿيون. اسٽاف کي هڪ ٻئي سان ڳالهائڻ يا دوستي ٺاهڻ جي اجازت ناهي."},{"question":"විචල්‍ය ප්‍රතිරෝධක යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"විචල්‍ය ප්‍රතිරෝධක යනු ප්‍රතිරෝධයේ ප්‍රතිරෝධකතාව වෙනස් කලහැති ප්‍රතිරෝධකයන්ය.මෙහි එක් පරාසයකට අදාලව ප්‍රතිරෝධය වෙනස්කිරීමට හැකිය.ප්‍රතිරෝධය අවශය ලෙස වෙනස් කිරීම මගින් ධාරාව පාලනය කරහැකිය.මෙවන් ප්‍රතිරෝධක ගුවන් විදුලි යන්ත්‍ර රූපවාහිනී යන්ත්‍ර වැනි විද්‍යුත් උපකරණවල දක්නට ලැබේ."},{"question":"Marubucin Shaihu Umar ya yi amfani da salon harshe maiOptionsA)ban haushiB)kaushiC)ƙarangiyaD)ban tausayi","answer":"D)ban tausayi"},{"question":"கல்லணை அணையில் சர் ஆர்தர் காட்டன் பங்களிப்பு என்ன?","answer":"இந்திய நீர் பாசனத்தின் தந்தை என அறியப்படும் சர் ஆர்தர் காட்டன் என்ற ஆங்கில பொறியாளர் கல்லணையை பல ஆண்டுகாலம் ஆராய்ந்தார்.கல்லணை பலகாலம் மணல் மேடாகி நீரோட்டம் தடைப்பட்டது. ஒருங்கிணைந்த தஞ்சை மாவட்டம் தொடர்ச்சியாக வெள்ளத்தாலும், வறட்சியாலும் வளமை குன்றியது. இந்த சூழலில் 1829 இல் காவிரி பாசன பகுதி தனி பொறுப்பாளராக ஆங்கிலேய அரசால் சர் ஆர்தர் காட்டன் நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.இவர்தான் பயனற்று இருந்த கல்லணையில் தைரியமாக சிறு சிறு பகுதியாய் பிரித்து எடுத்து மணல் போக்கிகளை அமைத்தார். அப்போது, கல்லணைக்கு அமைக்கப்பட்ட அடித்தளத்தை ஆராய்ந்த அவர் பழந்தமிழரின் அணை கட்டும் திறனையும் பாசன மேலாண்மையையும் உலகுக்கு எடுத்துக் கூறினார். கல்லணைக்கு கிரான்ட் அணைகட் என்ற பெயரையும் சூட்டினார்."},{"question":"Эгер Мистер менен Миссис Биггердин баласы бар болсо, үчөөнүн кимиси чоң болот эле? А: Бала, анткени бала бир аз чоңураак! Сиздин оюңузча, жогорудагы тамашанын маңызы эмнеде?","answer":"Түшүндүрмө: Жаңы жыл менен! Жаңы жылга карата балалуулар жөнүндө тамаша жасоо орундуу көрүндү. Эгерде бир нерсе башка нерседен бир аз чоңураак болсо, анда ал чоңураак дегенди билдирет. Мисалы, мен айтып коёюн, адатта, грейпфрут апельсинден бир аз чоңураак. Кээде алар алда канча чоң болот. Эгерде адамдын фамилиясы Чоңураак болсо, анда бүтүндөй маселе татаалдашат. Бул учурда, ымыркай кичинекей деп аталат, же кичинекей Чоң, чынында кичинекей, анткени ал ымыркай. Бул тамаша күлкүлүү, анткени кичинекей Чоң (бала) ата-энесинен бир аз чоңураак (чоңураак) боло албайт. Жаңы жылыңар өткөн жылга караганда бир аз жакшыраак болсун. (Мен чоңураак деп айткым келди, бирок бул эч кандай мааниге ээ эмес.) Келгиле, чоңураактын карама-каршы жагына көңүл буралы: кичинекей үйлөр!"},{"question":"Hur många sjöar finns det i Sverige?","answer":" Sverige finns det cirka 100 000 sjöar."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਸੁਖ ਸਾਗਰੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਹੈ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾਇ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਈਐ ਸਹਜੇ ਨਾਮਿ ਸਮਾਇ ॥ਅੰਦਰੁ ਰਚੈ ਹਰਿ ਸਚ ਸਿਉ ਰਸਨਾ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਇ ॥੧॥ਭਾਈ ਰੇ ਜਗੁ ਦੁਖੀਆ ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਸਰਣਾਈ ਸੁਖੁ ਲਹਹਿ ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸਾਚੇ ਮੈਲੁ ਨ ਲਾਗਈ ਮਨੁ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਹਰਿ ਧਿਆਇ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸਬਦੁ ਪਛਾਣੀਐ ਹਰਿ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਨਾਮਿ ਸਮਾਇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਗਿਆਨੁ ਪ੍ਰਚੰਡੁ ਬਲਾਇਆ ਅਗਿਆਨੁ ਅੰਧੇਰਾ ਜਾਇ ॥੨॥ਮਨਮੁਖ ਮੈਲੇ ਮਲੁ ਭਰੇ ਹਉਮੈ ਤ੍ਰਿਸਨਾ ਵਿਕਾਰੁ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਸਬਦੈ ਮੈਲੁ ਨ ਉਤਰੈ ਮਰਿ ਜੰਮਹਿ ਹੋਇ ਖੁਆਰੁ ॥ਧਾਤੁਰ ਬਾਜੀ ਪਲਚਿ ਰਹੇ ਨਾ ਉਰਵਾਰੁ ਨ ਪਾਰੁ ॥੩॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਜਪ ਤਪ ਸੰਜਮੀ ਹਰਿ ਕੈ ਨਾਮਿ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸਦਾ ਧਿਆਈਐ ਏਕੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਕਰਤਾਰੁ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਈਐ ਸਭਨਾ ਜੀਆ ਕਾ ਆਧਾਰੁ ॥੪॥੭॥੪੦॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 29 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਇਹ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ  ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੀਭ ਨਾਲ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾ ਕੇ ਹਿਰਦਾ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਾਲ ਇਕ-ਮਿਕ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਭੁਲਾ ਕੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਅਦਿਕ) ਹੋਰ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਜਗਤ ਦੁਖੀ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਤੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਹਰ ਰੋਜ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ; (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ) ਸੁਖ ਮਾਣੇਂਗਾ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗ ਸਕਦੀ, (ਉਸ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆਂ (ਸਿਮਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ) ਮਨ (ਭੀ) ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ । (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ) ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਗਿਆਨ ਚੰਗੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਰੌਸ਼ਨ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ (ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਅਗਿਆਨਤਾ ਦਾ ਹਨੇਰਾ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਮਲੀਨ-ਮਨ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੈਲ ਨਾਲ ਲਿਬੜੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਹਉਮੈ ਤੇ ਲਾਲਚ ਦਾ ਰੋਗ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈਇਹ ਮੈਲ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਉਤਰਦੀ, (ਸ਼ਬਦ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ) ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਸਹੇੜ ਕੇ ਖ਼ੁਆਰ ਹੋ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਜਨਮ-ਮਰਨ ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਪਏ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨਉਹ ਇਸ ਨਾਸਵੰਤ ਜਗਤ-ਖੇਡ ਵਿਚ ਫਸੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਇਸ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਨਾਹ ਉਰਲਾ ਬੰਨਾ ਲੱਭਦਾ ਹੈ ਨਾਹ ਪਾਰਲਾ ਬੰਨਾ ।੩।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ ਬਚਾਈ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆਰ ਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਸਦਾ ਕਰਤਾਰ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ (ਹੀ) ਸਿਮਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ) ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ (ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ) ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ \\""},{"question":"உங்கள் இல்லத்தில் நடைபெறும் திருமணவிழாவுக்கு வருகை தரும் விருந்தினர்களுக்கு மரக்கன்று ஒன்று தருவதாக முடிவு செய்துள்ளீர்கள். மரக்கன்று வாங்கும் நோக்கங்களையும் அதனைப் பயிரிடுவதால் ஏற்படும் பொது நன்மைகளையும் கொண்ட இருபக்கச் சிற்றேட்டை உருவாக்குக.","answer":"மரக்கன்று வழங்குதன் நோக்கம் :* மரங்கள் அழிக்கப்பட்டு வரும் சூழல்களில் மரக்கன்றுகள் நடுவதற்கான ஏற்ற சூழலை உருவாக்குதல்.* பழம், பட்சணம், வெற்றிலை போன்றவற்றைப் பையிலே போட்டுக் கொடுப்பதைவிட மரக்கன்றுகள் கொடுப்பது சாலச்சிறந்தது.* சுற்றுச்சூழலை நல்லமுறையில் அமைக்கவே மரக்கன்றுகள் வழங்குதல்.பொது நலன்கள் :* மரக்கன்றுகள் வளர்ப்பதால் நல்ல தூய காற்று கிடைக்கும்.* கோடையில் நிழல் உருவாகும்.* மரங்கள் மாசுக்களைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தும்* மரங்கள் குளிர்ச்சி தரும்* குளிர்ச்சியால் மழை உண்டாகும்.* மழை பொழிந்தால் மண் மகள் சிலிர்ப்பாள்.* மழையால் பயிர்வளம் பெருகும்.* பயிர்வளத்தால் விவசாயம் பெருகும்.* விவசாயம் பெருகினால் வீடு நலம் பெறும்.* வீடு நலம் பெற்றால் நாடு தானே வளம் பெறும்."},{"question":"लक्ष्मीप्रसाद देवकोटाको \\"म\\" कविता।","answer":"स्वर्ग र भूको सूक्ष्म हुँ स्पन्दन–दाना तिलको,यति छु मसिनो ! सक्छ को सम्झन ?दिल झिल्को ?अलग सचेतन सागर चेतनकण जलको !जति जति गिर्दछु उति उति उठ्दछु !अन्त न बलकोविश्व बनाउँछु, विश्वधनी छु—क्षण–झुल्को ।सृष्टि, स्थिति र प्रलय म भोग्दछु,प्रतिपलको ।मेरा नीलिम गहिराइमामेरै अनिलकोतपन, जपन र अन्तः स्वपन छन्ऋजु र कुटिलको ।सब ती विसर्जन मिल्दछु जलमै,जल–फुल्को !जोरिन्छ जतातिर मानवतासँग,साँध यो दिलको,अनन्त शक्ति र ज्योति छु उत्तमयुगको अमर झिल्को !"},{"question":"Dê um exemplo de curiosidade nesta categoria: política.","answer":"Até 2023, quais presidentes estadunidenses do século 21 não foram veteranos militares? Barack Obama, Donald Trump, e Joe Biden."},{"question":"Kailan itinatag ang Google?","answer":"Itinatag ang Google noong Setyembre 4, 1998 sa pamamagitan nina Larry Page at Sergey Brin na parehong mag-aaral sa Stanford University. Nagsimula ang Google bilang isang simpleng search engine na may pangalang \\"Backrub\\". Sa tulong ng mga investor, itinatag ng dalawa ang kompanyang Google sa Menlo Park, California. Sa ngayon, isa na ang Google sa mga pinakamalaking kompanya sa teknolohiya na may malaking impluwensya sa digital na mundo."},{"question":"(அ) ‘காய்நெல்’ என்று துவங்கும் பிசிராந்தையாரின் புறநானூற்றுப் பாடலை எழுதுக.(ஆ) ‘தலை’ என்று முடியும் குறளை எழுது.","answer":"(அ) ‘காய்நெல்’ என்று துவங்கும் பிசிராந்தையாரின் புறநானூற்றுப் பாடல்:காய்நெல் அறுத்துக் கவளம் கொளினே;மாநிறைவு இல்லதும், பல்நாட்கு ஆகும்;நூறுசெறு ஆயினும், தமித்துப்புக்கு உணினே,வாய்புகுவதனினும் கால் பெரிது கெடுக்கும்; (- பிசிராந்தையார் )(ஆ) ‘தலை’ என்று முடியும் குறள்:கடன் அறிந்து காலம் கருதி இடன் அறிந்துஎண்ணி உரைப்பான் தலை. ( – திருவள்ளுவர்)"},{"question":"Paragrafı tamamla: İklim değişikliğinin etkileri oldukça çeşitlidir. Deniz seviyesinin yükselmesi, kıyı bölgelerinde erozyon ve tuzlu suyun yeraltı su kaynaklarına sızması gibi sorunlara yol açar. Buna ek olarak ekstrem hava olayları, yoğun yağışlar, kuraklık, kasırgalar, sel","answer":"ve yangınlar gibi daha sık ve şiddetli hava olaylarını tetikleyebilir. Ayrıca ekosistemi değiştirerek sıcak hava dalgalarının artırmasına ve su kaynaklarına yönelik sorunlara neden olabilir. "},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Vắng bóng căn hộ 25 triệu đồng/m2 ở quận trung tâm Bộ Xây dựng vừa công bố thông tin nhà ở và thị trường bất động sản quý II/2022. Theo báo cáo, thị trường quý này đã có dấu hiệu hồi phục và phát triển tốt với tổng lượng giao dịch căn hộ chung cư, nhà ở riêng lẻ, đất nền cao hơn cùng kỳ năm 2021. Tỷ lệ hấp thụ sản phẩm ở hầu hết các phân khúc ở mức cao, hầu như không phát sinh lượng bất động sản tồn kho mới. Tỉ lệ trống văn phòng, mặt bằng thương mại cho thuê giảm dần… Thị trường bất động sản đã cân bằng trở lại giữa hoạt động đầu tư, kinh doanh với mua bán để sử dụng.  Các dự án nhà ở thương mại tại khu vực trung tâm của các đô thị hầu như không có căn hộ với mức giá dưới 25 triệu đồng/m2. Trong ảnh: Dự án chung cư tại khu Tây Nam Linh Đàm (Hoàng Liệt, Hoàng Mai, Hà Nội) đang mở bán với giá từ 40-45 triệu đồng/m2. Về giá bán, Bộ Xây dựng cho biết, giá căn hộ chung cư vẫn tăng so với thời điểm cuối năm 2021, mức độ tăng giá các phân khúc tập trung trong quý I/2022 chậm dần và có dấu hiệu chững lại trong các tháng quý II/2022. Theo báo cáo, các dự án nhà ở thương mại tại khu vực trung tâm của các đô thị hầu như không có căn hộ với mức giá dưới 25 triệu đồng/m2. Căn hộ có mức giá này chỉ có tại một số ít các dự án tại khu vực xa trung tâm. Trong khi đó, sản phẩm chủ đạo trên thị trường trong quý II vẫn là các căn hộ phân khúc trung cấp có giá từ 30-50 triệu đồng/m2. Đặc biệt, tại Hà Nội và TP. HCM một số dự án có vị trí đặc biệt, trung tâm có mức giá quảng cáo, chào bán rất cao lên đến 300-325 triệu đồng/m2... Mua gom đất rồi \\"phân lô, tách thửa\\" chào bán tràn lan Cũng theo Bộ Xây dựng, giá nhà ở riêng lẻ, đất nền cho xây dựng nhà ở tại các dự án trong quý II/2022 đang có xu hướng chững lại ở hầu hết các địa phương khi các hoạt động đầu tư, kinh doanh, dịch vụ thuộc các ngành nghề, lĩnh vực khác được phục hồi, bình thường trở lại.  Thị trường xuất hiện tình trạng các nhà đầu tư nhỏ lẻ tự mua gom đất ở, đất nông nghiệp, đất trồng cây lâu năm và lợi dụng các thông tin về quy hoạch, đầu tư hạ tầng để phân lô, tách thửa và chào bán tràn lan. Tại nhiều địa phương (như Đồng Nai, Bình Phước, Lâm Đồng, Vũng Tàu, Đắk Lắk,…) đã xuất hiện tình trạng các nhà đầu tư nhỏ lẻ tự mua gom đất ở, đất nông nghiệp, đất trồng cây lâu năm và lợi dụng các thông tin về quy hoạch, đầu tư hạ tầng để phân lô, tách thửa và chào bán tràn lan gây mất ổn định cho thị trường bất động sản. Trước tình hình đó, cơ quan quản lý tại các địa phương đã phải đưa ra các biện pháp ngăn chặn như siết chặt, dừng việc phân lô bán nền đối với các giao dịch đất đai trên địa bàn. Ngoài ra, để \\"siết\\" lại tình trạng này, Bộ Xây dựng yêu cầu các địa phương có biện pháp quản lý, ngăn chặn việc chia tách, \\"phân lô, bán nền\\" tại các khu vực chưa được phép đầu tư, thiếu hệ thống hạ tầng; tăng cường kiểm soát hoạt động của các sàn giao dịch bất động sản, các tổ chức, cá nhân hành nghề môi giới bất động sản; chấn chỉnh hành vi mua bán trao tay, \\"thổi giá\\" gây nhiễu loạn thông tin thị trường bất động sản. Đồng thời, theo dõi nắm bắt thông tin, tình hình diễn biến của thị trường và thực hiện các biện pháp xử lý kịp thời để bình ổn thị trường, không để xảy ra tình trạng sốt giá và bong bóng bất động sản trên địa bàn; Tăng cường kiểm tra, thanh tra đồng thời xử lý nghiêm với các trường hợp vi phạm về pháp luật về kinh doanh bất động sản, đất đai, xây dựng… Nguồn cung hạn chế Theo Bộ Xây dựng, nguồn cung mới các sản phẩm bất động sản ở tất cả các phân khúc trong nửa đầu năm 2022 đều hạn chế. Nguyên nhân chủ yếu là do việc siết chặt các thủ tục pháp lý của các dự án bất động sản, ngoài ra việc dòng vốn cho thị trường bị thu hẹp từ nhiều phía như kiểm soát chặt nguồn vốn tín dụng, phát hành trái phiếu doanh nghiệp, sự suy giảm của thị trường trái phiếu,… cũng là nguyên nhân khiến nguồn cung hạn chế. Nhà ở, đất nền vẫn là loại hình bất động sản thu hút sự quan tâm nhiều nhất trong nửa đầu năm 2022, đặc biệt là phân khúc nhà ở thương mại trung cấp, bình dân và nhà ở xã hội, tuy nhiên, nguồn cung cho phân khúc này tương đối ít. Nguồn: https://tienphong.vn/xuat-hien-tinh-trang-mua-gom-dat-de-phan-lo-tach-thua-chao-ban-gay-loan-thi...Nguồn: https://tienphong.vn/xuat-hien-tinh-trang-mua-gom-dat-de-phan-lo-tach-thua-chao-ban-gay-loan-thi-truong-post1457368.tpo ","answer":"Xuất hiện tình trạng mua gom đất để 'phân lô, tách thửa' chào bán gây loạn thị trường"},{"question":"狗睡覺時為什麼把鼻子藏起來？","answer":"　　狗的鼻子比其它動物的鼻子複雜的多，除了正常的鼻腔有嗅覺作用外，鼻子尖端的外表面，還有一塊無毛的部位，那兒長著無數小小的突起，外面還覆蓋著一層黏膜組織，在這層黏膜上“駐紮”著許多特殊的細胞，專門掌管嗅覺。　　對狗來說，靈敏的嗅覺實在太重要了，如果鼻子受到了傷害，將會給狗的生活帶來極大的不便，所以，狗特別愛護它的鼻子，因此睡覺時，總是把鼻子藏起來，防止睡著後受到意外的傷害。"},{"question":"What color is a giraffe's tongue?","answer":"The colour of the giraffe's tongue is best described as black, blue or purple with a pink base/back. It is generally assumed that the front part of the tongue has such dark coloration to protect it during frequent sun exposure while eating and prevent the tongue from getting sunburned, however, no one really knows."},{"question":"Bu metin hangi önemli olayla ilgilidir: Tayyareci Salih Ekrem Yüzbaşı Osmanlı’nın ilk pilotlarından olan bir genç subaydır. Eşi küçük kızının doğumunda ölmüştür. Şubat 1915’te İngilizler donanma ile saldırıya başlayınca Salih Ekrem de kızını annesine emanet ederek İstanbul’dan ayrılır ve “ilk uçaklardan biri olan” tayyaresi ile Çanakkale’ye yola çıkar.","answer":"Çanakkale"},{"question":"රතු පාට සහ හෘදය හැඩය ඇති පලතුරක් නම් කරන්න.","answer":"ස්ට්‍රෝබෙරි, රතු පාට සහ හෘදය හැඩය ඇති පලතුරකි."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la respuesta correcta a esta pregunta?: ¿Cómo se llamaba la tercera película de la precuela de La Guerra de las Galaxias?","answer":"La respuesta correcta es: Star Wars: Episodio III - La venganza de los Sith."},{"question":"Theo đoạn văn sau, cuộc khó khăn trong tình hình tín dụng và hệ thống ngân hàng của Việt Nam xuất phát từ những yếu tố gì?Theo số liệu của Ngân hàng Nhà nước, đến cuối tháng 11, dư nợ tín dụng tăng hơn 9%. Với hạn mức tín dụng cả năm 14%, dư địa còn lại của hệ thống ngân hàng cấp cho nền kinh tế khoảng 5%, tương đương 700.000 tỷ đồng. Thủ tướng bày tỏ sốt ruột khi mức tăng trưởng tín dụng thấp, không đồng đều, doanh nghiệp tiếp cận tín dụng khó khăn. Điều hành tín dụng còn bị động, một số cơ chế chính sách tín dụng chưa sát tình hình, cơ cấu lại tổ chức tín dụng yếu kém còn chậm. Nguyên nhân vốn trong ngân hàng dư thừa nhưng khó cho vay, theo lãnh đạo Chính phủ, đến từ phía cung và cầu. Ở phía cung, hồ sơ, thủ tục vay của các nhà băng còn phức tạp, cứng nhắc. Lãi suất giảm nhưng vẫn cao so với khả năng chi trả của doanh nghiệp.Trong khi đó, hệ thống ngân hàng vẫn tồn tại tình trạng sở hữu chéo, bất cập trong phát hành trái phiếu đơn lẻ. \\"Các ngân hàng phải chấm dứt tình trạng cho vay tập trung vào một số doanh nghiệp, dự án thuộc hệ sinh thái, hoặc thuộc sân sau của tập đoàn. Cùng đó, cấm việc mở rộng room tín dụng và dành lãi suất thấp cho thành viên ban lãnh đạo ngân hàng\\", Thủ tướng nêu quan điểm.","answer":"Theo đoạn văn, cuộc khó khăn trong tình hình tín dụng và hệ thống ngân hàng của Việt Nam xuất phát từ yếu tố cung và cầu"},{"question":"Kese ne zaman gözükür Hamilelikte?","answer":"Gebelik kesesi 4.5-5. haftalarda vajinal ultrason ile görülebilmekte iken 6. haftalarda da kesin karından görülmesi gerekmektedir. Gebelik kesesinin çapının transvajinal ultrasonografide 10 milimetreye ulaştığında yolk kesesi izlenmelidir. Bu oluşumun izlenmesi gebeliğin normal olduğu şeklinde yorumlanır."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"awal bulan\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud permulaan bulan. Contoh ayat:  Saya telah menduduki ujian untuk memasuki kelas memandu kereta itu pada awal bulan lalu."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన భావం వచ్చేలాగా ఒక పద్యాన్ని రాయండి:పరిశుద్ధమైన, ప్రకాశవంతమైన, ఓ దుందుభి నదీ! నిన్ను బంధించారు. ఇదెక్కడి పిచ్చి తెలివి ? పవిత్రమైన భావాలను ఆపడం సాధ్యమా ? మిక్కిలి తీవ్రమైన అగ్నిని తీసుకొని మూటలో బంధించడం, నీటిని ఆపడం స్వేచ్ఛయే జీవితంగా కలదానివైన నీ విషయంలో సాధ్యమవుతుందా ?","answer":"మ| నిను బంధించి రిదేటి వెర్రితల పాండిత్యమ్ము? శక్యంబె పావనభావమ్ముల నిగ్రహింప కడు తీవ్రంబైన జ్వాలావళిన్గొనిమూట న్బిగియింపగా సలిల సంకోచంబు స్వేచ్ఛెకజీవనవౌ నీయెడ సాగునే విమల భాస్వద్రూప శైవాలినీ!"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الذي قتل علي بن أبي طالب؟","answer":"الجواب: عبد الرحمن بن ملجم."},{"question":"Mitkä ovat borrelioosin oireet?","answer":"Noin puolella tartunnan saaneista punkinpureman alueelle kehittyy punoittava ja laajeneva ihottuma, erythema migrans. Ihottuma on tyypillisesti ympyrämäinen, mutta voi olla muunkin muotoinen.Ensioire voi olla myös lymfosytooma, joka on hyvänlaatuinen punoittava tai sinertävä pehmeä kasvannainen esimerkiksi korvalehdessä. Taudin varhaisvaihe voi olla myös oireeton, tai siihen voi liittyä vain flunssan kaltaisia yleisoireita. "},{"question":"ಒಂಟಿತನವನ್ನು ದೂರ ಮಾಡಲು ಐದು ಸಲಹೆಗಳನ್ನು ನೀಡಿ ","answer":"೧. ಬಲವಾದ ಸಂಬಂಧಗಳು ಬೆಳಸಿ ೨. ಫೇಸ್‌ಬುಕ್‌ನಂತಹ ಸಾಮಾಜಿಕ ಮಾಧ್ಯಮಗಳನ್ನು ಬಳಸುವುದನ್ನು ನಿಲ್ಲಿಸಿ೩. ದೈಹಿಕವಾಗಿ ಜನರನ್ನು ಭೇಟಿ ಮಾಡಿ೪. ನಿಮ್ಮ ಸ್ನೇಹಿತರು, ಕುಟುಂಬ ಮತ್ತು ಹಿರಿಯರನ್ನು ಗೌರವಿಸಿ೫. ನಿಮ್ಮ ಸಂಗಾತಿಯೊಂದಿಗೆ ಸಮಯ ಕಳೆಯಿರಿ"},{"question":"ඩී.එස්. සේනානායක ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"දොන් ස්ටීවන් සේනානායක (1884 ඔක්තෝබර් 20-1952 මාර්තු 22) නම් වූ ස්වාධීන ක්‍රියාකාරිකය, 1947 දී 1952 දක්වා ශ්‍රි ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරය දැරීය.ගම්පහ මීරිගම බෝතලේ නම් ගම්මානයේ මුදලි දොන් ස්පාමර් සේනානායක හා දෝන කැතරිනා එලිසඛෙත් පෙරේරා ගුණසේකර සේනානායක මැතිණියට දාව උපන් ඔහු බෞද්ධ පරිසරයක හැදී වැඩුණ ද, පියාගේ කීම මත ඇන්ග්ලිකානු ක්‍රිස්තු පාසලක් වු ශාන්ත තෝමස් විද්‍යාලයට බැදී ක්‍රිස්තියානුවෙකු බවට පත්විය. පසුව නැවත බුද්ධාගමට හැරවුණු ඔහු, අධ්‍යාපනයෙන් පසුව මිනින්දෝරු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට බැඳුණි. 1914 දී පළමු ලෝක සංග්‍රාමයත් සමඟ, 1915 දී සිංහල මුස්ලිම් කෝලාහල සැකකරුවෙකු ලෙස ඔහුව අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලදි.තම සහෝදරයා වූ එෆ්.ආර්. සේනානායක ගේ අඩිපාරේ යමින් 1926 කාලය වන විට ඔහු නිදහස් සටනේ පුරෝගාමියෙකු විය. 1931 දී ඔහුව කෘෂිකර්ම හා ඉඩම් ඇමති ලෙස පත්කරන ලදි. ඔහුගේ කෘෂිකර්ම ප්‍රතිපත්තිය ජනතා ප්‍රසාදයට ලක්විය. 1946 දී ඔහු එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය පිහිටුවීය. 1947 මැතිවරණයෙන් ඔහු අගමැති ධූරයට පත්විය. තමාට ප්‍රදානය කළ නයිට් පදවිය නොපිළිගත්තද බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය සමඟ යහපත් සබඳතා පැවැත්වීය. ගල්ඔය ව්‍යාපෘතිය අරඹමින් ඔහු ඉමහත් ජනතා සේවයක් කළේය. නමුත් 1952 මාර්තු 22 දා හැට අට හැවිරිදි ඩී.එස්. සේනානායක ගාලූ මුවදොර පිටියේදී අසු පිටින් වැටී පසුව එම නිසාම මිය ගියේය.සිංහලයන් සහ මුස්ලිම් ජනයා ඩී.එස්.සේනානායකට ඉතා ගරු කරන මුත් ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති ඇතැම් දෙමළ ජනයාගේ විරෝධයට හේතු විය.ඩී.එස්. සේනානායක මහතාගේ බිරිඳ මොලී දුනුවිල මහත්මියගේත් පුතණුවන් දෙදෙනා ඩඩ්ලි සේනානායක හා රොබට් සේනානායකය. ඩඩ්ලි සේනානායක මහතා 1952, 1960, 1965-1970 කාලයේ අගමැති ධූරය හෙබවීය. 1953 අගමැති වූ සර් ජෝන් කොතලාවල ද ඔහුගේ ඥාතියෙකි. ඔහුගේ මුණුපුරෙක් වන රුක්මන් සේනානායක මහතා දැනටද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ එ.ජා.ප සභාපති ධූරය දරයි."},{"question":"Mampatanjaka ve ny fanatanjahan-tena?","answer":"Eny, mampatanjaka ny fanatanjahan-tena."},{"question":"ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ, 4 ਮਾਰਚਉੱਤਰੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਖਾਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਪੰਜਾਬ, ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਅਤੇ ਦਿੱਲੀ ’ਚ ਪਰਾਲੀ ਸਾੜਨ ਕਾਰਨ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਵਾ ਪ੍ਰਦੂਸ਼ਣ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਹ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਤਰਾ ਵਧਦਾ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਲਾਨਾ 30 ਅਰਬ ਡਾਲਰ ਯਾਨੀ ਕਰੀਬ ਦੋ ਲੱਖ ਕਰੋੜ ਦਾ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਨੁਕਸਾਨ ਵੀ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਦੇ ਇੰਟਰਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਫੂਡ ਪਾਲਿਸੀ ਰਿਸਰਚ ਇੰਸਟੀਚਿਊਟ ਅਤੇ ਸਹਿਯੋਗੀ ਸੰਸਥਾਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਖੋਜੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਪਾਇਆ ਕਿ ਪਰਾਲੀ ਸਾੜਨ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਵਾ ਪ੍ਰਦੂਸ਼ਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਉੱਤਰੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਵੱਖ ਵੱਖ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਹ ਲੈਣ ’ਚ ਔਖਿਆਈ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਇਨਫੈਕਸ਼ਨ ਹੋਣ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਤਰਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਵੱਧ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਅਧਿਐਨ ’ਚ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪੰਜ ਸਾਲ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਉਮਰ ਦੇ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਨਫੈਕਸ਼ਨ ਦਾ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਸਾਹਮਣਾ ਕਰਨਾ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਇੰਸਟੀਚਿਊਟ ਦੇ ਰਿਸਰਚ ਫੈਲੋ ਅਤੇ ਅਧਿਐਨ ਦੇ ਸਹਿ ਲੇਖਕ ਸੈਮੁਅਲ ਸਕੌਟ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ,‘‘ਹਵਾ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਰਾਬ ਗੁਣਵੱਤਾ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਭਰ ’ਚ ਸਿਹਤ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੀ ਸਮੱਸਿਆ ਬਣ ਗਈ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਦਿੱਲੀ ’ਚ ਤਾਂ ਹਵਾ ’ਚ ਜ਼ਹਿਰੀਲੇ ਕਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਪੱਧਰ ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਸਿਹਤ ਸੰਗਠਨ ਦੇ ਮਾਪਦੰਡਾਂ ਤੋਂ 20 ਗੁਣਾ ਤਕ ਵੱਧ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।’’ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਹੋਰ ਕਾਰਨਾਂ ’ਚ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਅਤੇ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ’ਚ ਕਿਸਾਨਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਪਰਾਲੀ ਸਾੜਨ ਨਾਲ ਨਿਕਲਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਧੂੰਏਂ ਤੋਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ ’ਚ ਹਵਾ ਦੀ ਗੁਣਵੱਤਾ ’ਤੇ ਅਸਰ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਅਧਿਐਨ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਪਿੰਡਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼ਹਿਰਾਂ ’ਚ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਰ ਉਮਰ ਵਰਗ ਦੇ ਢਾਈ ਲੱਖ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਿਹਤ ਅੰਕੜਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਲੇਸ਼ਣ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਸਾ ਦੇ ਸੈਟੇਲਾਈਟ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਮੁਹੱਈਆ ਕਰਾਏ ਗਏ ਅੰਕੜਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਵੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਖੋਜੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਮੰਨਿਆ ਕਿ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਹੀ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ’ਚ ਪਰਾਲੀ ਸਾੜਨ ਦੀਆਂ ਘਟਨਾਵਾਂ ਵਧਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਤਾਂ ਸਾਹ ਲੈਣ ਦੀ ਤਕਲੀਫ਼ ’ਚ ਵਾਧਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਵਾਲੀ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਆਤਿਸ਼ਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਕਰਕੇ ਸਿਹਤ ’ਤੇ ਪੈਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਅਸਰ ਬਾਰੇ ਵੀ ਪੜਤਾਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਖੋਜੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਆਤਿਸ਼ਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਚਲਾਉਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਹਵਾ ਪ੍ਰਦੂਸ਼ਨ ਨਾਲ ਕਰੀਬ 7 ਅਰਬ ਡਾਲਰ ਜਾਂ ਕਰੀਬ 50 ਹਜ਼ਾਰ ਕਰੋੜ ਰੁਪਏ ਸਾਲਾਨਾ ਦਾ ਨੁਕਸਾਨ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਪਿਛਲੇ ਪੰਜ ਸਾਲਾਂ ’ਚ ਫ਼ਸਲੀ ਰਹਿੰਦ ਖੂੰਹਦ ਸਾੜਨ ਅਤੇ ਆਤਿਸ਼ਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਚਲਾਉਣ ਨਾਲ ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ਨ 190 ਅਰਬ ਡਾਲਰ ਜਾਂ ਕੁੱਲ ਜੀਡੀਪੀ ਦਾ ਕਰੀਬ 1.7 ਫ਼ੀਸਦੀ ਨੁਕਸਾਨ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ। ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ’ਚ ਵਾਸ਼ਿੰਗਟਨ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਦੀ ਸੁਮਨ ਚਕਰਵਰਤੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਸਰਦੀਆਂ ’ਚ ਉੱਤਰੀ ਭਾਰਤ ’ਚ ਹੈਲਥ ਐਮਰਜੈਂਸੀ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਾਲਾਤ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ। ਪਰਾਲੀ ਸਾੜਨ ਕਾਰਨ ਉੱਤਰ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਹ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਤਰਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"2003 ਤੋਂ 2019 ਤੱਕ, ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਖੇਤੀ ਰਹਿੰਦ-ਖੂੰਹਦ ਨੂੰ ਸਾੜਨ ਕਾਰਨ ਸਾਲਾਨਾ 44,000-98,000 ਸਮੇਂ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਮੌਤਾਂ ਹੋਈਆਂ। ਪੰਜਾਬ, ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਅਤੇ ਉੱਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਨੇ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਮੌਤਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ 67-90% ਦਾ ਯੋਗਦਾਨ ਪਾਇਆ। "},{"question":"ඉන්දියානු භාෂා මොනවාද?","answer":"ඉන්දියානු ජනරජයේ කතා කරන භාෂා භාෂා පවුල් කිහිපයකට අයත් වේ, ඉන් ප්‍රධාන ඒවා වන්නේ ඉන්දියානුවන්ගෙන් 78.05% ක් කතා කරන ඉන්දු-ආර්ය භාෂා සහ ඉන්දියානුවන්ගෙන් 19.64% ක් කතා කරන ද්‍රවිඩ භාෂා ය, පවුල් දෙකම එක්ව සමහර විට ඉන්දියානු භාෂා ලෙස හැඳින්වේ. ජනගහනයෙන් ඉතිරි 2.31% කතා කරන ඔස්ට්‍රොඒෂියාටික්, චීන-ටිබෙට්, තායි-කඩයි සහ තවත් සුළු භාෂා පවුල් කිහිපයකට සහ හුදකලා වීමට අයත් වේ. ඉන්දියාවේ මහජන වාග් විද්‍යා සමීක්ෂණයට අනුව, පැපුවා නිව්ගිනියාවට (840) පසු දෙවන වැඩිම භාෂා සංඛ්‍යාව (780) ඇත්තේ ඉන්දියාවයි. Ethnologue 456 හි අඩු සංඛ්‍යාවක් ලැයිස්තුගත කරයි."},{"question":"Aye le o, Adamu ran awọn agbanipa si ọga ẹ l’Agbado","answer":"Ileepo kan ti wọn n pe ni ‘Inspiration’, eyi to wa lagbegbe Matọgun, l’Agbado, ipinlẹ Ogun, ni ọkunrin yii, Adamu  Ibrahim, ti n ṣiṣẹ aṣọgba. Ṣugbọn bo ṣe n ṣiṣẹ nibẹ to naa lo n pete iṣubu fẹni to gba a siṣẹ, niṣe lo ni kawọn ọmọọta lọọ dena de ọga ẹ lọna, owo to to miliọnu mẹta naira lo ni ki wọn gba lọwọ ọkunrin naa bọwọ wọn ba to o, ki wọn si pa a pẹlu.Ohun ti DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, ṣalaye f’ALAROYE lori iṣẹlẹ yii ni pe awọn ọmọkunrin meji kan, Ajibọla Yusuf ati Bakare Ifakayọde, ni Adamu lọọ bẹ lọwẹ pe ki wọn ba oun da ọga oun lọna to ba n lọ sile ni nnkan bii aago mẹjọ alẹ.Adamu ṣalaye fawọn ọkunrin meji yii pe ọkada ni ọga oun to jẹ maneja ile-epo naa maa gbe kọja, o sọ ọna ibi to maa n gba fun wọn, bẹẹ lo sọ iru ọkada ti yoo gbe kọja.Afikun to ṣe fawọn to bẹ lọwẹ ni pe owo ti yoo wa lara ọga oun naa yoo to miliọnu mẹta naira, o ni bi wọn ba ti rowo ọhun gba lọwọ ẹ tan, niṣe ni ki wọn pa a patapata, ko ma di pe ẹnikẹni yoo maa wadii bowo ṣe sọnu lọwọ ẹ tabi ti aṣiri kankan yoo fi tu.Ṣugbọn ohun ti Adamu ko mọ ni pe awọn ọmọkunrin meji to bẹ lọwẹ yii ki i ṣe iru iṣẹ bẹẹ, awọn funra wọn ni wọn lọọ ta awọn ọlọpaa lolobo ni teṣan Agbado, ti wọn sọ fun DPO Kẹhinde Kuranga pe loootọ lawọn n ṣe bii ọmọọta laduugbo tawọn eeyan si mọ awọn, ṣugbọn awọn ki i ṣe adigunjale, awọn ko si ki i paayan rara.Wọn ni awọn ko jẹwọ fun Adamu pe awọn ki i ṣe iru iṣẹ bẹẹ, awọn n tan an pe awọn yoo ba a pa ọga rẹ ni, ṣugbọn awọn ko le ṣe bẹẹ, ohun to jẹ kawọn waa sọ fọlọpaa niyẹn.Ki wọn le ri afurasi naa mu lọrun ọwọ ni awọn ọlọpaa ṣe sọ fawọn gende meji naa pe ki wọn ma fu u lara, wọn ni ki wọn maa ba a sọrọ, ki wọn si maa ṣe bii pe ọwọ awọn ko ti i ba ẹni to ran wọn si ni.Nigba ti Adamu ko si mọ pe ijọba ti dẹ okun silẹ foun, niṣe lo n pe Ajibọla ati Bakare lori foonu lọpọ igba, to n sọ bi ọga rẹ yoo ṣe tun rin fun wọn, to si n sọ pe ki wọn ṣaa ba oun mu un balẹ bi wọn ba gba owo ọwọ ẹ tan.Ohun to n ṣe lọwọ naa ree lọjọ tawọn ọlọpaa bo o lopin ọsẹ yii, ti wọn mu un ṣinkun nibi to ti n pete ibi.O kọkọ n purọ pe oun ko ṣe oun to jọ bẹẹ, oun ko ran ẹnikẹni niṣẹ, ṣugbọn nigba ti wọn mu awọn gende meji naa jade si i pe ko koju wọn, Adamu jẹwọ pe loootọ, oun bẹ wọn pe ki wọn ba oun pa ọga oun.O tiẹ tun sọ pe nitori awọn ọkunrin meji naa jọ awọn kan to ti ja ileepo toun n ṣọ naa lole ri nigba kan loun ṣe ro pe wọn yoo le ba oun ṣiṣẹ naa lọtẹ yii, koun naa le ri nnkan pọnla ninu iṣẹ ti wọn ba ṣe.Amọran ti waa lọ sọdọ awọn agbanisiṣẹ pe ki wọn mọ iru eeyan ti wọn yoo maa gba siṣẹ daadaa ki wọn too fiṣẹ ṣe wọn loore.Ọga ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun,  CP Edward Ajogun, lo fi amọran naa ranṣẹ sawọn eeyan. Bo ṣe paṣẹ pe ki wọn taari Adamu sẹka ti wọn yoo ti wadii ẹ naa lo ni kawọn agbanisiṣẹ maa foju ṣọri ki wọn too gbaayan sibi iṣẹ wọn."},{"question":"Explain the concept of a deep belief network (DBN) in deep learning.","answer":"A DBN is a generative probabilistic model that consists of multiple layers of stochastic, latent variables. It is used for unsupervised learning and feature learning."},{"question":"Inona no anton' ny fiandrasam-aty amin'ny Malagasy?","answer":"Ny antony hiandrasam-paty dia ny tahotra ny handevim-belona.  Fanehoan’ny mpira-belona ny fiaraha-mizaka ny fahoriana ihany koa anefa ny fiandrasam-paty."},{"question":"(ephakamisa ikhanda) Sekunguwe njalo baba?(sakuncokola) Ubuza ibhasi libhaliwe?(naye athi ukumamatheka) Hawu! Kanti wena sewaba yibhasi? (bahlekebobabili)(ahlale kwesinye isihlalo) Uboshiwe ngempela uDlamini. Kusasa uzoyakobingelela imantshi.Ashile! Kuhle-ke uma eboshiwe. (athule kancane)Nginovadlwana kodwa mina baba.Kodwa! Kodwa! Uvadlwana! Yini manje?(ngokuzithoba) Baba! Igazi likaMbandlwa lichithekile, induna yaboshwa.Konke lokhu akusho lutho kuwe?(ngolaka) Uthini manje? Mina ngibona kuzobathambisa ukuboshwakwenduna.(aphakamise izwi nomoya wakhe wenyuke) Hhayi bo! Ubathathakancane wena abantu bakule ndawo. Uyakhumbula ngesikhathi sodlame?Iningi labantu balapha bayayithanda inkosi futhi bayayihlonipha. (ehliseumoya) Baba, ngicela ukubone lokhu engikushoyo. Mina bengingacabangiukuthi lesi simo sizoze sifike kuleli banga esesikulo. Uyabona, nenja umaikhonkotha uke unganaki. Wethuke uphele uma isizifikela ngamazinyokuwe. Baba, izwe lizobheduka. Mina ngibona kungcono wena uzehliseenkosini noma uyeke kwabona ubukhansela lobu.(ethukuthela) Hheyi! Hheyi! Kanti usudleni wena? Lezi zinto ozishoyozombili angizamukeli! Lungamane luchitheke uphoko! Lutho mfazi! Ngeke!(enyuke ngolaka naye) Ubani umfazi weBafana? Ubiza mina ngomfazi?Wena awufuni ukuboniswa! Ngiyakutshela, uyongikhumbula seluchithekilelolu phoko lwakho.(abhoke kakhulu) Uzwa kanjani wena! Angisilo ivaka mina! Futhi, vala lomlonyana wakho singaze sethusane.1. Ukuziphatha kukaDuma kuyahambisana yini nendlela umholi okhethwengabantu okufanele aziphathe ngayo? ","answer":"Cha. Uma ungumholi okhethwe ngabantu kumele uzehlise ukwaziukusebenzisana nabantu nazo zonke izinhlaka zobuholi emphakathini."},{"question":"बाबा आमटे.","answer":"मुरलीधर देवीदास आमटे म्हणजेच बाबा आमटे यांचा जन्म महाराष्ट्र मध्ये वर्धा जिल्ह्यामधील हिंगणघाट याठिकाणी २६ डिसेंबर १९१४ रोजी झाला. बाबा आमटे यांचे वडील ब्रिटिश गव्हर्मेंट मध्ये एका चांगल्या पदवी वर होते, बाबा आमटे यांना जीवनात कसलीही कमी नव्हती, ते खूप श्रीमंत होते. त्यांना त्यांचे वडील लहानपणापासूनच बाबा या नावाने हाक मारत असे म्हणून त्यांना बाबा आमटे ह्या नावाने ओळखले जाते.बाबा आमटे हे देवीदास आमटे यांचे सर्वात ज्येष्ठ पुत्र होते त्यांच्याकडे खूप जमीन आणि श्रीमंती होती. बाबा आमटे जेव्हा १४ वर्षाचे होते तेव्हा त्यांच्याकडे स्वतःची बंदूक होती. जेव्हा बाबा आमटे १८ वर्षाचे झाले तेव्हा त्यांच्याकडे एक स्वतःची सुंदर स्पोर्ट्स कार होती. लहानपणीच बाबा आमटे यांना गरीबा बरोबर होणाऱ्या मतभेदांची जाणीव होती.बाबा आमटे हे एन एल बी झाले होते ते वर्धा जिल्ह्यामध्ये वकिली करत होते. त्यांनी १९४२ मध्ये भारताला स्वातंत्र्य मिळवून देण्यासाठी सहभाग घेतला होता, याबरोबरच त्यांनी भारतामध्ये अनेक चळवळींमध्ये सहभाग घेतला होता जसे की नर्मदा बचाव आंदोलन. बाबा आमटे यांनी आपला काही वेळ सेवाग्रम मध्ये घालवला होता तिथे त्यांच्यावर गांधी विचारांचा प्रभाव पडला होता. जेव्हा महात्मा गांधीजींना माहीत झाले हे बाबा आमटे यांनी एका मुलीला क्रूर इंग्रज सैनिका पासून न घाबरता वाचवले होते तेव्हा गांधीजींनी बाबा आमटे यांना \\"अभय साधक\\" ही उपाधी दिली होती.बाबा आमटे यांना समाजातील गरिबांवर होणाऱ्या अत्याचाराची जाणीव होती. ते एक खऱ्या अर्थाने समाजसेवक होते जे नेहमी लोकांच्या मदतीसाठी तत्पर राहत असे. पण समाजसेवा करत असताना त्यांना काही लोकांचे निंदेचे घाव सोसावे लागले, काही लोक त्यांना ढोंगी, पाखंडी सांगू लागले होते, पण बाबांना कशाचे ही दुःख नव्हते आणि त्यांनी मग आनंदवनाची निर्मिती केली.आंधळे, मूकबधिर आणि रोगाने पिडीत असहाय्य लोकांना समाजात कोणीही जगा देत नसे त्यांना कोणाचाही आधार नव्हता. कुष्ठरोगाने पीडित लोकांचे वाईट हाल होत असे, लोक अशा व्यक्तींना जवळ सुद्धा येऊन देत नव्हते. अशा सर्व कुष्ठरोग पीडित लोकांचा आधार बाबा आमटे बनले, या सर्व लोकांना बाबा आमटे यांनी आपलेसे केले आणि त्यांच्या बरोबर आनंदवना मधे राहू लागले.बाबा आमटे यांनी आपले सर्व आयुष्य लोकांसाठी आणि आपल्या देशासाठी समर्पित केले आणि या कामात त्यांना त्यांच्या परिवाराचा सुद्धा पाठिंबा मिळाला होता. बाबा आमटे आणि त्यांच्या पत्नी डॉ. मंदा यांनी कुष्ठरोगाने पीडित लोकांसाठी आनंदवना मध्ये हॉस्पिटल ची निर्मिती केली.बाबा आमटे हे या आधुनिक युगाचे खरे संत होते आणि खऱ्या अर्थाने एक समाजसेवक होते. त्यांना त्यांच्या कार्यासाठी पद्मश्री ने १९७४ मध्ये सन्मानित केले होते."},{"question":"Àgùàlà (Venus)","answer":"Àgùàlà (Venus) tí a tún ń pè ní Ajá òṣùpá, jẹ́ plánẹ́ẹ̀tì kejì sí Oòrùn."},{"question":"छोटो नेपाली कथा लेख्नुहोस् । ","answer":"भर्खरै एक जना परिचित व्यक्तिले मलाई एउटा अचम्मको कथा सुनाए। युद्धको लगत्तै, रेलमा यात्रा गर्दै, एक बूढो मानिस उनको अगाडि गाडिमा बसेर उनलाई यो कथा सुनाएको थियो रे ।सुन्नुहोस्, म लाटभियाको राजधानी सहर रिगाको बाहिरी भागमा बस्छु। युद्ध हुनु भन्दा ठीक अगाडि मेरो घर नजिकै एकजना मानिस बस्दथ्यो । कुनै हृदय र सम्मान नभएको उ एक बेईमान, क्रूर र मुनाफाखोर मानिस थियो । कतिपय मानिसहरू भन्छन् कि उ बेइमानी गरेर पैसा कमाउँछ, उ लोभी छ- मानव शोक र बच्चाहरूको आँसुबाट पनि पैसा कमाउछ ।एक दिन जर्मनहरूले रीगा कब्जा गरे र सबै यहूदी मानिसहरूलाई बस्तीमा राखे। बस्तीमा बन्दा बन्दि गरिएको थियो। तिनीहरूले पचास कदम भित्र पुग्ने जो कोहीलाई गोली हाने। हरेक दिन सयौं यहूदीहरू, विशेष गरी केटाकेटीहरू मरिरहेका थिए। त्यसैले मेरो लोभी छिमेकीले आलुले गाडी भर्ने, जर्मन सुरक्षाकर्मीलाई बस्तीमा पस्न घूस दिने र आलुले गहना साट्ने राम्रो विचार गर्यो । हल्ला थियो कि बस्तीमा यहूदी मानिसहरूसँग अझै धेरै बहुमुल्य गहनाहरू छन्।उ बस्ति तिर जानु अघि मैले उसलाई सडकमा देखेँ। “म बच्चाहरू भएका महिलाहरूसँग मात्र व्यवहार गर्नेछु,” उसले घमण्ड गर्यो । “उनीहरूले आफ्ना बच्चाहरूको लागि जे पनि गर्नेछन्, त्यसैले म तीन गुणा बढी पैसा कमाउन सक्छु।” रगत मेरो मुट्ठीमा पुग्यो। यदि उसले तुरुन्तै छोडेको थिएन भने, मैले मेरो रिसमा उसलाई मार्न सक्थे ।ऊ आलुका बोराहरू बोकेर आफ्नो गाडीमा भरेर बस्ती तिर गयो। उसले वार्डनलाई घूस दियो, जसले भन्यो, “उनीहरूसँग खाली पेटबाहेक केही बाँकी छैन। तिमीले आफ्नो सडेको आलु घर फिर्ता लैजानुपर्छ, म त्यसमा शर्त राख्छु।”बस्तीमा पुगे पछि, ऊ ठूलो घरको आँगनमा गयो। महिला र केटाकेटीले उसको गाडीको परिक्रमा गरे। अचानक, उसलाई थाहा थिएन कि यो कसरी भयो, उसले बोरा च्यात्दै थियो र आलुलाई भुइँमा फ्याँकिरहेको थियो। “हतार गर!” उसले महिलाहरूलाई करायो। “मलाई बच्चाहरू देउ । म तिनीहरूलाई यहाँबाट लैजान्छु। उनीहरूलाई केवल नचलिकन चुप रहन देउ । छिटो गर !”आमाहरूले आफ्ना छोराछोरीलाई बोरामा हाल्न थाले। उनीहरूलाई थाहा थियो कि उनीहरूले उनीहरूलाई फेरि कहिल्यै भेट्ने छैनन्, तर उनीहरूले उनीहरूलाई बिदाइ चुम्बन गर्न पनि समय पाएनन्। उसले आफ्नो गाडीमा बोरामा लुकाएका बच्चाहरू बोक्यो, गाडीको प्रत्येक छेउमा आलुका एक-दुई बोरा छोड्यो र पछाडि फर्केर हेर्दै नहेरि हिँड्यो। केटाकेटीहरू मध्ये एकले रुन थाल्यो भने सबैलाई छोडिदिनु पर्छ कि भन्ने डरले उसले आफ्नो घोडालाई ठुलो स्वरमा ठोक्यो । तर केटाकेटी चुपचाप बसे ।वार्डनले उसलाई देख्यो र करायो, “के मैले तिमीलाई मूर्ख हौ तिमी भनेर भनेको थिइनँ? लेफ्टिनेन्ट आउनु अघि नै आफ्नो दुर्गन्धित आलु लिएर बाहिर निस्क ।” उसले वार्डनलाई गालि दियो। उ जंगल भएको सडक तिर गयो जहाँ बिद्रोहिहरु बस्दथे। उसले बच्चाहरूलाई उनीहरूसँगै छोड्यो। उसले आफ्नी पत्नीलाई जर्मनहरूले उसको आलु लगे भन्यो । जब युद्ध समाप्त भयो, उसले रिगा छोड्यो ।ट्रेनमा भएको बुढो लाटभियन केही बेर चुपचाप थियो। “अब मलाई लाग्छ,” उसले भन्यो, र पहिलो पटक मुस्कुरायो, “यदि मैले मेरो रिस गुमाएको भए र मेरो मुट्ठीले उसलाई मारेको भए यो अति नराम्रो हुन्थ्यो।”"},{"question":"Inona amin'ireto no valiny marina amin'ity ankamantatra ity :  \\"Hitsidika no naleha hay fahafatesana no hita .\\" :1- lelo2- vato3- masoandro","answer":"Ny valiny marina dia : 1- lelo ."},{"question":"பிடல் காஸ்ட்ரோவின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"\\"புரட்சி என்பது ரோஜாக்களின் படுக்கை அல்ல. ஒரு புரட்சி என்பது எதிர்காலத்திற்கும் கடந்த காலத்திற்கும் இடையிலான போராட்டம்.\\""},{"question":"Kodi tanthauzo la ufa ndi chiyani?","answer":"1. ufu utha kuchokera ku tirigu wogayidwa bwino. komaso,  chinthu chofananacho chopangidwa kuchokera kumbewu ina kapena chakudya (monga mbatata zouma kapena nsomba)2. ufa wofewa wabwino."},{"question":"வினா : உருது இலக்கியத்தின் தந்தை?","answer":"விடை : அமீர் குஸ்ரு"},{"question":"Ma waxaad u heysta hadi aad jaab marantahy ama koontadada bangiga ay eber tahay ina waxba bixin karin?","answer":"Ma waxaad u heysataa in hadii aad jeeb maran tahay ama koontadaada Bankiga ay eber tahay aadan waxba bixin karin?Dad badan waxaa farxadooda nolosha ka qaada iyagoo ka fakira ama ka walwala saboolnimo iyo faqri. Waxay ku fakiraan marki aad wax hesho ayaad wax qabsan kartaa ama wax bixin kartaa. Ma ogtahay in ay jiraan waxyaabo badan aad maalin kasta bixin karto kuwaasoo aan qiime ku kicin ama lacag u baahneyn:-1. Alle oo aad u Mahadceliso, dambi dhaafna weydiisato2. Faraha gacantaada oo aad ka tasbiixsato3. Wado aad dhib ka leexisay4. Hadal wanaagsan aad ku hadashay5. Waayeel aad u naxariisatay ama caawisay6. Salaanta Islaamka oo aad ku salaanto qof kasta oo kaa soo hor baxa 7. Caruurtaada oo aad ciyaarsiiso ama cashar u aqriso8. Qoys burbur qarka u saarnaa oo aad Nabad dhex dhigtay9. Afkaaga iyo adinkaaga oo umadu ka amaan heshay10. Waalidkaa iyo Walaalahaa oo aad u duceysay11. Qaraabo aad xiriirisay12. Asxaabtaada oo aad Alle ka cabsi ugu baaqday, Aakhirana xasuusisay13. Xoogaaga oo aad si mutadawacnimo ah ugu adeegtay arrimo dan guud ah14. Bukaan aad Cusbitaal ku booqatay15. Qof kurbo Aduun heyso oo aad dhiirigelisay ama Rejo gelisay.Xaqiiqdaa intaa iyo ka badan uma baahna wax lacag ah, waxaadna sameyn kartaa maalin kasta. Waa sadaqo, waxaad ka helaysaa Ajar iyo Xasanaad, waxay kuu iftiiminayaan maalintaada, waxaa kugu jeclaanaya Bulshada, waxaa kuu duceynaya dadka, waxaad dareemaysaa deganaan iyo farxad.Isma ogidee waxaad tahay Taajir weyn!.."},{"question":"Which actor won the best actor Oscar for the films Philadelphia (1993) and Forrest Gump (1994)?","answer":"Tom Hanks won the best actor Oscar for the films Philadelphia (1993) and Forrest Gump (1994)."},{"question":"XML යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"Extensible Markup Language (XML) යනු අත්තනෝමතික දත්ත ගබඩා කිරීම, සම්ප්‍රේෂණය කිරීම සහ ප්‍රතිනිර්මාණය කිරීම සඳහා වන සලකුණු භාෂාවක් සහ ගොනු ආකෘතියකි. එය මිනිසුන්ට කියවිය හැකි සහ යන්ත්‍රයෙන් කියවිය හැකි ආකෘතියකින් ලේඛන කේතනය කිරීම සඳහා නීති මාලාවක් නිර්වචනය කරයි."},{"question":"\\"Жылдызы жарык\\"-дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Кимдир бирөөнүн сүйкүмдүү, жаркылдаган, жайдары мүнөзүн туюндурат. Мисалы: Калича апа - жылдызы жарык ачык мүнөздүү адам."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'buruk dikembang pada orang, elok dipilih sama seorang'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud keburukan, kerugian atau kesusahan hendak ditanggung bersama-sama, tetapi keuntungan diambil sendiri."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన సమాచారం పరిగణించి సమాధానం రాయండినేను జఠర గ్రంథుల నుండి స్రవించబడే ఎంజైమ్ ను మరియు ప్రోటీన్ల మీద పనిచేస్తాను.","answer":"పెప్సిన్"},{"question":"Reescreva a seguinte frase: Oi David, tudo bem? Acabou o açúcar aqui em casa, pode me emprestar um pouco?","answer":"Olá David, como você está? Você teria açúcar em casa e poderia me emprestar? O meu acabou"},{"question":"Сырдык сөздөр деген эмне ?","answer":"Ар түрдүү учурларда адамдын ички сезимин жана айбанаттарга карата эрктик мамиленибилдирген, лексикалык мааниге ээ болбогон сөздөр – сырдык сөздөр. Мисалы: бах, чиркин, ай, аттиң, оой кош"},{"question":"Jubbantil mbind mii:Duñu ko mébét mukk ngir la seen yoxo ya jëf [ci lu bon]. Yàlla ku xam la way-tooñ ña.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Du ñu ko mébat mukk ngìr la séen yoxo ya jëf [ci lu bon]. Yàlla ku xàm la waytooñ ña."},{"question":"Conte uma piada que envolva um mineiro e um gringo.","answer":"Tem um mineiro e um gringo dirigindo, o mineiro estava na frente e freia bruscamente o que faz com que o gringo bata em sua traseira.Então, os dois descem do carro e o gringo diz: \\"Hello\\" e então o mineiro responde \\"Que relou o que sô? Bateu foi tudo\\" O humor dessa piada está no fato da sonoridade parecida de Hello em relou, contudo relou é uma gíria mineira que significa encostar de leve. E, nesse caso, não foi uma encostada de leve e sim uma batida"},{"question":"次の文章を読んで、その内容に適したタイトルを付けてください： 京都の山にある西明寺という寺は、紅葉が有名です。近くには川もあります。今年も寺や周りの木の葉が赤や黄色になって、紅葉がいちばんきれいな季節になりました。寺によると、今年は10月の終わりから朝や夕方の気温が低くなりました。このため、いつもより少し早く紅葉が始まりました。来ていた人は、散歩をしたり寺の建物から景色を見たりしていました。兵庫県から来た女性は「建物の中から見える紅葉が、額に入れた絵のようできれいでした」と話しました。西明寺の紅葉は11月中旬まで楽しむことができそうです。","answer":"京都の西明寺　紅葉がきれいな季節になる"},{"question":"Ọwọ EFCC tẹ awọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ mẹwaa l’Alagbado","answer":"Awọn mẹwaa ni wọn ti wa lakata ajọ to n gbogun ti iwa jibiti ati ajẹbanu nilẹ wa, EFCC. Ẹsun ti wọn fi kan wọn ni pe wọn n lu awọn eeyan ni jibiti lori ẹrọ ayelajara, wọn n ṣe ‘Yahoo’.Orukọ awọn tọwọ ba ọhun ni Rasheed Ogunlana, Jonathan Daniẹl Adebayọ, Prince Wilfred Efetobore, Waidi Lawal, Joseph Adeọṣun ati Rotimi Ṣowunmi.Awọn mẹrin to ku ni Ọmọtayọ Oseni, Emmanuel Fakiyesi, Gbemileke Taiwo ati Ṣẹgun Ọladunni.Gẹgẹ bi agbẹnusọ fun ajọ EFCC, Ọgbẹni Wilson Uwajuren, ṣe fidi ẹ mulẹ fun ALAROYE, o ni olobo kan lo ta awọn nipa awọn afurasi ọdaran wọnyi. O lo ti ṣe diẹ tawọn ti n fimu finlẹ nipa wọn, igba ti iṣẹ iwadii tawọn ṣe too fi ibi ti wọn n gbe han lawọn ṣẹṣẹ lọọ fi pampẹ ofin gbe wọn lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, to kọja yii.Lara awọn nnkan ti wọn ka mọ wọn lọwọ ni ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ mẹta, kọmputa agbeletan, foonu oriṣiiriṣii, pasipọọtu ati iwe sọweedowo, titi kan ẹrọ igbalode ti wọn fi n ya fidio.Ọgbẹni Wilson lawọn afurasi wọnyi ti ṣalaye ara wọn fawọn to n ṣiṣẹ iwadii lọdọ EFCC. O fi kun un pe iwadii naa lo maa pilẹ igbẹjọ wọn nigba ti wọn ba foju bale-ẹjọ laipẹ."},{"question":"Xagee Bey Ku Dhimatay Rasuulkeena (NNKH) Hooyadiis?","answer":"Waxay Ku Dhimatay Meesha La-Yiraahdo Abwaa Oo U Dhaxeesa Maka Iyo Madia."},{"question":"Рианна кайсы жерде төрөлгөн?","answer":"Рианна аттуу ырчы Барбадос аралында төрөлгөн."},{"question":"सुनको मानकले आधुनिक फिएट मुद्रा प्रणालीसँग कसरी तुलना गर्छ?","answer":"सुनको मानकले मुद्रा मूल्यलाई सुनको भण्डारसँग जोड्दछ, स्थिरता प्रदान गर्दछ तर लचिलोपनलाई सीमित गर्दछ, जबकि फिएट मुद्रा प्रणालीहरू सरकारी डिक्रीमा आधारित हुन्छन्, लचिलोपन प्रदान गर्दछ तर मुद्रास्फीतिको खतरा हुन्छ।"},{"question":"Жапон эли жөнүндө факты жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Суу тартыш болгондуктан бир адам жуунган сууга, үй-бүлөсүнүн баардыгы жуунуп чыгышат. Баары бүткөндөн кийин кайра ал сууга кир жуушат."},{"question":"「国際連合」の旗に描かれている植物といったら何でしょう？","answer":"オリーブ"},{"question":"اكتب لي فقرة عن التطريز الفلسطيني","answer":"حسناً. التطريز الفلسطيني هو فن ومكون هام في حياة المرأة الفلسطينية وهو جزء من الفلكلور الفلسطيني الذي ورثته المرأة الفلسطينية ونقلته إلى بناتها وأحفادها على مر العصور، إذ يرجع أصوله إلى عهد الكنعانيين كما تشير الآثار في مختلف أنحاء فلسطين التاريخية. استعملت المرأة في فلسطين التطريز في تزيين اثوابها بشكل رئيسي إضافة إلى عدد كبير من حاجات البيت كالمفارش والوسائد والمحافظ وغيرها، انتشر هذا الفن في معظم أنحاء فلسطين تحديدا المنطقة الوسطى منها.كانت الأنماط المستخدمة في التطريز متباينة وفقاً للمناطق الجغرافية، إذا كان من الأمكن التمييز عبرها إلى المنطقة التي تنتمي لها المرأة بل حتى إلى أي قرية تنتمي، تمت إضافته إلى قائمة التراث الثقافي غير المادي في لائحة منظمة الأمم المتحدة للتربية والعلم والثقافة (اليونسكو) عام 2021م."},{"question":"கேள்வி: திருக்குறளில் கோடி என்ற சொல் ----- இடங்களில் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது.அ) ஐந்துஆ) ஆறுஇ) ஏழுஈ) எட்டு","answer":"பதில் :இ ) ஏழு"},{"question":" Inona no tombony azo amin'ny fialan-tsasatra sy ny fisaintsainana amin'ny fitantanana ny adin-tsaina?","answer":"Ny fialan-tsasatra sy ny fisaintsainana dia afaka manampy amin'ny fampihenana ny haavon'ny cortisol, hanatsara ny fifantohana ary hampiroborobo ny fahatsapana ho tony."},{"question":"Ifẹ̀wàrà","answer":"Ìfẹ̀wàrà jẹ́ ìlú kékeré kan ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Ọ̀ṣun ni Nàìjíríà Gẹ́gẹ́ bí a sọ ṣaájú, ìwádìí lórí iṣẹ́ yìí dé Ìjọba Ìbílẹ̀ Àtàkúmọ̀sà tí ó ní ibùjókòó rẹ̀ ní Òṣú. Ní ìjọba ìbìlẹ̀ yìí, gbogbo àwọn ìlú àti abúlèko tí ó wà ní ibẹ̀ ló jẹ́ ti Ìjẹ̀ṣà. Ẹ̀yà ẹ̀ka-èdè Ìjẹ̀ṣà ni wọ́n sì ń sọ àfi Ifẹ̀wàrà tí ó jẹ́ ẹ̀yà ẹ̀kà-èdè Ifẹ̀ ni wọ́n ń sọ. Gẹ́gẹ́ bí ìtàn tí gbọ́, Ifẹ̀ ni àwọn ará Ifẹ̀wàrà ti ṣí lọ sí ìlú náà láti agboolé Arùbíìdì ní òkè Mọ̀rìṣà ní Ilé-Ifẹ̀1 . Ìwádìí fi hàn pé ọ̀rọ̀ oyè ló dá ìjà sílẹ̀ ní ààrin tẹ̀gbọ́ntàbúrò. Ẹ̀gbọ́n fẹ́ jẹ oyè, àbúrò náà sì ń fẹ́ jẹ oyè náà. Ọ̀rọ̀ yìí dá yánpọn-yánrin sílẹ̀ ní ààrin wọn. Lórí ìjà oyè yìí ni wọ́n w\`atí ẹ̀gbọ́n fi lọ sí oko. Ṣùgbọ́n kí ẹ̀gbọ́n tó ti oko dé, ipè láti jẹ oyè dún. Àbúrò tí ó wà ní ilé ní àsìkò náà ló jẹ́1. Ìfọ̀rọ̀wánilẹ́nuwò pẹ̀lú arábìnrin Julianah aya ni 17/6/92.2. Ìfọ̀rọ̀wánilẹ́nuwò pẹ̀lú Olóyè Fákówàjọ ni 17/6/92. Ipé náà. Ipè ti sé ẹ̀gbọ́n mọ́ oko. Èyí bí ẹ̀gbọ́n nínú nígbà tí ó gbọ́ pé àbúrò òun ti jẹ oyè, ó sì kọ̀ láti padà wá sí ilé nítorí pé kò lè fi orí balẹ̀ fún àbúrò rẹ̀ tí ó ti jẹ oyè. Ọ̀rọ̀ yìí di ohun tí wọn ń gbé ogun ja ara wọn sí fún ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ọdún. Nígbà tí ẹ̀gbọ́n yìí wá ń gbé ogun ja àbúrò rẹ̀ ní Ifẹ̀ lemọ́lemọ́, ni àwọn Ifẹ̀ bá fi ẹ̀pà ṣe oògùn sí ẹnu odi ìlú ní Ìlódè. Wọ́n sì fi màrìwò ṣe àmì sì ọ̀gangan ibi tí wọ́n ṣe oògùn náà sí. Láti ìgbà yìí ni ogun ẹ̀gbọ́n kò ti lè wọ Ifẹ̀ mọ. Àwọn Ìjẹ̀ṣà ní ó ni kí ẹ̀gbọ́n tí ó ń bínú yìí lọ tẹ̀dó sí Ìwàrà. Nígbà tí wọ́n dé Ìwàrà, wọ́n fi mọ̀rìwò ọ̀pẹ gún ilẹ̀, kí ilẹ̀ tó mọ́ mọ̀rìwò kọ̀ọ̀kan ti di igi ọ̀pẹ kọ̀ọ̀kan. Ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ tẹ̀lẹ̀, wọ́n sì pinnu pé àwọn kò níí lè bá àwọn àlejò náà gbé nítorí pé olóògùn ni wọn. Èyí ló mú kí àwọn ara Ìwàrà lé àwọn àlejò náà sí iwájú. Ibi tí àwọn àlejò náà tẹ̀dó sí lẹ́yìn tí wọ́n kúrò ní Ìwàrà ni a mọ̀ sí Ifẹ̀wàrà lónìí. Lóòtọ́ orí ilẹ̀ Ìjẹ̀ṣà ni Ifẹ̀wàrà wà ṣùgbọ́n kò sí àjọṣepọ̀ kan dàbí alárà láàrin Ifẹ̀wàrà, Iléṣà àti Ìwàrà títí di òní pàápàá nípa ẹ̀ka-èdè tí wọn ń sọ.Àkíyèsí fi hàn pé gbogbo orúkọ àdúgbò tí ó wà ní Ifẹ̀ náà ni ó wà ní Ifẹ̀wàrà. A rí agboolé bí Arùbíìdì, Mọ̀ọ̀rẹ̀, Òkèrèwè, Lókòrẹ́ àti Èyindi ní Ifẹ̀wàrà.Bákan náà ẹ̀yà ẹ̀ka-èdè Ifẹ̀ nì wọ́n ń sọ ní Ifẹ̀wàrà. Àsìkò tí wọ́n bá sì ń ṣe ọdún ìbílẹ̀ ní Ifẹ̀ náà ni àwọn ará Ifẹ̀wàrà máa ń ṣe tiwọn.Ìwádìí nípa ìtàn ìṣẹ̀dálẹ̀ àwọn ìlú tí iṣẹ́ yìí dé fi hàn gbangba pé mọ̀lẹ́bí ni Ifẹ̀, Ifẹ̀ẹ́tẹ̀dó pẹ̀lú Òkè-Igbo, àti Ifẹ̀wàrà. Wọ́n jọra nínú ìṣesí wọn. Ẹ̀ka-èdè wọn dọ́gba, orúkọ àdúgbò wọn tún bára mu, bákan náà ni ẹ̀sìn wọn tún dọ́gba. Àkókó tí wọ́n ń ṣe ọdún ìbílẹ̀ kò yàtọ̀ sí ara wọn. Bí ẹrú bá sì jọra, ó dájú pé ilé kan náà ni wọ́n ti jáde."},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து பிசைந்த உருளைக்கிழங்கு பந்துகள் செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:4 உருளைக்கிழங்கு½ கப் பொட்டு கடலை1 பெரிய வெங்காயம்1 பச்சை மிளகாய்½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி கரம் மசாலாதேவையான அளவு உப்புதேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்சிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லி","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் உருளைக்கிழங்கை சுத்தம் செய்து, வெங்காயம், பச்சை மிளகாய், மற்றும் கொத்தமல்லியை நறுக்கி வைத்து கொள்ளவும்2. அடுத்து ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் உருளைக்கிழங்கை வேக வைப்பதற்கு தேவையான அளவு தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி அதில் உருளைக்கிழங்கை போட்டு அதை சுமார் 20 லிருந்து 25 நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும்.3. 25 நிமிடத்துக்கு பிறகு அதை எடுத்து சிறிது நேரம் ஒரு பாத்திரத்தில் வைத்து ஆற விட்டு பின்பு அதை எடுத்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து நன்கு ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் மசித்து விடவும்.4. பிறகு அரை கப் அளவு பொட்டு கடலையை ஒரு மிக்ஸி ஜாரில் போட்டு அதை நன்கு நைசாக அரைத்து கொள்ளவும்.5. பின்னர் நாம் உருளைக்கிழங்கை மசித்து வைத்திருக்கும் கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் நாம் அரைத்து வைத்திருக்கும் பொட்டு கடலை மாவில் இருந்து இரண்டரை மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு மாவை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.6. பின்பு அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் வெங்காயம், பச்சை மிளகாய், கரம் மசாலா, மற்றும் தேவையான அளவு உப்பு சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கிளறி விடவும். (தண்ணீர் எதுவும் இதில் சேர்த்து விடக்கூடாது.)7. அடுத்து அதில் எலுமிச்சம் பழம் அளவு மாவை எடுத்து அதை நன்கு உருட்டி பின்பு அதை கையில் வைத்து பக்குவமாக தட்டி அதை தட்டையான வடிவிற்க்கு மாற்றி ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.8. இவ்வாறு மீதமுள்ள மாவுகளையும் உருட்டி பின்பு தட்டி தயார் செய்து தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.9. இப்பொழுது ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் 2 மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.10. எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் அதில் நாம் தட்டி வைத்திருக்கும் உருளைக்கிழங்கு மசாலாவை வைத்து அது ஒரு புறம் பொன்னிறமானதும் அதை மறு புறம் திருப்பி போட்டு அது பொன்னிறம் ஆகும் வரை அதை வேக விடவும்.11. அது இரு புறமும் பொன்னிறமானதும் அதை ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் எடுத்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து சுட சுட பரிமாறவும்.12. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் மிகவும் சுவையான பிசைந்த உருளைக்கிழங்கு பந்துகள் தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து உண்டு மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"Araka ny kolontsaina malagasy, inona no fanolotra ny ray aman-dreny lehibe indrindra rehefa misy fetim-pianakaviana?","answer":"Araka ny kolontsaina malagasy, ny fanolotra ray aman-dreny rehefa fetim-pianakaviana dia vody akoho."},{"question":"วันนี้ยิ้มหรือยัง","answer":"ยังเลย ไม่มีอารมณ์น่ะ"},{"question":"Awọn aṣofin buwọ lu aba eto iṣuna ọdun 2021 l’Ọṣun","answer":"Lẹyin oṣu kan ti Gomina Gboyega Oyetọla ti gbe aba eto iṣuna tipinlẹ Ọṣun yoo lo lọdun to n bọ lọ sile-igbimọ aṣofin, awọn aṣofin ti buwọ lu u lọsan-an ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ yii.Aba eto iṣuna naa ni apapọ owo inu rẹ din diẹ ni biliọnu lọna aadọfa naira (#109,855,051,640). Owo tijọba yoo na lori awọn iṣẹ akanṣe le diẹ ni biliọnu lọna aadọta naira, nigba ti owo ti yoo ba awọn ti ki i ṣe iṣẹ akanṣe lọ din diẹ ni biliọnu lọna aadọta naira.Abẹnugan ile, Rt. Hon. Timothy Owoẹyẹ, gboriyin fun awọn ẹgbẹ rẹ fun ifaraji ati ifọwọsowọpọ wọn lati ṣiṣẹ lori aba eto iṣuna naa kiakia. O ni nnkan ti bọjẹẹti naa da le lori ju lọ ni bi ipinlẹ Ọṣun yoo ṣe jajabọ lori wahala ti ajakalẹ arun korona ti mu ba eto iṣuna ninu ọdun yii.Bakan naa lo ni ọrọ awọn ọdọ ko ipa pataki ninu eto iṣuna naa nitori bii biliọnu kan aabọ naira (#1.4b) nijọba ya sọtọ lati na lori idagbasoke awọn ọdọ lọdun to n bọ.Owoẹyẹ ke si awọn ileeṣẹ ijọba lati tẹpa mọṣẹ, ki wọn si ṣe gbogbo nnkan ti wọn kọ silẹ ninu aba eto iṣuna naa pe awọn fẹẹ ṣe. O ni loorekoore lawọn yoo maa ṣepade pẹlu awọn ileeṣẹ naa lati mọ bi wọn ṣe n gbiyanju si lẹnu iṣẹ wọn.Lori irọkẹkẹ wahala korona to tun wa nilẹ bayii, Owoẹyẹ rọ gbogbo awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ọṣun lati ma ṣe tura silẹ rara, o ni gbogbo alakalẹ ati ilana ti yoo dena itankalẹ arun naa di dandan fun gbogbo eeyan lati maa tẹle bayii.O ni kiakia lawọn yoo gbe aba ti awọn buwọ lu naa lọ sọdọ gomina, ki oun naa le buwọ lu u, ko si le di ofin to ṣe e mu lo."},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકના એક લેખનના શરૂઆતના ફકરા નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે.\\"વિઠલો સુતાર હતો. હજુ નાનો હતો છતાં ચોડાં ફાડાતાં ને રોંકતા આવડાતું; પણ વિઠલાને ઇતિહાસ ભૂગોળ કેમે કરીને યાદ ન રહે. બિચારો ઘણું ગોખે !⁠માસ્તર તો લેસન ન આવડે એને કાં તો ગાળો દે ને કાં તો મારે. વિઠલાને તો ગાળો યે દે ને ઉપરથી વળી મારે. વિઠલાને અંગૂઠા પકડાવે; પછી ઉપરથી ઘમ કરી ઘૂંસતો લગાવે !\\"આ માથાફોડના આગળના ફકરા લખો.","answer":"⁠બિચારો વિઠલો ઉં... કરી જાય ને બોલે: “ભાઈશા’બ નથી આવડતું !” વિઠલાને ઈતિહાસ આવડ્યો જ નહિ; વિઠલાને સુતારકામ આવડ્યું. આજે એ એક સારો સુતાર મિસ્ત્રી છે.⁠બાપા કામ કરવા દેતા હતા; માસ્તર ભણાવતા હતા ને મારતા હતા."},{"question":"Mene ne fassara a Hausa?","answer":"Fassara ita ce juya ko sauya wata magana daga wani harshe zuwa wani. Wannan magana tana iya zama baka da baka, rubutacciya, daga baka zuwa rubutu, ko kuma daga rubutu zuwa maganar baka. Misali, idan na faɗi magana da Hausa, kamar in ce, “Ado mutumin kirki ne”, sai kai kuma ka juya ta zuwa Turanci ka ce, “Ado is a generous person”. To, fassara ta samu amma ta baka da baka. Ko kuma a rubuta “هَذَاكِتَابٌ”, kai kuma ka juya ta zuwa “wannan littafi ne”. A nan ma an yi fassara amma rubutacciya daga Larabci zuwa Hausa."},{"question":"大石内蔵助をはじめとする赤穂浪士や浅野内匠頭の墓があり、忠臣蔵ファンが多数参拝する東京都港区の寺は何でしょう？","answer":"泉岳寺（せんがくじ）です。"},{"question":"Jawab soalan berikut. Siapah yang memegang watak robot dalam siri The Orville?","answer":"Mark Jackson"},{"question":"نکات مهم در تربیت فرزند پسر ۶ ساله چیست؟","answer":"کودکان پسر معمولا کم‌تر از دختران مطیع والدین خود هستند، دراین سن کودک بیشتر بیرون از خانه می‌رود و درمراحل آغازین روابط اجتماعی به سر می‌برد و ممکن است لجبازی و سرپیچی را زیاد مشاهده کنید بنابراین تربیت کمی چالش برانگیزتر می‌شود.اعتماد به نفس درکودک این سنی که تازه پا به عرصه‌ ی اجتماع و روابط اجتماعی گذاشته از مهم‌ترین موارد است و والدین باید اهمیت این موضوع را به فرزندشان که قرار است در جامعه باشد آموزش دهند بنابراین آنان باید با تشویق ‌کردن و ارزشمند ‌شمردن کودک، تحقیر نکردن، پرهیز ازخشونت و رابطه‌ی خشونت ‌آمیز،کمک به بیان هرچه بیشتر احساسات و دغدغه ‌ها، و عکس العمل درست نشان‌ دادن در مقابل مشکلات و کارهای اشتباه و راهنمایی‌ کردن در ازای تحقیر و فریاد زدن به افزایش اعتماد به نفس و ایجاد رابطه‌ی هرچه صمیمی ‌تر با فرزند خود تلاش کنند."},{"question":"Kí ni oríkì ìlú Ìkirè?","answer":"Oríkì ìlú ÌkirèEwú ni wínrin, Ọmọ àdalè gbin'ewùrà, Ọmọ àdalè gbin isu Ìgángán, Ọmọ ewú filè hàn mí, Ọmọ ewú fònà hàn mí, Ọmọ ewú kí kòjé fabuja ilé  Ìkirè han ni, Ọmọ  àkànkù  ilé, Ọmọ  àkànkù ọ̀nà èjìgbò, Ọkan ókù oloku kò sin, Ọmọ asákú mawo, marooyin, Ọmọ  àkànkù mawo maroyinỌmọ gbinrin ni yeye aro,Ọmọ olóríṣà kò jẹ́kan, Èyí taa mú ohun méjì sebo lọ́jọ́ gbogbo ọmọ onígbó rúrú tí àjòjì ò́ gbọdò wò, àjòjì kàjòjì tó bá wobè yio dẹni ẹbọ,àjòjì wéré-wéré ọ̀nà Ìkirè,èyí tí pani sí  ju eji lọ.... Èyin ọmọ Ìkirè owó yín dá Kí Èdùmàrè tún Ìkirè ṣe. Kí ìpínlè Òsun má dàrú.."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'ibarat rumput yang sudah kering, ditimpa hujan segar kembali'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud perihal orang yang sengsara yang dengan tiba-tiba mendapat pertolongan sehingga hidupnya terasa sangat berbahagia"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Nghi phạm dùng súng AK cướp tiệm vàng ở TT- Huế bị bắt, lúc 14h15 chiều nay cho biết, Công an tỉnh TT-Huế vừa bắt giữ nghi phạm gây ra vụ cướp táo tợn tiệm vàng ở chợ Đông Ba (TP Huế) Danh tính nghi phạm chưa được cơ quan chức năng công bố. Thời điểm gây án, ngoài mang súng AK, đối tượng còn khoác trên người bộ đồng phục giống công an. Chị Hoàng T.P. – một người dân có mặt tại hiện trường vụ việc cho biết, khoảng 12h45 trưa nay, chị và nhiều người dân trên tuyến đường Trần Hưng Đạo hốt hoảng khi nghe 2 tiếng súng phát ra từ tiệm vàng Thái Lợi và Hoàng Đức trước cổng chợ Đông Ba. \\"Ngay sau tiếng súng, một người đàn ông mang đồ giống công an, cầm trên tay khẩu súng AK và nhiều túi nghi đựng vàng chạy ra khỏi tiệm. Ra đến đường Trần Hưng Đạo, đối tượng vứt những túi này xuống đường rồi","answer":"cầm súng chạy thoát hướng cầu Gia Hội\\", chị P. cho biết. Công an tỉnh TT-Huế nhanh chóng điều hàng chục cán bộ, chiến sĩ cùng xe bọc thép đến hiện trường. Đoạn dài đường Trần Hưng Đạo cũng bị phong toả để truy bắt nghi phạm. Khoảng 13h45, có tiếng súng vang lên ngay khu vực cầu Gia Hội, khiến người dân hoảng loạn. Lực lượng chức năng yêu cầu người dân đóng cửa, không ra khỏi nhà để đảm bảo an toàn. Một lãnh đạo Công an TP Huế cho biết, đối tượng bị bắt giữ tại khu vực công viên dưới chân cầu Gia Hội sau hơn 1 giờ gây án. Thời điểm bị bắt giữ, nghi phạm cởi trần, có dấu hiệu bị ngáo đá."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو اسم الصحابي الجليل أبو موسى الأشعري؟","answer":"الجواب: عبد الله بن قيس رضي الله عنه."},{"question":"Pag-isipan ang scenario na ito:Isang lalaki ang nakatayo sa isang tabi ng isang ilog, ang kanyang aso naman ay sa kabila. Tinawag ng lalaki ang kanyang aso kung saan ito ay tumawid kaagad sa ilog nang hindi nababasa at hindi gumagamit ng tulay o bangka. Paano ito ginawa ng aso?","answer":"Base sa impormasyon ng scenario kung saan ang aso ay mistulang nakatawid sa ilog na hindi gumagamit ng tulay o bangka at hindi nababasa, ang pinakapraktikal at lohikal na kasagutan ay maaaring nagyelo ang ilog kung saan pwede kang makalakad dito."},{"question":"\\" ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දෙමළ ගද්‍ය සාහිත්‍යයේ පියා \\" ලෙස බුහුමන් ලබන්නේ කවුද ?","answer":"\\" ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දෙමළ ගද්‍ය සාහිත්‍යයේ පියා \\" ලෙස බුහුමන් ලබන්නේ ශ්‍රී ආරුමුග නාවලර් තුමායි ."},{"question":"Manomeza ohabolana sy fomba fiteny dimy ,momba ny fiainana .","answer":"Ireto ny ohabolana sy fomba fiteny dimy ,momba ny fiainana :1- \\" Ny teny toy ny atody ka raha foy manana elatra .\\" , 2- \\" Rafotsibe mandinga-tatatra ka manitatra ny efa mikatona .\\" ,3- \\" Setroka sy tomany tsy mba sarotra fantarina .\\" ,4- \\"Tain'alika ka ny avo ihany no tovonana .\\" ,5- \\" Ny hazo no vanon-ko lakana, ny tany naniriany no tsara .\\" ."},{"question":"Ngimkhumbule namuhla uMntungwa. Sasivame ukuhlala sobabiliphansi kwalesi sihlahla. Ngixakwa yilaba abangibelesele ngendabakaDumisani. Bayahlanya. Abazi ukuthi angiyingeni indaba yokungenwamina. Kodwa yena uMntungwa angathini lapho ekhona? Noma ngabeuDumisani usekhulile nje, ngeke ungibone ngimgana mina. Minaangisiye owokuganga. Naye ngizomgada manje uma efikile. Umaengeshela nje ngiyomkhombisa ikheli. Ngimbuze ukuthi ungithandamanini nje. Uma enganakile futhi siyodumelana kube kuncane indawo.Uyazi angimazi nalo muntu owasungula isiko lokungenwa wayehlushweyini. Abantu bayathanda ukusungula amasiko adala izinkinga.(Ezwe izigi) Nangu umama eza. Uma eqala le ndaba yesiko lakheuzongizwa kahle namuhla. Angihleki angithi nsi. Angifuni ndoda njeeduze kwami manje.Uyawuthanda lo msebenzi wokuthunga koti bo. (Ahlale phansi)Ngenzela ukuthi ngingakhohlwa mama. Nawo umshini awufuni ukuhlalaisikhathi eside ungasebenzi.Kuzofuneka ungifundise nami makoti ngizithungele.Awu mama uthi kungalunga ufundiswa imfundamakhwela?Akubonakali ukuthi usafunda koti. Ukwenza kwakho kukhombisaubumpetha. Impela ngicela ungifundise. Siningi kabi isikhathiesizosihlala nawe ngingagcina sengiwushaya njengawe nje.Usho ukuthini umama uma ethi sisazohlala isikhathi eside?Kanti uyahamba yini?Ngingeze ngasho ukuthi ngiyahamba mama. Uma sekukhunyulwe inzilobengizocela ukuba ngibuyele ekhaya. 1. Yimuphi lo msebenzi uMaMbatha ayefuna ukuwufundiswa nguThenjiwe? ","answer":"Ukuthunga ngomshini.√"},{"question":"Нивелир деген эмне ?","answer":"Нивелир-жер бетиндеги чекиттердин бийиктен айырмаларын өлчөөдө колдонулуучу геодезиялык аспап."},{"question":"Beqil ma mbind mii:Melax ga xaw naa yuri seeni gët: saa su leen leeralee [yoon wa] ñu dox ca leer ga;saa su lëndëmee ñu taxaw. Bu neexoon Yàlla mu tëxloo leen, gumbaloo leen, Yàlla am na kàttanu def lu ne.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Melax ga xàw na a yuri séen i gët: saa su léen leeralee [yoon wa] ñu dox ca leer ga; saa su lëndamee ñu taxaw. Bu neexoon Yàlla mu tëxloo léen, gumbaloo léen, Yàlla àm na kàttan u def lu ne."},{"question":"Ayat 1: Pada tahun 1897, sebuah kereta api telah dibina ke pacuan kuda dan kereta api dan stesen telah dikeluarkan pada tahun 1957. Ayat 2: Pada tahun 1897 sebuah kereta api telah dipindahkan ke Racecourse. Kereta api dan stesen dibina pada tahun 1957. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Tidak"},{"question":"भारत की राजधानी क्या है?","answer":"नई दिल्ली भारत की राजधानी है। दिल्ली राजधानी होने के नाते केंद्र सरकार की तीनों इकाइयों- कार्यपालिका, संसद और न्यायपालिका के मुख्यालय नई दिल्ली और दिल्ली में स्थापित हैं। १४८३ वर्ग किलोमीटर में फैला दिल्ली जनसंख्या के तौर पर भारत का दूसरा सबसे बड़ा महानगर है। यहाँ की जनसंख्या लगभग १ करोड़ ७० लाख है। यहाँ बोली जाने वाली मुख्य भाषाएँ हैं : हिन्दी, पंजाबी, उर्दू और अंग्रेज़ी। "},{"question":"නිසඟ අර්ධ සන්නායක යනු මොනවද ? ","answer":"නිසඟ අර්ධ සන්නායක වලට පාලිත තත්ත්ව යටතේ වෙනත් සුදුසු මූලද්‍රව්‍ය පරමාණු ස්වල්පයක් එකතු කර බාහ්‍ය අර්ධ සන්නායක සාදනු ලැබේ. මෙම ක්‍රියාවලියෙන් පසු අර්ධ සන්නායක ද්‍රව්‍ය තවදුරටත් සංශුද්ධ තත්වයේ නොපවතින බැවින් පිටතින් එක් කරන ද්‍රව්‍ය අපද්‍රව්‍ය ලෙස හැදින්වේ.මෙහිදී අපද්‍රව්‍ය පරමාණු එකතු කිරීම මාත්‍රණය කිරීම් නම් වේ.මෙහිදී මාත්‍රණය කිරීම් සඳහා III සහ V කාණ්ඩවල මූලද්‍රව්‍ය  පරමාණු යොදා ගැනේ.මාත්‍රණය කිරීමෙන් අර්ධ සන්නායකවල සන්නායකතාව වැඩි වේ.මාත්‍රණය සඳහා යොදා ගන්නා මූලද්‍රව්‍ය අයත්වන කාණ්ඩයය අනුව බාහ්‍ය අර්ධ සන්නායක ප්‍රධාන කොටස් දෙකකි.p වර්ගයේ බාහ්‍ය අර්ධ සන්නායක (p-type)n වර්ගයේ බාහ්‍ය අර්ධ සන්නායක (n-type)"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ॥ਗੁਣਵੰਤੀ ਗੁਣ ਵੀਥਰੈ ਅਉਗੁਣਵੰਤੀ ਝੂਰਿ ॥ਜੇ ਲੋੜਹਿ ਵਰੁ ਕਾਮਣੀ ਨਹ ਮਿਲੀਐ ਪਿਰ ਕੂਰਿ ॥ਨਾ ਬੇੜੀ ਨਾ ਤੁਲਹੜਾ ਨਾ ਪਾਈਐ ਪਿਰੁ ਦੂਰਿ ॥੧॥ਮੇਰੇ ਠਾਕੁਰ ਪੂਰੈ ਤਖਤਿ ਅਡੋਲੁ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਪੂਰਾ ਜੇ ਕਰੇ ਪਾਈਐ ਸਾਚੁ ਅਤੋਲੁ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਹਰਿਮੰਦਰੁ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਤਿਸੁ ਮਹਿ ਮਾਣਕ ਲਾਲ ॥ ਮੋਤੀ ਹੀਰਾ ਨਿਰਮਲਾ ਕੰਚਨ ਕੋਟ ਰੀਸਾਲ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਪਉੜੀ ਗੜਿ ਕਿਉ ਚੜਉ ਗੁਰ ਹਰਿ ਧਿਆਨ ਨਿਹਾਲ ॥੨॥ਗੁਰੁ ਪਉੜੀ ਬੇੜੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗੁਰੁ ਤੁਲਹਾ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਉ ॥ਗੁਰੁ ਸਰੁ ਸਾਗਰੁ ਬੋਹਿਥੋ ਗੁਰੁ ਤੀਰਥੁ ਦਰੀਆਉ ॥ਜੇ ਤਿਸੁ ਭਾਵੈ ਊਜਲੀ ਸਤ ਸਰਿ ਨਾਵਣ ਜਾਉ ॥੩॥ਪੂਰੋ ਪੂਰੋ ਆਖੀਐ ਪੂਰੈ ਤਖਤਿ ਨਿਵਾਸ ॥ਪੂਰੈ ਥਾਨਿ ਸੁਹਾਵਣੈ ਪੂਰੈ ਆਸ ਨਿਰਾਸ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਪੂਰਾ ਜੇ ਮਿਲੈ ਕਿਉ ਘਾਟੈ ਗੁਣ ਤਾਸ ॥੪॥੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 17 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਸ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਵਸਾਈ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਕਥਾ ਵਾਰਤਾ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ) ਔਗੁਣ ਹੀ ਔਗੁਣ ਹਨ ਉਹ (ਆਪਣੇ ਹੀ ਔਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਹੇਠ) ਸਦਾ ਝੂਰਦੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ! ਜੇ ਤੂੰ ਖਸਮ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈਂ, ਤਾਂ (ਚੇਤੇ ਰੱਖ ਕਿ) ਕੂੜੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸੇ ਰਿਹਾਂ ਪਤੀ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲ ਸਕਦੀ (ਤੂੰ ਤਾਂ ਮੋਹ ਦੇ ਸਮੰੁਦਰ ਵਿਚ ਗੋਤੇ ਖਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈਂ) ਤੇਰੇ ਪਾਸ ਨਾਹ ਬੇੜੀ ਹੈ, ਨਾਹ ਤੁਲਹਾ ਹੈ, ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਪਤੀ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭ ਸਕਦਾ, (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਉਹ ਤਾਂ (ਇਸ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਰ ਹੈ,) ਦੂਰ ਹੈ ।੧।ਮੇਰੇ ਪਾਲਣਹਾਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਅਹਿੱਲ ਟਿਕਾਣਾ ਉਸ ਤਖ਼ਤ ਉੱਤੇ ਹੈ ਜੇਹੜਾ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਾਂਗ ਹੀ) ਸੰਪੂਰਨ ਹੈ (ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਉਕਾਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ)। ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਤੋਲ-ਮਾਪ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਪੂਰਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਜੇ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰੇ, ਤਾਂ ਹੀ ਉਹ ਮਿਲ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਹਰੀ-ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਮਾਨੋ) ਇਕ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਮੰਦਰ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਮਾਣਕ ਲਾਲ ਮੋਤੀ ਤੇ ਚਮਕਦੇ ਹੀਰੇ ਹਨ (ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਦੁਆਲੇ) ਸੋਨੇ ਦੇ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਕਿਲੇ੍ਹ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਉਸ (ਮੰਦਰ-) ਕਿਲੇ੍ਹ ਉਤੇ ਪਉੜੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਚੜ੍ਹਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ । (ਹਾਂ,) ਜੇ ਗੁਰੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਧਿਆਨ ਧਰਿਆ ਜਾਏ, ਜੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਧਿਆਨ ਧਰਿਆ ਜਾਏ, ਤਾਂ ਦਰਸਨ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਉਸ (ਹਰਿ-ਮੰਦਰ-ਕਿਲੇ੍ਹ ਉੱਤੇ ਚੜ੍ਹਨ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਗੁਰੂ ਪਉੜੀ ਹੈ, (ਇਸ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੰੁਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘਣ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਗੁਰੂ ਬੇੜੀ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ (ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ) ਗੁਰੂ ਹੀ ਤੁਲਹਾ ਹੈ ਗੁਰੂ ਸਰੋਵਰ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਸਮੰੁਦਰ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਹੀ ਜਹਾਜ਼ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਹੀ ਤੀਰਥ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਦਰੀਆ ਹੈ ਜੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਹੋਵੇ, ਤਾਂ (ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ) ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਸ਼ੁੱਧ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਸਰੋਵਰ ਵਿਚ (ਮਾਨਸਕ) ਇਸ਼ਨਾਨ ਕਰਨ ਜਾਣ ਲੱਗ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਹਰ ਕੋਈ ਆਖਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਉਕਾਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਿਵਾਸ ਭੀ ਐਸੇ ਤਖ਼ਤ ਉੱਤੇ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਘਾਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਉਹ ਪੂਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਉਕਾਈ-ਹੀਣ ਥਾਂ ਤੇ ਬੈਠਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਟੁੱਟੇ ਦਿਲਾਂ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਆਸਾਂ ਪੂਰੀਆਂ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਉਹ ਪੂਰਨ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਪਏ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਕੋਈ ਘਾਟ ਆ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ?।੪।੯।\\""},{"question":"प्रदेश सभामा मतदान कसरी हुन्छ ?","answer":"प्रदेश सभामा निर्णयका लागि पेश गरिएका सबै प्रश्नहरूको निर्णय उपस्थित सदस्यहरूको बहुमत र मतदानमा भाग लिनेछ। बैठकको अध्यक्षता गर्ने सदस्यलाई मतदान गर्ने अधिकार हुने छैन ।"},{"question":"How to say 131072 in a casual conversation","answer":"In a casual conversation, you might say \\"one thirty-one thousand seventy-two\\" for the number 131072. This is a more relaxed and less formal way of stating the number."},{"question":"ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’ ਬਾਰੇ ਦਸੋ।ਜਦੋਂ ਵੱਖਰੇ ਵਿਅਕਤਿਤਵ ਵਾਲੇ ਦੋ ਇਨਸਾਨ ਭਾਵਨਾਵਾਂ ‘ਚ ਬਹਿ ਕੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਵਰਗੇ ਅਟੁੱਟ ਬੰਧਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੱਝਦੇ ਹਨ ਤਾਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਰਿਸ਼ਤਾ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਸਮੇਂ ਲਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਟਿਕਟਾ। ਇਸੇ ਮੁੱਦੇ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਨੂੰ ਜਿਊਣਾ ਸਿਖਾਉਣ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਬਿਹਤਰੀਨ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ‘ਚ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਇਮਰਾਨ ਤੇ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਆ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ, ਉੱਥੇ ਸ਼ਕੁਨ ਬਤਰਾ ਦੀ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਵਜੋਂ ਇਹ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਇੱਕ ਡੱਬੂ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੇ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਆਰਕੀਟੇਕਟ ਰਾਹੁਲ (ਇਮਰਾਨ ਖ਼ਾਨ) ਤੇ ਹੇਅਰ ਸਟਾਈਲਿਸਟ ਕ੍ਰਿਸਚੀਅਨ ਕੁੜੀ, ਰਿਆਨਾ ਬ੍ਰਿਗੇਂਜ਼ਾ (ਕਰੀਨਾ ਕਪੂਰ) ਦੇ ਆਲੇ-ਦੁਆਲੇ ਘੁੰਮਦੀ ਹੈ। ਰਾਹੁਲ ਦਾ ਪਾਲਣ-ਪੋਸ਼ਣ ਇੱਕ ਅਲੱਗ ਹੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਾਹੌਲ ‘ਚ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਾਂ-ਬਾਪ ਦੇ ਦਬਾਅ ਹੇਠ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਫ਼ੈਸਲੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਾਂ-ਬਾਪ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਲਏ ਗਏ ਹਨ, ਚਾਹੇ ਉਹ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਦਾ ਸਵਾਲ ਹੋਵੇ, ਖਾਣ-ਪੀਣ ਦਾ ਜਾਂ ਕੱਪੜਾ ਪਹਿਨਣ ਦਾ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਕਦੋਂ ਕੀ ਕਰਨਾ ਹੈ? ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕਰਨੀ ਹੈ? ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਾਂ-ਬਾਪ ਹੀ ਤੈਅ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਦੋਂ ਕਿ ਰਿਆਨਾ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹੇ ਵਿਚਾਰਾਂ ਵਾਲੀ ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੀ ਲੜਕੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੇ ਮਾਅਨੇ ਸਮਝਦੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਜਿਊਣੀ ਹੈ। ਲਾਸ ਵੇਗਾਸ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਬਾਜ਼ਾਰ ‘ਚ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਅਜੀਬੋ-ਗ਼ਰੀਬ ਮਾਹੌਲ ‘ਚ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਤੇ ਰਿਆਨਾ ਦੀ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਜੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ‘ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੇਲ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਤਾਂ ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਕਦੇ ਰਿਆਨਾ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲ ਨਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਪਰ ਮਾਹੌਲ ਹੀ ਕੁਝ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦਾ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਸਿਲਸਿਲਾ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਸ਼ਰਾਬ ਪੀਣ ਬੈਠ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ। ਦਸ ਬਾਰਾਂ ਪੈੱਗ ਪੀ ਜਾਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਸਾਰੀ ਰਾਤ ਨਸ਼ੇ ‘ਚ ਗੁਜ਼ਰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਸਵੇਰੇ ਜਦੋਂ ਨਸ਼ਾ ਉਤਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਤਲਾਕ ਲਈ ਅਦਾਲਤ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਤਲਾਕ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਤਲਾਕ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਬਾਵਜੂਦ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਤੇ ਰਿਆਨਾ ਦੀ ਦੋਸਤੀ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤਾਂ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਰਹਿੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਨਵੇਂ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਰਿਆਨਾ, ਰਾਹੁਲ ਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਜਿਊਣਾ ਸਿਖਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਵਿਅਕਤਿਤਵ ‘ਚ ਭਾਰੀ ਤਬਦੀਲੀ ਲਿਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ।। ਕਰਨ ਜੌਹਰ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’ ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਵੂਡੀ ਏਲਨ ਦੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੈਲੀ ਤੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਿਤ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਸ਼ਕੁਨ ਬਤਰਾ ਨੇ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਤਜਰਬੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਨ। ਉਹ ਵੂਡੀ ਏਲਨ ਦੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਕ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਸ਼ੈਲੀ ਨੂੰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਅਪਨਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।। ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੀਆਂ ਕਈ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ‘ਚ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੇ ਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ‘ਚ ਕੈਮਰਾ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਨਾਲ ਚੱਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁਝ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਹੀ ਦੇਖਣ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲੇਗਾ।ਕੁਛ-ਕੁਛ ਹੋਤਾ ਹੈ, ਕਭੀ-ਖੁਸ਼ੀ ਕਭੀ ਗ਼ਮ, ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਹੋ ਨਾ ਹੋ, ‘ਵੇਕ ਅੱਪ ਸਿਡ’ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਈ ਨੇਮ ਇਜ਼ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਜਿਹੀਆਂ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਕਰਨ ਜੌਹਰ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਪਰੰਪਰਾਗਤ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਸਿਤਾਰਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਜੋੜੀ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਵੀ ਚਰਚਾ ‘ਚ ਹੈ। ਕਰੀਨਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਇਮਾਰਨ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਕਰਨ ਜੌਹਰ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸੋਚ ਸਮਝ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਇਸ ਜੋੜੀ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਦੇ ‘ਤੇ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਕਿ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਵਿਸ਼ੇ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਢੁਕਵਾਂ ਹੈ। ਅਸੀਂ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਲਿਆਉਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਸੀ ਜੋ ਅਸਲੀਅਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਵੱਖਰੇ ਹੋਣ। ਸ਼ਕੁਨ, ਇਮਰਾਨ ਦੇ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਕਰੀਬ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਦੋਸਤੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਸਨ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ  ‘ਵੇਕ ਅੱਪ ਸਿਡ’ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਣਬੀਰ ਕਪੂਰ ਅਤੇ ਕੋਕਨਾ ਸੇਨ ਦੀ ਜੋੜੀ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਹ ਤਜਰਬਾ ਕਰ ਚੱਕੇ ਸਨ। ਕਦੇ-ਕਦੇ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਅਨੋਖੀ ਜੋੜੀ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਦੇ ‘ਤੇ ਦੇਖਣਾ ਮਜ਼ੇਦਾਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ।ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਸ਼ਕੁਨ ਬਤਰਾ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਇੱਕ-ਦੋ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ‘ਚ ਛੋਟੇ ਜਿਹੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਅ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਹਨ। ਸਹਾਇਕ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ‘ਚ ਉਹ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਬਤੌਰ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਇਹ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ। ਸ਼ਕੁਨ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਮਰਾਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਇਨ ਹਾਊਸ ਹੀਰੋ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਜਿੱਥੋਂ ਤਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦਾ ਸਵਾਲ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਸੰਦੇਸ਼ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਦੇਵੇਗੀ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਅਸੀਂ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਮਾਤਾ-ਪਿਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਭਵਿੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਹਰ ਚੀਜ਼ ਜਾਂ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ‘ਤੇ ਥੋਪਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ, ਬਲਕਿ ਬੱਚੇ ਦੀ ਰੁਚੀ ਨੂੰ ਧਿਆਨ ‘ਚ ਰੱਖ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਤ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।ਇਮਰਾਨ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਮਨੋਰੰਜਨ ਭਰਪੂਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ। ਜੇ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਸਬਕ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਵਧੀਆ ਗੱਲ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਮੇਰਾ ਮੰਨਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਦੇਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ, ਮਨੋਰੰਜਨ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਜਾਗਰੂਕਤਾ ਲਿਆਉਣਾ ਹੈ। ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਮੇਰਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਜਬ ਵੂਈ ਸੈੱਟ ਦੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਦਾ-ਜੁਲਦਾ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਬੇਫ਼ਿਕਰ ਕੁੜੀ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹਾਂ, ਜੋ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਨੂੰ ਹਰ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਮਾਨਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਵੇਗੀ। ਇਮਰਾਨ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਰੀ ਕੈਮਿਸਟਰੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਵਧੀਆ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਸ਼ਕੁਨ, ਕਰਨ, ਇਮਰਾਨ ਤੇ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਮੌਲਿਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ। ਜ਼ਿਕਰਯੋਗ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ‘ਚ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਵੱਟ ਹੈਪਨ ਇਨ ਲਾੱਸ ਵੇਗਾਸ’ ਦੀ ਨਕਲ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਚਰਚੇ ਹਨ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਲੈਣ ਦੀ ਸਲਾਹ ਵੀ ਇਮਰਾਨ ਨੇ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ। ਇਮਰਾਨ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਬਚਪਨ ਤੋਂ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੇ ਦੀਵਾਨੇ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਹੁਣ ਤਕ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ, ਕਰੀਨਾ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ‘ਚੋਂ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਖੂਬਸੂਰਤ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਰਫਿਊਜੀ ‘ਚ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖ ਕੇ ਦੀਵਾਨਾ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਖਿੱਚ ਸੀ। ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਅਹਿਸਾਸ ਨੂੰ ਬਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ। ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਹੋਰ ਨੇੜੇ ਤੋਂ ਜਾਣਨ ਦਾ ਮੌਕਾ ਮਿਲਿਆ। ਮੈਂ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੀ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਕੁਝ ਤਸਵੀਰਾਂ ਵੀ ਲਈਆਂ। ਕਰੀਨਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਹਤਰ ਇਹ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਸੀ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਕੌਣ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਕਰਨ ਜੌਹਰ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Bada Tatsuniya Kura da Kare","answer":"Gata nan gata nanaku. Ta zo mu ji ta.Akwai wani mafarauci ana ce da shi Fautaranga, sai wata rana ya je gidan namun daji (dabbobin daji) ya ce da wa za mu farauta? Sai kura ta ce ni, sai ya ce da ita “dama ke nake nema”, sai suka tafi tare da kura. Suna cikin tafiya sai kura ta ce da shi tana jin yunwa, sai ya ce da ita ta bari sai sun ƙara gaba zai bata abinci.Suna cikin tafiya sai suka isa wani kogi, sai ya ce da ita ta sha ruwa iya shanta. Da ta sha ta ƙoshi, sai shi kuma ya kafa bakinsa ya shanye dukkan ruwan kogin. Bayan ya shanye sai suka ɗebo kifayen cikin kogin suka cinye. Suna nan har dare ya yi, saboda haka da za su kwanta barci sai Fautaranga ya ce da kura “kar ki kwanta a bayana ina tusar ƙashi” sai kura ta ce bata yarda ba sai ta kwanta. Suna kwance can cikin dare sai kura ta ji ƙashi ya zo ya cake ta ya koma, sai ta tashi ta koma gabansa ta kwanta, da ta kwanta sai da gari ya waye sai kura ta ce da shi ashe dama abin da ka faɗa gaskiya ne ba ƙarya ba?Daga nan sai ya ce da kura yanzu za mu je wajen wasu giwaye guda goma, idan mun je ki zage su, idan suka biyo ki sai ki yi tsalle ki faɗa cikin cikina. Da suka je sai kura ta zagi giwayen nan, da suka biyo ta da gudu sai ta yi tsalle ta faɗa cikin Fautaranga. Shi kuma sai ya kama giwayen nan ɗaya-bayan-ɗaya ya yayyanka su.Kura kuma daga cikin maharbin nan sai ta wuce hancinsa ta taras da kasuwa tana ci a ciki, a cikin kasuwar sai ta je gurin mai tsire ta ce da shi za ta yi masa talla, sai ya ɗora mata tallar a faranti. Can sai Fautaranga ya kira kura ya ce “kura”, ya ji shiru, ya sake cewa “kura”, ya ji shiru, sai ya fyato ta (kamar yadda ake fyace majina) da farantin talla a kanta, da ya ga haka sai ya ce da kura ta je ta mayar da faranti ta fito su tafi.Sai kura ta mayar da farantin, shi kuma mai tsire ya bata tsire ladar talla, da kura ta karɓa sai ta zauna ta cinye tsiren, bayan ta cinye sai ta fito suka ƙara gaba.Da za su tafi sai aka ɗorawa kura cinyar giwa ta kasa tafiya, sai ya ɗauka ya raba shi kashi uku ya ɗora mata kaso ɗaya, shi kuma ya ɗauki dukkan sauran. Daga nan sai suka tafi gida.Da suka iso gida sai ya bata kasonta ya ce ta je ta soya ta ci. Da ta soya ta ji daɗi, sai ta kira kare ta ce su zo su koma farautar, sai ta je aka haɗa mata hancin laka. Suna cikin tafiya sai kare ya ga zomo, da ya ga zomon sai ya ce da kura in ɗauka? Sai kura ta yi masa shiru, shi kuma sai ya faki idonta ya ɗauka ya jefa a ruzu.Bayan sun yi doguwar tafiya, sai kare ya ce da kura yana jin ƙishirwa, sai suka je kogin da suka sha ruwa da Fautaranga, sai kura ta ce da kare ya sha iya shansa, kare ya sha, daga nan sai kura ta kafa kanta ta kasa shanye ruwan wannan kogi, da ta kasa sai kare ya ce da ita ya kika kasa shanyewa? Sai ta ce ai yanzu bana jin ƙishirwa. Sai kura ta ce da kare su shiga su kamo kifi, bayan da suka samu ɗan abin da suka samu, sai kura ta ce su ci gaba. Suna cikin daji dare ya yi musu, sai kura ta ce da kare “kar ka kwanta a bayana ina tusar ƙashi”, sai kare ya kwanta, har gari ya waye kura bata yi tusa ba. Sai kare ya tambayeta ya aka yi baki yi tusar ƙashin ba? Sai kura ta ce ai yau bata ci abinci ba shi ya saka. Daga nan sai ta ce da shi za su je wajen wasu giwaye, idan sun je kare ya tsokano giwayen nan idan sun biyo shi ya yi tsalle ya faɗa cikin hancinta.Da suka isa sai kare ya tsokani giwaye, da suka biyo shi sai ya yi tsalle ya dira a kan hancin kura (hancin taɓo), sai hancin ya ruguje, daga nan sai kura ta ce kowa ya yi ta kansa, ka bi ta tudu na bi ta gangare. Da suka iso gida sai kura ta je gurin Fautaranga ta gaya masa cewa sun je wajen giwayen nan amma sun biyo su da gudu. Sai ya ce da ita, me ya hana ki zuwa ki karɓi magani a wajena kafin ku tafi?Daga nan sai kare da kura kowa ya kama gabansa, da suka isa gidajensu sai kare ya ɗauko zomon nan ya fara suya, da kura ta ji ƙanshi sai ta laɓaɓo gidan kare ta taras da shi yana suya. Sai kura ta tambaye shi ta ce “kai kuma wa ya baka nama ka ke soyawa?” Sai kare ya ce da ita suya aka bashi idan ya gama ya suɗe kaskon. Sai ta ce da shi tana son naman idan kuma ya hanata ta cinye shi duka shi da naman. Sai ta ce za ta je ta dawo kafin ya gama.Fitar kura ke da wuya sai kare ya je ya ɓoye naman nan a ɗaki, sai ya suɗe kaskon ya tofa yawu da majina a ciki, ya soya, ya ajiye. Da kura ta dawo sai ya bata sai ta suɗe, sai ta ce “kare wannan naman da daɗi idan aka baka zaka bani?” Sai ya amsa mata da cewa ai tuni aka bashi ya cinye.Tunƙurunƙus, badan Gizo ba da na yi ƙarya."},{"question":"ഭൂകമ്പങ്ങളുടെ തീവ്രതയുടെ വിഭജനം അനുസരിച്ച്, പ്രതിവർഷം ഉണ്ടാകുന്ന 10,000 ഭൂകമ്പങ്ങളിൽ 1994 ലെ ഭൂകമ്പം എത്ര ശതമാനം ഉൾപ്പെടുത്തിയിട്ടുണ്ട്? മേൽപ്പറഞ്ഞ ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഒരു ഖണ്ഡിക എഴുതുക. അത് 1 - 20 വാക്യങ്ങളാകാം. പശ്ചാത്തലം:","answer":"ഓരോ വർഷവും തെക്കൻ കാലിഫോർണിയ മേഖലയിൽ 10,000 ഭൂകമ്പങ്ങൾ ഉണ്ടാകാറുണ്ട്. മിക്കവാറും എല്ലാ അവയവങ്ങളും വളരെ ചെറുതാണ്, അവ അനുഭവപ്പെടുന്നില്ല. ഏതാനും നൂറുകണക്കിന് എണ്ണങ്ങൾ മാത്രമാണ് 3.0 മാഗ്നിറ്റ്യൂഡിനേക്കാൾ വലുത്, ഏകദേശം 15-20 എണ്ണങ്ങൾ മാത്രമാണ് 4.0 മാഗ്നിറ്റ്യൂഡിനേക്കാൾ വലുത്. 1994 ലെ 6.7 തീവ്രതയുള്ള നോർത്ത്രിഡ്ജ് ഭൂകമ്പം പ്രത്യേകിച്ചും വിനാശകരമായിരുന്നു, ഇത് ധാരാളം മരണങ്ങൾക്കും പരിക്കുകൾക്കും ഘടനാപരമായ തകർച്ചകൾക്കും കാരണമായി. അമേരിക്കൻ ചരിത്രത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും വലിയ ഭൂകമ്പം, 20 ബില്യൺ ഡോളറിലധികം നാശനഷ്ടം."},{"question":"Inona ary izany: tsy ray tsy reny ka iantsapatsapazana?","answer":"Ny valiny dia: fandriana"},{"question":"බාලදක්ෂ ව්‍යාපාරයේ පියා කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"බේඩ්න් පවල් සාමි"},{"question":"Inona no lokon'ny ràn'ny horinta na amin'ny teny frantsay hoe pieuvre ?1- mena2- manga3- mavo","answer":"2- manga . Tsy mena tahaka ny an' ireo biby mampinono hafa ny lokon'ny ràn'ny horinta ."},{"question":"fenoy ny banga:\\"Tafita vao rendrika toy _\\"","answer":"\\"Tafita vao rendrika toy ny boka milomano\\""},{"question":"Wọn dana sun afurasi adigunjale pẹlu ọkada rẹ n’Ilọrin","answer":"Afurasi adigunjale jale kan pade iku airotẹlẹ lalẹ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, lagbegbe Maraba, niluu Ilọrin.Ọkunrin ti ko sẹni to mọ orukọ rẹ, lawọn ọdọ kan ya bo, Wọn kọkọ dana sun ọkada rẹ, lẹyin naa ni wọn gba ti i. Bi wọn ṣe da igi bo o ni wọn n ju nnkan mọ ọn titi ti ko fi le dide.Kawọn eeyan too mọ ohun to n ṣẹlẹ, wọn ti gbe taya ati epo bẹntiroolu de, loju-ẹsẹ ni wọn ju u si i lọrun, ti wọn si kana lu u.Alukoro ọlọpaa ni Kwara, Ajayi Ọkasanmi, ni ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ṣi n ṣewadii iṣẹlẹ naa."},{"question":"ප්‍රභාසංශ්ලේෂණ ආධාරයෙන් ශාක තමන්ගේම ආහාර සාදයි.","answer":"සැබෑ"},{"question":"Mas matangkad si John kay Jason. Mas matangkad si Rebecca kay Jason. Si Sara ay mas matangkad kay John. Si Beverly ay mas maikli kay Rebecca at mas matangkad kay Sara. Ilagay ang lahat ng tao sa pagkakasunud-sunod ng kanilang taas.","answer":"Ang pagkakasunod-sunod mula sa pinakamatangkad hanggang sa pinakamababa ay: Rebecca, Beverly, Sara, John, at Jason"},{"question":"राज्यातील बस स्थानक स्वच्छ सर्वेक्षणात A वर्गात कोणत्या बसस्थानकाने प्रथम क्रमांक पटकावला आहे?(A)  जिंतूर(B)  चोपडा(C)  बारामती(D)  जामनेर","answer":"(B) चोपडा"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Aza ny fahantrako no jerena, ............................................  \\" ","answer":"\\"  Aza ny fahantrako no jerena,fa ny toe-tsaina hananako. \\" "},{"question":"Кыргызстандагы акыркы эң оор жер титирөө кайсы жерде болгон?","answer":"Кыргызстанда эң чоң жоготууга жана кыйроого алып келген акыркы жер титирөө 2008-жылдын октябрында Ош облусунун Алай районуна караштуу Нура айылында болуп, 75 адамдын өмүрүн алып кеткен эле."},{"question":"පහත ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළේ අර්ථය කුමක්ද ? \\"අතේ ඉන්න එක කුරුල්ලා‍ පදුරෙ ඉන්නා දහයකට වඩාවටී\\"","answer":"තමා  ලග තිබෙන සුළු දෙයක් වුවද අනුන් ලග තිබෙන විශාල දෙයට වඩා වටිනා බව"},{"question":"පුරාවිද්‍යාඥයන් ඩයිනෝසරයන් හාරනවාද?","answer":"නැහැ, පුරාවිද්‍යාඥයන් ඩයිනෝසරයන් හාරන්නේ නැහැ. ඔවුන් මානව සංස්කෘතිය අධ්‍යයනය කරයි; එබැවින් ඔවුන් මිනිස් වාඩිලෑමට අදාළ ස්ථාන හාරති."},{"question":"ග්‍රීසියේ මූලික භූගෝලීය ලක්ෂණය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ග්‍රීසියේ ප්‍රධාන භූගෝලීය ලක්ෂණයක් වන්නේ එහි කඳුකර භූමි ප්‍රදේශයයි. රටෙන් 80% ක් පමණ කඳු සහිත වන අතර, පින්ඩස් සහ රෝඩෝප් වැනි කැපී පෙනෙන කඳු වැටි ඇත. කඳුකරය ග්‍රීක සංස්කෘතියේ සහ ඉතිහාසයෙහි වර්ධනයට සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස බලපා ඇති අතර, බොහෝ විට ප්‍රජාවන් හුදකලා කරමින් පුරාණ කාලයේ ස්වාධීන නගර රාජ්‍යයන් පිහිටුවීමට මඟ පෑදී ඇත.මීට අමතරව, ග්‍රීසිය එහි පුළුල් වෙරළ තීරය සහ බොහෝ දූපත් සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධය. රට පිහිටා ඇත්තේ බෝල්කන් අර්ධද්වීපයේ දකුණු කෙළවරේ වන අතර බටහිරින් අයෝනියන් මුහුදෙන් ද දකුණින් මධ්‍යධරණී මුහුදෙන් ද නැගෙනහිරින් ඒජියන් මුහුදෙන් ද වටවී ඇත. සුප්‍රසිද්ධ ග්‍රීක දූපත් සමහරක් ක්‍රීට්, රෝඩ්ස්, මයිකොනොස් සහ සැන්ටෝරිනි ඇතුළත් වේ."},{"question":"Cad a dhéanann conraitheoir? ","answer":"Is éard atá i gconraitheoir ná duine a íoctar chun seirbhísí a sholáthar i méid ama comhaontaithe agus faoi shraith sonrach dálaí."},{"question":"Jawablah pertanyaan berikut berdasarkan konteks cerita rakyat di bawah ini:Konteks cerita: Jaka Tarub merupakan cerita rakyat yang terkenal dan bahkan diabadikan dalam naskah populer Sastra Jawa Baru berjudul Babad Tanah Jawi. Cerita rakyat ini mengisahkan tentang seorang pemuda yang mencuri selendang salah satu dari tujuh bidadari kayangan ketika mereka mandi di hutan. Bidadari yang kehilangan selendangnya pun tidak bisa kembali ke kayangan dan menikah dengan Jaka Tarub. Namun, ketika mereka sudah memiliki anak, terungkaplah bahwa Jaka Tarub adalah seorang pencuri. Bidadari tersebut merasa sedih dan sakit hati. Ia meminta selendang tersebut dikembalikan agar ia bisa kembali ke kayangan.Siapa tokoh dalam cerita rakyat di atas?Jawaban:","answer":"Tokoh atau karakter dalam cuplikan dongeng atau cerita rakyat di atas ada dua, yaitu: Jaka Tarub dan Bidadari yang menjadi istri Jaka Tarub."},{"question":"Indro misy fehezanteny:Hoy i RAHAJARIZAFY:  “ Lahatra avy amin-Janahary no ahataperan’ny andron’ny olona eto an-tany”Manomeza fanontaniana azo apetraka momba io fehezanteny io.","answer":"Indro misy fanontaniana azo apetraka momba io fehezanteny io:"},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：什么是印度古典音乐？","answer":"答案：印度古典音乐是印度传统音乐的一种形式，以其丰富的旋律、复杂的节奏和情感表达而著名。它通常使用乐器如坚果、塔巴拉、斯坦巴和声乐来演奏。"},{"question":"నిలిపి ఉంచిన ఆర్జనలు గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"సాధారణముగా ఒక కంపెనీ ఆర్జించిన లాభము మొత్తాన్ని వాటాదారులకు డివిడెండ్గా పంచరు. కొంత మొత్తాన్ని భవిష్యత్ అవసరాలకు వేరుగా ఉంచుతారు. ఈ మొత్తాన్ని నిలిపి ఉంచిన ఆర్జనలు అంటారు. కంపెనీ అంతర్గత ఆర్థిక వనరులలో ఇది చాలా ముఖ్యమైనది. ఈ విధముగా లాభాల నుంచి రిజర్వు నిధిగా ఏర్పరచిన మొత్తాన్ని మూలధన వనరులుగా వినియోగించడాన్ని ‘లాభాల పునరాకర్షణ’ అంటారు."},{"question":"问题：韩国有哪些世界遗产？","answer":"答案：韩国有许多世界遗产，如庆州市的景福宫和金刚山的智圆寺等。"},{"question":"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ ਹਉਮੈ ਕਰਮ ਕਮਾਵਦੇ ਜਮਡੰਡੁ ਲਗੈ ਤਿਨ ਆਇ ॥ ਜਿ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਨਿ ਸੇ ਉਬਰੇ ਹਰਿ ਸੇਤੀ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਮਨ ਰੇ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇ ॥ ਧੁਰਿ ਪੂਰਬਿ ਕਰਤੈ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਤਿਨਾ ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਨਾਮਿ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ ਵਿਣੁ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪਰਤੀਤਿ ਨ ਆਵਈ ਨਾਮਿ ਨ ਲਾਗੋ ਭਾਉ ॥ ਸੁਪਨੈ ਸੁਖੁ ਨ ਪਾਵਈ ਦੁਖ ਮਹਿ ਸਵੈ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੨॥ ਜੇ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਕੀਚੈ ਬਹੁਤੁ ਲੋਚੀਐ ਕਿਰਤੁ ਨ ਮੇਟਿਆ ਜਾਇ ॥ ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਭਾਣਾ ਭਗਤੀ ਮੰਨਿਆ ਸੇ ਭਗਤ ਪਏ ਦਰਿ ਥਾਇ ॥੩॥ ਗੁਰੁ ਸਬਦੁ ਦਿੜਾਵੈ ਰੰਗ ਸਿਉ ਬਿਨੁ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਲਇਆ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ ਜੇ ਸਉ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਨੀਰੀਐ ਭੀ ਬਿਖੁ ਫਲੁ ਲਾਗੈ ਧਾਇ ॥੪॥ ਸੇ ਜਨ ਸਚੇ ਨਿਰਮਲੇ ਜਿਨ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਨਾਲਿ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਕਾ ਭਾਣਾ ਕਮਾਵਦੇ ਬਿਖੁ ਹਉਮੈ ਤਜਿ ਵਿਕਾਰੁ ॥੫॥ ਮਨਹਠਿ ਕਿਤੈ ਉਪਾਇ ਨ ਛੂਟੀਐ ਸਿਮ੍ਰਿਤਿ ਸਾਸਤ੍ਰ ਸੋਧਹੁ ਜਾਇ ॥ ਮਿਲਿ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਸਾਧੂ ਉਬਰੇ ਗੁਰ ਕਾ ਸਬਦੁ ਕਮਾਇ ॥੬॥ ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਨਿਧਾਨੁ ਹੈ ਜਿਸੁ ਅੰਤੁ ਨ ਪਾਰਾਵਾਰੁ ॥ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸੇਈ ਸੋਹਦੇ ਜਿਨ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰੇ ਕਰਤਾਰੁ ॥੭॥ ਨਾਨਕ ਦਾਤਾ ਏਕੁ ਹੈ ਦੂਜਾ ਅਉਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਇ ॥ ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੀ ਪਾਈਐ ਕਰਮਿ ਪਰਾਪਤਿ ਹੋਇ ॥੮॥੨॥੧੯॥","answer":"ਹੇ (ਮੇਰੇ) ਮਨ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ। (ਨਾਮ ਬੜੀ ਦੁਰਲੱਭ ਦਾਤਿ ਹੈ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਤੇ ਤੁਰ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਹੀ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ) ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨਤਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਕਰਤਾਰ ਨੇ ਧੁਰੋਂ ਹੀ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਜਨਮ ਦੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਨੇਕ ਕਮਾਈ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਲੇਖ ਲਿਖ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ।1। ਰਹਾਉ।ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਕੋਈ ਮਿਥੇ ਹੋਏ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ) ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ (ਤੇ ਇਹ) ਹਉਮੈ (ਭੀ) ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ (ਕਿ ਅਸੀਂ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਾਂ) , ਉਹਨਾਂ (ਦੇ ਸਿਰ) ਉੱਤੇ ਜਮ ਦਾ ਡੰਡਾ ਆ ਕੇ ਵੱਜਦਾ ਹੈ। (ਪਰ) ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (-ਚਰਨਾਂ) ਵਿਚ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ (ਇਸ ਮਾਰ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ।1।ਗੁਰੂ (ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ) ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਸਰਧਾ ਪੈਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ, ਨਾਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਨਤੀਜਾ ਇਹ ਨਿਕਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ) ਸੁਪਨੇ ਵਿਚ ਵੀ ਸੁਖ ਨਸੀਬ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਘਿਰਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ।2।(ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਜੇ ਇਹ ਬੜੀ ਤਾਂਘ ਭੀ ਕਰੀਏ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰੇ (ਤਾਂ ਭੀ ਇਸ ਤਾਂਘ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਨਾ ਵਿਚ ਸਫਲਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ, ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਜਨਮਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਕੀਤੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਮਿਟਾਇਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ। ਭਗਤ ਜਨ ਹੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਵਾਨ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਭਗਤ ਹੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਕਬੂਲ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ।3।ਗੁਰੂ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਨਾਲ (ਆਪਣਾ) ਸ਼ਬਦ (ਸਰਨ ਆਏ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ) ਪੱਕਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ (ਗੁਰੂ ਭੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ) ਕਿਰਪਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ। (ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਬੇਮੁਖ ਮਨੁੱਖ, ਮਾਨੋ, ਇਕ ਐਸਾ ਰੁੱਖ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਜੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੌ ਵਾਰੀ ਭੀ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਸਿੰਜੀਏ ਤਾਂ ਭੀ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਹਰ ਦਾ ਫਲ ਹੀ ਛੇਤੀ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ।4।ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ (ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ) ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਹਉਮੈ ਦਾ ਜ਼ਹਰ ਹਉਮੈ ਦਾ ਵਿਕਾਰ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਜੀਵਨ ਬਿਤਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ।5।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਬੇ-ਸ਼ੱਕ ਤੁਸੀ ਸ਼ਾਸਤ੍ਰਾਂ ਸਿਮ੍ਰਿਤੀਆਂ (ਆਦਿਕ ਧਰਮ ਪੁਸਤਕਾਂ) ਨੂੰ ਗਹੁ ਨਾਲ ਪੜ੍ਹ ਕੇ ਵੇਖ ਲਵੋ, ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਹਠ ਨਾਲ ਕੀਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਕਿਸੇ ਭੀ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ (ਹਉਮੈ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਹਰ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕੀਦਾ। ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਜੀਵਨ ਬਣਾ ਕੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਹੀ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਰ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚਦੇ ਹਨ।6।ਜਿਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਅੰਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈ ਸਕਦਾ, ਜਿਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਹਸਤੀ ਦਾ ਉਰਲਾ ਪਾਰਲਾ ਬੰਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭ ਸਕਦਾ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ (ਸਭ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਦਾ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ) ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਇਹ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ) ਸੋਹਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬਣਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ।7।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਗੁਰੂ ਹੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ) ਦਾਤਿ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਨਹੀਂ (ਜੋ ਇਹ ਦਾਤਿ ਦੇ ਸਕੇ। ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਸ਼ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ।8।2।19।"},{"question":"Nakasabit ako sa iyong dingding at nagpapakita sa iyo ng mga cartoons. Ano ako?","answer":"Ako ay isang telebisyon."},{"question":"Unsay ngalan sa dulaang cowboy sa Toy Story? ","answer":"Woody"},{"question":"தெற்கு ஆசியாவின் சாக்ரடீஸ் என்று பட்டம் வழங்கப்பட்ட நாள் ……………… ஆகும்.அ) 26.05.1970ஆ) 26.07.1970இ) 24.06.1970ஈ) 27.06.1970","answer":"ஈ) 27.06.1970"},{"question":"Danutė Domikaitytė 2020 m. tapo pirmąja moterimi per Lietuvos istoriją, Europos čempionate iškovojusia bronzos medalį šioje sporto šakoje. Kokia tai sporto šaka? Vyrai sportininkai joje skirtingais metais yra iškovoję du olimpinius medalius, vieną sidabro ir vieną bronzos.","answer":"Ši sporto šaka yra imtynės."},{"question":"請用簡潔的語言回答以下問題：問題：臨床心理學如何幫助人們應對創傷經歷？","answer":"答案：臨床心理學通過創傷後心理治療、心理支持和應對策略教育等方式幫助人們應對創傷經歷。"},{"question":"கேள்வி:மகாகவி பாரதியாரைப் பற்றி சில வரிகள் எழுதுங்கள்?","answer":"பதில்:நவீன தமிழ் கவிதைகளுக்கு தகப்பன் தான் நம் மீசை கவிஞ்சன் பாரதி. தமிழ், தமிழர் நலன், பெண் விடுதலை, தீண்டாமை போன்றவற்றிற்காக ஒரு நூற்றண்டிற்கு முன்னரே தன் கவிதையால் உரக்க கதியவன் தான் நம் தேசிய கவிஞன். மகாகவி சுப்ரமணிய பாரதியார் ஒரு கவிஞனாக மட்டும் இல்லாமல் ஒரு சிறந்த எழுத்தாளராகவும், நல்ல பத்திரிக்கையாசிரிராகவும் இருந்தவர். “பட்டங்கள் ஆள்வதும் சட்டங்கள் செய்வதும் பாரினில் பெண்கள் நடத்த வந்தோம்” என்று பெண்ணுரிமைக்காக பாடியவரும் இவர் தான், “சாதிகள் இல்லையடி பாப்பா; குலத் தாழ்ச்சி உயர்ச்சி சொல்லல் பாவம்;” என்று தீண்டாமை ஒழிப்பு குறித்து பாடியவரும் இவர் தான். தம் எழுத்துக்கள் மூலமாக மக்களின் மனதில் விடுதலை உணர்வை ஊட்டிய நம் முண்டாசு கவிஞ்சன் பாரதியாரின் வாழ்க்கை வரலாறை பற்றி இங்கு காண்போம் வாருங்கள். மகாகவி பாரதியார் பெயர் சுப்பையா (எ) சுப்பிரமணியன் பிறப்பு டிசம்பர் 11, 1882 பிறந்த இடம் எட்டயபுரம், தமிழ்நாடு மற்ற பெயர்கள் முண்டாசுக் கவிஞன், சக்தி தாசன், பாரதியார், மகாகவி இருப்பிடம் திருவல்லிக்கேணி, சென்னை பணி கவிஞர், எழுத்தாளர், விடுதலை போராட்ட வீரர், பத்திரிக்கையாசிரியர் பெற்றோர் சின்னசாமி ஐயர், இலக்குமி அம்மாள் துணைவியார் பெயர் செல்லம்மாள் பிள்ளைகள் தங்கம்மாள், சகுந்தலா முக்கிய படைப்புகள் கண்ணன் பாட்டு, குயில் பாட்டு. பாஞ்சாலி சபதம் மற்றும் பல சமயம் இந்து இறப்பு செப்டம்பர் 11, 1921 பாரதியார் பிறப்பு மகாகவி பாரதியார், சின்னசாமி ஐயருக்கும், இலட்சுமி அம்மாளுக்கும், 1882 ஆம் ஆண்டு, டிசம்பர் மாதம் 11 ஆம் தேதி , திருநெல்வேலி மாவட்டத்திலுள்ள எட்டயபுரத்தில் மகனாக பிறந்தார். அவருக்கு தம் பெற்றோரோர் இட்ட பெயர் சுப்பிரமணி.பாரதியார் இளமை பருவம் 5 வயதிலேயே தன் தாயை இழந்த பாரதியார், ஏழு வயது முதலே கவிதையால் கர்ஜிக்க தொடங்கினார். இவருக்கு 11 வயது இருக்கும்போது இவரது கவி பாடும் ஆற்றலையும் புலமையையும் பாராட்டி இவருக்கு பாரதி என்ற பட்டத்தை வழங்கினார் எட்டயபுர மன்னர். அன்றில் இருந்து இவர் பெயர் சுப்பிரமணிய பாரதியார் என்றானது. திருநெல்வேலியில் உள்ள இந்து கல்லூரியில் 9 ஆம் வகுப்பு வரை படித்த பாரதியார், அப்போதே தமிழ் அறிஞ்சுகளோடும், பண்டிதர்களோடும் சொற் போரில் சுதந்திரமாக ஈடுபட்டார். அதனால் அவரின் தமிழ் புலமை மேலும் அதிகரித்தது. அன்றைய திருநெல்வேலி சீமையில் வசித்த பலர் இவரின் புலமையை கண்டு வியக்க துவங்கினர் பாரதியார் திருமண வாழ்க்கை 1897 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூன் மாதம் 15 ஆம் தேதி பாரதி தம் வாழ்நாளில் மறக்க முடியாத தேதியாக மாறியது. 14 வயது மட்டுமே நிறைவடைந்த அவருக்கு 7 வயது சிறுமியான செல்லம்மாளோடு நடந்தேறியது பாலியல் திருமணம். இது போன்ற தவறுகள் இனி நடக்கவே கூடாது என்று அவர் அப்போது எண்ணினார் என்னவோ தெரியவில்லை. பின்னாளில் தன் கவிதைகள் மூலம் பாலியல் திருமணத்திற்கு எதிராக பொங்கி எழுந்தார் மகாகவி பாரதியார். பாரதியார் கற்ற மொழிகள் 16 வயதில் தன் தந்தையையும் இழந்த பாரதியார் அதன் பிறகு வறுமையில் வடித் தவித்தார். பிறகு எப்படியோ கஷ்டப்பட்டு காசிக்கு சென்று அலகாபாத் பல்கலை கழகத்தில் சம்ஸ்கிருத மொழியையும், இந்தி மொழியையும் கற்றறிந்த. இது தவிர ஆங்கிலம், வங்காளம் போன்ற பிற மொழிகளிலும் தனிப் புலமை பெற்று விளங்கினார் பாரதியார். இத்தனை மொழிகளில் புலமை பெற்றதால் தான், “யாம் அறிந்த மொழிகளிலே தமிழ்மொழி போல் இனிதாவது எங்கும் காணோம்” என்று தெளிவாக சொன்னார் மகா கவி பாரதியார்.  பாரதியார் செய்த பணி 4 ஆண்டுகள் காசியில் இருந்துவிட்டு தமிழகம் திரும்பினார் பாரதியார். பிறகு எட்டயபுர மன்னரின் அழைப்பை ஏற்று அரசவை கவிஞ்சராக பணியாற்றினார். அழகிய தமிழ் கவிதைகள் பலவற்றிற்கு சொந்தக்காரரான பாரதியாரின் எழுத்துக்கள் முதல் முதலில் 1903 ஆண்டு அச்சில் வந்தது. அதன் பிறகு மதுரை சேதுபதி பள்ளியில் தமிழ் ஆசிரியராக பணியாற்றினார் பாரதியார். பிறகு சுதேயசிய மித்திரன் பத்திரிகையின் துணை ஆசிரியராக பொறுப்பேற்றார். இந்திய விடுதைலை போராட்டத்தில் பாரதியார் ஆற்றிய பணி தன்னுடைய தீராத சுதந்திர தாகத்தை தணிக்க 1905 ஆண்டு முதல் அரசியலில் ஆர்வம் காட்டினார் மகாகவி பாரதியார். அதன் பிறகு கப்பல் ஓட்டிய தமிழன் வ.உ சிதம்பரம் பிள்ளை போன்றோரோடு நெருங்கிய தொடர்ப்பு ஏற்பட்டது. அதன் பிறகு கல்கத்தாவில் தாதாபாய் நவ்ரோஜி தலைமையில் நடைபெற்ற மகா சபை கூட்டத்திலும் கலந்து கொண்டார். அப்போது சுவாமி விவேகானந்தரின் சிஷ்யர் நிவேதிக்கா தேவியை சந்திக்கும் வாய்ப்பு அவருக்கு கிடைத்தது. அவரிடம் ஆசி பெற்ற பாரதியார், அவரை தம் ஞயான குருவாக ஏற்றுக்கொண்டார். 1907 ஆம் ஆண்டில் “இந்தியா” என்னும் வார ஏட்டையும் “பால பாரதம்” என்ற ஆங்கில இதழையும் பொறுப்பேற்று நடத்தினார் பாரதியார். இந்தியா விடுதலை போராட்டத்தில் பாரதியார் தீவிரமாக ஈடுபட துவங்கினார். தாம் ஆசிரியராக இருந்த இந்தியா என்னும் பத்திரிகையை விடுதலைக்காக பயன்படுத்தினார். சுதந்திரப் போராட்டத்தில், பாரதியாரின் பாடல்கள் காட்டுத்தீயாய் பரவி தமிழர்களை வீறுகொள்ள செய்தது. கத்தியின்றி ரத்தமின்றி  யுத்தமொன்று வருகுது சத்தியத்தின் நித்தியத்தை நம்பும்யாரும் சேருவீர்  என்று நெருப்பு கனலாய் கொந்தளித்தார் மகாகவி பாரதியார். பாரதியாருக்கு கைது வாரென்ட் பாரதியாரின் சுதந்திர எழுச்சி மிக்க பாடல்களும் கேலி சித்திரங்களும் சுதந்திர போராட்டத்திற்கு கை கொடுத்து வழி நடத்தியது. இதனால் “இந்தியா” பத்திரிகை மீது பிரிட்டிஷ் அரசின் பார்வை விழுந்தது. மேலும் பாரதியாருக்கு கைது வாரென்ட் பிறப்பித்ததாக தகவல் வந்தது. அதனால் தன் நண்பர்களின் வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க பிரெஞ்சு நாட்டின் ஆதிக்கத்தில் இருந்த பாண்டிச்சேரியில் தலைமறைவாக வாழ்ந்தார் பாரதியார். 1908 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் “இந்தியா” பத்திரிக்கை புதுவையில் இருந்து வெளி வர துவங்கியது. தன் பேணா எழுத்துக்கள் மூலம் பெரும் புரட்சியை ஏற்படுத்திக்கொண்டிருந்தார் பாரதியார். அவரது பத்திரிக்கை பிரச்சாரத்திற்கு பெரும் வரவேற்பு கிடைத்தது. பத்திரிகையின் செல்வாக்கும் படிப் படியாக அதிகரித்தது. இதனை கவனித்த பிரிட்டிஷ் அரசு, அந்த பத்திரிகையை படிக்க தடை விதித்தது. இதனால் சென்னையில் பிறந்து புதுவையில் வளர்ந்த “இந்தியா” பத்திரிகையும் பாதை அறியாது பாதியில் நின்றது. புதுவையில் பாரதியாரின் கவிதை பத்திரிக்கை முடங்கியதே தவிர பாரதியாரின் புலமை முடங்கவில்லை. அந்த காலகட்டத்தில் தான், கண்ணன் பாட்டு, குயில் பாட்டு, பாஞ்சாலியின் சபதம் போன்ற அமர கவிதைகள் பலவற்றை இயற்றினார் பாரதியார். அதோடு 1912 ஆம் ஆண்டு பகவத் கீதையை தமிழ் மொழியில் மொழி பெயர்த்து வெளியிட்டார் பாரதியார். பாரதியார் கைது 1918 ஆம் ஆண்டு பாண்டிச்சேரியில் இருந்து வெளி ஏறி பிரிட்டிஷ் எல்லையில் காலடி எடுத்து வைத்த உடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார் பாரதியார். 34 நாட்கள் சிறையில் வைக்கப்பட்டு பிறகு விடுதலை செய்யப்பட்டார் பாரதியார். விடுதலையானதும் தம் மனைவியின் ஊரான கடையம் என்னும் ஊரில் குடியேறினார். அடுத்த இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளையும் கடயத்திலேயே செலவிட்டார். வறுமையில் பாரதியார் கடையதில் இருந்த காலகட்டத்தில் பாரதியாரை வறுமை மீண்டும் சூழ்ந்துகொண்டது. தம் நிலையை விளக்கி சீட்டு கவிதை ஒன்றை எட்டயபுர மன்னருக்கு அனுப்பினார் பாரதியார். அனால் மன்னரிடமிருந்தும் எதிர் பார்த்த உதவி கிடைக்கவில்லை. உலகில் எல்லா உயிரினங்களும் பசியில்லாமல் வாழவேண்டும் என்ற எண்ணம் பாரதியாரிடம் அந்த வறுமை காலத்திலும் மேலோங்கி இருந்தது. வீட்டில் தன் மனைவி சமைக்க வைத்திருக்கும் சிறிதளவு அரிசியை கூட காக்கைக்கும் குருவிகளுக்கு வாரி இறைத்து விட்டு, தான் பசியோடு வாழ்ந்த நாட்கள் ஏறலாம். இத்தகையை உணர்வுள்ள ஒருவரால் தான், “தனி ஒரு மனிதனுக்கு உணவில்லை எனில் இந்த ஜகத்தினை அழித்திடுவோம்” என்று கவி பாட முடியும். வறுமையில் கூட தன்மானத்தோடு தான் வாழ்ந்தார் அந்த புரட்சி தமிழன். பொதுவாக கொடுக்கிற கை மேலேயும் வாங்குகிற கை கீழேயும் இருக்கும். ஆனால் அந்த இலக்கணத்தையும் மாற்றினார் நம் தேசிய கவி. ஒருமுறை தன்னுடைய பணக்கார நண்பர் ஒருவர், தட்டில் பணத்தையும் பட்டாடையையும் வைத்து பாரதியாரிடம் கொடுத்தாராம். ஆனால் பாரதியோ, தட்டை உம்மிடமே வைத்துக்கொள் என்று கூறி , தமது கைகளால் அந்த தட்டில் இருந்ததை எடுத்துக்கொண்டாராம். தன்னுடைய கை எதற்காகவும் தாழ்ந்துவிட கூடாது என்பதில் கவனமாய் இருந்துள்ளார் பாரதியார். காந்தி, பாரதியார் சந்திப்பு வறுமையில் சில காலம் வாழ்ந்த பாரதியார், 1919 ஆம் ஆண்டு மீண்டும் சென்னைக்கு வந்தார். அப்போது ராஜாஜியின் வீட்டிற்கு ஒரு முறை சென்றபோது அங்கு மகாத்மா காந்தியை சந்தித்தார். இந்தியாவின் மும்மூர்த்திகளான ராஜாஜி, காந்தி மற்றும் மகா கவி பாரதியார் சந்தித்தது அதுவே முதலும் கடைசியும் ஆகும். பாரதியார் இறப்பு 1921 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம், தான் வழக்கமாக செல்லும் திருவல்லிக்கேணி பார்த்தசாரதி கோவிலுக்கு சென்றார் பாரதியார். அங்கு யாரும் எதிர்பாரா விதமாக அந்த கோவில் யானை அவரை தூக்கி எரிந்தது. அதனால் தலையிலும் கையிலும் அவருக்கு காயங்கள் ஏற்பட்டது. அதோடு அவருக்கு இது ஒரு பேரதிர்ச்சியாக இருந்தது. அதனால்  அவர் நோய்வாய்ப்பட்டார். சில நாட்களுக்கு பிறகு அவர் யானை தந்த அதிர்ச்சியில் இருந்து மீண்டபோதும் வயிற்று கடுப்பு நோயால் பாதிக்கப்  பட்டார். மருந்துகளை சாப்பிட மறுத்த அவர் தனது 39 வது வயதில், 1921 ஆம் ஆண்டு செப்டம்பர் மாதம் 11 ஆம் தேதி இவுலக வாழ்வை நீத்தார்.  இளம் வயதில் இத்தகைய பெரும் கவி இறந்தது ஒரு சோகம் என்றால், அதை விட பெரும் சோகம் ஒன்றை “கவிராஜன் கதை” என்னும் நூலில் கவி பேரரசு வைரமுத்து குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். பாரதியாரின் இறுதி ஊர்வலத்தில் கலந்துகொண்டவர்கள் மிகச்  சிலரே என்பதை குறிப்பிடுகையில், “இறுதி ஊர்வலத்தின் எண்ணிக்கை இருபதுக்கும் குறைவாக இருந்ததாம் தோழர்களே, மகாகவிஞனுக்கு மரியாதை பார்த்தீரோ! அவன் உடம்பில் மொய்த்த ஈக்களின் எண்ணிக்கையில் கூட ஆட்கள் இல்லையே!” என்று குறிப்புபிட்டுள்ளார். தான் இறந்தாலும் தன் கனவுகள் அனைத்தையும் நம்மிடமே விட்டு சென்றார் அந்த தீர்க்க தரிசி. “ஆடுவோமே பள்ளு பாடுவோமே ஆனந்த சுதந்திரம் அடைந்துவிட்டோம்” என்று விடுதலைக்கு முன்பாகவே பாடிய பாராதியை தீர்க்க தரிசி என்று தானே நாம் கூற வேண்டும். பாரதியார் எழுதிய நூல்களில் சில பாஞ்சாலி சபதம், பாரதி அறுபத்தாறு, தேசிய கீதங்கள், விநாயகர் நான்மணிமாலை, கண்ணன் பாட்டு, குயில்பாட்டு, தோத்திரப்பாடல்கள், ஞானப்பாடல்கள், புதிய ஆத்திச்சூடி, பதஞ்சலியோக சூத்திரம், சந்திரிகையின் கதை, ,விடுதலைப் பாடல்கள், சின்னஞ்சிறு கிளியே, பொன்வால் நரி, பாரதியார் பகவத் கீதை, ஞானரதம், நவதந்திரக் கதைகள், ஆறில் ஒரு பங்கு. பாரதியார் நினைவுச்சின்னங்கள் : பாரதியார் பிறந்த ஊரான எட்டயபுரத்தில், அவருக்கு மணிமண்டபமும், திருவுருவச் சிலையும் அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. எட்டயபுரத்திலும், சென்னை திருவல்லிக்கேணியிலும் பாரதியார் வாழ்ந்த வீட்டினை, பாரதியார் நினைவு இல்லமாக மாற்றி அதை இன்றுவரை தமிழ்நாடு அரசு பராமரித்து வருகிறது. அதோடு அங்கு பொதுமக்களும் சென்று பார்வையிடும் வகையில் வசதிகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"வினா : எப்சம் உப்பின் வேதிப்பெயர் ","answer":"விடை : மெக்னீசியம் சல்பேட்"},{"question":"Mutsara 1: Mukupesana, vaGermanist vakasimbirira pakuzvimiririra kwemasangano evashandi uye vakaona bato risiri reparamende sechinhu bedzi mumiriri wezvematongerwe enyika webato revashandi rezvematongerwe enyika. Mutsara 2: Mukupesana, vaAllemanist vakasimbirira pakuzvimiririra kwemasangano evashandi uye vakaona bato rezvematongerwe enyika rinongova mumiriri wezvematongerwe enyika webato revashandi risiri reparamende. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hungu kana kuti Kwete?","answer":"Kwete"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Nếu như trước đây chỉ cần 1-2 phút là dán xong thẻ thu phí không dừng ETC thì những ngày qua tình trạng người dân, nhất là ở các tỉnh phía Nam đổ xô đi dán khiến thời gian chờ đợi kéo dài, quá tải cho các đơn vị cung cấp. Trước đó ngày 26-7, Tổng công ty Đầu tư phát triển đường cao tốc Việt Nam (VEC) chính thức khai thác vận hành hệ thống thu phí ETC trên đường cao tốc TP.HCM - Long Thành - Dầu Giây. Từ đó đến nay, tình trạng ùn tắc kéo dài nghiêm trọng đã liên tục xảy ra. Liên quan vấn đề này, ông Hồ Trọng Vinh - phó tổng giám đốc Công ty TNHH thu phí tự động (VETC) - cho hay nguyên nhân là do lượng xe sử dụng ETC thấp nhất là những ngày đầu đưa vào vận hành. Nhiều xe không thẻ hoặc có thẻ nhưng không nạp tiền đã đi vào làn ETC, gây ùn ứ giao thông. Theo ông Vinh, cả nước có 4,8 triệu ôtô thì hiện xe đã dán thẻ đạt trên 3,5 triệu xe (của cả hai nhà cung cấp dịch vụ VETC và VDTC), chiếm 75% số lượng xe toàn quốc. Theo số liệu của VETC, nếu như ngày 20-7 chỉ dán được 12.000 xe/ngày thì hai hôm nay số lượng dán lên đến 27.000 xe/ngày, trong đó tập trung phần lớn ở các tỉnh phía Nam. Với tốc độ dán hiện nay, trong vòng 60 ngày nữa tỉ lệ các xe dán thẻ trên toàn quốc sẽ đạt 80 - 90% theo yêu cầu của Chính phủ. Lãnh đạo VETC cũng đánh giá khu vực phía Nam số lượng xe dán thấp hơn so với khu vực phía Bắc lý do một phần là trước đây khu vực phía Bắc triển khai thu phí không dừng nhiều hơn, số lượng người có nhu cầu dán nhiều hơn. Điển hình tỉ lệ dán thẻ ETC Hà Nội trên 85%, TP.HCM và các tỉnh Đông Nam Bộ dưới 65%. Ông Bùi Trình, tổng giám đốc Công ty cổ phần Giao thông số","answer":"Việt Nam (VDTC - cung cấp thẻ ePass), cũng cho rằng mật độ sử dụng ETC tại các tỉnh phía Nam thấp hơn hẳn so với các tỉnh phía Bắc. \\"Tại các tỉnh phía Nam lưu lượng xe rất cao, lượng dùng ETC thấp, trong khi đó việc triển khai dán thu phí không dừng tại các tuyến cao tốc lại gấp rút chỉ đến 1-8 dẫn đến ùn tắc xe đến dán. Còn tại miền Bắc một số cao tốc đã triển khai thu phí không dừng và chủ phương tiện thấy rõ tiện ích nên dùng nhiều hơn\\", ông Trình lý giải. Cạnh đó đại diện VDTC cũng chỉ rõ một nguyên nhân khác là số lượng tuyến cao tốc ở các tỉnh phía Nam, Đông Nam Bộ ít hơn so với phía Bắc. Thêm vào đó, tuyến cao tốc TP.HCM - Trung Lương dừng thu phí trong hơn 3 năm dẫn đến các chủ phương tiện không quan tâm sử dụng, dán thẻ thu phí không dừng. Đối với các phương tiện xe tải vận chuyển trên các quốc lộ chủ yếu mua vé tháng thay cho vé lượt. Do nhu cầu dán thẻ của khách hàng tăng cao, đại diện VETC cho hay mỗi ngày tiếp nhận trên 25.000 cuộc gọi đến tổng đài, tăng gấp 5 lần so với trước nên đường dây thường xuyên bận. Còn VDTC cũng tiếp nhận khoảng 20.000 cuộc gọi đến tổng đài mỗi ngày, tăng gấp 5 lần so với các tháng trước. Đa số chủ xe đăng ký dán thẻ, hỏi thông tin về thủ tục dán, hướng dẫn nạp tiền... Công ty phải tăng 50 nhân sự trực tổng đài, chia sẻ công việc với gần 40 người cũ."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：深度学习和机器学习有什么区别？","answer":"答案：深度学习是机器学习的一个子集，它使用神经网络模型来模拟人脑的工作原理，并在处理复杂数据时表现出色。"},{"question":"tumhara naam kya hai","answer":"mera naam sshubam hai"},{"question":"\\"අම්මා\\" ග්‍රන්ථය රචනා කරන ලද්දේ කවුරුන් විසින්ද?","answer":"\\"අම්මා\\" ග්‍රන්ථය රචනා කරන ලද්දේ මැක්සිම් ගෝර්කි විසිනි."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa Suuradii Nebiguﷺ, yidhi waxaan ka jeclahay Aduunka iyo waxa dhex yaala?","answer":"Waa Suuratu Al-Fatax."},{"question":"കൊൽക്കത്ത എന്തിന് പ്രസിദ്ധമാണ്?","answer":"ഇന്ത്യൻ സംസ്ഥാനമായ പശ്ചിമ ബംഗാളിന്റെ തലസ്ഥാനമാണ് കൊൽക്കത്ത എന്നും അറിയപ്പെടുന്ന കൊൽക്കത്ത. സമ്പന്നമായ ചരിത്രത്തിനും സാംസ്കാരിക പൈതൃകത്തിനും ബൗദ്ധിക പാരമ്പര്യത്തിനും പേരുകേട്ടതാണ് ഇത്. കൊളോണിയൽ വാസ്തുവിദ്യ, ട്രാമുകൾ, ഹൗറ ബ്രിഡ്ജ്, വിക്ടോറിയ മെമ്മോറിയൽ, ഇന്ത്യൻ മ്യൂസിയം, ഭക്ഷണങ്ങൾ, പ്രത്യേകിച്ച് തെരുവ് ഭക്ഷണം എന്നിവയാണ് കൊൽക്കത്ത അറിയപ്പെടുന്ന ഏറ്റവും ശ്രദ്ധേയമായ ചില കാര്യങ്ങൾ. ശക്തമായ സാഹിത്യപരവും കലാപരവുമായ പാരമ്പര്യങ്ങൾക്കും ഇന്ത്യയിലെ പ്രധാന വിദ്യാഭ്യാസ കേന്ദ്രം എന്ന നിലയിലും ഇത് അറിയപ്പെടുന്നു."},{"question":"紀元前27年に即位した、ローマ帝国の初代皇帝といえば誰でしょう？","answer":"アウグストゥス／オクタヴィアヌスです。"},{"question":"テニスや卓球などで球の打ち合いが続くことをなんと言う？","answer":"ラリーです。"},{"question":"Ao amin'ny fanangonana akanjo dia misy lobaka, pataloha ary palitao. Ny lobaka rehetra dia lava tanana, ny pataloha rehetra dia matevina, ary ny palitao rehetra dia maivana.Inona no azontsika tsoahina avy amin’ireo fanambarana etsy ambony ireo?A. Ny palitao rehetra dia matevina.B. Tsy misy lobaka fohy tanana .D. Maivana avokoa ny pataloha rehetra.E. Ny palitao rehetra dia lava tanany.","answer":"Ny valiny marina dia B. Tsy misy lobaka fohy tanana ."},{"question":"Su'aasha 2aad Hanka sare halkee ayuu ka soo burqadaa? ","answer":"Han ka sare (himmada sare) booskeedu iyo halka ay dagan tahay waa qalbiga, xubnaha kalena waxay fuliyaan wixii himmad ah oo qalbigaas kasoo fula, qofkuna himmadiisa wuxuu ku gaaraa oo ku helaa darajo uusan ficilkiisa ku gaarin.  Bal xadiiskan dhuux: - اَ   أن النبي  عن سهل بن حنيف    الشهه َ اللَّه َلَأَ س ْنَ قال : ( م ٍ ب َةَد َ قْ ص د ُ ب هَ لهغ (1909( اش ه  ) رواه مسلم َ ى ف ر َلَ ع َ ات َ م ْ إ ن َ اء  و َدَهُّ الش َ از ل َنَ م ُاللَّه((Qofkii Alle waydiista shahaado si dhab ahna wu weydiista, Alle waa gaarsiiyaa qofkaas darajada shuhadada, waloow gogoshiisaba haku naf baxee)).  Bal xadiiskanna aan dhuuxno, si ay inoo ku caddaato qiimaha ay leedahay inuu qofku han sare yeesho.  عن ابن عباس   عن رسول الله   :فيما يرويه عن ربه تبارك وتعالى قال  (إن الله كتب الحسنات والسيئات، ثم بين ذلك، فمن هم بحسنة فلم يعملها كتبها الله عنده حسنة كاملة..................... ) رواه البخاري و مسسلم . ((Alle wuxuu qoray xasanaadka iyo xumaanta, kadibna waa cadeeyay, qofkii ku hammiya khayr inuu sameeyo, goortaasna aan samyn, Alle wuxu u qoraa xasano dhamays tiran ) . Labadaan xadiis waxaynu ka faa'iidaysanaynaa arimahan soocodada: - - Qof walba hammigiisa meeshuu dhigo weeye, qofkii han sare leh, hankiisaasi wuxuu gaarsiinayaa, shay uusan ficilkiisu gaarsiin karin. - Qofka hankiisu sareeyo Alle wuxuu ka dalbadaa wax weyn, Allena wuu siiyaa qofkaas wuxuu ka dalbaday niyadiisa ayuuna ku siiyaa."},{"question":"கேள்வி : பத்திர ஒழுங்கு முறை சட்டம் எந்த ஆண்டு நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது ? ","answer":"பதில் : 1956"},{"question":"\\"Аарынын уюгундай\\" дегенди кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"1. Абдан уу-дуу болгондой, ызы-чуусу, кыжы-кужусу көп. Залдын ичи аарынын уюгундай кыжылдайт (Баялинов).2. Башаламан, иретсиз, бөөт-чөөт, М: Аарынын уюгундай болгон үйлөр."},{"question":"Башка улуттарда бешик болгонбу?","answer":"Түрк тилдүү калктарда бешиктин негизги функционалдык милдети окшош, бирок оюу-чийүүсү, формасы боюнча бири-биринен айырмаланып турат. Түрк, азербайжан, түркмөн, өзбек эли – \\"бешик\\", казактар \\"бесик\\" дешери маалым болду.Азия элдеринин ичинен азыркы күнгө чейин Тажикстандын басымдуу бөлүгү баланы бешикте (гахвора) чоңойтуп келишет."},{"question":"Tani Ààrẹ orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà lọ́wọ́ báyìí? ","answer":"Ààrẹ Bọ́lá Ahmed Tinubu ni."},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: [Tin nhanh tối 31-7-2022] Một người bị đâm chết ở TP.HCM","answer":"Một người bị đâm chết ở TP.HCM Rạng sáng 31/7, người dân nghe tiếng cự cãi lớn tại một con hẻm ở phường An Lạc, quận Bình Tân. Một số người sau đó phát hiện H. (khoảng 30 tuổi) bị thương, đưa đi cấp cứu song không qua khỏi. Ngày 31-7, Công an quận Bình Tân, TP.HCM, đang điều tra vụ một người đàn ông tử vong tại quán nước nằm trong sân bóng ở phường Bình Hưng Hòa B. Theo điều tra ban đầu, tối 30-7, một nhóm người đi đá bóng thấy một người đàn ông khoảng 50 tuổi nằm bất động trên võng ở khu vực bán nước. Họ tới kiểm tra thì phát hiện nạn nhân đã tử vong. Sự việc được trình báo công an. Nhận tin báo, Công an quận Bình Tân phối hợp với Công an phường Bình Hưng Hòa B khám nghiệm hiện trường, đưa thi thể nạn nhân về nhà xác để khám nghiệm tử thi. Nguyên nhân người đàn ông tử vong đang được làm rõ. Ô tô tải va chạm xe đạp điện, bé gái 12 tuổi tử vong Chiều 31-7, Phòng CSGT Công an tỉnh Đắk Lắk phối hợp với cơ quan chức năng huyện Lắk để điều tra, làm rõ nguyên nhân vụ tai nạn khiến bé gái khoảng 12 tuổi tử vong. Khoảng 15h10 cùng ngày, tài xế tên L.T.N. (35 tuổi, trú xã Ea Khal, huyện Ea H'leo) điều khiển xe tải biển số 47H-008.71 lưu thông trên quốc lộ 27 hướng từ Đắk Lắk đi Lâm Đồng. Khi ô tô chạy đến Km 43+300 thuộc thị trấn Liên Sơn, thì bất ngờ va với xe đạp điện lưu thông cùng chiều do một cô bé khoảng 12 tuổi (trú thị trấn Liên Sơn, huyện Lắk) cấm lái. Cú va chạm mạnh và bất ngờ khiến bé gái ngã xuống đường, tử vong tại chỗ, xe đạp điện bị hư hỏng. Lực lượng CSGT Công an tỉnh Đắk Lắk có mặt tại hiện trường, phân luồng giao thông, phối hợp với cơ quan chức năng điều tra, làm rõ nguyên nhân vụ tai nạn. Cá mập Greenland gây bất ngờ khi xuất hiện ở biển Caribbean Một cá thể cá mập Greenland đã được phát hiện trong khu vực san hô ở ngoài khơi Belize - quốc gia nhiệt đới ven biển Caribbean - khiến giới nghiên cứu sửng sốt. Đây là lần đầu tiên loài cá mập này được phát hiện ở khu vực phía tây biển Caribe, theo thông cáo báo chí của Đại học Quốc tế Florida (Mỹ), CNN đưa tin ngày 31-7. Theo thông cáo, bà Devanshi Kasana, nghiên cứu sinh tiến sĩ tại Đại học Quốc tế Florida, phát hiện cá thể này khi dán nhãn theo dõi lên các cá thể cá mập báo tại Belize cùng với các ngư dân địa phương, vì nó có ngoại hình khác với những con cá khác. Nga mời Liên Hợp Quốc điều tra vụ tù nhân Ukraine bị sát hại Bộ Quốc phòng Nga tuyên bố đã mời Liên Hợp Quốc và Ủy ban Chữ thập đỏ Quốc tế (ICRC) điều tra vụ trại giam ở vùng ly khai Donetsk bị tấn công khiến 50 người thiệt mạng, hãng thông tấn TASS ngày 31-7 đưa tin. \\"Nga đã chính thức mời chuyên gia Liên Hợp Quốc và Ủy ban Chữ thập đỏ Quốc tế tham gia cuộc điều tra vụ tấn công trung tâm giam giữ ở Olenivka, khiến một số tù nhân chiến tranh Ukraine thiệt mạng\\", tuyên bố của Bộ Quốc phòng Nga cho biết. Tuy nhiên, hiện chưa rõ thời điểm chuyên gia Liên Hợp Quốc và ICRC có thể tới hiện trường tiến hành điều tra. Tổng hợp"},{"question":"Mana nu teu kaasup kadaharan tina aci?(a) Cimol(b) Ciréng(c) Cilok(d) Géhu","answer":"Anu teu kaasup kadaharan tina aci nyaéta (d) Géhu kusabab Géhu dijieun tina togé jeung tahu."},{"question":" Мамбет Чокмор уулу башка манасчылардан эмнеси менен айырмаланат?а) жаш кезинен “Манас” айтып калуусунунб) ал оозеки чыгармачылыктын башка түрлөрүнө кызыккан эмесв) оюнан чыгарып айтуучу болгондугунанг) айырмаланган деле эмес","answer":"б) ал оозеки чыгармачылыктын башка түрлөрүнө кызыккан эмес."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أطول آية في القرآن الكريم، وأين توجد؟","answer":"الإجابة: آية الدين أو آية المداينة هي أطول آية في القرآن الكريم وهي الآية 282 من سورة البقرة."},{"question":"కింది పదాలు చదవండి. విగ్రహవాక్యాలు రాయండి. అవి ఏ తత్పురుష సమాసాలో రాయండి.అ) రాజపూజితుడుఆ) ధనాశఇ) పురజనులుఈ) జటాధారిఉ) భుజబలంఊ) అగ్నిభయం","answer":"అ) రాజపూజితుడు = రాజు చేత పూజితుడు (తృతీయా తత్పురుషం)ఆ) ధనాశ = ధనము నందు ఆశ (సప్తమీ తత్పురుషం)ఇ) పురజనులు = పురము నందలి జనులు (సప్తమీ తత్పురుషం)ఈ) జటాధారి = జడలను ధరించువాడు (ద్వితీయా తత్పురుషం)ఉ) భుజబలం = భుజము యొక్క బలం (షష్ఠీ తత్పురుషం)ఊ) అగ్నిభయం = అగ్ని వలన భయం (పంచమీ తత్పురుషం)"},{"question":"Giá vé vào cổng của Bà Nà Hills tại năm 2023 là bao nhiêu?","answer":"Giá vé vào cổng của Bà Nà Hills vào năm 2023 là 900.000 đồng với một người lớn ngoại tỉnh và 750.000 đồng cho trẻ em. Vé đã bao gồm cáp treo khứ hồi, tham quan Cầu Vàng, Fantasy Park, lâu đài Mặt Trăng..."},{"question":"Ƙirƙiri labarin don kanun labarai mai zuwa: Kannywood: Hadiza Gabon ce ta fi fice a Google a 2019","answer":"Tauraruwar fina-finan Hausa Hadiza Aliyu Gabon ta shiga cikin jerin taurarin da aka fi neman karin bayani a kansu a shafin matambayi-ba-ya-bata na Google a shekarar 2019 a Najeriya. Taurarin fim din kudancin Najeriya wato Nollywood, Regina Daniels da Genevieve Nnaji da Tonto Dike, su ne kan gaba, yayin da Hadiza Gabon take biye masu a matsayi na hudu. Shafin Google yakan fitar da kalmomi ko kuma sunayen da mutane suka fi bincikawa a shafin duk shekara a kowace kasa a fadin duniya. Sannan kuma shafin kan yi wa sunayen rukuni ne, inda ake da rukunan mawaka da wakar kanta da wasanni da 'yan fim da fina-finan kansu da kuma tambayoyi. Kamar yadda bayanai suka nuna, Hadiza ta fi yin fice ne daga ranar 7 ga watan Afrilu zuwa 13 ga Afrilun. A watan Afrilu ne wani bidiyo ya bulla, inda ya nuna Gabon tana dukan Amina Amal bayan Amal din ta zarge ta da yin madigo. kuma wannan ya taimaka wurin kara yawan neman bayanai kan tauraruwar a Google. Kalmomin da aka fi amfani da su wurin neman karin bayani a kanta su ne: 'hadiza gabon and amal, hadiza gabon and amina amal, hadiza gabon instagram, tarihin hadiza gabon.' 'Yan Kano ne suka fi bincika Hadiza Gabon din, inda suke da kashi 100%, sai Kaduna da suke da kashi 63%, sai Abuja masu kashi 52, sai Legas masu 41% da kuma jihar Bayelsa masu kashi 38%. Wannan na nufin Hadiza gabon ta fi kowane mutum fice a shafin na Google a Arewacin Najeriya ban da Atiku Abubakar, wanda yake na biyu a rukunin mutane a bayan mawaki Naira Marley. Gabon tana da mabiya miliyan daya da dubu 400 a shafin Instagram, dubu 416 a Facebook da kuma dubu 194 a Twitter."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Kepentingan Mempelajari Mata Pelajaran Sejarah di Sekolah.","answer":"Dalam dunia yang dilingkari kemajuan sains dan teknologi ini generasi muda semakin melupakan sejarah yang tercipta demi kemudahan hidup pada masa kini. Sejarah adalah penemuan, pengumpulan, pengurusan, dan persembahan maklumat terhadap peristiwa silam atau lampau. Ia juga bermaksud tempoh masa yang lalu selepas catatan penulisan telah dicipta. Bagi memastikan masa hadapan masyarakat dan negara berada pada tahap yang terbaik, generasi muda yang bakal mengambil tempat pemimipin hari ini seharusnya mempelajari sejarah kerana kepentingannya yang sangat bermanfaat. Oleh itu, wajar untuk kita bincangkan kepentingan-kepentingan yang akan diperoleh sekiranya generasi muda hari ini mempelajari sejarah domestik mahupun antarabangsa.Antara kepentingan dalam mempelajari sejarah bagi generasi muda adalah memupuk semangat patriotik. Jika kita lihat keadaan pada hari ini, masyarakat tidak lagi menghargai jasa-jasa pejuang tanah air kita yang telah bersusah payah membebaskan negara kita daripada dijajah. Generasi muda seharusnya mengingati jasa dan sumbangan tokoh-tokoh tanah air seperti Tunku Abdul Rahman, Tun H.S Lee dan Tun Dr. Ismail. Negarawan ini telah berhempas pulas mencari jalan terbaik supaya kita dapat menikmati kemakmuran dan kedamaian untuk hidup dalam masyarakat hari ini. Maka, semangat patriotisme dapat dipupuk dalam jiwa generasi muda malah mereka akan sentiasa bersyukur dan memberi penghargaan terhadap pengorbanan pejuang tanah air terdahulu. Semoga nama mereka sentiasa meniti di bibir masyarakat kerana harimau mati meninggalkan belang, manusia mati meninggalkan nama.Selain itu, mempelajari sejarah akan menyemai perpaduan antara kaum terutamanya dalam kalangan generasi muda. Persis kata peribahasa, melentur buluh biarlah dari rebungnya. Sistem pendidikan yang terasing sedikit merencat perkembangan perpaduan antara kaum generasi muda hari ini. Namun begitu, dengan mempelajari sejarah, elemen perpaduan itu akan dipupuk secara tidak langsung. Kestabilan negara boleh diibaratkan seperti negara kita adalah pokok dan rakyat ibarat akar, pokok tidak akan berdiri kukuh tanpa akar begitu juga negara kita. Jika rakyat mengutamakan nilai perpaduan, keamanan dan kestabilan negara pasti akan terjamin. Negara kita pernah mencatatkan sejarah hitam selepas merdeka iaitu tragedi persalahfahaman antara kaum pada 13 Mei 1969. Tragedi ini meragut banyak nyawa dan perpaduan negara itu ibarat telur di hujung tanduk, Selepas terjadinya peristiwa hitam ini, kita mestilah sentiasa memastikan bahawa hubungan antara kaum dipelihara agar tragedi tidak berulang kembali.Pada masa yang sama, mempelajari sejarah akan dapat membantu generasi muda dalam mengambil iktibar daripada peristiwa masa dahulu. Hal ini demikian kerana dalam peristiwa-peristiwa sejarah yang terdahulu mengandungi pelbagai pengajaran yang tersirat. Tamsilnya, peristiwa Tanah Melayu dijajah dan ditindas oleh penjajah British memberi pengajaran kepada generasi muda supaya jangan terlalu mudah mempercayai orang asing. Penjajah digambarkan dengan licik dan jahat pada masa itu kerana sanggup menggunakan tipu muslihat atau taktik kotor untuk meluaskan kawasan jajahan mereka di tanah air kita. Intihannya, generasi yang bakal memacu masa hadapan negara dapat memperbaiki kesilapan masa lalu dan mencipta kejayaan yang lebih gemilang. Tanpa mempelajari kesalahan dan kesilapan masa lalu, kita mungkin mengulangi kesilapan lampau yang bukan sahaja merugikan seseorang individu tetapi mungkin juga kepada keluarga, masyarakat dan negara.Akhir sekali, kepentingan generasi muda untuk mempelajari sejarah adalah supaya mereka menghargai budaya, warisan dan tradisi yang dimiliki oleh tanah air ini. Sebagai contoh, pasukan bola sepak negara pernah layak untuk beraksi di kejohanan Olimpik pada satu ketika dahulu, Pasukan tersebut terdiri daripada kaum Melayu, Cina dan India dimana ia tercatat sebagai sejarah terulung dalam arena bola sepak tanah air. Tetapi sejak kebelakangan ini, timbul isu rasisme daripada penyokong terhadap pemain yang bermain d atas padang. Oleh itu, sekiranya generasi muda mempelajari sejarah, mereka akan bersikap terbuka dan toleransi seterusnya berusaha menghidupkan budaya negara yang terdiri daripada pelbagai kaum. Selain itu, tradisi seperti pertunjukkan wayang kulit, permainan wau dan gasing perlu dipelajari oleh generasi muda kerana kalau bukan mereka yang akan memelihara tradisi tersebut, siapa yang akan melakukannya. Intihanya, pemeliharaan warisan, tradisi dan budaya masyarakat kita dapat dijaga sekiranya generasi muda mempelajari sejarah di sebaliknya.Konklusinya, pelbagai kepentingan yang tersurat dan tersirat apabila generasi muda mempelajari sejarah. Golongan yang bakal menggantikan pemimpin hari ini di masa akan datang tidak sepatutnya mempunyai anggapan bahawa sejarah adalah sesuatu yang sudah lapuk dan ketinggalan zaman. Setiap di antara kita memainkan peranan penting dalam memupuk minat generasi muda dalam mempelajari sejarah. Peribahasa Melayu berkata, bagai kacang lupakan kulit. ungkapan tersebut adalah nilai yang kita cuba jauhi agar generasi muda sedar mereka akan menggalas tanggungjawab dalam memacu negara ke tahap kemajuan yang lebih baik. Semoga dengan mempelajari sejarah, generasi muda dapat memberikan wawasan dan membawa negara Malaysia duduk sama rendah dan berdiri sama tinggi dengan negara-negara maju yang lain."},{"question":"Frase 1: \\"1i Productions è un gioco da tavolo americano. E' stato creato nel 2004 da Jenna, William e Colin Byrne.\\"Frase 2: \\"1i Productions è un editore americano di giochi da tavolo. E'stato fondato nel 2004 da Colin Byrne, William e Jenna.\\"Domanda: La frase 1 e la frase 2 esprimono lo stesso significato? - Sì o no?","answer":"No."},{"question":"இணர்ச்சி விதிகளை விளக்குக.","answer":"நியூட்டனின் முதல் விதி என்றும் அழைக்கப்படும் மந்தநிலை விதி, ஒரு உடல் ஓய்வில் இருந்தால் அல்லது ஒரு நேர்கோட்டில் நிலையான வேகத்தில் நகர்ந்தால், அது ஓய்வில் இருக்கும் அல்லது ஒரு விசையால் செயல்படாத வரை நிலையான வேகத்தில் ஒரு நேர்கோட்டில் நகரும் என்று இயற்பியலில் கூறுகிறது."},{"question":"Viết tiếp đoạn văn sau: Ngoài việc gửi nguồn cung vũ khí riêng, Ba Lan còn là quốc gia trung chuyển quan trọng cho vũ khí mà Mỹ và các nước phương Tây khác đang gửi đến Ukraine. Ba Lan cũng tiếp nhận khoảng một triệu người tị nạn Ukraine từ khi chiến sự xảy ra.Quan hệ giữa Warsaw và Kiev leo thang căng thẳng sau khi Ba Lan tuần trước đơn phương duy trì lệnh cấm nhập khẩu ngũ cốc Ukraine, bất chấp Ủy ban châu Âu thông báo chấm dứt lệnh cấm áp đặt từ tháng 5. Hungary và Slovakia cũng phản đối quyết định của Ủy ban châu Âu.Ukraine đáp trả bằng cách khiếu nại Ba Lan, Hungary và Slovakia lên Tổ chức Thương mại Thế giới (WTO). Kiev cũng cảnh báo có thể áp lệnh cấm đối với trái cây, rau quả nhập khẩu từ Ba Lan.Vấn đề ngũ cốc đặc biệt nhạy cảm với Ba Lan, ","answer":"khi nước này chuẩn bị diễn ra cuộc tổng tuyển cử vào tháng tới. Đảng Luật pháp và Công lý cầm quyền hiện nhận được ủng hộ mạnh mẽ của các cử tri vùng nông thôn.\\"Chúng tôi là những người đầu tiên làm rất nhiều điều cho Ukraine và đó là lý do chúng tôi mong đợi họ hiểu cho lợi ích của chúng tôi\\", ông Morawiecki nói ngày 20/9. \\"Tất nhiên chúng tôi tôn trọng mọi vấn đề của họ, nhưng với chúng tôi, lợi ích của nông dân là quan trọng nhất\\".Ukraine hôm 21/9 cho biết sẽ tổ chức các cuộc đàm phán với Ba Lan về vấn đề ngũ cốc \\"trong những ngày tới\\" và nhấn mạnh hai nước vẫn có mối quan hệ \\"thân thiết\\"."},{"question":"Iza amin'ireo planeta ao amin'ny rafi-masoandrontsika no fantatra amin'ny anarana hoe \\"Planeta Mena\\"?A) tanyB) VenusC) Mars","answer":"Ny valiny marina dia:C) Mars dia fantatra amin'ny anarana hoe \\"Planet Mena.\\""},{"question":"\\" \\"Ny aina tsy ananam-piry\\": koa nataon'ny razana fa ny mety dia ny mahafoy ny sisa rehetra hiarovana azy. Izany no tsy mba nandalàny vola aman-karena hitadiavam-panefitra tany amin'ny mpanandro sy ny mpisikidy ary nivarotany hatramin'ny zava-tsy foy indrindra aza, fa \\"aina\\"; hono , \\"mamy ny aina\\". Izany koa no nahatonga ny hoe: \\"raha ho faty ny havana, matesa ny omby, fa raha ho faty ny tena, matesa Rahavana\\" \\". Inona ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra io dia ny fitsimbinana ny aina."},{"question":"* كم قاطعا في فم الإنسان ؟","answer":"8 قواطع"},{"question":"Mi o ku o, mi o si ninu awọn ti ṣọja yinbọn pa ni Lẹkki-Eniọla Badmus","answer":"Ọkan pataki ninu awọn oṣere ilẹ, Ẹniọla Badmus,  wa ti dupẹ lọwọ gbogbo awọn ti wọn n pe e, ti wọn n fi atẹjiṣẹ ranṣẹ si i nipa iroyin pe ọmọbinrin naa ti ku.  Oṣere naa ni oun ko ku o, alaafia ara loun wa, o ni oun ko tiẹ si ni ibi iwọde naa lanaa rara.Ninu ọrọ kan to gbe sori ikanni instagraamu re l’Ọjọbọ, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii lo ti sọ pe oun wa laye, oun si wa laaye, ohunkohun ko ṣe oun.Lati ana ni awọn eeyan ti n gbe e kiri ori ẹrọ ayelujara pe oṣere naa wa ninu awọn ti wọn yinbọn fun lalẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, to si ti ku, nigba ti awọn ṣọja ya bo awọn ọdọ naa nibi ti wọn kora pọ jọ si, ti wọn si n yinbọ fun wọn. Ọpọ awọn ọdọ naa lo ku, nigba ti pupọ ninu wọn tun farapa yanna yanna, ti wọn si n gba itọju nileewosan di ba a ṣe n sọ yiiOṣere naa wa dupẹ lọwọ gbogbo awọn afẹnifẹre ti wọn ti n pe e lati beere alaafia re. Bẹẹ lo ni ki enikẹni ma sunkun fun oun o, nitori oun ko ku, oun wa laye, oun wa laaye, ṣugbọn inu oun ko dun nitori aburu ti awọn ṣọja ṣe si aọn ọdọ ti wọn n ṣewọde jẹẹjẹẹ wọn."},{"question":"Viết tiếp đoạn văn sau: Bởi vậy, khi lượng nước từ vùng núi phía tây đổ về quá lớn, cả hai con đập đều nhanh chóng bị xói lở và vỡ, khiến khoảng 30 triệu m3 nước đổ về Derna. Phó thị trưởng Derna Ahmed Madroud cho hay khu vực đông dân cư nhất của thành phố nằm ngay trên đường chảy của dòng lũ quét đổ ra biển.Williams lưu ý rằng thành phố Derna còn nằm dưới chân một dãy núi rất dốc. Đây là vị trí đỉnh của khu vực gọi là \\"quạt phù sa\\", được hình thành từ trầm tích do các sông, suối mang đến. Khi mưa lớn xảy ra, các vùng \\"quạt phù sa\\" thường đối mặt nguy cơ xuất hiện lũ quét mạnh, bất ngờ, có thể cuốn trôi mọi thứ trên đường đi.\\"Ít nhất 20% thành phố đã bị phá hủy trong trận lũ\\", Madroud nói.","answer":"Bà Hall lưu ý chính quyền địa phương cũng không cảnh báo nguy hiểm với người dân khi mưa lớn xảy ra. \\"Thông thường, chúng ta sẽ có một hệ thống cảnh báo sớm để kêu gọi người dân sơ tán hoặc trú ẩn nếu cần thiết. Nhưng trong trường hợp này thì không\\", bà nói."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Có một lâu đài cổ tích ẩn mình giữa trung tâm thành phố Rome mà ít người biết đến","answer":"La Casina Delle Civette là một ngôi nhà thú vị và đầy mê hoặc nằm bên trong công viên Villa Torlonia, nằm tại thủ đô Rome, Italia. Ý nghĩa của cái tên La Casina Delle Civette có nghĩa là Ngôi nhà của những chú cú. Lý do là bởi nơi đây được trang trí bằng rất nhiều hoạ tiết và đồ vật có liên quan đến loài vật này.  Ngôi nhà được xây dựng lần đầu vào năm 1840 theo yêu cầu của hoàng tử Alessandro Torlonia và được thiết kế bởi kiến trúc sư Giuseppe Jappelli. Ngôi nhà có vẻ ngoài mộc mạc một cách có chủ ý, bên trong được sơn màu giả gạch xây và ván gỗ. Ban đầu, nơi đây được đặt cho cái tên là \\"La Capanna Svizzera\\" có nghĩa là Căn nhà gỗ Thuỵ Sĩ do bề ngoài nó rất giống với một nơi ẩn náu lãng mạn trên dãy núi Alps mộng mơ.  Năm 1908, hoàng tử Giovanni Torlonia Jr, cháu trai của Alessandro đã cho cải tạo căn nhà để biến đây trở thành nơi ở của mình và làm đảo lộn hoàn toàn kiến trúc cũ. Các cửa sổ kính màu, mái vòm và tháp được trang trí bằng đá quý màu đã được thêm vào, căn nhà được thay đổi diện mạo hoàn toàn mới và trở nên giống như một biệt thự thời trung cổ. Người ta nói hoàng tử Giovanni là một người khó gần và u ám, chưa bao giờ kết hôn và không có người thừa kế, ông sống trong căn nhà này cho đến khi qua đời vào năm 1939.  Chỉ đến năm 1914, căn nhà mới được đổi tên thành La Casina Delle Civette như ngày nay bởi hai tấm kính màu ở cửa sổ, mô tả hai con cú cách điệu giữa những chồi cây thường xuân, được tạo ra bởi Dulllo Cambellottl. Hoàng tử Giovanni là một người vô cùng yêu thích những biểu tượng huyền bí. Đối với ông, hình ảnh con cú có ý nghĩa vô cùng đặc biệt nên rất nhiều đồ đạc, đồ nội thất, trang trí trong căn nhà đều có hình ảnh của loài vật này.  Năm 1917, Vincenzo Fasolo đã thiết kế thêm vào mặt tiền phía Nam của ngôi nhà và trang trí nó theo phong cách tự do. Ông sử dụng nhiều loại vật liệu và chi tiết trang trí để tạo nên sự tương tác và gắn kết giữa các khối không gian khác nhau. Ngoài ra ông sử dụng thêm tông màu xám bao quanh bề mặt mái nhà, trong đó có những viên ngói đá phiến mỏng với nhiều hình dạng khác nhau đã được sử dụng. Kính màu vẫn luôn là yếu tố trang trí phổ biến, tạo nên đặc trưng và nét nghệ thuật cho ngôi nhà.  Trong Thế chiến thứ hai, căn nhà đã bị phá huỷ nặng nề do sự chiếm đóng của lực lượng quân đồng minh Anh-Mỹ kéo dài trong hơn 3 năm. Sau nhiều năm bị lãng quên, vào năm 1978 nó đã được chính quyền thành phố Rome mua lại trong tình trạng xuống cấp nghiêm trọng. Một trận hoả hoạn vào năm 1991 cùng với nạn trộm cắp, phá hoại đã khiến cho ngôi nhà càng thêm đổ nát.  Năm 1992, một công trình trùng tu kéo dài 5 năm đã được thực hiện để đưa La Casina Delle Civette trở về thời hoàng kim. Người ta đã phải tham khảo rất nhiều các tư liệu có liên quan đến căn nhà còn xót lại, để có thể khôi phục một công trình kiến trúc đặc biệt và thú vị, được xây dựng vào những năm đầu của thế kỷ trước. Ngày nay, nơi đây trở thành một bảo tàng dành riêng cho nghệ thuật kính màu. Căn nhà đã lấy lại được hào quang trước đây, trở thành một địa điểm thú vị và lãng mạn, mang đầy màu sắc cổ tích cho khách du lịch khi ghé thăm thành phố Rome. Nguồn: https://arttimes.vn/du-lich/co-mot-lau-dai-co-tich-an-minh-giua-trung-tam-thanh-pho-rome-ma-it-n...Nguồn: https://arttimes.vn/du-lich/co-mot-lau-dai-co-tich-an-minh-giua-trung-tam-thanh-pho-rome-ma-it-nguoi-biet-den-c43a8447.html "},{"question":"കേരളത്തിൽ നിന്നുള്ള ആളുകളെ എന്താണ് വിളിക്കുന്നത്?","answer":"മലയാളി"},{"question":"Happiness tawọn ajinigbe ji l’Ekiti ti gba ominira","answer":"Ọkunrin kan tawọn ajinigbe ji lọjọ ọdun Keresi, Happiness Ajayi, ti gba ominira lọwọ awọn ẹruuku ọhun lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii.Happiness ati mọlẹbi ẹ kan, Oluwaṣeun Fatile, ko sọwọ awọn oniṣẹ laabi ọhun loju ọna Iṣan-Ekiti si Iludun-Ekiti, ni nnkan bii aago mẹfa irọlẹ, lasiko ti wọn n lọ siluu Ẹda Oniyọ toun naa wa l’Ekiti.Oju ọna yii kan naa lawọ̣n ajinigbe ti ji Komiṣanna feto ọgbin nipinlẹ naa, Fọlọ̣runṣọ Ọlabọde, gbe ti wọn si pa kanṣẹlọ to wa mọto ọhun, Ọlatunji Ọmọtọshọ, loṣu kẹrin, odun yii.Ọkọ jiipu Lexus kan ni Happiness ati Oluwaṣeun gbe kawọn eeyan naa too deede yọ si wọn lojiji, bi wọn si ṣe fẹẹ sare dari ọkọ naa pada lawọn mi-in yọ si wọn lati ẹyin, ti wọn si da ibọn bolẹ. Ọkọ kan to wa lẹyin atawọn to wa lagbegbe naa la gbọ pe wọn sare pe ikọ Amọtẹkun, tawọn yẹn si ri Oluwaṣeun gba silẹ.Lẹyin iṣẹlẹ naa lawọn ajinigbe ọhun kọkọ beere fun miliọnu lọna ọgọrun-un naira, ki wọn too din in si miliọnu mẹwaa, eyi to pada di miliọnu meji. Inu igbo kan ni Isapa, nipinlẹ Kwara, la gbọ pe wọn ti fi i silẹ ni nnkan bii aago meji ọsan.Nigba to n sọrọ lori bi wọn ṣe fi Happiness silẹ, adari ikọ Amọtẹkun l’Ekiti, Ajagun-fẹyinti Joe Kọmọlaf̣e, sọ pe lẹyin tawọn le awọn ajinigbe naa fun ọjọ mẹta ni wọn fi i silẹ.O ni ko sẹni to sanwo fawọn eeyan naa, agbara ju agbara lọ ni wọn ṣe fẹsẹ fẹ ẹ.Bakan naa ni Happiness funra ẹ sọ pe awọn rin lati ọjọ Keresi naa ti i ṣe ọjọ Ẹti to kọja, awọn si rin ninu igbo di aago meji oru ọjọ Satide, bẹẹ ni wọn ko fun oun lounjẹ.O ni awọn mẹfa lo ṣiṣẹ ibi ọhun, ọkan ninu wọn lo si gbọ oyinbo diẹ, Hausa lawọn to ku n sọ, wọn si n dunkooko pe toun ba fun wọn ni wahala, awọn yoo gbe oun lọ si ipinlẹ Zamfara."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Första portugisiska republiken omfattar en 16-årspierod i Portugals historia, mellan 5 oktoberrevolutionen i Portugal 1910","answer":"och 28 maj-kuppen i Portugal 1926 . 1926 års statskupp blev början på militärdiktatur i Portugal \\"Ditadura Nacional\\" som följdes av regimen \\"Estado Novo\\" ledd av António de Oliveira Salazar."},{"question":"அமெரிக்கர்கள் பேரார்வத்துடன் ஈடுபட்டதுறை \\t1. பங்கு வணிகச்சந்தை2. சினிமா்3. சூதாட்டம்4. வணிகம்","answer":" \\t1. பங்கு வணிகச்சந்தைஒரு பங்குச் சந்தை என்பது ஒரு பொதுச் சந்தை (பொருளாதார பரிமாற்றங்களின் தளர்த்தப்பட்ட நெட்வொர்க். ஆனால் ஒரு நிஜ அமைப்போ அல்லது தனித்தியங்கும் அமைப்போ அல்ல), அதில் நிறுவனங்களின் பங்கு மற்றும் தொடர்பான கூறுகள் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளக்கூடிய விலையில் வியாபாரம் செய்யப்படும்; இவை பங்கு பரிமாற்றகத்தில் பட்டியலிடப்பட்ட கடனீட்டு ஆவணங்கள் ஆகும், அதோடு அவை தனிப்பட்ட விதத்தில் மட்டும் விற்பனை செய்யப்படும்.அக்டோபர் 2008இன் தொடக்கத்தில் உலக பங்குச் சந்தையின் அளவு ஏறக்குறைய 36.6 டிரில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு கணக்கிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. மொத்த உலக பங்கு தொடர்பான பொருட்களின் சந்தை 791 டிரில்லியன் டாலர்களுக்கு முகப்பு அல்லது பண மதிப்பாக கணக்கிடப்பட்டுள்ளது, அது உலக பொருளாதாரத்தின் மொத்த அளவை விட 11 மடங்கு பெரியதாகும். பங்கு தொடர்பான பொருட்களின் மதிப்பு, குத்துமதிப்பான மதிப்புகளைக் கொண்டு குறிப்பிடப்படுவதால், அதனை ஒரு பங்குக்கோ அல்லது நிரந்தர வருமான பாதுகாப்பு ஆவணத்துக்கோ இணையாக ஒப்பிட முடியாது, அது காலாகாலமாக ஒரு நிஜ மதிப்பாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டு வருகிறது. அதிகப்படியாக, பல அதிகமான 'பங்கு தொடர்பான பொருட்கள்' ஒன்றை ஒன்று 'ரத்து' செய்து கொள்ளும் (அதாவது, ஒரு நிகழ்வில் நிகழ்த்தப்படும் தொடர்புப் பொருளின் 'பந்தயம்' அதனுடன் தொடர்புடைய மற்றொரு நேராத நிகழ்வின் 'பந்தயத்தால்' வீழ்த்தப்பட்டுவிடும்). அது போன்ற இழப்பு நேரக்கூடிய பாதுகாப்பு பத்திரங்கள் ஒரு நிஜ சந்தை மதிப்பாக இல்லாமல் மாதிரியாகக் குறிக்கப்பட்டவை என மதிப்பிடப்படும்.பங்குகளையும் பாதுகாப்புப் பத்திரங்களையும் ஒன்றாகப் பட்டியலிடப்பட்ட இடத்துக்கு நிறுவனங்களின் வாங்குபவர்களையும் விற்பவர்களையும் கொண்டுவரும் தொழிலில் சிறப்பு வாய்ந்த நிறுவனங்களின் உறுப்புகள் அல்லது சமபங்கு நிறுவனங்கள் கொண்ட பங்குச் சந்தைகளில் பங்குகள் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டு வியாபாரம் செய்யப்படும். அமெரிக்காவில் (என் யை சி இ )என்ற பங்குச் சந்தை, கனடாவில் டொரண்டோ பங்குச் சந்தை. பல முக்கிய ஐரோப்பிய பங்குச் சந்தைகளாக எடுத்துக்காட்ட லண்டன் பங்குச் சந்தை, பாரீஸ் போர்ஸ், மற்றும் டச் போர்ஸைக் குறிப்பிடலாம். ஆசிய சந்தைகளாக டோகியோ பங்குச் சந்தை, ஹாங்காங் பங்குச் சந்தை, மற்றும் பாம்பே பங்குச் சந்தையைக் குறிப்பிடலாம். லத்தீன் அமெரிக்காவில், (பி எம்&எப் ) போவஸ்பா மற்றும் பிஎம்வி சந்தைகள் உள்ளன."},{"question":"Жусуп Баласагындын \\"Куттуу билим\\" эмгегинен 1-2 сап жазып бере аласыңбы ?","answer":"Маңыз сөздүн көрө албадым пайдасын,Көп сүйлөсөң чалынасың сен бачым."},{"question":"Aşağıdaki ifadeyi tamamlayın: Heykellerin ana kaidesiyle beraber günümüzde Sultanahmet Meydanı olarak bilenen Hipodrom'da yer aldığı düşünülür. Heykeller 1204 yılında düzenlenen","answer":"Dördüncü Haçlı Seferi sırasında Konstantinopolis'te yer almaktaydı. Kentin yağmalanmasının ardından heykeller Dük Enrico Dandolo emriyle Venedik'e getirilmiştir. 1254 yılında San Marco Bazilikası ön cephesindeki teras kısmına yerleştirilmiştir."},{"question":"खालसा राज्याची स्थापना कोणी केली ?","answer":"महाराजा रणजितसिंगाने"},{"question":"Кыргызстанды спорт боюнча таанытып жүргөн кыздарыбыз кимдер?","answer":"Кыргызстандын даңкын далайга чыгарып жүргөн спорт чеберлери Валентина Шевченко, Айсулуу Тыныбекова, Мээрим Жуманазарова, Айпери Медет кызы ж.б.у.с"},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan keperihalan tentang perhimpunan pagi di sekolah.","answer":"Pada setiap hari Ahad, sekolah saya akan mengadakan perhimpunan pagi. Semua murid dan guru berkumpul di dewan sekolah. Murid-murid beratur mengikut kelas masing-masing.           Pada pukul 7.30 pagi, perhimpunan pagi pun bermula. Murid-murid dan guru-guru berdiri tegak untuk menyanyikan lagu Bangsa Johor, Negaraku dan lagu sekolah. Murid-murid bernyanyi dengan penuh semangat. Kemudian, seorang pengawas yang bertugas mengetuai upacara melafazkan ikrar Rukun Negara.          Selepas itu, guru besar menyampaikan hadiah kepada para pemenang pertandingan yang menyertai pertandingan di dalam dan di luar sekolah. Beliau juga memberikan sijil penghargaan kepada kelas yang terbersih. Seorang guru yang bertugas mengambil gambar murid-murid dengan menggunakan kamera digital yang canggih untuk dijadikan kenangan.         Kemudian, guru besar menyampaikan ucapan di atas pentas. Beliau menasihati murid-murid supaya belajar dengan bersungguh-sungguhnya agar mendapat keputusan yang cemerlang dalam peperiksaan. Beliau juga meminta murid-murid sentiasa berdisiplin dan mendengar nasihat guru serta menjaga kebersihan kawasan sekolah.         Selepas setengah jam, perhimpunan pagi pun bersurai. Kemudian,  murid-murid beratur masuk ke kelas masing-masing untuk meneruskan sesi pembelajaran yang seterusnya."},{"question":"अशी कोणती गोष्ट आहे ज्याला पाणी प्यायला दिल्याने ते मरून जाते?","answer":"आग"},{"question":"Боз үй, жайлоо, бетегелүү шиберде жамбаштап жаткан кандай сонун э. Эгерде бул контексттен суроо жаратсак, ал суроого жооп \\"бетегелүү\\" болсо, анда суроо кандай болмок? ","answer":" Кандай шиберде жамбаштап жаткан сонун ?"},{"question":"வினா:நேரத்தை பொறுத்து இடப்பெயர்ச்சியின் மாறுபாட்டு வீதம் என்ன?1. வேகம்2. திசை வேகம்3. முடுக்கம்4. தொலைவு","answer":" விடை:திசை வேகம்"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai akan mengaji suratlah hilang; akan bertanya gurulah mati\\"?","answer":"Masalah tidak dapat diselesaikan oleh sebab puncanya sudah hilang"},{"question":"*ما هو الحيوان الذي تحولت له عصا موسى عندما ألقاها ؟","answer":"الثعبان"},{"question":"Isikhathi sihambe. Lutho umakoti. Usecasukile manje uBheki. Umfundisi athi abangenemanje abakwamkhwenyana. Bavume. Bangena nje uBheki uyazihudula. Yilokhuebheka emuva into engapheli. Abone ukuthi kusobala ukuthi isu likaBhatomulisebenzile. Axakwe ukuthi abasezi ngani ukuzobika uma kukhona ingxaki.Kuzwakale umsinjwana phandle. Yibo oTholi. Abazilungisile bayaconsa. UkhonanoPamella. Akhululeke kancane uBheki. Umfundisi athumele ukuthi bangenengokushesha. Nempela bangene. Kukikizelwe, kuchwaze esotweni.Kube ukungena nje aqale umsebenzi umfundisi. Kuthi kuphakathi kusukume uyisekaTholi, amemeze khona esontweni lapha: 'Ubani othathe ilobolo lalo makoti?'Abantu babheke kulo baba omemezayo. Amehlo abomvu klubhu kulo baba. Bathibayamthulisa athethe aye phambili. Alizwe leli izwi elibuzayo uBheki. Ezwe efikelwaumjuluko omncane. Kusobala ukuthi imali yakhe idliwe uZenze yonke. Uthe esalalelelokho, wasukuma uTholi waqonda ngqo kulo baba omemezayo. Weswela umgodiwokucasha uBheki. Umfundisi athi akuculwe. Licule ibandla. Afike uTholi athiukukhuluma noyise, ahlale phansi uyise.Athi efika eduze kukaBheki uTholi, abuze uBheki ukuthi ubeyothini kuyise.'Kanti nalishonisaphi ilobolo Tholi?' Ubuza ngokuhleba ecasukile manje uBheki.1. Hluza le noveli ubhekise kulezi zihlokwana ezilandelayo:Bhala amaphuzu AMABILI ngesihlokwana NGASINYE. Ukulandelana kwezigameko Umyalezo","answer":"Izigameko kule noveli zihleleke kahle ukusuka kwezincane kuze kufikekwezinkulu.  Izigameko ezibalulekile zihambisana nemixhantela yezinkinga okuyizonaezikhulisa udweshu endabeni. Izigameko kule noveli yizona ezibhebhethekisa inkinga yomlingiswaomkhulu onguBhekani.  Lezi zigameko azithinti uBhekani kuphela kodwa zihlukumeza wonkeumndeni wakubo.  Izigameko ziqala ekuqaleni kwendaba, zikhule ziye kuvuthondaba, zizekupholavuthondaba, zigcine ekupheleni kwendaba."},{"question":"Кыргызстандык алгачкы жазгыч манасчы ким болгон?а) Байымбет Абдрахманов б) С. Каралаевв) С. Орозбаков г) Балык Сазан уулу","answer":"Кыргызстандык алгачкы жазгыч манасчы Байымбет Абдрахманов.Ошентип, туура жообу:а) Байымбет Абдрахманов"},{"question":"Nitori afikun owo-epo bẹntiroolu ati ina ijọba, awọn eeyan bẹrẹ ifẹhonu han l’Ọṣun","answer":"Agbarijọpọ ẹgbẹ awọn ajafẹtọọ-ọmọniyan, iyẹn Coalition of Civil Societies, tipinlẹ Ọṣun, fọn sojuu titi laaarọ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, opin ọsẹ yii lati fẹhonu han lori afikun owo-epo bẹntiroolu ati owo ina tijọba kede rẹ laipẹ yii.Lati aago meje aarọ ni wọn ti pejọ si Freedom Park, niluu Oṣogbo, pẹlu awọn agbofinro ti wọn duro wamuwamu.Bii aago mẹjọ ṣe kọja ni wọn fọn si titi pẹlu oniruuru orin ati akọle lọwọ pe ki i ṣe ayipada ti Aarẹ Buhari ati ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC ṣeleri fawọn araalu niyi.Ọkan lara awọn adari wọn, Comrade Waheed Saka, sọ pe awọn fun ijọba apapọ ni gbedeke ọjọ marun-un pere lati tun ero rẹ pa lori igbesẹ naa, lai jẹ bẹẹ, awọn yoo bẹrẹ ifẹhonu han ti yoo mi gbogbo ipinlẹ Ọṣun titi.Waheed ṣalaye pe pẹlu nnkan ti oju awọn araalu ri lasiko ajakalẹ arun Korona, ko yẹ kijọba tun gbe ẹru afikun owo epo bẹntiroolu ati owo ina le awọn araalu lori."},{"question":"Album-தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்","answer":"தொகுப்பு"},{"question":"Mitovy hevitra ve ireto fehezanteny roa manaraka ireto?1. “Tamin’ny fampakaram-bady no nihaona voalohany.”2. \\"Tao amin'ny lanonana fampakaram-bady no nihaonany voalohany.\\"","answer":"Eny, mitovy hevitra ny fehezanteny roa."},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: Tailandia sarauta ce ta tsarin mulki a kudu maso gabashin Asiya. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: GaskiyaA haƙiƙa, wannan magana ba daidai ba ce. Tailandia sarauta ce ta tsarin mulki a kudu maso gabashin Asiya, ba Kudancin Asiya ba. Tana cikin tsakiyar yankin Indochinese Peninsula a babban yankin kudu maso gabashin Asiya."},{"question":"ශුද්ධ වටිනාකම යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ශුද්ධ වටිනාකම යනු පුද්ගලයෙකු, සමාගමක් හෝ සංවිධානයක් වේවා, ආයතනයක වටිනාකම මැනීමට භාවිතා කරන මූල්‍ය සංකල්පයකි. එය ගණනය කරනු ලබන්නේ සියලු වත්කම්වල (වටිනාකම ඇති හෝ පාලනය වන දේ) මුළු වටිනාකමෙන් සියලු වගකීම් (ණය සහ බැඳීම්) අඩු කිරීමෙනි. එහි සංරචක දෙස සමීප බැල්මක් මෙන්න:1. වත්කම්: වත්කම්වලට මුදල්, ආයෝජන (කොටස්, බැඳුම්කර, ආදිය), නිශ්චල දේපල, වාහන, වටිනා පුද්ගලික අයිතම (ස්වර්ණාභරණ හෝ චිත්‍ර වැනි) වැනි දේ ඇතුළත් වන අතර ව්‍යාපාර සම්බන්ධයෙන්ද එයට ඇතුළත් වේ. ඉන්වෙන්ටරි, උපකරණ සහ බුද්ධිමය දේපල. මූලික වශයෙන්, මුදල්මය වශයෙන් අගය කළ හැකි ඕනෑම දෙයක් වත්කමක් ලෙස සැලකේ.2. වගකීම්: වගකීම් යනු පුද්ගලයා හෝ ආයතනය විසින් ගෙවිය යුතු ණය හෝ බැඳීම් වේ. මෙයට ණය, උකස්, ක්‍රෙඩිට් කාඩ් ණය සහ අනෙකුත් මූල්‍ය බැඳීම් ඇතුළත් වේ.ශුද්ධ වටිනාකම සඳහා  සූත්රය වන්නේ:ශුද්ධ වටිනාකම} = {සම්පූර්ණ වත්කම්} - {මුළු වගකීම්}පුද්ගලයන් සඳහා, ධනාත්මක ශුද්ධ වටිනාකමක් යනු වත්කම් වගකීම් ඉක්මවා යාමයි, එය සාමාන්‍යයෙන් මූල්‍ය සෞඛ්‍යයේ සලකුණක් ලෙස සැලකේ. ඍණාත්මක ශුද්ධ වටිනාකමක්, වගකීම් වත්කම් ඉක්මවන විට, මූල්‍ය දුෂ්කරතා පෙන්නුම් කරයි.ව්‍යාපාර හෝ සංගතවල සන්දර්භය තුළ, ශුද්ධ වටිනාකම (බොහෝ විට \\"පොත් වටිනාකම\\" හෝ \\"කොටස් හිමියන්ගේ කොටස්\\" ලෙස හැඳින්වේ) සමාගමේ වටිනාකම පිළිබිඹු කරන අතර එය සමාගමේ මූල්‍ය සෞඛ්‍යය සහ ස්ථාවරත්වය තක්සේරු කිරීම සඳහා මූල්‍ය විශ්ලේෂණයේදී භාවිතා කරන සැලකිය යුතු දර්ශකයකි.ශුද්ධ වටිනාකම ගණනය කිරීම පුද්ගලික සහ ආයතනික මූල්‍යකරණයේ මූලික පරිචයක් වන අතර එය සැලසුම් කිරීම, ආයෝජන තීරණ ගැනීම හෝ ණය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ප්‍රයෝජනවත් වන මූල්‍ය තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ සැණෙළියක් සපයයි."},{"question":"வினா:தலையில் ஏற்படும் பொடுகை நீக்கும் வழி என்ன?","answer":"விடை:பொடுகு  உருவாகக்  காரணம் :வறண்ட சருமம், ஹார்மோன்களின் அளவில் ஏற்படும் மாறுபாடு, பூஞ்சை போன்ற நுண்ணுயிரித் தொற்றுகள், மனஅழுத்தம், முறையற்ற உணவுப் பழக்கம், தலையைச் சுத்தமாகப் பராமரிக்காதது போன்றவை பொடுகுப் பிரச்னை உருவாக முக்கியக் காரணங்கள்.பொடுகை நீக்கும் வழி :தேங்காய் எண்ணெய்-எலுமிச்சைச் சாறு மசாஜ்எலுமிச்சைச் சாறு, தேங்காய் எண்ணெய் இரண்டிலும் தலா இரண்டு டேபிள்ஸ்பூன் எடுத்து நன்றாகக் கலந்துகொள்ளவும். இந்தக் கலவையை தலைமுடியில் மசாஜ் செய்வதுபோலத் தேய்த்து, 20 நிமிடங்கள் வரை ஊறவைக்க வேண்டும். பிறகு ஷாம்பூ தேய்த்து, தலையை அலச வேண்டும். தேங்காய் எண்ணெய், முடிக்கு ஊட்டமளிக்கும். எலுமிச்சைச் சாறு பொடுகுத் தொல்லையை நீக்கி, முடி வளர்ச்சிக்கு உதவும்.தயிர் தேய்த்துக் குளியல்தயிரைத் தலையில் நன்றாகத் தேய்த்துக்கொள்ள வேண்டும். சுமார் ஒரு மணி நேரம் கழித்து, சிறிது ஷாம்பூ போட்டுக் குளிக்கலாம். தயிர், உடல் உஷ்ணத்தைக் குறைக்கும்; முடிக்கு பளபளப்பையும் தரும். சைனஸ், ஒற்றைத் தலைவலி வரும் பிரச்னை இருப்பவர்கள், இதைத் தவிர்க்கவும்.பேக்கிங் சோடா பேக்ஈரமான தலைமுடியில் சிறிது பேக்கிங் சோடாவைத் தேய்க்கவும். இரண்டு நிமிடங்களுக்குப் பிறகு தலையை அலசவும். பேக்கிங் சோடா பொடுகுக்கு மிகச் சிறந்த நிவாரணி. இது, தலையில் உள்ள இறந்த செல்கள் நீங்கவும், பொடுகுத் தொல்லையில் இருந்து விடுபடவும் உதவும். பேக்கிங் சோடாவை அதிக நேரம் தலையில் வைத்து இருந்தால் தலைமுடி வறண்டு விடும்... கவனம்!கூந்தல் ஊட்டத்துக்கு டீ ட்ரீ எண்ணெய்தேயிலை மரத்திலிருந்து பிரித்தெடுக்கப்படுவது, தேயிலை மர எண்ணெய். இது பொடுகை உருவாக்கக்கூடிய கிருமிகளை எதிர்த்து போராடக்கூடியது. கூந்தலுக்கு ஊட்டச்சத்தை அளித்து, முடி உதிர்வையும் தவிர்க்க உதவும். டீ ட்ரீ எண்ணெயைச் சில துளிகள் எடுத்து, தலை முழுக்கத் தடவி, ஐந்து நிமிடங்கள் ஊறவைக்க வேண்டும். பிறகு ஷாம்பூ போட்டுக் குளிக்கலாம்.ஆப்பிள் சிடர் வினிகர் - பொடுகு மருந்துஆப்பிள் சிடர் வினிகர் பெரிய கடைகளில் கிடைக்கும். சிறிது ஆப்பிள் சிடர் வினிகரை எடுத்து, அதனுடன் சம அளவு தண்ணீர் சேர்த்துக் கலந்துகொள்ள வேண்டும். இதை தலையில் தேய்த்து ஊறவைக்க வேண்டும். இருபது நிமிடங்கள் கழித்து தலையை அலசிவிட வேண்டும். இது பொடுகுக்கு சிறந்த மருந்து; முடி உதிர்வைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தும்.வெந்தயம்இரண்டு டீஸ்பூன் வெந்தயத்தை ஊறவைக்கவும். மறுநாள் அதை அரைத்துக்கொள்ளவும். இதை தலையில் தேய்த்து, அரை மணி நேரம் ஊறவைத்து தலைக்குக் குளிக்கவும். இது உடல் உஷ்ணத்தைக் குறைக்கும்; முடி வளர்ச்சிக்கு உதவும்.வெங்காயம்வெங்காயத்தை அரைத்து தலையில் தடவி, 30 நிமிடங்களுக்கு ஊறவைக்கவும். பிறகு தலைக்குக் குளித்தால், பொடுகுத் தொல்லையில் இருந்து விடுபடலாம். வேப்பிலை கசப்பு... பாக்டீரியாவுக்கு எதிரி!கைப்பிடி வேப்பிலைகளை பேஸ்ட்போல அரைத்துக்கொள்ளவும். இதைத் தலையில் தேய்த்து ஊறவைத்து, 10 நிமிடங்கள் கழித்துக் குளிக்கவும். இதன் கசப்பு தன்மை, தலையில் உள்ள பாக்டீரியா போன்ற தலைமுடிக்குத் தீங்கிழைக்கும் நுண்ணியிரிகளை அழித்துவிடும்.ஆரஞ்சு தோல்ஆரஞ்சு தோல்களை நன்கு அரைத்துக்கொள்ளவும். இதனுடன் சிறிது எலுமிச்சைச் சாற்றைச் சேர்த்துக்கொள்ளவும். இதைத் தலையில் தேய்த்து, 30 நிமிடங்கள் ஊறவைத்து பிறகு குளித்தால், பொடுகுத் தொல்லை நீங்கும்.மருதாணி இலை கைப்பிடி மருதாணி இலைகளை அரைத்து, அதில் சிறிது தயிர் மற்றும் எலுமிச்சைச் சாறு சேர்த்துக்கொள்ளவும். இதைத் தலைமுடியில் நன்றாகத் தேய்க்கவும். இரண்டு மணி நேரம் ஊறவைக்கவும். பின்னர் கூந்தலை அலசி, குளிக்கலாம். இதனால் பொடுகுத் தொல்லை நீங்கும்; நரை முடி பிரச்னைக்கும் தீர்வு கிடைக்கும். சைனஸ், ஒற்றைத் தலைவலி, சளி பிடிக்கும் பிரச்னை ஆகியோர் தவிர்க்கவும்."},{"question":"Napisz kontynuację:  W roku 1991 przeprowadził się z obwodu oszyńskiego, gdzie się urodził, do stolicy Kirgistanu, Biszkeku. Tutaj nauczył się gry w szachy, w krótkim czasie osiągając poziom mistrzowski. W 1998 roku, mając 13 lat, zadebiutował w drużynie narodowej na","answer":"szachowej olimpiadzie w Eliście, uzyskując na VI szachownicy 6½ pkt w 9 partiach oraz po raz pierwszy odnosząc zwycięstwo nad arcymistrzem, którym był Wiktor Kuprejczyk. W następnym roku zdobył tytuł mistrza Azji juniorów do lat 16. Sukcesy te zwróciły uwagę prezydenta Międzynarodowej Federacji Szachowej Kirsana Iljumżynowa, który zaprosił Inarkiewa wraz z rodziną do Kałmucji i zaczął go wspierać finansowo, m.in. zapewniając stałą opiekę trenerską Marka Dworeckiego. W 2000 po raz drugi wystąpił w drużynie Kirgistanu na olimpiadzie w Stambule, uzyskując na IV szachownicy 9 pkt w 14 partiach. Od tego też roku w rozgrywkach międzynarodowych reprezentuje barwy Rosji."},{"question":"নিন্মলিখিত অনুচ্ছেদের সারাংশ লেখ:জীবনের কল্যাণের জন্য, মানুষের সুখের জন্য এ জগতে যিনি কথা বলিয়া থাকেন তাহাই সাহিত্য।বাতাসের উপর কথা ও চিন্তা স্থায়ী হইতে পারে না মানব জাতি তাই অক্ষর আবিষ্কার করিয়াছে। মানুষের মূল্যবান কথা, উৎকৃষ্ট চিন্তাগুলি কোন যুগে পাথরে, কোন যুগে গাছের পাতায় এবং বর্তমানে কাগজে লিখিয়া রাখা হইয়া থাকে। যে নিতান্তই হতভাগা সেই সাহিত্যকে অনাদর করিয়া থাকে। সাহিত্যে মানুষের সকল আখাঙ্ক্ষার মীমাংসা হয়। তোমার আত্মা হইতে যেমন তুমি বিচ্ছিন্ন হইতে পার না, সাহিত্যকেও তেমনি তুমি অস্বীকার করিতে পার না উহাতে তোমার মৃত্যু, তোমার দুঃখ ও অসম্মান হয়।","answer":"মানব কল্যাণে ও সুখের নিমিত্তে সুবিন্যস্ত কথামালার স্থায়িত্ব দেওয়ার জন্য লেখকগণ অক্ষর আবিষ্কার করেন। কালের পরিক্রমায় মানুষের মূল্যবান বাণী, উৎকৃষ্ট চিন্তা ও গবেষণা বিবর্তনের ধারাবাহিকতায় প্রস্তরখ খন্ডে, গাছের পাতায়, পশুর চামড়ায়, কাগজে, লিপিবদ্ধ হচ্ছে। সাহিত্য হিসেবে বিবেচিত সকল কথামালা জাতিসত্ত্বার আখাঙ্ক্ষারই প্রতিচ্ছবি। যার অপ্রয়োজনীয়তা অনুভব মূর্খতার শামিল।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kerbau punya susu, sapi dapat nama'?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah pihak lain yang mendapat kepujian walaupun seseorang bersusah payah melakukan sesuatu. "},{"question":"Hãy viết một bài báo có thể sử dụng tiêu đề này: \\"Đại gia bất động sản Trung Quốc Country Garden tìm cách tránh vỡ nợ\\"","answer":"Country Garden đang huy động vốn để tránh vỡ nợ, trong bối cảnh nhà đầu tư lo ngại khủng hoảng thanh khoản địa ốc lan ra khắp Trung Quốc.Hôm 30/8, hãng bất động sản Trung Quốc Country Garden cho biết có kế hoạch phát hành 350 triệu cổ phiếu với giá 0,77 đôla Hong Kong (0,1 USD). Tổng giá trị số cổ phiếu là 270 triệu HKD (34,4 triệu USD).Country Garden sẽ không nhận tiền từ giao dịch này. Thay vào đó, chúng sẽ được dùng để trả cho chủ nợ của họ là Kingboard Holdings – một hãng sản xuất nhựa tổng hợp ở Hong Kong (Trung Quốc).Động thái trên cho thấy nỗ lực mới nhất của Country Garden nhằm huy động tiền và trấn an nhà đầu tư. Năm ngoái, họ là hãng bất động sản lớn nhất Trung Quốc về doanh số.Rắc rối tài chính của Country Garden trở thành tâm điểm gần đây. Hồi đầu tháng, họ lỡ hạn thanh toán lãi suất hai lô trái phiếu trị giá 22,5 triệu USD. Nhà đầu tư lo ngại nếu vỡ nợ, Country Garden sẽ giáng thêm đòn vào niềm tin vốn đang mong manh của nhà đầu tư. Việc này lại diễn ra trong bối cảnh giới chức Trung Quốc nỗ lực giải cứu bất động sản – chìa khóa cho tăng trưởng kinh tế nước này.Vài tuần trước, Country Garden thông báo sẽ ngừng giao dịch 11 lô trái phiếu trong nước kể từ ngày 14/8. Khi đó, giới truyền thông Trung Quốc đưa tin Country Garden chuẩn bị tái cấu trúc nợ. Chỉ riêng tháng 9, Country Garden cần phải trả hơn 9 tỷ nhân dân tệ (1,25 tỷ USD) trái phiếu nội địa.Tuần trước, công ty này dời thời hạn biểu quyết cho các trái chủ từ 25/8 sang 31/8. Họ sẽ phải bỏ phiếu về kế hoạch gia hạn trả nợ 3,9 tỷ nhân dân tệ trái phiếu của Country Garden.Đầu tuần này, Country Garden cho biết dự án 100 tỷ USD của họ tại Malaysia \\"vẫn đang hoạt động bình thường\\". Đây là dự án lớn nhất của họ tại nước ngoài. Country Garden khẳng định hoạt động của mình tại đây \\"vẫn an toàn và ổn định\\". Thông báo này, cùng việc Trung Quốc công bố chính sách hỗ trợ bất động sản, đã giúp cổ phiếu Country Garden tăng giá tại Hong Kong.Hãng hôm nay dự kiến công bố lợi nhuận nửa đầu năm. Nhà đầu tư đang chờ đợi báo cáo chi tiết về dòng tiền và cách công ty này đối mặt với vấn đề nợ khổng lồ của công ty."},{"question":"what is the capital of KSA?","answer":"Riyadh known as Hajr al-Yamamah is the capital of KSA."},{"question":"క్రింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండి: భారతదేశాన్ని ఉత్తర, దక్షిణ భాగాలుగా విభజించే జాతీయ రహదారి?","answer":"ఎన్.హెచ్. - 6"},{"question":"Ṣe àpilẹ̀kọ àyọkà fún àkòrí yìí: Anthony Joshua àti Pulev: Ẹ̀bùn ọdún Kérésìmesì ni àseyọrí Joshua lẹ́yìn tó na Pulev lálùbolẹ̀ - Dàpọ̀ Abíọ́dún.","answer":"Gómínà ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn, Dàpọ̀ Abíọ́dún ti kí abẹ̀ṣẹ́kùbíòjò, Anthony Joshua kú oríire l'ẹ́yìn tó borí ojúgbà rẹ̀ l'áti orílẹ̀-èdè Bulgaria, Kubrat Pulev ní gbàgede SSE Arena nì ìlú London lálẹ́ ọjọ́ Àbámẹ́ta. Nínú àtẹ̀jáde kan tí agbẹnusọ rẹ̀, Kúnlé Sọ́mọrín fi léde, Abíọ́dún ní Joshua gbé ògo ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn ga. Gẹ́gẹ́ bí ohun tí gómínà náà sọ, ó ní ẹ̀bùn ńlá ni àṣeyọrí náà jẹ́, àti pé yóò tún jẹ́ ohun ìwúrí fún àwọn ẹlòmíràn l'áti tẹpá mọ́ ohunkóhun tí wọ́n bá yàn láàyò. Àtẹ̀jáde náà ni \\"gbogbo wa ní ìpínlẹ̀ yìí ni a gbàdúrà fún àṣeyọrí rẹ̀ láì wo ti ẹ̀sìn. Mo le ka àṣeyọrí ńlá tó wáyé lálẹ́ àná ní London gẹ́gẹ́ bí ẹ̀bùn ọdún Kérésìmesì l'áti ọ̀dọ̀ Ọlọ́run àti Anthony Joshua fún gbogbo wa ní ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn.\\" Abíọ́dún ṣ'àlàyé pé Anthony Joshua, tó tún jẹ́ ọmọ bíbí ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn ti gbé ògo Nàìjíríà ga, ó sì tún fi han àwọn èèyàn pé orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà ṣì máa borí gbogbo ìdojúkọ tó ń là kọjá. Gómínà náà sọ pé ádùrá àwọn èèyàn ló ń gbà l'órí abẹ̀ṣẹ́kùbíòjò náà tí adé IBF, WBA àti WBO kò tíì fi bọ́ mọ lọ́wọ́. Nígbà tó ń sọ̀rọ̀ l'ójú òpó Twitter rẹ̀, Abíọ́dún fi kun pé àṣeyọrí náà ti fi hàn pé gbogbo owó tí ìjọba ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn ná àti akitiyan rẹ̀ l'órí eré ìdárayá kò lọ lásán. Alẹ́ ọjọ́ Àbámẹ́ta, ọjọ́ kejìlá, oṣù Ọ̀pẹ ọdún 2020, ni ìjà náà wáyé ní gbàgede SSE Arena, ní ìlú London, níbi tí Joshua ti fi ẹ̀ṣẹ́ já Pulev bọ́ bí àpò ìrẹsì. Yàtọ̀ sí Abíọ́dún, Ààrẹ Muhammadu Buhari náà ti kí Joshua kú oríire àṣeyọrí ọ̀hún."},{"question":"Unogona here kuronga kuti timu yega yega yeNFL inodaidzwa nezita?","answer":"\\"Arizona Cardinals - MhukaAtlanta Falcons - MhukaBaltimore Ravens - MhukaMabhiri eBuffalo - Akatumidzwa zita reBuffalo Bill CodyCarolina Panthers - MhukaChicago Bears - MhukaCincinnati Bengals - MhukaCleveland Browns - Akatumidzwa mushure meMurairidzi Mukuru Paul BrownDallas Cowboys - Yakatumidzwa zita revarume vanofudza mombeDenver Broncos - MhukaDetroit Shumba - MhukaGreen Bay Packers - Yakatumidzwa mushure mekutanga mutsigiri wechikwata, Indian Packing CompanyHouston Texans - Yakatumidzwa zita revanhu vanogara muTexasIndianapolis Colts - MhukaJacksonville Jaguars - MhukaKansas City Chiefs - Yakatumidzwa zita reaimbova meya weKansas CityLas Vegas Raiders - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu anorwisa muvengi wavoLos Angeles Charger - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu anoenda kumberi nesimba uye nesimbaLos Angeles Rams - MhukaMiami Dolphins - MhukaMinnesota Vikings - Yakatumidzwa zita reboka revanhu vanobva kuScandinaviaNew England Patriots - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu anotsigira nyika yavoNew Orleans Saints - Inonzi mushure memunhu uyo zvitendero zvinoziva semutsvene uye akanakaNew York Giants - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu wehukuru hwakasiyanaNew York Jets - Yakatumidzwa zita rejet ndegePhiladelphia Eagles - MhukaPittsburgh Steelers - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu anoshanda mufekitori yesimbiSan Francisco 49ers - Yakatumidzwa zita remunhu akatora chikamu muGoridhe RushSeattle Seahawks - MhukaTampa Bay Buccaneers - Yakatumidzwa mushure memuparadziTennessee Titans - Inonzi zita remunhu ane simba kwazvoWashington Commanders - Anonzi mushure memunhu muuto\\""},{"question":"أريد أن أعلِّم صفي عن موضوع الشباب (مجلة). هل يمكنك أن تكتب لي مقالاً يمكنني أن أعطيهم لقراءته كواجب منزلي؟ يجب أن تجيب متى صدرت النسخة الأولى لمجلة الشباب ؟ ، وتكون باللغة العربية  وتكون رسمية. لو سمحت.","answer":"صدر العدد الأول من المجلة عام 1977 وكان اسمها وقتها مجلة الشباب وعلوم المستقبل وكانت تعني بالمجالات العلمية فقط إلى أن أصبحت متنوعة بعد ذلك ليتغير اسمها إلى مجلة الشباب وتعد المجلة الأكثر توزيعا في فئتها في مصر"},{"question":"曹植的个人品质如何？","answer":"答：曹植被誉为“文帝”，他温文尔雅，善良仁慈，深受人民的敬爱。"},{"question":"ගණිතයේ ප්‍රධාන ශාඛා මොනවා ​ද?","answer":"ගණිතයේ ප්‍රධාන ශාඛා පහත දැක්වේ.වීජගණිතයවිශ්ලේෂණයව්‍යවහාරික ගණිතයකලනයජ්‍යාමිතියසම්භාවිතාවකුලක වාදයසංඛ්‍යානයස්ථල විද්‍යාවත්‍රිකෝණමිතිය"},{"question":"Dime cuál es el tema principal o categoría de esta pregunta: ¿El último libro de Harry Potter salió antes del 2010?","answer":"La categoría de esta pregunta es literatura. "},{"question":"จงเติมข้อความดังต่อไปนี้ให้ครบด้วยคำเดียว - เกิด แก่ เจ็บ ","answer":"ตาย"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ॥ਕਿਰਤੁ ਪਇਆ ਨਹ ਮੇਟੈ ਕੋਇ ॥ਕਿਆ ਜਾਣਾ ਕਿਆ ਆਗੈ ਹੋਇ ॥ਜੋ ਤਿਸੁ ਭਾਣਾ ਸੋਈ ਹੂਆ ॥ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕਰਣੈ ਵਾਲਾ ਦੂਆ ॥੧॥ਨਾ ਜਾਣਾ ਕਰਮ ਕੇਵਡ ਤੇਰੀ ਦਾਤਿ ॥ਕਰਮੁ ਧਰਮੁ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਮ ਕੀ ਜਾਤਿ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਤੂ ਏਵਡੁ ਦਾਤਾ ਦੇਵਣਹਾਰੁ ॥ਤੋਟਿ ਨਾਹੀ ਤੁਧੁ ਭਗਤਿ ਭੰਡਾਰ ॥ਕੀਆ ਗਰਬੁ ਨ ਆਵੈ ਰਾਸਿ ॥ਜੀਉ ਪਿੰਡੁ ਸਭੁ ਤੇਰੈ ਪਾਸਿ ॥੨॥ਤੂ ਮਾਰਿ ਜੀਵਾਲਹਿ ਬਖਸਿ ਮਿਲਾਇ ॥ਜਿਉ ਭਾਵੀ ਤਿਉ ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪਾਇ ॥ਤੂੰ ਦਾਨਾ ਬੀਨਾ ਸਾਚਾ ਸਿਰਿ ਮੇਰੈ ॥ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਦੇਇ ਭਰੋਸੈ ਤੇਰੈ ॥੩॥ਤਨ ਮਹਿ ਮੈਲੁ ਨਾਹੀ ਮਨੁ ਰਾਤਾ ॥ਗੁਰ ਬਚਨੀ ਸਚੁ ਸਬਦਿ ਪਛਾਤਾ ॥ਤੇਰਾ ਤਾਣੁ ਨਾਮ ਕੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਰਹਣਾ ਭਗਤਿ ਸਰਣਾਈ ॥੪॥੧੦॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 154 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਨਮਾਂ ਜਨਮਾਂਤਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਸੰਸਕਾਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਮੂਹ ਜੋ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ (ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ) ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਮਿਟਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ । (ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਅਗਾਂਹ ਲਈ ਭੀ ਕਰਮ-ਧਰਮ ਤੋਂ ਚੰਗੇ ਨਤੀਜੇ ਦੀ ਆਸ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਹੈ) ਕੋਈ ਸਮਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ਕਿ ਆਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਜੀਵਨ-ਸਮੇ ਵਿਚ ਕੀਹ ਵਾਪਰੇਗਾ । (ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਛੱਡੋ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਤੁਰਨਾ ਸਿੱਖੋ) ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਕੁਝ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ (ਉਸੇ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰੋ) ।੧। ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਠੀਕ ਕੀਮਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਣਦਾ (ਮੈਂ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਮਹੱਤਤਾ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ), (ਦੂਜੇ ਪਾਸੇ, ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਤੇਰੀਆਂ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਦਾਤਾਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭੀ ਮੈਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਮਝ ਸਕਦਾ (ਇਹ ਖ਼ਿਆਲ ਕਰਨਾ ਮੇਰੀ ਭਾਰੀ ਭੁੱਲ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੇਰੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ । ਇਹ ਤਾਂ ਤੇਰੀ ਨਿਰੋਲ ਮਿਹਰ ਹੈ ਮਿਹਰ) । ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਮੇਰੀ ਜਾਤਿ ਹੈ, ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਮੇਰਾ ਕਰਮ-ਧਰਮ ਹੈ (ਮੈਨੂੰ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਓਟ ਹੈ । ਨਾਹ ਮਾਣ ਹੈ ਕਿਸੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਕਰਮ-ਧਰਮ ਦਾ, ਨਾਹ ਕਿਸੇ ਉੱਚੀ ਜਾਤਿ ਦਾ) ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੂੰ ਦਾਤਾਂ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਇਤਨਾ ਵੱਡਾ ਦਾਤਾ ਹੈਂ (ਭਗਤੀ ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਭੀ ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ) ਤੇਰੇ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਭਗਤੀ (ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ) ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਘਾਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ, (ਆਪਣੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੰਗੇ ਆਚਰਨ ਬਾਰੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ) ਕੀਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਕੁਝ ਸਵਾਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ, ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਜਿੰਦ ਤੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਤੇਰੇ ਹੀ ਆਸਰੇ ਹੈ । (ਜਿਵੇਂ ਤੂੰ ਸਰੀਰ ਦੀ ਪਰਵਰਿਸ਼ ਲਈ ਰੋਜ਼ੀ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤਿਵੇਂ ਜਿੰਦ ਨੂੰ ਭੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਦੀ ਖ਼ੁਰਾਕ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਹੈਂ) ।੨। (ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਦੇ ਕੇ, ਮੇਰੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ, ਮੇਰਾ ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਮਾਰ ਕੇ, ਤੇ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਭਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਾ ਕੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ । ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰੇ ਦਿਲ ਦੀ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ (ਮੇਰੀ ਹਾਲਤ) ਵੇਖਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਿਰ ਉੱਤੇ (ਰਾਖਾ) ਹੈਂ, ਮੈਂ ਸਦਾ ਤੇਰੇ ਹੀ ਆਸਰੇ ਹਾਂ (ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ) ।੩। (ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਨ (ਤੇਰੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ) ਰੰਗਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੈਲ ਨਹੀਂ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਬਚਨਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਤੁਰ ਕੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਪਛਾਣ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ (ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾ ਲਈ ਹੈ), (ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਲੈਣ ਦੇ ਥਾਂ) ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! (ਆਖ—) ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਤੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੪।੧੦।\\""},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kuman di seberang lautan tampak, gajah bertengger di pelupuk mata tiada tampak'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kesalahan (keburukan) orang dapat dilihat tetapi kesalahan sendiri tidak disedari"},{"question":"Asa ka nagskwela?","answer":"Nagskwela ko sa Xavier University."},{"question":"من هو الصحابي الملقب بمزعج الأصنام ؟","answer":"بلال بن رباح"},{"question":"Ga-i ko ug mga recipes nga ma himo nimo gamit ang pan, butter, mga itlog, ug cheese nga gamit pud ko stovetop, toaster, ug frying pan.","answer":"Nia ray mga recipes na ma imong mahimo gamit ang mga ingredients ug tools imong gi mention.1. Grilled cheese ug sunny-side up na itlog:Ipa init ang imong frying pan sa ibabaw sa stove. Magpa-init ug gamay na butter sa frying pan hangtod ma lanay unya pag butang ug duha ka slices of pan ug ipag-tapad ang duha sa pan. Ibutang ang cheese sa isa ka kilid sa pan ug painita hangtod ang pan mahimong crispy ug malanay ang cheese. Pag-human, e cover ang slice sa pan nga naay nalanay nga cheese sa isa ka slice na pan unya kuha-i sa frying pan.Hinay-hinayi ug buak ang itlog ug ibutang sa frying pan. Luto-i ang itlog hangtod mu gahi ang mga egg-whites ayha nimo luto-i ang mga egg-yolk. Luto-i ang egg-yolk sa imong gusto na consistency.2. Toast ug cheese omelette:Ibutang ang pan sa toaster ug luto-i sa imong gusto na level. E spread ang butter sa gusto nimo nga amount sa pan. Ipa init ang frying pan sa ibabaw sa stove. Magpa init ug gamay na butter sa frying pan hangtud malanay. Samtang galanay pa ang butter, hinayhinayi ug buak ang itlog sa isa ka bowl ug e whisk. Ibutang ang na whisk nga mga itlog sa nainit na nga frying pan hangtod mugahi ang mga itlog. Ibutang ang cheese sa itlog ug e pilo.3. Scrambled eggs with toast:Pag butang ug pan sa taoster ug e luto sa imong gusto na level. E spread ang butter sa pan sa imong gusto.Ipa init ang frying pan sa ibabaw sa stove. Painit ug gamay na butter sa frying pan hangtud malanay. Samtang ga lanay ang butter, hinayhinay ug buak ang mga itlog sa bowl ug e whisk. Ibutang ang na whisk na mga itlog sa init na frying pan ug mix ug ayo. Ibutang ang cheese sa pan ug padayon ug mix hangtod mu set ang mga itlog."},{"question":"మీకు తెలిసిన వీరవనితల గురించి రాయండి.","answer":"రాణి రుద్రమదేవి :కాకతీయుల వంశంలో ఒక ధృవతారగా వెలిగిన మహారాణి రుద్రమదేవి. కాకతీయ వంశానికి గొప్ప పేరు ప్రఖ్యాతులు తెచ్చిన వీరవనిత. భారతదేశ చరిత్రలో రాజ్యా లను పరిపాలించిన వీరవనితలలో అగ్రగణ్యురాలు రుద్రమదేవి.ఈమె అసలు పేరు రుద్రాంబ. ఈమె తండ్రి గణపతిదేవ చక్రవర్తి. ఆయనకు మగపిల్లలు లేరు. అందుచేత రుద్రాంబను కుమారుడిలా పెంచాడు. రుద్రదేవుడని నామకరణం చేశాడు. ఆమెను వీరభద్రుడికిచ్చి వివాహం చేశాడు.క్రీ.శ. 1269లో ‘రుద్రమహారాజు’ అనే బిరుద నామంతో రుద్రమదేవి సింహాసనం అధిష్టించింది. స్త్రీని. పరిపాలకురాలిగా అంగీకరించని సామంతులు కొందరు తిరుగుబాటు చేశారు. రుద్రమ వారిని సమర్థవంతంగా అణచివేసింది. దేవిగిరి రాజుతో చేసిన యుద్ధం చాలా పెద్దది. కీలకమైనది. దిక్కు లేక అతను సంధికి దిగి వచ్చి మూడుకోట్ల సువర్ణాలు యుద్ధ పరిహారంగా ఇచ్చాడు. రుద్రమదేవికి రాయగజ కేసరి, ఘటోధృతి అనే బిరుదులున్నాయి. మార్కొపోలో రుద్రమ గురించి వివరంగా వ్రాశాడు. చక్కటి పరిపాలన నందించిన వీరవనిత రుద్రమదేవి.ఝాన్సీ లక్ష్మీబాయి :ఝాన్సీ లక్ష్మీబాయి 1828 నవంబరు 19న మహారాష్ట్రలో సతారలో జన్మించింది. ఆమె తల్లిదండ్రులు మోరోపంత్ తాంబే, భాగీరథీబాయి. వీరిది సంప్రదాయ బ్రాహ్మణ కుటుంబం. ఆమె చిన్నప్పటి పేరు మణికర్ణిక. ముద్దుగా ‘మను’ అని పిలిచేవారు. ఆమె 4వ ఏటనే తల్లి మరణించింది. చిన్నతనంలోనే గుర్రపు ” స్వారీ, కత్తియుద్ధం నేర్చుకొంది.ఆమెను 13వ ఏట ఝాన్సీ రాజు గంగాధరరావు ఆమెను పెండ్లాడాడు. గంగాధరరావు మరణానంతరం ఝాన్సీని బ్రిటిషువారు కైవసం చేసుకోవాలనుకొన్నారు. కాని లక్ష్మీబాయి అంగీకరించలేదు. తిరుగుబాటు చేసింది. బ్రిటిషువారికి కంటిమీద కునుకు లేకుండా గెరిల్లా పోరాటాలు చేసింది. చివరకు బ్రిటిషువారి దుర్మార్గానికి 1858 జూన్ 18న గ్వాలియర్లో మరణించింది. ఆమె తండ్రిని బ్రిటిషువారు ఉరితీశారు. ఆమె వారసుడిగా దామోదర్ రావుని ప్రకటించారు."},{"question":"Розшифруй формули речовин А, В, С, D та Х в задачі, враховуючи, що на нейтралізацію розчину 0.0968 г одноосновної кислоти Х витрачається 15.00 мл розчину NaOH з концентрацією 0.150 моль/л.Задача \\"Вибухонебезпечні речовини А і В, які є бінарними сполуками, мають однаковий якісний, але різний кількісний склади. Сполука А є червоно-помаранчевою рідиною, а В – темно-червоними кристалами. Речовину А можна отримати взаємодією срібної солі кислоти Х з простою речовиною С (Dповітря(C) = 5.511). Речовину В гіпотетично можна отримати шляхом взаємодії речовини С з речовиною D (DНе(D) = 4.255), проте із-за високої нестабільності В, що вибухає навіть при -100°С, її отримують складнішими способами.\\"","answer":"A – BrN3, B – NBr3, C – Br2, D – NH3, X – HN3."},{"question":"جمله اول: پدرش مهندس لولا بادر (1892 - 1945) بود ، مادرش پل فیشر (1905 - 1973) بود. جمله دوم: پدرش مهندس «پال فيشر» (1892 تا 1945) بود ، مادرش  «لولا بادر» (1905 تا 1973) بود. سوال: آیا جمله 1 و جمله 2 همان معنی را بیان می کنند؟ بله یا نه؟","answer":"نه."},{"question":" जैन धर्मातील सम्यक ज्ञान, सम्यक दर्शन व सम्यक चरित्र या त्रिरत्नांचा उपदेश देणाऱ्या वर्धमान महावीरांचा जन्म केव्हा झाला?","answer":"वर्धमान महावीर जयंती, ज्याच्या उपलक्ष्यात जैन धर्माच्या संस्थापक महावीर स्वामीचा जन्म होतो, हे परंपरागतपणे निर्धारित केले आहे की इ.स.पू. 599 मध्ये जैन धर्माच्या संस्थापक महावीर स्वामी यांचा जन्म झाला होता."},{"question":"أكمل العبارة التالية:  ومع ذلك، فإن فشل الجيش الأحمر في","answer":"الحملة البولندية قد وضع خطط الثورة البلشفية في الانتظار. في الوقت نفسه، اتبعت شخصية جوزيف ستالين المتنامية أجندة مختلفة. رأى لينين إنشاء جمهوريات وطنية كميزة دائمة تمشيا مع سياساته. في ربيع عام 1922، عانى لينين من سكتة دماغية أولى، وحصل ستالين، الذي لا يزال مفوضًا شعبيًا للقوميات، على كرسي رسمي جديد كأمين عام للحزب الشيوعي."},{"question":"Emi kọ ni mo dẹ tọọgi sawọn to n ṣewọde SARS l’Alausa- Sanwo-Olu","answer":"Gomina Babajide Oluṣọla Sanwo-Olu tipinlẹ Eko ti sọ pe ijọba oun kọ lo dẹ tọọgi sawọn to n ṣewọde SARS ni Alausa, n’Ikẹja, laaarọ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee yii.Kọmiṣanna fun eto iroyin nipinlẹ Eko, Ọgbẹni Gbenga Ọmọtọṣọ lo sọrọ lorukọ Sanwo-Olu ninu atẹjade kan to fi ṣọwọ s’ALAROYE lori iṣẹlẹ ọhun. O ni awọn ọta gomina lo wa nidii ẹsun ọhun, tori eeyan alaafia ni Sanwo-Olu, ko si ran ẹnikẹni niṣẹ lati lọọ dabaru awọn to n ṣe iwọde naa, o ni ẹtọ awọn oluwọde naa ni wọn n ja fun, ofin ilẹ wa si faaye gba wọn lati fi ero ati imọlara wọn han.O ni Sanwo-Olu koro oju si ohun to waye laaarọ yii, o si fọkan awọn araalu balẹ pe ijọba yoo ri i pe aabo to peye wa fawọn to n sẹ iwọde ọhun.Atẹjade naa fi kun un pe Sanwo-Olu yoo ba awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Eko sọrọ ni aago marun-un irọlẹ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, lori iṣẹlẹ yii ati iwọde to n lọ lọwọ naa.Bakan naa ni alaga ẹgbẹ awọn onimọto, NURTW, l’Ekoo, Ọgbẹni Musiliu Akinsanya ti inagijẹ rẹ n jẹ MC Oluọmọ, ti sọ pe oun ko mọ ohunkohun nipa bawọn janduku ṣe de ọdọ awọn to n ṣe iwọde ọhun.Nigba to n sọrọ niwaju geeti ile-igbimọ aṣofin, nibi tawọn oluwọde naa parojọ si, o ni ẹsẹkẹsẹ toun gbọ nipa iṣẹlẹ naa loun ti ke si awọn alakooso ẹgbẹ onimọto to ku, eyi lo si mu koun wa, lati le awọn janduku naa kuro.Ṣugbọn ọpọ awọn oluwọde naa sọ pe irọ ni ijọba ipinlẹ Eko ati Oluọmọ n pa. Ọgbẹni Oluwaṣeyi Ayọọla to ba akọroyin wa sọrọ sọ pe bawo lawọn janduku naa ṣe ri mọto BRT ijọba lo ti ko ba jẹ ijọba lo ran wọn niṣẹ, tori inu mọto naa ni gbogbo wọn ti rọ jade pẹlu ada, kumọ, igi, okuta ati aake, ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i le awọn eeyan kijokijo.Ayọọla ni ṣebi kamẹra to n rikọọdu ohun to ba ṣẹlẹ ninu ati layiika wa lara bọọsi BRT kọọkan, o ni kijọba ṣafihan ohun ti kamẹra bọọsi naa ka silẹ han gbogbo aye, ti ki i baa ṣe pe awọn ni wọn yọnda bọọsi ọhun fun wọn.Ṣa, awọn ọdọ rẹpẹtẹ kan ta a gbọ pe agbegbe Ikorodu ni wọn ti wa, ti dara pọ mọ awọn to n ṣe iwọde naa bayii, lẹyin ti awọn janduku naa ti lọ.Pẹlu orin, ilu, ijo ati akọle oriṣiiriṣii, awọn oluwọde naa ti lọọ ti ọna marosẹ Eko si Ibadan pa, bẹẹ ni wọn si gbe igi dina awọn ọna mi-in to gba agbegbe Alausa kọja, wọn ni ko sẹni to maa ni kawọn ma fi ero awọn han si aidaa tawọn ọlọpaa SARS ti ṣe."},{"question":"GARASHADA GUUSHA!","answer":"Marka ay timaaddo qeexidda kelmedda ‘guul’ waxaad arkaysaa in qof walba uu ku bees gareeynayo aragtidiisa, waana arrin dib ugu laabanaya kala duwanaanshaha bini’aadamka. Si kale u dhig, sida ay wejiyadeenu u kala duwan yihiin ayay maskaxdeennuna u kala duwan tahay; sida ay maskaxdeenu u kala duwan tahay ayay aragtideennuna u kala duwan yihiin; sida ay aragtideenu u kala duwan yihiin ayay qeexitaankeena guushana u kala duwan yihiin. Waxaa la sheegaa Bill gates in uu yahay ninka dunida ugu taajirsan, isagana wuxuu isku arkaa in uu yahay guulayste liibaanay, balse aniga iyo adiga waxaan u aragnaa in uu yahay qof aan weli ku guulaysan guusha dhabta ah ee waaraysa. Dhanka kale, saxaabiga Cumar Binu Khadaab, annaga waxaan u aragnaa in uu yahay qof adduunyo iyo aakhiraba ku guulaystay, balse waxaa jira dad u arka in uusan guulaysan. Sababtu maxay tahay? Waxa adiga guul kuu ah dadka kale guul uma aha! Haddaba, si aan wax badan uga ogaado sida ay dhallinyarada u arkaan macneha guusha ayaan weyddiin la xiriirta guusha ku qoray bogga aan ku leeyahay barta xiriirka bulshada ee faysbuug (Facebook). Weyddiintu waxay u qorneed sidan: Waa Maxay guul? Dadka intooda badan waxay kaga soo warceliyeen siyaabo kala duwan, balse waxaan ka soo dhex xushay shan warcelinood oo kala ah: -1. Guushu waa hadafkaaga oo aad gaarto. 2. Guushu waa gaarista yoolkaaga; waa helitaanka nolol dhammaystiran, adduunyo iyo aakhiraba ku anfacaysa. 3. Guushu waa in shakhsi ama ummad yeelato yool, kuna dadaasho yoolkooda, kana mirodhaliso.  4. Guushu waa hadafkaaga oo aad ka run sheegto. 5. Guushu waa kelmed soo koobaysa wax si wanaagsan u qabsoomay, ugu dambeyntiina ku dhammaaday heer sare."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kasih itu roh yang buta'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kasih itu tidak memilih yang baik atau yang cantik sahaja"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：以下哪位是中國著名女演員？(a) 趙薇 (b) 劉亦菲 (c) 張曼玉 (d) 梁詠琪","answer":"答案：(b) 劉亦菲"},{"question":"マルの中にバツの記号は電気回路図ではランプ。では地図記号では何を表わすでしょう？","answer":"警察署です。"},{"question":"How has Sri Lanka's commitment to wildlife conservation positively influenced global efforts to protect endangered species and biodiversity?","answer":"Sri Lanka's commitment to wildlife conservation has had a positive influence on global efforts to protect endangered species and biodiversity. Conservation programs for iconic species like elephants and leopards have gained international recognition. By showcasing successful conservation models, Sri Lanka contributes valuable insights to the global community, inspiring collaborative efforts to safeguard biodiversity and preserve natural ecosystems."},{"question":"¿En qué año tuvo lugar el accidente de la central nuclear de Chernóbil? ","answer":"En 1986 una explosión en la central nuclear de Chernóbil propagó una nube radioactiva en gran parte de lo que fue la Unión Soviética y que ahora son los territorios de Belarús, Ucrania y la Federación de Rusia."},{"question":"Jamiu ba aṣẹwo lo pọ tan, lo ba gun un lọbẹ pa l’Abẹokuta","answer":"Jamiu Malọmọ lọmọkunrin yii n jẹ, ọmọ ọdun mejidinlogun pere ni (18), ṣugbọn ni bayii, o ti wa lẹka ti wọn ti n gbọ ẹjọ awọn apaayan nipinlẹ Ogun, nitori niṣe lo gun aṣẹwo to ba lo pọ lọbẹ lọrun, o si ri i daju pe o ku patapata.Ohun to ṣẹlẹ gan-an gẹgẹ bi DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi ṣe fi to wa leti ni pe lọjọ kejidinlogun, oṣu keje, ọdun 2021 yii, Alaga agbegbe Ilupeju, Oke-Arẹgba, mu ẹjọ lọ si teṣan ọlọpaa Adatan, pe niṣe lawọn ji ba oku ọmọbinrin kan lori apata to wa lagbegbe naa. O ni oju ibi ti wọn ti gun obinrin naa lọbẹ han ketekete, ọbẹ ti wọn si fi gun un pa naa wa lẹgbẹẹ rẹ nibẹ to kun fun ẹjẹ.Awọn ọlọpaa lọọ gbe oku naa, wọn gbe e lọ si mọṣuari ijọba to wa n’Ijaye, l’Abẹokuta. Lẹyin eyi ni wọn bẹrẹ iwadii to lagbara lati mọ ẹni to ku yii, ati bo ṣe rin irin ẹ to fi pari ẹ sori apata.Ninu iwadii ni wọn ti ri i daju pe ọmọkunrin yii, Jamiu Malọmọ, ni awọn eeyan ri gbẹyin pẹlu oloogbe naa. Ọjọbọ ti i ṣe ọjọ kejilelogun, oṣu keje, lọwọ si ba a nibi ile ọti kan to wa ni Panṣẹkẹ, l’Abẹokuta.Niṣe lo tiẹ tun fẹẹ gbe aṣẹwo mi-in nibi ti wọn ti mu un naa, iyẹn ni nnkan bii aago mejila oru ku iṣẹju mẹẹẹdogun. Nigba ti wọn mu un tan ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i da ibeere bo o, ọmọ ọdun mejidinlogun yii jẹwọ ohun to ṣe. Jamiu ṣalaye fawọn ọlọpaa pe oloṣo lọmọ to doloogbe yii, Azeezat Akande lo n jẹ. O ni oun gbe e lọ sile lọjọ naa lati ba a sun, iyẹn lẹyin tawọn pari ọrọ si ẹgbẹrun mẹwaa naira owo ibasun naa.Ọmọkunrin yii ṣalaye pe nigba toun ba a sun tan, aṣẹwo naa beere owo rẹ, oun si ko ẹgbẹrun mẹjọ naira fun un dipo mẹwaa tawọn jọ sọ koun too ba a ṣe pọ.O ni oloṣo naa yari pe afi kowo oun pe, eyi si di ariyanjiyan laarin awọn, eyi lo jẹ koun mu foonu oun fun un pe ko mu un dani na, ko si duro de oun loju ọna tawọn jọ wa lasiko toun fun un lowo naa, koun lọọ ba a mu ẹgbẹrun meji to ku wa nile.Nibi ti Azeezat ti n duro de e ni Jamiu ti de ẹyin rẹ lojiji, o si fi ọbẹ gun un lọrun to jẹ niṣe lọmọbinrin naa ku lẹsẹkẹsẹ. Bo ti huwa laabi naa tan lo sa lọ.Ṣugbọn nigba tọwọ ọlọpaa ti tẹ ẹ bayii, ọmọdekunrin yii ti wa lẹka awọn ti wọn fẹsun ipaniyan kan, ẹjọ ti yoo si lọọ jẹ ni kootu laipẹ naa niyẹn."},{"question":"Resm-i Arus vergisi nedir?","answer":"Evlenen kadınların erkeklerinden alınan vergi hakkında kullanılan bir tabirdir. Arus;Arapça \\"gelin\\" demektir.Bu vergi İslam ve gayrimüslime göre değiştiği gibi evlenen kadının kız veya dul oluşuna değişir."},{"question":"Inona no renivohitr'i Kanada?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Kanada dia Ottawa."},{"question":"اكتب قصة اليوم الأول لطفل في المدرسة الابتدائية.","answer":"كان الطفل الصغير يشعر بالحماس والخوف معًا، فقد كان هذا اليوم الأول له في المدرسة الابتدائية. كان يرتدي كنزة حمراء ساطعة وبنطلون أسود جديد، وحمل حقيبته الصغيرة على ظهره، ووجهه يبدو متوترًا بينما كان يمشي مع والداه نحو باب المدرسة.عندما دخل الفصل الدراسي الخاص به، وجد أن كل شيء جديد ومثير. كانت الصفوف مصفوفة بشكل مثالي، والطاولات والكراسي الصغيرة تظاهر بأنها بانتظار طالب جديد. تعرف الطفل على معلمته الجديدة، والتي كانت تشعر بنفس الحماس تجاه السنة الدراسية الجديدة.بدأت الدروس، وأصبح الفصل ممتلئًا بالكلام والأصوات. كان الطفل متحمسًا بشكل خاص لدرس الرياضيات، وهو ما وجد بعض الصعوبة في حل المسائل الجديدة، لكن فرحته عندما حل المسألة بنفسه كانت كبيرة جدًا.بعد الصلاة والغذاء، جاءت فترة الاستراحة، والتي كانت مناسبة للشاب لتكوين صداقات جديدة مع زملائه الجدد، واللعب معهم في الفناء الخارجي. بينما كان يلعب، وجد شخصين يلعبان بطريقة غريبة، حيث كانوا يستخدمون الإعداد الذهني لحل المسائل الرياضية بسرعة. سألهم يشير الانحدار - في علم الإحصاء وعلم الرياضيات - إلى العلاقة بين متغير مستقل ومتغير تابع. يمكن توضيح الفرق بين الانحدار الخطي والانحدار غير الخطي كما يلي: 1. الانحدار الخطي: الانحدار الخطي هو عندما تكون العلاقة بين المتغيرات بسيطة وثابتة. يعني ذلك أنه كلما زاد أو نقص أحد المتغيرين ، زاد أو نقص المتغير الآخر بنفس النسبة. مثلا ، إذا كانت المتغيرات هي الوزن والطول ، فإن الانحدار الخطي سيحدث إذا كان كل متر إضافي في الطول يزيد الوزن بكيلوغرام واحد.2. الانحدار الغير خطي:الانحدار الغير خطي هو عندما تكون العلاقة بين المتغيرات معقدة ولا تتبع قاعدة بسيطة. في هذه الحالة ، لا يمكن تمثيل العلاقة بخط مستقيم أو معادلة خطية. بل يكون للعلاقة شكل منحني أو متغير أو غير منتظم. وهذا يعني أن تغيير صغير في أحد المتغيرات قد يسبب تغيير كبير أو صغير أو لا شيء في المتغير الآخر. ومن الأمثلة على الانحدار الغير خطي هو الانحدار اللوجستي ، الذي يصف كيفية نمو السكان أو انتشار الأمراض أو غيرها من الظواهر التي تتأثر بالعوامل المحددة.عن هذا الأسلوب، وشرح لهم أنهم كانوا يحضّرون للمسابقة المدرسية القادمة.بمجرد انتهاء اليوم، خرج الطفل مع والديه من المدرسة، وكان يشعر بالرضا والاستيعاب بعد يوم أول رائع في المدرسة الابتدائية. كان يتطلع إلى المزيد من الأيام المثيرة والمليئة بالتحديات والفرص الجديدة."},{"question":"छत्रपती शाहूचा राज्यभिषेक कोठे झाला ?","answer":"सातारा येथे"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أكبر قارة في العالم؟","answer":"الإجابة: قارة آسيا"},{"question":"Ukara 1: Iki ditemokake ing sisih kidul-wétan Florida, Bahama, Kuba, Kepulauan Cayman, lan bisa uga ing pulau-pulau Karibia liyane. Ukara 2: Dumunung ing sisih kidul-wétan Florida, Kapuloan Cayman, Bahama, Kuba lan mbokmenawa ing pulo Karibia liyané. Pitakonan: Apa ukara 1 lan ukara 2 padha tegesé? Ya utawa Ora?","answer":"Ya"},{"question":"యువత – జీవన నైపుణ్యాలు గురించి వ్యాసం రాయండి.","answer":"ఒకదేశ అభివృద్ధి. ఆ దేశ యువత శక్తిసామర్థ్యాలపై ఆధారపడివుంటుంది. మెరుగైన సమాజ నిర్మాణంలో యువతీయువకులే కీలక పాత్ర పోషిస్తారు. యువతరం శిరమెత్తితే నవతరం గళమెత్తితే చీకటి మాసిపోతుందని, లోకం మారిపోతుందని కవులు ఉపదేశించారు. ఉక్కు నరాలు ఇనుప కండరాలు కలిగిన పదిమంది యువకులతో ఉన్నత సమాజాన్ని నిర్మించ వచ్చునని స్వామి వివేకానంద గొప్పభరోసాను అందించాడు.ప్రపంచంలో అత్యధిక సంఖ్యలో యువతీయువకులు కలిగిన దేశం భారతదేశం. ఉత్తుంగ తరంగాలతో పొటెత్తే నదికి ఆనకట్ట కట్టి, ఆ నదీజలాలతో బంగారు పంటలు పండించినట్లు, నెత్తురుమండే శక్తులు నిండే యువతీయువకులను సమర్థ మానవవనరులుగా తీర్చిదిద్ది ప్రగతి సిరులను పండించవచ్చు. యువతీయువకులు సునిశితమైన జీవన నైపుణ్యాలను సమకూర్చుకుంటే దేశ భావినిర్ణేతలుగా రాణిస్తారు. “We cannot always build the future for our youth, but we can build our youth for the future” అని ఫ్రాంక్ లిన్ డి. రూజ్ వెల్ట్ అన్నట్లుగా సమున్నతమైన భవితకోసం సమర్థవంతమైన యువతరం రూపొందాలి.జ్ఞానసముపార్జనతోపాటు ఆ జ్ఞానసంపదను సద్వినియోగ పరుచుకోవటానికి జీవన నైపుణ్యాలను పెంపొందింపజేసుకోవాలి. విద్యార్థులు, యువకులు పోటీ ప్రపంచంలో విజేతలుగా ఎదగడానికి, ఉత్తమ పౌరులుగా, నవ సమాజనిర్మాతలుగా రూపొందటానికి తగిన జీవన నైపుణ్యాలను విధిగా అలవర్చుకోవాలి.పరీక్షల్లో ఉత్తీర్ణులు కావటమే ప్రధానం కాదు, అవరోధాలను అధిగమించి, ఉపద్రవాలను సాహసోపేతంగా ఎదుర్కొని జీవితాన్ని గెలిచే నైపుణ్యాలను కూడా నేటి యువత సొంతం చేసుకోవాలి. జీవన నైపుణ్యాల తీరుతెన్నుల గురించి ఎంతోమంది ఎన్నో రకాలుగా చర్చించారు. బాల్యం నుండి విద్యార్థులు సమకూర్చుకోవలసిన కింది జీవన నైపుణ్యాల గురించి ప్రపంచ ఆరోగ్య సంస్థ ముఖ్యంగా ప్రస్తావించింది.1. స్వీయ అవగాహన:ప్రతి మనిషికి తనపైన తనకు అవగాహన ఉండాలి. తన సామర్థ్యంపట్ల సరైన అంచనా ఉండాలి. ‘స్వీయ లోపమ్ములెరుగుట పెద్ద విద్య అన్నాడు దాశరథి. తనను తాను తెలుసుకోవడమే అసలైన విద్య. ఎప్పటికప్పుడు ఆత్మవిమర్శ చేసుకుంటూ, లోపాలను సవరించుకుంటూ, ఉన్నత గుణాలను సమకూర్చు కుంటూ యువత ముందడుగు వేయాలి. తమ బలాలను, బలహీనతలను సహేతుకంగా సమీక్షించుకొని, అందుకనుగుణమైన లక్ష్యాన్ని నిర్దేశించుకొని, ఆ లక్ష్యసాధనకు అకుంఠిత దీక్షతో యువత కృషిచేయాలి.2. సహానుభూతి:పరస్పరం సహాయమర్థిస్తూ జీవించే మానవుల సమూహమే సమాజం. కావున, సాటి మనిషి కష్టసుఖాల పట్ల సహానుభూతి ఉండాలి. ఇతరుల సమస్యలకు తక్షణం స్పందించగలిగే మానవీయస్పృహను యువత అందిపుచ్చు కోవాలి. తద్వారా మానవ సంబంధాలు బలోపేతమవుతాయి.3. భావవ్యక్తీకరణ నైపుణ్యం:మాటే మనిషికి శాశ్వత ఆభరణం. మంచిమాట తీరువల్ల మహాకార్యాలను కూడా చక్కబెట్టుకోవచ్చు. సమయస్ఫూర్తితో కూడిన, నైపుణ్యవంతమైన భావవ్యక్తీకరణ మనకు అనేక విధాలుగా మేలుచేస్తుంది. విద్యావిషయక స్ఫూర్తిని ఇనుమడింపజేసుకోవడానికి, ఉద్యోగ, ఉపాధి అవకాశాలను పొందటానికి, వ్యాపార సంబంధాలను మెరుగుపరుచుకోవడానికి, రోజువారి వ్యవహారాలను త్వరితగతిని సాధించు కొనటానికి భావవ్యక్తీకరణ నైపుణ్యం ఎంతగానో ఉపయోగపడుతుంది. కావున ఉద్వేగరహితంగా, ప్రభావశీలంగా, ప్రియంగా, హితంగా, సత్యసమ్మతంగా, అంగీకారయోగ్యంగా మాట్లాడే సామర్థ్యాలను యువత సంపాదించుకోవాలి.4 భావోద్వేగాల నియంత్రణ:యువతీయువకుల హృదయాల్లో ఎన్నోరకాల భావోద్వేగాలు అనునిత్యం సుడులు తిరుగుతుంటాయి. ఈ భావోద్వేగాలను అదుపులో ఉంచుకోవాలి. ఆగ్రహావేశాలను సంయమనంతో నియంత్రిం చు కోవాలి. సమయ, సందర్భాలను అనుసరించి ఓపికతో వ్యవహరించాలి. యువత భావోద్వేగాలను అదుపులో పెట్టుకోకపోతే అనేక అనర్థాలు సంభవిస్తాయి.5. సమస్యనధిగమించే నైపుణ్యం:సమస్య ఎదురైనప్పుడు ఒత్తిడికి గురికాకుండా, సానుకూల దృష్టితో సావధానంగా ఆలోచించి తగిన పరిష్కారాన్ని కనుగొనాలి. నిరాశ చెందకూడదు. చిన్నసమస్యను అతి పెద్దగా ఊహించుకొని ఒత్తిడికి గురి కాకూడదు. ప్రతికూల ఆలోచనతో సమస్యనుండి పారిపోకూడదు. మనచుట్టూ ఉన్నదారులన్నీ మూసుకుపోయినప్పుడు ఏమాత్రం భయపడకూడదు. ఇక లాభం లేదని క్షణికావేశంతో ఆత్మహత్యకు పాల్పడకూడదు.ఎక్కడో మరొకదారి మన కోసం తెరిచేవుంటుం దన్న నమ్మకంతో, ఆశావహదృక్పథంతో నలుమూలలా అన్వేషించాలి. సమస్య గురించి స్నేహితులతో, శ్రేయోభిలాషులతో నిర్భయంగా చర్చించాలి. సానుకూల అవగాహనతో ఆత్మవిశ్వాసంతో, వివేకంతో ఆపదనుండి బయటపడాలి. గెలుపు ఓటములను, కష్టసుఖాలను సమతౌల్యంతో స్వీకరించే స్థితప్రజ్ఞతను యువత అలవాటు చేసుకోవాలి.6. నిర్ణయం తీసుకునే నైపుణ్యం:సరైన సమయంలో సముచిత నిర్ణయం తీసుకోవడం వల్ల సత్వర ఫలితాలను పొందవచ్చు. ఒక అంశం గురించి అన్ని కోణాలలో ఆలోచించి, అనంతర పర్యవసానాలను గ్రహించి, లాభనష్టాలను అంచనావేసి మరీ నిర్ణయం తీసుకోవాలి. ఒక నిర్ణయం తీసుకునేటప్పుడు ఏమాత్రం కాలయాపన చేయకూడదు. ఆ నిర్ణయం బహుళ ప్రయోజనదాయకంగా ఉండాలి.7. విమర్శనాత్మక ఆలోచనా నైపుణ్యం:ప్రతివిషయాన్ని గురించి విమర్శనాత్మకంగా ఆలోచించాలి. స్వీయదృక్కోణంలో నుండి మాత్రమే కాకుండా బహుముఖీన కోణాల నుండి ఆలోచించాలి. శాస్త్రీయంగా ఆలోచించాలి. ఎవరో పెద్దలు చెప్పారనో, ఇంకెవరో సెలవిచ్చారనో ప్రతివిషయాన్ని గుడ్డిగా నమ్మకూడదు. స్వీయానుభవాల ఆధారంగా, ప్రమాణబద్ధంగా నిర్ధారించుకున్న తరువాత సంబంధిత విషయాన్ని ఆమోదిం చాలి. తార్కిక అవగాహనతో ఆలోచించాలి.8. సృజనాత్మక ఆలోచనా నైపుణ్యం:యువతలో అనుకరణ ధోరణి బాగా పెరిగిపోతుంది. ఆయా రంగాలలో ప్రసిద్ధులైన వారి ఆలోచనాధోరణితో వేలం వెర్రిగా ముందుకుపోతున్నారు. వారిని స్ఫూర్తిగా మాత్రమే తీసుకోవాలిగాని అనుకరించడం వల్ల ప్రయోజనం ఉండదు. ప్రతిక్షణం కొత్తగా ఆలోచించాలి. కాలానుగుణంగా స్వతంత్రంగా ఆలోచించడం మూలంగా అందరికీ మార్గదర్శకంగా ఉండవచ్చు.ఈ విధమైన జీవననైపుణ్యాలతో పాటు నాయకత్వ లక్షణాలను, పరోపకారదృష్టిని, సామాజిక స్పృహను, పర్యావరణ ఎరుకను, దేశభక్తిని సమకూర్చుకుంటే యువతీయువకులు జీవితంలో ఉన్నత శిఖరాలను చేరుకోవచ్చు. ‘పావన నవజీవన బృందావననిర్మాత’లుగా జాతిపునర్నిర్మాణంలో భాగస్వాములు కావచ్చు."},{"question":"Responde la siguiente pregunta : ¿A qué partido pertenecía el presidente estadounidense durante el atentado del 11 de septiembre de 2001?. ","answer":"El presidente estadounidense en el momento del atentado  del 2001 era George W. Bush, el era miembro del Partido Republicano. "},{"question":"కరెన్సీ గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థలో చలామణీలో ఉన్న నాణేలు, కాగితపు నోట్లు. కాగితపు కరెన్సీని కేంద్ర బ్యాంకు జారీ చేస్తుంది. ఒక రూపాయి నోట్లను తప్ప మిగతా కరెన్సీ నోట్లను మనదేశంలో రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు జారీ చేస్తుంది. రూపాయి నోట్లను భారత ఆర్థిక మంత్రిత్వ శాఖ ముద్రిస్తుంది."},{"question":"जगात असा कोणता जीव आहे ज्याच्या जवळ मेंदू नसतो?","answer":"उत्तर: जेलीफिश जगात असा जीव आहे ज्याच्या जवळ मेंदू नसतो. "},{"question":"รถไฟฟ้าสายแรกของประเทศไทยคือสายอะไรและเปิดใช้งานเมื่อไร","answer":"รถไฟฟ้าบีทีเอส หรือรถไฟฟ้าสายสีเขียว เป็นรถไฟฟ้าสายแรกของไทย ซึ่งเปิดให้บริการเมื่อ 5 ธันวาคม พ.ศ.2542"},{"question":"”Iru ẹlẹnu meji bii Sanwo-Olu ko yẹ nipo olori ijọba l’Ekoo”","answer":"Sannde, ọjọ Aiku yii, ni Alukoro fun ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP l’Ekoo, Ọgbẹni Taofik Gani, sọ pe pẹlu idaamu ti ipinlẹ Eko ti ri lati nnkan bii ọjọ diẹ sẹyin, ko jọ pe Gomina Babajide Sanwo-Olu ṣi ni ipa ati agbara lati dari ipinlẹ ọhun mọ, fun idi eyi, ko kọwe fipo silẹ.Ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP yii fi kun ọrọ e pe ti ipinlẹ Eko ba ṣi ri bayii fun bii ọjọ mẹta si i, o lo ṣe pataki ki Babajide Sanwo-Olu kọwe fipo silẹ, nitori ohun to foju han bayii ni pe eto akoso ipinlẹ naa ti daru mọ ọn lọwọ.O ni, “ Iru gomina yii ni mo ri ri, ẹni to sọ pe oun ko mọ bi awọn ṣọja ṣe lọọ kọ lu awọn ọdọ to n ṣewọde ni Lẹkki, ṣugbọn ti awọn ṣọja pada tu aṣiri ẹ pe oun gan-an lo bẹ awọn niṣẹ, ohun to si foju han ni pe iru ẹlẹnu meji bẹẹ ko yẹ nipo olori ijọba nipinlẹ Eko.’’Alukoro yii fi kun un pe ohun to yẹ ẹ bayii ni ko kọwe fipo silẹ kiakia.  Ati pe awọn eeyan Eko paapaa ko le gba a gbọ mọ lori ipa to ko lasiko rogbodyan SARS.Lojuẹsẹ ni ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC ti fun awọn PDP lesi, ohun ti wọn si sọ ni pe Gomina Babajide Sanwo-Olu ko ni ipo kankan ti yoo fi silẹ, oun to bẹrẹ saa yii naa lo maa pari ẹ, pẹlu awọn iṣẹ idagbasoke to yaranti to ti n ṣe kaakiri ipinlẹ Eko, gẹgẹ bi ileri ẹ fawọn araalu.Alukoro ẹgbẹ naa l‘Ekoo, Ṣẹyẹ Ọladẹjọ, sọ pe o jọ pe ọwọ awọn ọmọ egbẹ oṣelu ọhun ko mọ lori wahala to be silẹ ọhun pẹlu ariwo ti wọn n pa pe ki gomina kọwe fipo silẹ nitori rogbodiyan to ṣelẹ l’Ekoo.Bakan naa lo sọ pe ohun ti wọn sọ yii fi PDP han gẹgẹ bi ẹgbẹ oṣelu ti ijakulẹ ti ba laimọye igba nipa ilakaka ẹ lati gba ipinlẹ Eko mọ APC lọwọ, ṣugb̀ọn ti nnkan ko rọgbọ fun rara.Ọladẹjọ, fi kun ọrọ ẹ pe iṣẹ idagbasoke ko duro l’Ekoo, paapaa bi gomina ṣe bẹrẹ atunṣe oju ọna Ẹlẹkọ si ilu Ẹpẹ, bakan naa lo fi kun un pe eto aabo ati bi igbe aye irọrun yoo ṣe wa fun araalu lo jẹ ijọba Sanwo-Olu logun ju lọ"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഹ്രസ്വകാല വായ്പകൾക്ക് ബാങ്കുകൾ പരസ്പരം ഈടാക്കുന്ന പലിശ നിരക്ക് എത്രയാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഹ്രസ്വകാല വായ്പകൾക്കായി ബാങ്കുകൾ പരസ്പരം ഈടാക്കുന്ന പലിശ നിരക്ക് ഇന്റർബാങ്ക് ലെൻഡിംഗ് നിരക്ക് അല്ലെങ്കിൽ ഇന്റർബാങ്ക് ഓഫർ നിരക്ക് (LIBOR) എന്നാണ് അറിയപ്പെടുന്നത്."},{"question":"එකම පළාත් සභාව තුල වඩාත්ම දුරින් පිහිටි නගරයන් දෙක කුමක්ද?","answer":"එකම පළාත් සභාව තුල වඩාත්ම දුරින් පිහිටි නගරයන් දෙක නැගෙනහිර පළාතේ ඇ​ති ත්‍රීකුණාමලය-අම්පාර (200 Km) යන නගර දෙකයි."},{"question":"Ndivanaani vamwe vemuZimbabwe vane mukurumbira muindasitiri yevaraidzo?","answer":"Zimbabwe yakabura vanhu vane tarenda vane tarenda muindasitiri yezvekuvaraidza. Mamwe mazita anozivikanwa anosanganisira:Oliver Mtukudzi: Muimbi ane mukurumbira pasi rose uye munyori wenziyo, anozivikanwa nemweya wake wakanaka weAfro-jazz uye nekushoropodza mumhanzi wake.Danai Gurira: Mutambi ane mukurumbira, mutambi, uye muratidziri anozivikanwa nebasa rake mu \\"The Walking Dead\\" uye \\"Black Panther.\\"Jah Prayzah: Muimbi wemazuva ano ane mukurumbira uye mutambi ane vateveri vakawanda muZimbabwe nekumhiri.Tendai \\"Beast\\" Mtawarira: Mutambi werugby akawana mukurumbira semutevedzeri wechikwata chenyika cheSouth Africa, maSpringboks."},{"question":"把以下的古文成现代汉字：王冕者，诸暨人。七八岁时，父命牧牛陇上，窃入学舍，听诸生诵书；听已，辄默记。暮归，忘其牛。父怒挞之。已而复如初。母曰：“儿痴如此，曷不听其所为？”冕因去，依僧寺以居。夜潜出，坐佛膝上，执策映长明灯读之，琅琅达旦。佛像多土偶，狞恶可怖；冕小儿，恬若不见。会稽韩性闻而异之，录为弟子，遂为通儒。","answer":"王冕是诸暨县人。七八岁时，父亲叫他在田埂上放牛，他偷偷地跑进学堂，去听学生念书。听完以后，总是默默地记住。傍晚回家，他把放牧的牛都忘记了。王冕的父亲大怒，打了王冕一顿。过后，他仍是这样。他的母亲说：“这孩子想读书这样入迷，何不由着他呢？”王冕从此以后就地离开家，寄住在寺庙里。一到夜里，他就暗暗地走出来，坐在佛像的膝盖上，手里拿着书就着佛像前长明灯的灯光诵读，书声琅琅一直读到天亮。佛像多是泥塑的，一个个面目狰狞凶恶，令人害怕。王冕虽是小孩，却神色安然，好像没有看见似的。安阳的韩性听说，觉得他与众不同，将他收作学生，（王冕）于是学成了博学多能的儒生。"},{"question":"வினா: ஆணி வேர் தொகுப்பு காணப்படும் தாவரம் எது ?1.பீட்ரூட்2.ஆஸ்ட்ரிக்3.புளியமரம்4.கேரட்","answer":"விடை:3.புளியமரம்"},{"question":"तिमीलाई रूसको बारेमा के थाहा छ?","answer":"रूस, वा रूसी संघ, पूर्वी यूरोप र उत्तरी एशिया फैलिएको एक देश हो। यो क्षेत्रफलको आधारमा विश्वको सबैभन्दा ठूलो देश हो, एघार समय क्षेत्रहरूमा फैलिएको छ, र चौध देशहरूसँग भूमि सीमाहरू साझा गर्दछ। यो विश्वको नवौं-सबैभन्दा बढी जनसंख्या भएको देश र युरोपको सबैभन्दा धेरै जनसंख्या भएको देश हो। देशको राजधानी र सबैभन्दा ठूलो शहर मास्को हो। सेन्ट पीटर्सबर्ग रूसको सांस्कृतिक केन्द्र र दोस्रो ठूलो शहर हो। देशका अन्य प्रमुख सहरी क्षेत्रहरूमा नोवोसिबिर्स्क, येकातेरिनबर्ग, निजनी नोभगोरोड, चेल्याबिन्स्क, क्रास्नोयार्स्क र काजान समावेश छन्।पूर्वी स्लाभहरू ईसाई ३ र ८ औं शताब्दीको बीचमा युरोपमा एक मान्यता प्राप्त समूहको रूपमा देखा पर्यो। पहिलो पूर्वी स्लाभिक राज्य, Kievan Rus', ९ औं शताब्दीमा उठ्यो, र ९८८, यसले बाइजान्टिन साम्राज्यबाट अर्थोडक्स ईसाई धर्म अपनायो। रुसको अन्ततः विघटन भयो र मस्कोको ग्रान्ड डची रुसको त्सारडम बन्न पुग्यो। १८ औं शताब्दीको प्रारम्भमा, रूसले विजय, कूटनीति, र रूसी अन्वेषकहरूको प्रयासहरू मार्फत व्यापक रूपमा विस्तार गरेको थियो, रूसी साम्राज्यमा विकास हुँदै, जुन इतिहासको तेस्रो-सबैभन्दा ठूलो साम्राज्य रहन्छ। यद्यपि, 1917 मा रूसी क्रान्तिको साथ, रूसको राजतन्त्र शासन समाप्त भयो र अन्ततः रूसी SFSR - विश्वको पहिलो संवैधानिक समाजवादी राज्य द्वारा प्रतिस्थापित गरियो। रूसी गृहयुद्ध पछि, रूसी SFSR ले तीन अन्य सोभियत गणतन्त्रहरूसँग सोभियत संघ स्थापना गर्‍यो, जस भित्र यो सबैभन्दा महत्त्वपूर्ण र प्रमुख घटक थियो। लाखौं जीवनको खर्चमा, सोभियत संघले १९३० को दशकमा द्रुत औद्योगीकरण गर्यो र पछि पूर्वी मोर्चामा ठूलो मात्रामा प्रयासहरूको नेतृत्व गरेर दोस्रो विश्वयुद्धमा सहयोगीहरूको लागि निर्णायक भूमिका खेल्यो। शीतयुद्धको सुरुवातसँगै यसले विश्वव्यापी वैचारिक प्रभावका लागि संयुक्त राज्य अमेरिकासँग प्रतिस्पर्धा गर्‍यो। २० औं शताब्दीको सोभियत युगले पहिलो मानव निर्मित उपग्रह र बाह्य अन्तरिक्षमा पहिलो मानव अभियान सहित केही महत्त्वपूर्ण रूसी प्राविधिक उपलब्धिहरू देख्यो।१९९१ मा, रूसी SFSR स्वतन्त्र रूसी संघ को रूप मा सोभियत संघ को विघटन बाट उत्पन्न भयो। नयाँ संविधान जारी भयो, जसले संघीय अर्ध-राष्ट्रपति प्रणाली स्थापित गर्यो। शताब्दीको पालोदेखि, रूसको राजनीतिक प्रणालीमा भ्लादिमिर पुटिनको प्रभुत्व रहेको छ, जसको नेतृत्वमा देशले लोकतान्त्रिक पछाडि हटेको र अधिनायकवादतर्फ परिवर्तन भएको अनुभव गरेको छ। रुस छिमेकी राष्ट्रहरूमा २०१४ मा अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय रूपमा अपरिचित क्रिमियालाई छिमेकी युक्रेनबाट विलय गर्ने, त्यसपछि २०२२ मा जारी आक्रमणको क्रममा अन्य चार क्षेत्रहरूलाई थप विलय सहित, छिमेकी राज्यहरूमा धेरै द्वन्द्वहरूमा सैन्य रूपमा संलग्न भएको छ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"air diminum sembiluan\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kesedihan yang menyebabkan tidak enak makan dan minum"},{"question":"ما هي السورة التي وضحت تقسيم الغنائم؟\\t","answer":"سورة الأنفال"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Bangon-takatra ka indray .............................. \\"","answer":"Toy izao ilay ohabolana feno : \\"Bangon-takatra ka indray mikopaka dia vita\\"."},{"question":"‘ਯਾਰ ਅਣਮੁੱਲੇ’ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਅਭਿਨੈ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਭਾਸ਼ਾਲੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ ਨੇ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਪਰਪੱਕ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਦਾ ਲੋਹਾ ਮਨਵਾਇਆ ਹੈ। ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਜ਼ੀਮ ਫ਼ਨਕਾਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਜਾਣੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹੰਸ ਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ ਦੇ ਪੁੱਤ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਨੇਹੀ ਯੁਵੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ, ਦਾ ਸੁਪਨਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਵਾਂਗ ਸੰਗੀਤਕ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੁਲੰਦੀਆਂ ਸਰ ਕਰਨਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਲਈ ਉਹ ਤਨਦੇਹੀ ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਅਤੇ ਰਿਆਜ਼ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਅੰਜ਼ਾਮ ਦੇ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਸਬੱਬ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੀ ਰਾਹ ਵੱਲ ਮੋੜ ਲਿਆਏ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਛਾਣ ਇਸ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮਵਰ ਅਤੇ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਕਲਾਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਰਵਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ। ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਸਨਅਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਪੈੜ੍ਹਾਂ ਸਥਾਪਤ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਨਾਲ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੈਰੀਅਰ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਪਹਿਲੂਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਹੋਈ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੇ ਪੇਸ਼ ਹਨ ਸੰਖੇਪ ਅੰਸ਼:ਸਵਾਲ: ਸੰਗੀਤਕ ਰਾਹਾਂ ਤੈਅ ਕਰਦੇ-ਕਰਦੇ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵੱਲ ਕਿੰਜ ਮੁੜੇ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਇਹ ਬਿਲਕੁਲ ਸਹੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੇਰਾ ਮੂਲ ਰੁਝਾਨ ਪਿਤਾ ਜੀ ਵਾਂਗ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੋਕਪ੍ਰਿਯਤਾ ਦੇ ਨਵੇਂ ਆਯਾਮ ਕਾਇਮ ਕਰਨਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਪਰ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਅਨੁਰਾਗ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਜੀ ਅਤੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ‘ਯਾਰ ਅਣਮੁੱਲੇ’ ਦਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਾ ਅਤੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਰੱਖੀ, ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖਦਿਆਂ ਇਨਕਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਹੌਸਲਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਿਆ।ਸਵਾਲ: ‘ਯਾਰ ਅਣਮੁੱਲੇ’ ਦੀ ਕਾਮਯਾਬੀ ਨੇ ਗਾਇਕ ਯੁਵੀ ਨੂੰ ਕਿੰਨਾ ਕੁ ਬਦਲਿਆ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸ਼ੁਕਰਗੁਜ਼ਾਰ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਦਾ ਹੱਕਦਾਰ ਬਣਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੈਂ ਕਦੇ ਕਲਪਨਾ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ। ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਮਿਲੇ ਇਸ ਸਨੇਹ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਕੁਝ ਸਮੇਂ ਲਈ ਦੂਰ ਤਾਂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਮੈਂ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਖੇਤਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਾਹੁਣ ਵਾਲਿਆਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਆਸਾਵਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਖ਼ਰਾ ਉਤਰਨ ਦੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰਾਂਗਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਤਜਰਬਾ ਕਿੱਦਾਂ ਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਬੇਹੱਦ ਸ਼ਾਨਦਾਰ, ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਇੰਡਸਟਰੀ ਦੇ ਕਾਬਿਲ ਅਤੇ ਯੁਵਾ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣਾ ਸ਼ੁਮਾਰ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਅਨੁਰਾਗ ਸਿੰਘ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਟੀਮ ਹਰੀਸ਼ ਵਰਮਾ, ਆਰੀਆ ਬੱਬਰ ਆਦਿ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਹੀ ਆਧਾਰਤ ਰਹੀ। ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਅਭਿਨੈ ਸਾਂਝ ਬਣਾਉਣੀ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਯਾਦਗਾਰੀ ਤਜਰਬਾ ਰਿਹਾ, ਇਸ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਕੁਝ ਸਿੱਖਣ, ਸਮਝਣ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਮੌਕਾ ਮਿਲਿਆ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਭੂਮਿਕਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਤਰਜੀਹ ਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹੋ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਮੇਰੀ ਤਵੱਜੋਂ ਕੇਵਲ ਉਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਭੂਮਿਕਾਵਾਂ ਹਨ, ਜੋ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ ਦੀ ਤਰਜਮਾਨੀ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਸੰਦੇਸ਼ਮਕ ਵੀ ਹੋਣ। ਇਸੇ ਲਈ ਗਿਣੀਆਂ-ਚੁਣੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਸਵੀਕਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਨੂੰ ਪਹਿਲ ਦੇ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਆਗਾਮੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਜੈਕਟ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਆਪਣੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਖੇਤਰ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਲਈ ਆਪਣੀ ਪਲੇਠੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਐਲਬਮ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੰਜ਼ਾਮ ਦੇ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾ, ਜੋ ਅਗਲੇ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਪੱਧਰ ’ਤੇ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਣ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਉਮੀਦ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਇਸ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਸਰੋਤਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਮਣਾਂਮੂੰਹੀ ਪਿਆਰ-ਸਤਿਕਾਰ ਹਾਸਲ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਹਾਡੀ ਇਸ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਐਲਬਮ ਦੀ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ਤਾ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਾਪਦੰਡ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਮਿਆਰੀ ਲੀਹਾਂ ਸਥਾਪਤ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਰਹਿਣਗੇ। ਇਸੇ ਸੋਚ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਜ਼ਾਮ ਦਿੰਦਿਆਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਇਸ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਐਲਬਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਗੀਤ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਮਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਤਰਜਮਾਨੀ, ਭੰਗੜੇ ਦੀ ਤਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਸੂਫ਼ੀਆਨਾ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਦੇ ਹਰ ਰੰਗ ਸੁਣਨ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਣਗੇ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਹੰਸ ਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ ਦਾ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਰੁਝਾਨ ਸੂਫ਼ੀਆਨਾ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਵੱਲ ਰਿਹਾ। ਇਸ ਦਾ ਅਸਰ ਤੁਹਾਡੀ ਗਾਇਕੀ ’ਤੇ ਕਿੰਨਾ ਕੁ ਹਾਵੀ ਰਹੇਗਾ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਪਿਤਾ ਜੀ, ਵਾਂਗ ਮੈਂ ਵੀ ਸੂਫ਼ੀਆਨਾ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਨੂੰ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਪਸੰਦ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਪਰ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਬਾਵਜੂਦ ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਜ਼ ਵੀ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਮੋਂਹਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਮੇਂ-ਸਮੇਂ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਦਾ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਤਾਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਬਣਾਵਾਂਗਾ। ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਵੀ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਗੀਤ, ਸੰਗੀਤ ਦੀ ਰੰਗਤ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਪੰਜਾਬੀਅਤ ਕਦਰਾਂ-ਕੀਮਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ਬੂ ਡੁੱਲ੍ਹ-ਡੁੱਲ੍ਹ ਪਵੇਗੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਐਲਬਮ ਦੇ ਵਿਸ਼ੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸੋ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਅਗਲੇ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਣ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਮੇਰੀ ਇਸ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਐਲਬਮ ਦੇ ਗੀਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਰਚਨਾ ਕੁਮਾਰ, ਜੱਗੀ ਮੁੰਬਈ, ਧੰਮੀ ਹੇਰਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਅਤੇ ਪਿਰਥੀ ਸੀਲੋ ਵਾਲਾ ਨੇ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਗੁਰਮੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਤਿਆਰ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਐਲਬਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਅੱਗੇ ਯੋਜਨਾ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਕੁਝ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰਾਂਗਾ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁਝ ਕਰ ਗੁਜ਼ਰਨ ਲਈ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਯੋਜਨਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਜ਼ਾਮ ਦੇਵਾਂਗਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਇਸ ਮੁਕਾਮ ਤੱਕ ਪਹੁੰਚਣ ਲਈ ਕਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਅਹਿਮ ਯੋਗਦਾਨ ਮੰਨਦੇ ਹੋ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਤਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਹੰਸ ਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ, ਮਾਤਾ ਰੇਸ਼ਮ ਕੌਰ, ਵੱਡੇ ਭਰਾ ਨਵਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਦੁਆਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਥੋਂ ਤੱਕ ਪਹੁੰਚਣ ਲਈ ਸਿਜਦਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਅਨੁਰਾਗ ਸਿੰਘ, ਬਤਰਾ ਪ੍ਰੋਡਕਸ਼ਨ ਅਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਦੋਸਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਧੰਨਵਾਦੀ ਹਾਂ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਅੱਗੇ ਵਧਣ ਲਈ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਹੌਂਸਲਾ ਅਫ਼ਜਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ ਨੇ ਪਹਿਲੀ  ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਦਸੋ ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ  ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ ਨੇ ਪਹਿਲੀ  ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ‘ਯਾਰ ਅਣਮੁੱਲੇ’ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Gomina Ebonyi lugbadi koronafairọọsi, aṣẹ bọ sọwọ igbakeji","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ebonyi, Dave Umahi, ti lugbadi arun koronafairọọsi pẹlu awọn amugbalẹgbẹ rẹ kan.Umahi lo kede ọrọ ọhun funra ẹ ninu atẹjade kan to fọwọ si lonii, ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide.Atẹjade naa ṣalaye pe igbakeji gomina, Kelechi Igwe, ni yoo maa tukọ ipinlẹ naa lati oni lọ titi digba ti ara gomina yoo ya.Lọwọlọwọ bayii, irinwo-le-mejidinlogoji (438) eeyan lo ti lugbadi koronafairọọsi nipinlẹ Ebonyi, ninu eyi ti ọọdunrun-le-mẹtadinlọgọta (357) ti ri iwosan, tawọn mẹta si ti dagbere faye.Ẹwẹ, ṣaaju ni ijọba ipinlẹ Benue ti kede pe iyawo gomina, Eunice Ortom, ọmọ rẹ atawọn oṣiṣẹ ile ijọba kan ti lugbadi koronafairọọsi."},{"question":"Iku pa olori awọn Amọtẹkun kan l’Ọyọọ","answer":"Ọkan ninu awọn adari ẹṣọ Amọtẹkun, ẹka ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ọgbẹni Tajudeen Ìdòwú Salaudeen, ti jade laaye. Ọkunrin yii ni olori awọn Amọtẹkun ijọba ibilẹ Kajọla, ni ipinlẹ yìí. Ọkunrin yii ṣalaabapade iku ojiji lasiko ijamba ọkada to ṣẹlẹ sí i laaarọ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee ọse ta a lo tan yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe ilu Okeho lọmọ bibi Ilero yii n gun alupupu rẹ lọ ni idaji Ọjọbọ, ko to too gba ipe lori foonu rẹ pe iṣẹ pajawiri kan n duro de e niluu abinibi ẹ.Kò pẹ pupọ to pada sọna Ilero nijanba ọhún ṣẹlẹ sí i, to sí dagbere faye lẹyin iṣẹju diẹ to ṣubú lori alupupu naa.Oludari agba ẹṣọ Amọtẹkun nipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ajagun-fẹyinti Ọlayinka Ọlayanju, fidi ẹ mulẹ pe laaarọ Tọsidee nijanba to gbẹmi ọga ikọ Amọtẹkun nijọba ibilẹ Kajọla yii waye, aarọ Furaidee ni wọn sinkú ẹ̀ nilana isinku Musulumi"},{"question":"ప్రశ్న: ఇక్ష్వాకులు అన్ని తెగల వారిని ఏకం చేయగలిగారు. నీవు దీనిని అంగీకరిస్తావా లేదా విభేదిస్తావా ? అవును అయితే వారు ఏయే పద్ధతులను ఉపయోగించారు?","answer":"ఇక్ష్వాకులు అన్ని తెగల వారిని ఏకం చేయగలిగారు, నేను దీనికి అంగీకరిస్తున్నాను. ఏ పద్దతులు ఉపయోగించారు అంటే,1. ఇతర తెగల వారితో వివాహ సంబంధాలు ఏర్పాటు చేసుకొనుట ద్వారా2. యజ్ఞ, యాగాదులు (అశ్వమేథ యాగం మొ||) చేయటం ద్వారా3. రామాయణంలోని శ్రీరాముని వారసులుగా చెప్పుకొనుట ద్వారా"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta ɗari uku da ashirin da shida a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 326"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Ny mihomehy lavo aza misy todiny _\\"","answer":"\\"Ny mihomehy lavo aza misy todiny maika fa ny mitsambiki-mikipy\\""},{"question":"Окуганда сапаттуу окуңуз. Чын көңүл менен окуңуз. Окууну адатка айлантып окуңуз. Ар күнү окуңуз. Кайталап окуудан, анализдеп окуудан ырахат алыңыз. Кандайдыр бир иш кылып жатсаңыз, майын чыгара кылыңыз. Кылып жаткан ишиңизди эч качан жаман көрбөңүз, эптеп бүтсүн дебеңиз. Кылган ишиңиз башка үчүн болсо дагы, анын сообу, ал жерден алган тажрыйбаңыз, үйрөнгөн нерселериңиз сиз үчүн экенин унутпаңыз. Кылганың мен үчүн болсо, үйрөнгөнүң өзүң үчүн деп ошондуктан айтылса керек да.Эгерде бул контексттен суроо жаратсак, ал суроого жооп \\"окууну\\" болсо, анда суроо кандай болмок? ","answer":"Эмнени адатка айлантып окуу керек?"},{"question":"Aiza no foiben'ny fikambanan’ny firenena mikambana?1) Madagasikara2) Etazonia3) France","answer":"Safidy 2: Any Etazonia, New York no foiben'ny fikambanan'ny firenena mikambana"},{"question":"Siapakah Kee Thuan Chye? Jelaskan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 140 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Kee Thuan Chye ialah pelakon, dramatis, pemuisi, dan wartawan Malaysia. Walaupun telah menceburi diri dalam bidang teater, filem, dan televisyen selama 30 tahun lebih, beliau kini masih terus berlakon dan menulis. Pada tahun 1981, Kee menjadi pengasas bersama sekumpulan teater yang bernama KAMI di Kuala Lumpur. Kee juga seorang pendukung hak awam yang terkemuka. Kee menyatakan pandangan politiknya melalui drama terhadap apa-apa jua yang tidak boleh dinyatakan dalam akhbar aliran utama di bawah Akta Mesin Cetak dan Penerbitan (PPPA). Dia menyatakan \\"Saya kemudiannya telah menulis penentasan politik. Salah satu darinya ‘The Big Purge’, dengan berani memperolok Mahathir dan Operation Lalang.\\" Kee telah dipilih sebagai salah satu penerima awal Anugerah Kebebasan Bersuara The Annexe Heroes apabila anugerah itu dilancarkan pada 2008. Pada tahun 2010, beliau juga dipilih sebagai Warga Malaysia Ke-34 Yang Paling Boleh Dipercayai dalam suatu tinjauan yang dijalankan oleh Reader's Digest."},{"question":"తే. సర్వతీర్ధాంబువులకంటె సమధికంబుపావనంబైన జనయిత్రి పాదజలమువరతనూజున కఖిలదేవతల కంటెజనని యెక్కుడు సన్నుతాచారనిరతపైన ఇచ్చిన పద్యం అనుసరించి ప్రశ్నకి జవాబు ఇవ్వండి:“పావనంబైన జనయిత్రి పాదజలము” అంటే ఏమిటి?","answer":"జనయిత్రి అంటే తల్లి. జన్మనిచ్చిన తల్లి సర్వదేవతల కంటే ఎక్కువ. అటువంటి తల్లి యొక్క పాదాలు కడిగిన నీరు చాలా పవిత్రమైనది. విష్ణువు పాదాల నుండి జన్మించింది గంగ. అది ఎంతో పవిత్రమైంది. అటువంటి పవిత్రత కలిగిందే తల్లి పాదాలు కడిగిన నీరు."},{"question":"Inona no fahagagana farany nataon’i Jesosy, araka ny Testamenta Vaovao?","answer":"Ny fahagagana farany nataon’i Jesosy, araka ny Testamenta Vaovao, dia ny fitsanganan’i Lazarosy tamin’ny maty, araka ny voalaza ao amin’ny Filazantsaran’i Jaona toko faha-11."},{"question":"සබ්බාසව සූත්‍රයවැනි නිර්වාණය සඳහා වඩාත් අදාල සූත්‍ර මොනවාද?","answer":"ගොඩක් සූත්‍ර අදාලයි ඉතින්සබ්බාස්‍රව සූත්‍රය දෙන්නෙත් එක මට්ටමක නිවනට සිතියමක්නිවනට කෙලින්ම අදාල සතර සතිපට්ඨාන සූත්‍රය "},{"question":"O que RHCP significa?","answer":"RHCP é a sigla para a banda norte-americana Red Hot Chili Peppers"},{"question":"‘என்னுயிர் தமிழ்மொழி என்பேன்’ என்னும் தலைப்பில் நீவிர் கொண்டுள்ள மொழிப்பற்றினை எழுதுக.","answer":"எனக்கு உயிர் தந்தவள் தாய். தான் ஊட்டிய பாலோடு, உலகை அறிமுகம் செய்ய மாட்டி வளர்த்த மொழி தமிழ். என் உயிரோடு கலந்து உடலோடு வளர்ந்தது. வளர்ந்தபின் வளிமான மொழியைக் கற்றபோது, அதன் வளத்தோடு வீச்சும், ஆழமும் புரிந்தது.“யாமறிந்த மொழிகளிலே தமிழ் மொழிபோல் இனிதாவது எங்கும் காணோம் என்று, என் பாட்டன் பாரதி சொன்னதன் பொருளைப் புரிந்துகொண்டேன். “தமிழுக்கு அமுதென்று பேர்” என்று பாரதிதாசன் கூறியதைத் தெளிந்தேன். “தமிழன் என்றோர் இனமுண்டு! தனியே அவர்க்கோர் குணமுண்டு” என்று, நாமக்கல் கவிஞர் சொன்னதன் ஆழ்பொரும் அறிந்தேன். அதனால், என் தமிழை உயிரினும் மேலானதாக மதிக்கிறேன்."},{"question":"கேள்வி: உணவே மருந்து என்ற கூற்றை ஆராய்க?.","answer":"பதில்: உணவே மருந்து:முன்னுரை:திருவள்ளுவர் உணவே மருந்து பற்றிய சிறப்பினை “மருந்தென வேண்டாவாம் யாக்கைக்கு அருந்தியது அற்றது போற்றி உணின்” என்ற குறள் மூலம் சிறப்பாக விளக்கியுள்ளார்.இந்த குறளுக்கான அர்த்தம் உடலுக்கு எது பொருத்தமான உணவோ அதை தேர்ந்தெடுத்து உண்டால் நாம் நெடுநாள் எந்த நோயும் இல்லாமல் வாழலாம் என்பதை குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.மனிதர்களுடைய வாழ்வில் உணவு என்பது மிகவும் முக்கியமான ஒன்றாக இருக்கிறது. எனவே மனிதர்களாகிய நாம் உணவிற்கு அதிக முக்கியத்துவத்தை கொடுக்க வேண்டியது அவசியம்.உணவு முறைகளும் நமது ஆரோக்கியமும்:நம் முன்னோர்கள் சுவர் இருந்தால் தான் சித்திரம் வரையலாம் என்று கூறியது போல உடலில் நல்ல ஆரோக்கியம் இருந்தால் தான் நல்வாழ்வினை வாழ முடியும்.இந்த இயற்கையானது நமக்கு பல வளங்களை கொடுத்துள்ளது. அதில் விளைகின்ற பழ வகைகள், தானியங்கள், காய்கறிகள் போன்ற அனைத்தும் ஊட்டச்சத்து நிறைந்தவை. நல்ல வளமான நிலத்தில் வளரும் பயிர் போல ஆரோக்கியமான உணவுகளை உண்ணும் மனிதனும் வளமாக வாழ முடியும்.இயற்கை உணவுகள்:இயற்கையான முறையில் கிருமி நாசினிகள் தெளிக்கப்படாத தானிய வகைகள், கிழங்குகள், கீரைகள், பசும்பால் உணவுகள், பழங்கள் போன்ற இயற்கையான உணவுகள் உடல் ஆரோக்கியத்திற்கு சிறந்தன.இன்றைய விவசாயத்தில் பெரும்பாலும் மனித உடலுக்கு தீங்கு விளைவிக்கக்கூடிய செயற்கை உரங்கள் தான் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது. இதனால் கூட மனிதர்களுக்கு நோயின் தாக்கம் அதிகமாகிவிட்டது.இயற்கை சார்ந்த உணவுகளை அதிகமாக எடுத்துக்கொள்வதன் மூலம் உடலில் பிணி இல்லாமல் நெடுநாள் வாழ முடியும்.மாறிவரும் உணவு முறைகள்:இன்றைய சூழலில் அனைவரும் உடலுக்கு தீங்கு தரக்கூடிய ஜங்க் புட்ஸ், பாஸ்ட் புட்ஸ் போன்ற துரித உணவுகளையே பெரிதும் விரும்பி சாப்பிடுகிறார்கள்.நமது பிரதேசங்களில் அதிகம் விற்பனையாகும் “பெப்சி, கொக்கா கோலா ” போன்ற குளிர்பானங்களை அதிகம் அருந்துவதை தவிர்க்க வேண்டும்.நாகரீக வளர்ச்சியின் காரணமாக நம்முடைய இயற்கையான உணவு முறைகளும் அடியோடு மாறிவிட்டது. கொழுப்பு நிறைந்த உணவுகளை வெளியில் அதிகம் சாப்பிடுவதால் உடல் எடை அதிகரித்து பல நோய்களுக்கு நம்மை நாமளே ஆளாக்கிக்கொள்கிறோம். இயற்கையான உணவுகளை எடுத்துக்கொண்டு உடலை ஆரோக்கியமாய் வைத்துக்கொள்ளுவோம்.நோய் அதிகரிப்பு:நாம் எடுத்துக்கொள்கின்ற உணவு முறைதான் நம்முடைய நீண்ட நாள் ஆரோக்கியத்திற்கு வழிவகுக்கும்.சிரிய வயதிலிருந்து உணவிற்கு மதிப்பு கொடுக்காமல் நாம் எடுத்து கொள்கின்ற ஆரோக்கியமற்ற உணவுகள் தான் இன்று அதிகளவான நோய்களுக்கு காரணமாக உள்ளது.தமிழர் மருத்துவத்தில் உணவு என்பது அணைத்து நோய்களையும் தீர்க்கக்கூடிய சஞ்சீவி மருந்தாக கருதப்படுகிறது.பசியின் கொடுமையை “பசிப்பிணி என்னும் பாவி” என மணிமேகலை கூறுகிறது.“உண்டி கொடுதோர் உயிர் கொடுத்தோரே” என மணிமேகலையும், புறநானூறும் கூறுகின்றன.திருக்குறளில் மருந்து என்னும் அதிகாரத்தில் உணவே மருந்தாகும் தன்மையை திருவள்ளுவர் தெளிவாக கூறியுள்ளார்.நம் நாட்டு சமையலுக்கு புழுங்கல் அரிசியே சிறந்தது.நோய்க்கு முதல் காரணம் உப்பு.“மீதூண் விரும்பேல்” என்றவர் ஔவை.நோய் நீக்கும் மூலிகைகள்1.துளசி:துளசி செடியின் இலைகளை நீரில்இட்டு கொதிக்க செய்து ஆவி பிடித்தால் மார்புசளி, நீர்க்கோவை, தலைவலி நீங்கும்.துளசி இலைகள் பூசினால் படை நீங்கும்.2.கீழ்க்காய்நெல்லி:இதனை கீழாநெல்லி, கீழ்வாய்நெல்லி என்றும் கூறுவர். மஞ்சட் காமாலைக்கு கைகண்ட மருந்தாக பயன்படுகிறது. இதனை கற்கண்டுடன் சேர்த்து உண்பதால் சிறுநீர்த் தொடர்பான நோய்கள் நீங்கும்.3.தூதுவளை:இது செடி வகை இல்லை, இது கொடி வகையை சேர்ந்தது. இக்கொடியில் சிறு முள்கள் உண்டு. இதனை தூதுளை, சிங்கவல்லி என்றும் அழைப்பர். வள்ளலார் இதனை “ஞானப்பச்சிலை” என்று கூறுவார். இது குறள் வளத்தை மேம்படுத்தும், வாழ்நாளை நீடிக்கும்.4.குப்பைமேனி:குப்பைமேனி, நச்சுக்கடிகளுக்கு நல்ல மருந்து. இதனை “மேனி துலங்க குப்பைமேனி” என்று சிறபிப்பர்.5.கற்றாழை:இது வறண்ட நிலத்தாவரம். இதனை “குமரி” என்பர். பெண்களின் கருப்பை சார்ந்த நோய்களை நீக்குவதால் “குமரி கண்ட நோய்க்கு குமரி கொடு” என்பர்.6.முருங்கை:இதனை அரைத்து தடவினால் எலும்பு முறிவு விரைவில் கூடும். இரும்பு சத்து நிறைந்துள்ளதால் கூந்தலை வளரச் செய்வதில் பெரும் பங்கு உண்டு.7.கறிவேப்பிலலை:இது சீதபேதி, நச்சு போன்றவற்றை சரிசெய்யும்.8.கரிசலாங்கண்ணி:இரத்தசோகை, செரிமான கோளாறு, மஞ்சள் காமாலைக்கு சிறந்த மருந்து. கண் பார்வையை தெளிவாக்கும். நரையை போக்கும். இதனை “கரிசாலை, கையாந்தகரை, பிருங்கராசம், தேகராசம்” என்று கூறுவர்.9.பிற மூலிகைகள்:மணித்தக்காளிக் கீரை வாய்ப்புண்னையும், குடற்புண்ணையும் குணபடுத்தும். அகத்திக்கீரை பல் சார்ந்த நோய்களை குணமாக்கும். வல்லாரை நினைவாற்றலை பெருக்க உதவும்.முடிவுரை:மனிதன் இன்று பொருளாதார நிலை, தொழில்நுட்ப வளர்ச்சி, விஞ்ஞானம் என்று நாட்டின் வளர்ச்சியை மட்டுமே யோசிக்கிறார்களே தவிற மனிதருடைய உடல் ஆரோக்கியம் பற்றி யாரும் நினைத்து பார்ப்பதில்லை.அதனால் நோய்கள் வந்து தாக்கிய பிறகு அதனை பற்றி கவலை கொள்வதில் எந்த பயனும் இல்லை. எனவே உணவு முறையில் நாம் எப்போதும் அதிக அக்கறை செலுத்த வேண்டும். இதனையெல்லாம் சரி செய்வதற்கு ஒரே வழி உண்டு என்றால் இயற்கை விவசாயத்தை மீண்டும் உருவாக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"How does the BYM model account for spatial dependence? ","answer":"The BYM (Besag, York, and Mollié) model is widely used in spatial epidemiology to account for spatial dependence in disease mapping. It is particularly effective in modeling the spatial distribution of disease incidence and risk. The model does this by incorporating two key components: a spatially structured random effect and an unstructured random effect. Here's how these components contribute to accounting for spatial dependence:Spatially Structured Random Effect: This component of the BYM model captures the spatial correlation in the data. It is often implemented using a conditional autoregressive (CAR) model. In a CAR model, the value of the random effect at a specific location (such as a region or district) is modeled as being dependent on the values of its neighboring locations. This dependency structure allows the model to capture spatial autocorrelation, meaning that areas that are geographically close are likely to have similar values of the random effect (and hence similar disease risks).Unstructured Random Effect: This component accounts for overdispersion and heterogeneity that cannot be explained by the spatial structure. It represents random variation between areas that is not due to spatial proximity. This is modeled as an independent and identically distributed (i.i.d.) random effect.By combining these two components, the BYM model can distinguish between spatially structured variation (which might be due to underlying environmental or social factors that have a spatial pattern) and unstructured variation (which could be due to random fluctuations or other non-spatial factors).In summary, the BYM model's ability to account for spatial dependence lies in its dual approach of incorporating both spatially structured and unstructured random effects, making it a powerful tool for understanding and predicting spatial patterns in disease incidence and other spatially dependent phenomena."},{"question":"Lamun batur nyarita, \\"A Adit, kuring mesen Indomie, hiji.\\", naon nu dirasakeun anjeunna?","answer":"Anjeunna ngarasa nétral kusabab di dinya teu aya hal boh nu positip atawa négatip."},{"question":"Gabriel Okara","answer":"Wọ́n bi Gabriel Imomotimi Okara ni ojo Kerinlelogbon osu Kerin odun 1921 (born 24 April 1921). eni ti won bi ni Bumoundi  Yenagoa, Bayelsa State. O je akewi ati olukotan omo orile ede Naijria[1]  O je okan lara awon akewi igbalode (Modernist poet of Anglophone Africa) ile alawo dudu ti o n so Geesi. Won mo Gabriel latari awon iwe itan , The Voice (1964), ati iwe ewi ti o ko ti o fi gba ami eye, iyen: The Fisherman's Invocation (1978), The Dreamer ati His Vision (2005). Ninu awon iwe itan aroso ati ewi re ni Okara ti ma n fi eko, esin, alo-onitan ati awon ami oniruuru ile alawo dudu han. fun idi eyi, ni won se n pee ni \\"the Nigerian Negritudist\\".[2] Gege bi alatunse awon ise re Brenda Marie Osbey, se so, o ni \\" A le so wipe awon ise olokan-o-jokan paapaa julo ewi akoko ti Gabriel Okara koko ko ni ise litireso orile-ede Naijiiria ati ewi igbalode ile Adulawo ti bere.\\"Gabriel Imomotimi Gbaingbain Okara, je omo oloye ile Ijọ kan,[4]  won bi ni  Bomoundi ni ilu Niger Delta ni odun 1921. O keko nile eko ijoba ti  Government College Umuahia, ti o si tun lo si ile eko agba ti later Yaba Higher College. Lasiko ogun agbaye elekeji (World War II), o gbiyanju lati dara po mo omo ogun oke ti ile Britiko iyen British Royal Air Force sugbon ko pari eko wiwa oko ofurufu, amo o ba ile ise papako ofurufu ti  British Overseas Airway Corporation  ti won pada yi si (British Airways).[5]Ni odun 1945, Okara ri ise gege bi atewe fun ile ise itewe ijoba amunisin ile Naijiria. O sise ni ile ise yii titi di igba ti oun naa fi bere si ni kowe jade. O koko sogbufo ewi kan lati ede Ijaw si ede Geesi, ti o si ko iwe fun ile ise iroyin asoro-magbesi ijoba . O keko nipa imo igbohun-safefe ni ile eko agba ti  Northwestern University ni odun 1949 saaju ija ogun abele Nigerian Civil War to be sile ni odun(1967–70).  O si tun sise gege bi Information Officer fun apa Ariwa ijoba Naijiria (Eastern Nigerian Government Service), ati onkowe Chinua Achebe, Okara tun je asoju fun Biafra laarin odun1969.[6] Lati 1972 si 1980, O je adari fun ile ise atewe ipinle Rivers State to wa ni Port Harcourt.leyin ti Okara kuro nile iwe, o ko iwe ere onise pelu aroko fun ile ise igbohun-safefe, ewi re ti o ko ni odun 1953 iyen: \\" \\"The Call of the River Nun\\" ni o fi gba ami eye ni odun idije fun ise atinuda (Nigerian Festival of Arts). Lara awon ewi re ni won te jade ninu iwe iroyin olose-ose ti Black Orpheus, ni 1960 o ti di ilu mooka lori agbekale ise re. Opo awon ewi re ni won ti se ogbufo re si orisirisi ede. Okara kopa ninu akojopo African Writers Conference ti o waye ni 1June,196 ni Makerere University College ni Kampala, Uganda, pelu awon onkowe bi: Chinua Achebe, Rajat Neogy, Bloke Modisane, Okot   p'Bitek, Bernard Fonlon, Ngugi Wa Thiong'o, Segun Olusola, Grace Ogot, Jonathan Kariara, Rebecca Njau, Wole Soyinka, John Pepper Clark, Saunders Redding, Christopher Okigbo, Francis Ademola, Ezekiel Mphahlele, Arthur Maimane, ati awon miiran bee. Eyi ti o gbajumo julo ninu awon ewi Okara ni \\"Piano and Drums\\".  Ewi miran to tun ;gbajumo ni \\"You Laughed and Laughed and Laughed\\", ni o fara han julo ninu awon iwe ajokopo ewi. Ohun ti o je  Okara lokan ju ni ipenija ti asa ati ise ile Adulawo n koju latari olaju awon Oyinbo Western culture, ni eyi ti ewi re \\"Once Upon a Time\\" so nipa re.[8]O safihan akori yii ninu itan aroso re ti, The Voice (1964).  Ti olu eda itan  Okolo, feran asa igbalode awon  Geesi ju  asa ibile abinibi re lo.\\"Lafik awon ewi re ati itan aroso re Okara tun ti ko ere onise ti won ti ka seti igbo awon ara ile ninu ero asoro magbesi .Opo awon aroko re ti ko tii di tite jade lo ba ogun abele Biafara lo.Ni April 2017, won se  odun litireso ti won pe ni (Gabriel Okara Literary Festival) ni ogba ile eko University of Port Harcourt lati fi seye fun.[9][10] Ojogbon Chidi T. Maduka gbe iwe kan jade ti o pe ni \\"Gabriel Okra\\"  May 2017.  ti o fi salaye pe\\"Gabriel Okara ni won ko fi si ipo ti o ye ki o wa laarin awon onkowe litireso ile Adulawo\\" . Bakan naa ni   Lindsay Barrett, so wipe \\" Okara funra re ko ba ile eko Yunfasiti kan se\\" nigba ti Odia Ofeimun lu  Okara logo enu wipe \\"kii se wipe Okara je eni ti o  tipe ninu ise apileko nikan bi n ko se wipe oun ni bi ko se wipe oun ni o bere ise tite iwe litireso ni apa ile Adulawo\\".Awon ami eye re1953: Best All-Round Entry In Poetry at the Nigerian Festival of Arts, for \\"The Call of the River Nun\\"1979: Commonwealth Poetry Prize, for The Fisherman's Invocation2005: NLNG Prize, for The Dreamer, His Vision2009: Pan African Writers' Association Honorary Membership Award[12][13]2017: Gabriel Okara Literary FestivalAwon ise akanse re1964: The Voice (novel), London: Deutsch, first edition; Heinemann African Writers Series (No. 68), 1970. Africana Publishing, ISBN 0-8419-0015-90-8419-0015-9.1978: The Fisherman's Invocation (poems)1981: Little Snake and Little Frog (for children)1992: An Adventure to Juju Island (for children)2005: The Dreamer, His Vision (poems)2006: As I See It (poems)2016: Collected Poems (edited and with an introduction by Brenda Marie Osbey), University of Nebraska Press, African Poetry Book Series, ISBN 978-0-8032-8687-0978-0-8032-8687-0."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Tkachuk draftades av Ottawa Senators i första rundan i 2018","answer":"års draft som fjärde spelare totalt."},{"question":"පාර්ලිමේන්තු ක්‍රමයේ නිජබිම ලෙස සැලකෙන රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"එක්සත් රාජධානිය බොහෝ විට නූතන පාර්ලිමේන්තු ක්‍රමයේ උපන් ස්ථානය ලෙස සැලකේ. ශතවර්ෂ ගණනාවක් පුරා බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දියුණුව අද හැඳින්වෙන පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය සඳහා අඩිතාලම දැමීය. 1215 දී මැග්නා කාර්ටා සහ 1295 දී ආදර්ශ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව වැනි ආයතන පිහිටුවීමත් සමඟ පාර්ලිමේන්තු ක්‍රමයේ මූලයන් මධ්‍යතන යුගයේ සිට සොයා ගත හැකිය. කාලයත් සමඟ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බලතල පුළුල් වූ අතර එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය අංගයක් බවට පත්විය රට පාලනය කිරීම, වෙනත් ජාතීන් තුළ සමාන පද්ධති සංවර්ධනයට බලපෑම් කිරීම."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la capital de San Luis Potosí?","answer":"La capital es San Luis Potosí y tiene 911,908  habitantes."},{"question":"mene LIKIDIRI ?","answer":"Yana nufin butiki ne amma na karfe "},{"question":"Manana zo hianatra ve ny ankizy?","answer":"Manana zo hanangona fahalalana isan’ambaratongany ny ankizy rehetra: fanabeazana fototra, ambaratonga faharoa, ambaratonga ambony), saingy miankina amin’ny fahefa-manatanteraka ireo (vola, saina, vatana, ...)"},{"question":"Fintino ny lahatsarotra manaraka: \\"Ny fihinanana voankazo sy legioma isan-karazany dia manome vitaminina sy otrikaina tena ilaina izay manohana ny fahasalamana ankapobeny. Ny loko samihafa dia manondro ny otrikaina samihafa, ka ny sakafo isan-karazany dia fanalahidin'ny fahazoana otrikaina voalanjalanja.\\"","answer":"Toy izao ny famintinana ny lahatsoratra: \\"Ny fihinanana voankazo sy legioma maro loko dia miantoka ny fihinana sakafo voalanjalanja misy otrikaina tena ilaina.\\""},{"question":"tohizo ity ohabolana ity: \\"Miova andriana miova sata; miova vady ...\\".","answer":"ny tohin'ny ohabolana dia : \\"Miova andriana miova sata; miova vady miova nahandro\\""},{"question":"உரையாடல் என்பது இரண்டு அல்லது அதற்கு மேற்பட்ட நபர்களுக்கு இடையேயான ஊடாடும் தொடர்பு . உரையாடல் திறன் மற்றும் ஆசாரம் ஆகியவற்றின் வளர்ச்சி சமூகமயமாக்கலின் ஒரு முக்கிய பகுதியாகும். ஒரு புதிய மொழியில் உரையாடல் திறன்களை வளர்ப்பது மொழி கற்பித்தல் மற்றும் கற்றலில் அடிக்கடி கவனம் செலுத்துகிறது . உரையாடல் பகுப்பாய்வு என்பது சமூகவியலின் ஒரு பிரிவாகும், இது மனித தொடர்புகளின் கட்டமைப்பு மற்றும் அமைப்பை ஆய்வு செய்கிறது, மேலும் உரையாடல் தொடர்புகளில் அதிக கவனம் செலுத்துகிறது.மேலே உள்ள பத்தியைப் பயன்படுத்தி, தலைப்பைக் கண்டறிந்து அதன் தொடர்ச்சியை ஒரு கட்டுரையாக எழுதுங்கள்.","answer":"கொடுக்கப்பட்ட பத்தி 'உரையாடல்' பற்றியது. அதன் தொடர்ச்சி பின்வருமாறு:ஒரு உரையாடலில் குறைந்தபட்சம் இரண்டு நபர்கள் ஒன்றாகப் பேசுவதை உள்ளடக்கியது என்பதைத் தாண்டி, உரையாடலுக்கு பொதுவாக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட வரையறை எதுவும் இல்லை. இதன் விளைவாக, இந்த சொல் பெரும்பாலும் அது இல்லாதவற்றால் வரையறுக்கப்படுகிறது. பரஸ்பர வாழ்த்து போன்ற ஒரு சடங்கு பரிமாற்றம் ஒரு உரையாடல் அல்ல, மேலும் ஒரு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க நிலை வேறுபாட்டை உள்ளடக்கிய ஒரு தொடர்பு (முதலாளி உத்தரவுகளை வழங்குவது போன்றவை) ஒரு உரையாடல் அல்ல. இறுக்கமாக கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்ட தலைப்பு அல்லது நோக்கத்துடனான தொடர்பு பொதுவாக உரையாடலாகக் கருதப்படுவதில்லை. இந்த பண்புகளை சுருக்கமாக, ஒரு அதிகாரம் எழுதுகிறது, \\"உரையாடல் என்பது முறைசாரா, சமச்சீர் மற்றும் சமூக உறவுகளை நிறுவுதல் மற்றும் பராமரிக்கும் நோக்கங்களுக்காக நடக்கும் பேச்சு.\\"குறைவான தொழில்நுட்பக் கண்ணோட்டத்தில், இருபதாம் நூற்றாண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் ஆசாரம் குறித்த எழுத்தாளர், நிறுவனத்திற்காக மக்கள் ஒருவருக்கொருவர் பேசும் விஷயங்களை கண்ணியமாக கொடுக்கவும் எடுத்துக்கொள்ளவும் உரையாடலை வரையறுத்தார். உரையாடல்கள் ஆசார விதிகளைப் பின்பற்றுகின்றன, ஏனெனில் உரையாடல்கள் சமூக தொடர்புகளாகும், எனவே சமூக மரபு சார்ந்தது . உரையாடலுக்கான குறிப்பிட்ட விதிகள் கூட்டுறவுக் கொள்கையிலிருந்து எழுகின்றன . இந்த விதிகளைக் கடைப்பிடிக்கத் தவறினால், உரையாடல் மோசமடைகிறது அல்லது இறுதியில் முடிவடைகிறது. உரையாடலுக்கான பங்களிப்புகள் முன்பு கூறப்பட்டவற்றுக்கான பதில்கள்.பங்கேற்பாளர்களின் நோக்கத்தைப் பொறுத்து உரையாடல்கள் தகவல்தொடர்புக்கான உகந்த வடிவமாக இருக்கலாம் . எடுத்துக்காட்டாக, ஒவ்வொரு தரப்பினரும் ஒப்பீட்டளவில் சமமான தகவல் பரிமாற்றத்தை விரும்பும் போது அல்லது கட்சிகள் சமூக உறவுகளை உருவாக்க விரும்பும் போது உரையாடல்கள் சிறந்ததாக இருக்கலாம். மறுபுறம், நிரந்தரம் அல்லது அத்தகைய தகவலை மதிப்பாய்வு செய்யும் திறன் முக்கியமானது என்றால், எழுதப்பட்ட தொடர்பு சிறந்ததாக இருக்கலாம். அல்லது நேரத்திற்கேற்ற தகவல் தொடர்பு மிக முக்கியமானதாக இருந்தால், பேச்சு விரும்பத்தக்கதாக இருக்கலாம். உரையாடல் என்பது சொற்களுக்கு அடியில் இருக்கும் மிகவும் நுணுக்கமான மற்றும் மறைமுகமான சூழலை உள்ளடக்கியது.வகைப்பாடு: கேலி பேசுபவர்:\\"பேண்டர்\\" இங்கு வழிமாற்றுகிறது. வானொலி நிகழ்ச்சிக்கு, பான்டர் (வானொலி நிகழ்ச்சி) பார்க்கவும் .பான்டர் என்பது தனிநபர்களுக்கு இடையே முன்னும் பின்னுமாக குதிக்கும் குறுகிய நகைச்சுவையான வாக்கியங்கள். பறப்பது , தவறான புரிதல்கள் (பெரும்பாலும் வேண்டுமென்றே), ஜிப்பி வைஸ்கிராக்ஸ், ஜிங்கர்ஸ், ஊர்சுற்றல் மற்றும் சிலேடைகள் போன்ற புத்திசாலித்தனமான புட்-டவுன்கள் மற்றும் நகைச்சுவையான அவமானங்களை அடிக்கடி கேலி பேசுபவர் பயன்படுத்துகிறார் . கருத்து என்னவென்றால், கேலியின் ஒவ்வொரு வரியும் அதற்கு முன் உள்ளதை \\"மேலே\\" இருக்க வேண்டும் மற்றும் சுருக்கமாக, புத்திசாலித்தனமான வாய்மொழி யுத்தமாக இருக்க வேண்டும்.உரையாடல்களின் கட்டமைப்பின் வழியாக கேலி செய்வதைப் பயன்படுத்திய திரைப்படங்கள்:\\t\\t\\tஅ) ப்ரிங்கிங் அப் பேபி (1938)ஆ) அவரது பெண் வெள்ளி (1940)இ) தி பிக் ஸ்லீப் (1946)ஈ) மச் அடோ அபௌட் நத்திங் (1993)கேலி பேசுவதில் முக்கிய காரணிகள் துணை உரை, சூழ்நிலை மற்றும் நபருடனான உறவு. ஒரு கேலிக்கூத்தில் உள்ள ஒவ்வொரு வரியும் ஒருவரின் உணர்வுகளைப் புண்படுத்தாமல் உணர்ச்சிபூர்வமான பதிலையும் உரிமையையும் தூண்டக்கூடியதாக இருக்க வேண்டும். சம்பந்தப்பட்ட தரப்பினர் புரிந்து கொள்ளும் ஒரு கட்டமைப்பைப் பின்பற்றுவது முக்கியம், பொருள் மற்றும் அமைப்பு அபத்தமாக இருந்தாலும், ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட அளவிலான முன்னேற்றம் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட தரப்பினருடன் இணைக்கும் வகையில் வைக்கப்பட வேண்டும்.பல்வேறு கதை சொல்லும் முறைகள் கேலி பேசுவதற்கு பயன்படுத்தப்படலாம், அதாவது கட்டமைப்பின் ஓட்டத்தில் எதிர்பாராத திருப்பத்தை ஏற்படுத்துதல் (சுகமான கட்டமைப்பை குறுக்கிடுதல்), கேள்விகள், சந்தேகங்கள், சுய-மனசாட்சியைத் தூண்டுதல் (வேண்டுமென்றே தவறான புரிதலை உருவாக்குதல்) ஆகியவற்றுடன் உரையாடலை எதிர்பார்க்கும் கச்சா வடிவத்தை நோக்கி கொண்டு செல்லலாம். ), அல்லது ஏற்கனவே உள்ள வடிவத்தை பல நங்கூரங்களுடன் அடுக்கி வைப்பது. விளையாட்டு மைதான விதிகளின் உணர்திறனுடன் கேலி செய்வதை விட்டுவிடுவது முக்கியம், இரு தரப்பினரும் ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட புள்ளிக்குப் பிறகு, தொடர்ந்து ஒருவரையொருவர் முதலிடம் வகிக்க வேண்டும். ஷேக்ஸ்பியர் சொன்னது போல் \\"சுருக்கமானது புத்தியின் ஆன்மா.\\"விவாதம்:இரண்டு பழைய நண்பர்களுக்கிடையேயான உரையாடல்:உரையாடலின் ஒரு கூறு விவாதம் : உரையாடலின் போது சிந்திக்கப்படும் விஷயங்களில் கருத்துக்களைப் பகிர்ந்துகொள்வது. கண்ணியமான சமுதாயத்தில் விவாதம் சர்ச்சையாகவோ அல்லது சர்ச்சையாகவோ மாறுவதற்கு முன் பொருள் மாறுகிறது . உதாரணமாக, இறையியல் விவாதிக்கப்படுகிறதென்றால் , ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட கருத்தை ஏற்கும்படி யாரும் வலியுறுத்தவில்லை.பொருள்:பல உரையாடல்களை அவற்றின் முக்கிய பொருள் உள்ளடக்கத்தின்படி நான்கு வகைகளாகப் பிரிக்கலாம்:அ) அகநிலை கருத்துக்கள் , இது பெரும்பாலும் புரிதலையும் விழிப்புணர்வையும் நீட்டிக்க உதவுகிறது.ஆ) புறநிலை உண்மைகள் , இது பரந்த பார்வையை ஒருங்கிணைக்க உதவும்.இ) மற்ற நபர்கள் (பொதுவாக இல்லாதவர்கள்), இது விமர்சன ரீதியாகவோ , போட்டியாகவோ அல்லது ஆதரவாகவோ இருக்கலாம் . இதில் வதந்திகளும் அடங்கும்.ஈ) தன்னை , இது சில நேரங்களில் கவனத்தைத் தேடும் நடத்தையைக் குறிக்கிறது அல்லது உரையாடலில் பங்கேற்பவர்களுக்கு தன்னைப் பற்றிய பொருத்தமான தகவலை வழங்க முடியும்.வகைகளுக்கிடையே கொடுக்கப்பட்ட எந்தவொரு உரையாடலின் விகிதாசார விநியோகம் பங்கேற்பாளர்களின் மனநிலையைப் பற்றிய பயனுள்ள உளவியல் நுண்ணறிவுகளை வழங்க முடியும். இருப்பினும், நடைமுறையில், சில உரையாடல்கள் பிரத்தியேகமாக ஒரு வகைக்குள் அடங்கும். பெரும்பாலான உரையாடல்களை வகைப்படுத்துவது கடினமாக இருப்பதற்கு இதுவே காரணம்.செயல்பாடுகள்:பெரும்பாலான உரையாடல்கள் அவற்றின் இலக்கின் அடிப்படையில் வகைப்படுத்தப்படலாம். உரையாடல் முடிவில் உரையாடலின் வாழ்க்கையில் மாறலாம்.அ) செயல்பாட்டு உரையாடல் ஒரு தனிநபர் அல்லது குழு இலக்கை அடைய உதவும் வகையில் தகவலை தெரிவிக்க வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.ஆ) சிறு பேச்சு என்பது ஒரு வகையான உரையாடலாகும், இதில் சமூக நோக்கத்தை விட மக்களுக்கு இடையே பிணைப்பை அடைவது அல்லது தனிப்பட்ட தூரத்தை நிர்வகித்தல் போன்ற 'வானிலை எப்படி உள்ளது' போன்றவற்றை ஒரு உதாரணமாக சித்தரிக்கலாம், இது எந்த நடைமுறையையும் வெளிப்படுத்தாது."},{"question":"Inona ny anaran'ny rakibolana novokarin'i Donal Baxter McMillan ? ","answer":"Ny anaran'ny rakibolana novokarin'i Donal Baxter McMillan dia ny Eskimo - English. "},{"question":"पुढीलपैकी कोणत्या शब्दाचा उल्लेख भारतीय राज्य घटनेत केलेला नाही?(A) अटॉर्नी जनरल(B) अर्थसंकल्प(C) कॅबिनेट(D) नियंत्रक आणि महालेखा परीक्षक=> ","answer":"(B) अर्थसंकल्प"},{"question":"الجملة 1: أتالاكميا مولتي لينييا هو نوع من حلزون البحر أو ليمبت حقيقي ، وهو حشرة بحرية في عائلة لوتييداي ، واحدة من عائلات ليمبتات حقيقية. الجملة 2: أتالاكميا مولتي لينييا هو نوع من الحلزون البحري أو الحلزون الحقيقي ، وهو ريحان بحري من عائلة لوتيتيدي ، واحدة من عائلات الحلزونات الحقيقية. سؤال: الجملة 1 والجملة 2 بتعبر عن نفس المعنى؟ نعم ولا لا؟","answer":"ايوه، الجملتان تعبران عن نفس المعنى"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"_ dia niova fo ho Kristianina izay nandray anjara lehibe tamin'ny fampielezana ny finoana.\\"","answer":"Valiny: I Paoly avy any Tarsosy dia niova fo ho amin'ny Kristianisma izay nandray anjara lehibe tamin'ny fampielezana ny finoana."},{"question":"Quốc kỳ Brunei có một dòng chữ Arab, đúng hay sai?","answer":"Đúng. Quốc kỳ Brunei có một dòng chữ Arab màu vàng, có thể dịch là \\"Luôn phục vụ dưới sự dẫn đường của Thượng đế\\".Quốc kỳ Brunei được thông qua vào ngày 29/9/1959 khi quốc gia này trở thành một nước được Anh bảo hộ, sau đó được giữ lại khi Brunei giành độc lập vào 1/1/1984.Quốc kỳ có nền màu vàng - màu của hoàng gia và tượng trưng cho vương quốc Hồi giáo, cùng hai dài màu trắng, đen, tượng trưng cho hai bộ trưởng của Brunei. Quốc huy màu đỏ được đặt chính giữa, dòng chữ Arab nằm trên quốc huy."},{"question":"குறுந்தொகை நூலை முதலில் பதிப்பித்தவர்?      1. சௌரிபெருமாள் அரங்கனார்   2. பன்னாடு தந்த பாண்டியன் மாறன் வழுதி   3. சி.வை.தாமோதரம் பிள்ளை   4. உப்பூரி குடிகிழார் மகனார் உருத்திரசன்மனார்","answer":"   3. சி.வை.தாமோதரம் பிள்ளை"},{"question":"विश्वमा सबैभन्दा बढि बाल मजदुर भएको देश कुन हो?","answer":"भारत"},{"question":"ইসরো কী?","answer":"ভারতীয় মহাকাশ গবেষণা সংস্থা (ইসরো) ভারতের রাষ্ট্রীয় মহাকাশ গবেষণা সংস্থা, যার কার্যালয় বেঙ্গালুরু শহরের অবস্থিত। মহাকাশ গবেষণার প্রয়োজনীয়তা স্বীকার করে বিজ্ঞানী বিক্রম সারাভাইয়ের অনুরোধে ১৯৬২ সালে জওহরলাল নেহেরু পরমাণু শক্তি বিভাগের (ডিএই) অধীনে ইন্ডিয়ান ন্যাশনাল কমিটি ফর স্পেস রিসার্চ (ইনকোসপার) প্রতিষ্ঠা করেন। ডিএই-এর মধ্যে ইনকোসপার বিকশিত হয়ে ১৯৬৯ সালে ইসরো হয়ে ওঠে |"},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Under 1800-talet minskade haciendasystemets betydelse, parallellt med att många tidigare spanska kolonier blev självständiga stater. I Dominikanska republiken delades storgodsen upp i mindre lantegendomar eller jordbruk. I Mexiko försvann haciendasystemet 1917, efter Mexikos revolution","answer":"1911, och systemet försvann senare på liknande sätt även från Bolivia (jordbruksreformer 1969) och Peru (vänsterrevolutionen 1952)."},{"question":"What is the male reproductive system?","answer":"Male Reproductive SystemThe male reproductive system mostly exists outside of your body. The external organs include the penis, scrotum, and testicles. Internal organs include the vas deferens, prostate, and urethra. The male reproductive system is responsible for sexual function and urination.What does the male reproductive system do?The organs that make up the male reproductive system perform the following:Produce, maintain, and transport sperm cells and semen. Sperm cells are male reproductive cells. Semen is the protective fluid around sperm.▪️Discharge sperm.produce and secrete male sex hormones.How does the male reproductive system function?The entire male reproductive system depends on hormones. Hormones are chemicals that stimulate or regulate activity in your cells or organs. The primary hormones that help the male reproductive system function include:▪️ Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) Your pituitary gland makesFSH. FSH is necessary to produce sperm (spermatogenesis).▪️Luteinizing hormone (LH). Your pituitary gland also makes LH. LH is necessary to continue the process of spermatogenesis.▪️Testosterone. Testosterone is the main sex hormone in people. It helps you develop certain characteristics, including muscle mass and strength, fat distribution, bone mass, and sex drive (libido).What are the external parts of the male reproductive system?Most of the male reproductive system is on the outside of your abdominal cavity or pelvis. The external body parts of the male reproductive system include the penis, scrotum, and testicles. Another name for these parts is genitals or genitalia.PenisThe penis is the male organ for sexual intercourse. It contains many sensitive nerve endings, and it has three parts:▪️Root. The root is the base of your penis. It attaches to the wall of your abdomen.▪️Body (shaft). The body has a shape like a tube or cylinder. It consists of three internal chambers: the two larger chambers are the corpora cavernosa, and the third chamber is the corpus spongiosum. The corpora cavernosa runs side by side, while the corpus spongiosum surrounds your urethra. There’s a special, sponge-like erectile tissue inside these chambers. The erectile tissue contains thousands of spaces. During sexual arousal, the spaces fill with blood, and your penis becomes hard and rigid (erection). An erection allows you to have penetrative sex. The skin of the penis is loose and stretchy, which lets it change size when you have an erection.▪️Glans (head). The glans are the cone-shaped tips of the penis. A loose layer of skin (foreskin) covers the glans. Healthcare providers sometimes surgically remove the foreskin (circumcision).In most people, the opening of the urethra is at the tip of the glans. The urethra transports pee and semen out of your body. Semen contains sperm. You expel (ejaculate) semen through the end of your penis when you reach sexual climax (orgasm).When your penis is erect, your corpora cavernosa presses against the part of your urethra where pee flows. This blocks your pee flow so that only semen ejaculates when you orgasm.ScrotumThe scrotum is the loose, pouch-like sac of skin that hangs behind the penis. It holds the testicles (testes) as well as nerves and blood vessels.The scrotum protects your testicles and provides a sort of “climate-control system.” For normal sperm development, the testes must be at a temperature that’s slightly cooler than body temperature (between 97 and 99 degrees Fahrenheit or 36 and 37 degrees Celsius). Special muscles in the wall of the scrotum let it contract (tighten) and relax. Your scrotum contracts to move your testicles closer to your body for warmth and protection. It relaxes your body to cool them.TesticlesThe testicles (testes) are oval-shaped organs that lie in your scrotum. They’re about the size of two large olives. The spermatic cord holds the testicles in place and supplies them with blood. Most people with AMAB have two testicles, on the left and right sides of the scrotum. The testicles make testosterone and produce sperm. Within the testicles are coiled masses of tubes. These are the seminiferous tubules. The seminiferous tubules produce sperm cells through spermatogenesis.EpididymisThe epididymis is a long, coiled tube that rests on the back of each testicle. It carries and stores the sperm cells that your testicles create. The epididymis also brings the sperm to maturity; the sperm that emerge from the testicles are immature and incapable of fertilization. During sexual arousal, muscle contractions force the sperm into the vas deferens.What are the internal parts of the male reproductive system?There are several internal (accessory) organs in the male reproductive system. They include:▪️Vas deferensThe vas deferens is a long, muscular tube that travels from the epididymis into the pelvic cavity, just behind the urinary bladder. The vas deferens transports mature sperm to the urethra in preparation for ejaculation.▪️Ejaculatory ductsEach testicle has a vas deferens that joins with seminal vesicle ducts to form ejaculatory ducts. The ejaculatory ducts move through your prostate, where they collect fluid to add to semen. They empty into your urethra.▪️UrethraThe urethra is the tube that carries pee from your bladder outside of your body. If you have a penis, it also ejaculates semen when you reach orgasm.▪️Seminal vesiclesThe seminal vesicles are sac-like pouches that attach to the vas deferens near the base of the bladder. Seminal vesicles make up to 80% of your ejaculatory fluid, including fructose. Fructose is an energy source for sperm and helps them move (motility).▪️Prostate glandThe prostate is a walnut-sized gland that rests below your bladder, in front of your rectum. The prostate adds additional fluid to ejaculate, which helps nourish sperm. The urethra runs through the center of the prostate gland.▪️Bulbourethral (Cowper) glandsThe bulbourethral glands are pea-sized structures on the sides of your urethra, just below your prostate. They create a clear, slippery fluid that empties directly into the urethra. This fluid lubricates the urethra and neutralizes any acids that may remain from your pee."},{"question":"Арча жөнүндө маалымат бере аласызбы?","answer":"Арча (латынча Juniperus) — Кипарис (Cupressaceae) түркүмүндөгү түбөлүк жашыл, ийне жалбырактуу бадалдар жана дарактар түрү.Падышалык өсүмдүк"},{"question":"Nuucyada nafaqo iyo shaqadooda .","answer":" Nafaqo ayaa guud ahaan waxa ay tahay sheeyama kimiko aad cuneyso si aad uga hesho tamar,caafimaad iyo koritaanka jirkaaga si aad u siinoolaato. Nafaqada ayaa guud ahaan waxaa loo kalaqeybiyaa labaa nuuc oo waaweyn oo kala ah  A) kuwa tamar looga baahan yahay oo loo yaqaan energy giving food  b) iyo kuwa kale oo aan tamar looga baahneyn oo ayagana loo yaqaannon-energy giving food. "},{"question":"In one sentence, describe the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on global healthcare systems","answer":"The COVID-19 pandemic strained healthcare systems worldwide, highlighting the need for preparedness, healthcare infrastructure, and global cooperation in addressing health crises."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ayam itik\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud ayam dan itik yang dipelihara"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"மனிதன் முன்னேற்றத்தை தடுக்க ஏற்படுத்தியவையே கடவுளும் மதங்களும்."},{"question":"Mchicha huliwa?","answer":"Naweza kusema ndio, mchicha ni chakula chenye kufaa kwa ajili ya afya kina wingi wa madini mbalilimbali na protein kiasi, pamoja na nyuzi nyuzi, zinazosaidia kumeng'enya chakula hicho."},{"question":"મઠિયાં સ્પેશ્યલ રેસીપી જણાવો ","answer":"સામગ્રી : એક કિલો મઠનો લોટ, 200 ગ્રામ અડદનો લોટ, 50 ગ્રામ સફેદ મરચું, 5 ટેબલ સ્પૂન મીઠુ અથવા સ્વાદ પ્રમાણે મીઠુ, 100 ગ્રામ દળેલી ખાંડ,અજમો 2 ટી સ્પૂન, તળવા માટે તેલ (પાતળાં મઠિયામાં હળદર નાખવી નહી) બનાવવાની રીત - એક કપ ગરમ પાણીમાં ખાંડ ઓગાળી લો, એક કપ પાણીમાં સફેદ મરચુ, મીઠું અને અજમો નાખી સારી રીતે મિક્સ કરી લો. બંને લોટને બરાબર મિક્સ કરી લો. હવે તેમા ખાંડનુ પાણી અને સફેદ મરચાનુ પાણી નાખી કઠણ લોટ બાંધો. આ લોટને સાધારણ તેલ નાખી સારી રીતે કૂટીને અને ખેંચો. લોટ નરમ પડી જવો જોઈએ. લોટને એક સરખા લુવા પાડી લો અને તેને ઢાંકી મુકો. હવે આ લૂઆને થાળી પર પ્લાસ્ટિક મુકી તેના પર તેલ લગાવી પાતળા મઠિયા વણી લો. મઠિયા ઉપરાઉપરી મુકતા જાવ જેથી સુકાય નહી. બધા મઠિયા વણાય જાય કે તેલ ખૂબ સારી રીતે તપાવી પછી મધ્યમ તાપ પર તળી લો.  નોંધ : મઠિયા તરત જ તળાય જાય છે તેથી તેને જલ્દી જલ્દી કાઢવા જોઈએ."},{"question":"Content: విశాఖపట్నంబుధవారం(18.03.2020) జరిగిన సచివాలయ ఉద్యోగుల సంఘం ఎగ్జిక్యూటివ్ కమిటి సమావేశంలో ఈ విషయంపై చర్చించారు. మే నెలాఖరు నాటికి విశాఖ వెళ్లడానికి సిద్ధంగా ఉండాలని ఉద్యోగ సంఘ నాయకులు సచివాలయ సిబ్బందికి సూచించారు.అమరావతి నుంచి కార్యనిర్వాహక రాజధానిని విశాఖ తరలించాని ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్ ప్రభుత్వం కొద్దికాలం కిందట నిర్ణయించింది.ప్రభుత్వ నిర్ణయంతో సచివాలయం విశాఖపట్నానికి తరలనుండడంతో ఉద్యోగులూ అక్కడికి వెళ్లాల్సి వస్తోంది.విశాఖ వెళ్తున్న నేపథ్యంలో తమ డిమాండ్లకు ప్రభుత్వం సానుకూలంగా ఉందని ఉద్యోగ సంఘాల నాయకులు చెప్పారు. దీనికి సంబంధించి ఏమైనా సమస్యలుంటే సంఘం దృష్టికి తేవాలని సూచించారు.ఉద్యోగుల ప్రధాన డిమాండ్లు* ఇళ్ల స్థలాలు* 2015-19 మధ్య ఇళ్లు కానీ ఇళ్ల స్థలాలు కానీ కొనుగోలు చేసినవారికి వడ్డీలేని రుణాలు.* విశాఖలో పాఠశాలలో అడ్మిషన్లు* భార్య లేదా భర్త ఉద్యోగస్తులైతే (కేంద్రం, బ్యాంకులు, ఇతర ప్రభుత్వ సంస్థలు లేదా శాఖలు) వారి బదిలీలు, అంతర్రాష్ట్ర బదిలీలు, స్థానిక హోదా* షిఫ్టింగు అలవెన్స్* బ్యాచిలర్లు, కుటుంబాలకు వసతి* అమరావతిలో ఇళ్లు లేదా స్థలాలు కొనని వారికి ప్రత్యేక లోన్లు* ౩౦ శాతం ఇంటి అద్దె భత్యం* రవాణా సౌకర్యం, ఇతర అంశాలు.సానుకూలంగా ప్రభుత్వంఉద్యోగులకు ఉండే సాధారణ సమస్యలు అంటే.. అక్కడ వసతి కల్పించడం, స్కూల్ అడ్మిషన్లు, ఇంటి స్థలాలు, భాగస్వామి బదిలీలు వంటి వాటిపై ప్రభుత్వం సానుకూలంగా ఉంది. ''మాకున్న సౌకర్యాలు ఐదు రోజుల పని, ౩౦ శాతం అద్దె అలవెన్సు విషయంలో కూడా ప్రభుత్వం సానుకూలంగానే ఉంది. ఇక అమరావతి పరిసరాల్లో పనిచేస్తున్న స్పౌజ్ ట్రాన్సఫర్లు, తెలంగాణలో ఉండిపోయిన వారి బదిలీల విషయంలో ప్రభుత్వం డేటా అడిగింది. అది మ్యూచువల్ గా చేయవచ్చేమో ఆలోచిస్తోంది. స్కూల్ అడ్మిషన్లు ఎంత మందికి కావాలి? అమరావతిలో ఇప్పటికే ఇళ్లు కట్టుకున్న వారు ఎంత మంది? బ్యాచిలర్ ఎకామిడేషన్ ఎందరికి అవసరం వంటివి కూడా డాటా ఇవ్వమన్నారు.'' అని సచివాలయ ఉద్యోగ సంఘం అధ్యక్షులు వెంకట్రామి రెడ్డి బీబీసీతో చెప్పారు.జూన్ మొదటి వారంలో వెళ్లాల్సి ఉంటుందని తాము అనుకుంటున్నామని, అదే విషయం ఉన్నతాధికారులు చెప్పామన్నారాయన. కోర్టు కేసులు వంటి అంశాలు ఈ తరలింపును ప్రభావితం చేస్తాయని ఇప్పటివరకు రాజధాని తరలింపు విషయంలో అందరి కంటే ఎక్కువ ప్రభావితం అయ్యే వారిలో సచివాలయ ఉద్యోగులు కూడా ఉన్నారని అన్నారు. కాగా సచివాలయ ఉద్యోగులు తొలి నుంచీ...","answer":"ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్‌కు కార్యనిర్వాహక రాజధాని(ఎగ్జిక్యూటివ్ కేపిటల్‌)గా ప్రస్తుత ప్రభుత్వం నిర్ణయించిన విశాఖపట్నానికి తరలేందుకు సచివాలయ ఉద్యోగులు సిద్ధమవుతున్నారు."},{"question":"MAGTA LAGA BIXINAYO HADDII HAWEENEY LA DILO !MA BOQOLLEYBAA MISE WAA KONTONLEY? ","answer":"Marka uu dilku ku dhaco si kama’ ah qudheeda waxa keliya oo loo kala saari karaa, sida ay Aayadduba u caddaysay, dhibanaha ama marxuumka saddex nooc oo kala ah:- 1- in dilkaasi uu ku dhacay qof mu’min, Alle rumeeye, ah, kuna nool dal Islaami ah – darul-islam, ehelkiisu/keeduna ay Muslimiin yihiin. 2- In uu dilkaasi ku dhacay qof mu’min ah, laakiin ku dhexnool ciddiisa oo aan iyagu Muslimiin ahayn, hase ahaatee ay ballan nabadgelyo ihi kala dhexayso Muslimiinta. 3- In kan/tan la dilay ahaa Mu’min ku dhexnool ciddiisii oo aan Muslimiin ahayn, laguna kari waayey Islaamka, kulana jiray Muslimiinta dagaal ka fool ka fool ah.Xukunka labada xaaladood ee hore waa laba ciqaabood oo wada socota: midda koowaad waa in uu soo buuxshaa tiradii Muslimiinta ee uu dhimay, oo keenaa qof cusub halkii uu ka dilay qofka. Taasi waxa ay ku dhacaysaa in uu xoreeyo qof Mu’min ahaa oo laga haystay Mu’miniinta kale si gumaysi ah ama xabsi dheer ah (in uu dad cusub diinta gaarsiiyo iyadu awalba waajib ayey ku ahayd). Midda labaadna waa in uu/ay faraha ka saaraa/taa magdhaw layaqaan ciddii uu/ay qofka ka dilay/shay si gaar ahaaneed. Taas macneheedu waxaa weeye in ruuxa Muslimka ihi uu ka baxay laba qoys. Qoyskii uu ka dhashay ama u dhaxay (civil law) iyo qoyska Muslimiinta adduunka oo dhan ah (public law). Sidaa darteed gacan ku dhiigluhu waa in uu labadiiba qanciyaa. Xukunka xaaladda dambe waa mid keliya oo ah in uu xoreeyo naf Mu’min ah oo loo haystay gumaysi ahaan ama xabsi lahaystenimo ku ahaa maxbuus loo haysto madaxfurasho, ama la madaxfuran karo. Taas macneheedu waxaa weeye. Ruuxaas Mu’minka ihi ma lahayn tol iyo qaraabo aan ka ahayn Muslimiinta adduunka oo dhiigiisa leh. Sidaa darteed waa in uu gacan ku dhiigluhu u magdhawaa Mu’miniinta adduunka ku nool oo faraha ka soo saaraa naf ruux cusub halkii uu ka maqnaysiiyey midkii hore7. Hadduuse gacan ku dhiigluhu waayo cid uu xoreeyo, si kastaba ha ku dhacdee, waa in uu/ ay soomaa/ntaa laba bilood oo xiriir ah si uu/ay isaga gudo magtii dadweynaha Muslimiinta ah iyo Eebeba ay u haysteen.Guud ahaanba sharaxaadaasi waxa u si toos ah iyo si dadbanba u haysatay marka la gooyo nafta ruux Mu’minah iyada oo aan loola kicin ee shil lama filaan ihi ku dhacay. Marnaba Aayaddaan iyo Aayad kale toona makala saarin nafta qofka Muslimka ah, nooca uu doono ha noqdee. Haddaba waxaa is weydiin weyn noqon karta mar hadday diinta Islaamku sidaas aan caadku saarnayn u cadaysay qiimaha nafta Muslimadda ah ee gar darrada ama shilka lama filaanka ah lagu gooyey ragahaataa iyo dumar ahaataaba, xaggee laga keenay in lakala qiima saraysiiyo oo qolana badh qudh ah laga siiyo diyadoodii qolana loo dhamays tiro? "},{"question":"ලෝක කම්කරු සංවිධානයේ මූලස්ථානය පිහිටා  ඇත්තේ කොහේද?","answer":"ජාත්‍යන්තර කම්කරු සංවිධානයේ (ILO) මූලස්ථානය ස්විට්සර්ලන්තයේ ජිනීවා  නුවර පිහිටා  ඇත."},{"question":"Indro misy fehezanteny amin'ny teny anglisy: \\"The sun is shining brightly in the sky.\\"Adikao ho amin'ny teny malagasy io fehezanteny io. ","answer":"Rehefa adika amin'ny teny malagasy io fehezanteny io dia lasa hoe: \\"Mamiratra eny amin'ny lanitra ny masoandro.\\""},{"question":"Inona no renivohitr'i Espaina?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Espaina dia Madrid."},{"question":"Je hebt een stapel met 23 kaarten. Op elke kaart staat aan de ene kant een kruisje, en aan de andere kant een rondje. Je weet dat er in de stapel 14 kaarten met een kruisje naar boven liggen, en dus 9 met een rondje naar boven liggen, maar je weet niet in welke volgorde de kaarten liggen. Bovendien bevind je je in een volledig donkere kamer, zodat je niets kunt zien.De vraag: Hoe kun je, terwijl je niets kunt zien, de stapel kaarten in twee kleinere stapeltjes verdelen, zodanig dat in beide stapeltjes evenveel kaarten met een kruisje naar boven liggen?","answer":"Neem 14 kaarten van de stapel. Van deze 14 kaarten liggen k kaarten met een kruisje naar boven, en dus 14-k kaarten met een rondje naar boven. In het resterende stapeltje van 9 kaarten liggen 14-k kaarten met een kruisje naar boven.Draai dan het stapeltje met 14 kaarten om. Nu liggen er dus in beide stapeltjes 14-k kaarten met een kruisje naar boven.Merk op dat we niet precies weten hoeveel kaarten met een kruisje naar boven liggen in beide stapeltjes (of hoeveel kaarten met een rondje naar boven liggen). We weten alleen dat in beide stapeltjes evenveel kaarten met een kruisje naar boven liggen. "},{"question":"Nitori bi eto aabo to dẹnukọlẹ, ijọba ṣepade pẹlu awọn adari Fulani ni Kwara ","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Kwara, Abdulrahman Abdulrazaq, ti ṣepade pẹlu awọn adari Fulani nipinlẹ naa nitori eto aabo to dẹnukọlẹ, ati ki alaafia le maa jọba.Ọjọ Aje, Monde, ọṣẹ yii, ni Abdulrazak ṣepade pọ pẹlu adari ẹya Fulani latari gbedeke ọjọ ti ẹkun Guusu Naijiria fun awọn Fulani darandaran lori didaranjẹ ni gbangba ni ẹkun naa, ti awọn Fulani ọhun si n ya wọ ipinlẹ Kwara bo ṣe wu wọn. Gomina ti waa sọ fun awọn adari Fulani naa lati ri i daju pe wọn wa wọrọkọ fi sada lori bi awọn darandaran ọhun ṣe n ya wọ ipinlẹ Kwara bo ṣe wu wọn, to si jẹ ewu gidi fun aabo ipinlẹ ọhun.Abdulrazaq tẹsiwaju pe awọn Fulani darandaran yii, pẹlu awọn agbẹ gbọdọ mọ bi wọn yoo ṣe maa gbe pọ ni alaafia ati ifọkanbalẹ, tori pe ipade naa ko sẹyin ipo ti eto aabo wa ati awọn ohun to n ṣẹlẹ ni awọn agbegbe ni ipinlẹ Kwara lọwọ lọwọ. Bakan naa ni gomina ni oniruuru eto ni ijọba Kwara ti gbe kalẹ lati fi ṣe ilanilọyẹ lori bi Fulani ati agbẹ yoo ṣe maa gbe pọ lai si gbọnmi si i, omi o to o laarin wọn.Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Kwara, CP Tuesday Assayomo, to sọrọ nibi ipade ọhun sọ pe awọn pe ipade yii lati rọ awọn Fulani ati agbẹ ki wọn fọwọsowọpọ laarin ara wọn gẹgẹ bii ijọba ati awọn ẹsọ alaabo ṣe n gbiyanju lati ri i daju pe aabo to duroo re rẹsẹ walẹ ni ipinlẹ Kwara. Aarẹ awọn agba Fulani, ẹka ti ipinlẹ Kwara, Alhaji Ahmed Magaji, ti oun naa sọrọ nibi ipade ọhun sọ pe ibanujẹ ọkan lo jẹ bo ṣe jẹ pe wọn sọ awọn Fulani ni orukọ buruku, ati pe lati ọdun pipẹ ni awọn eniyan awujọ ti n dẹyẹ si ẹya Fulani, kọda wọn o jẹ ki ẹya naa jẹ anfaani eto ẹkọ to jiire lorile-ede yii."},{"question":"Who is the youngest person to become the president of the United States, and how did he get into office?","answer":"The youngest person to become President of the United States was Theodore Roosevelt. He assumed office at the age of 42, following the assassination of President William McKinley in 1901. Roosevelt was serving as Vice President at the time, and according to the U.S. Constitution, the Vice President is the first in line of succession to the presidency in the event of the president's death, resignation, or removal from office. This is how Roosevelt became president, making him the youngest person to hold the office in American history."},{"question":"إينا واحد فيهم مالح اكثر, البحر الأحمر أو المتوسط ؟","answer":"البحر الأحمر"},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය සිලෝන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය (University of Ceylon) යි. එය වර්ෂ 1942 සිට 1972 දක්වා පැවති අතර ඉන් පසුව එය, ශ්‍රී ලංකා විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය ලෙසත් 1978 වර්ෂයේ දී කොලඹ විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය (University of Colombo), පේරාදෙණිය විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය (University of Peradeniya), කැලණිය විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය/විද්‍යාලංකාර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය (University of Kelaniya/Vidyalankara University) සහ ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය/විද්‍යෝදය විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය (University of Jayawardenapura/Vidyodaya University) ලෙස විශ්වවිද්‍යාල හතරකට බෙදා දක්වන ලදී."},{"question":"De-me um exemplo de trivialidade na seguinte categoria: geografia.","answer":"Qual a única capital europeia localizada na fronteira com dois outros países?Bratislava, capital da Eslováquia, e localizada na fronteira com a Áustria e a Hungria."},{"question":"താഴെപ്പറയുന്ന വാചകം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക: പക്ഷേ അതേ സമയം, സാലിയെ കുറിച്ചും, അവൾ കടന്നുപോകുന്നതിനെ കുറിച്ചും അവൾക്ക് ഭയങ്കര ആശങ്കയുണ്ടായിരുന്നു. കണ്ണുനീര് വരാൻ തുടങ്ങി. അവൾ സമ്മതിച്ചുകൊണ്ട് തലയാട്ടി എന്നിട്ട് തിരിഞ്ഞു നോക്കി, അങ്ങനെ അവർ അവളെ കരയുന്നത് കാണില്ല.","answer":"സെത്ത്"},{"question":"قم بإنشاء قصيدة قصيره من بحر السريع.","answer":"شَكَت إِلى الرُوم أَحياؤُنامِن فِتية تَفتي عَلى جَهلِهافَأَرسَل الفتيا مَليك الوَرىلِنَجل فَرفور عَلى رسلهاوَأَصبَح الفَضل لَنا قائِلاًأَدّوا الأَمانات إِلى أَهلِها"},{"question":"‘నీ కరుణాకటాక్షవీక్షణములకై నిరీక్షించుచున్నారము’ ఈ వాక్యంలోని అలంకారాన్ని గుర్తించి, లక్షణం రాయండి.","answer":"ఈ వాక్యంలో ‘వృత్త్యనుప్రాస’ అలంకారం ఉంది.లక్షణం : ఒకే అక్షరము పలుమార్లు ఆ వృత్తియగుట వృత్త్యనుప్రాస."},{"question":"Believes so fervently in humanity that it feels almost anachronistic , and it is too cute by half. But arriving at a particularly dark moment in history, it offers flickering reminders of the ties that bind us. How does the reviewer feel about the movie?","answer":"They loved it."},{"question":"APC lo yege ibo alaga kansu ni gbogbo ijọba ibilẹ ogun nipinlẹ Ogun","answer":"Ẹyọ kan ṣoṣo bayii ko ṣẹku ninu ijọba ibilẹ Ogun to wa nipinlẹ Ogun, eyi ti ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC ko mu ninu ibo ijọba ibilẹ ti wọn di lọjọ Satide to kọja yii, iyẹn fun ti awọn alaga ijọba ibilẹ. Gbogbo awọn to dupo ṣiamaanu wọn lo wọle pata.Aarọ kutu ọjọ Sannde ti i ṣe ọjọ kẹẹẹdọgbọn, oṣu keje, ni Alaga ajọ eleto idibo Ogun, Ọgbẹni Babatunde Osibodu, ti kede pe ijọba ibilẹ mẹtadinlogun (17) ti ja mọ APC lọwọ nipo alaga, iyẹn ninu ijọba ibilẹ Ogun to wa nipinlẹ yii.Nigba ti yoo fi di aago meji-aabọ ọsan ọjọ Sannde naa, Osibodu ti kede pe gbogbo ijọba ibilẹ Ogun pata ti ja mọ APC lọwọ fawọn alaga, ko si ẹgbẹ alatako kankan to rọwọ mu, awọn ondije lẹgbẹ APC ni kinni naa bọ si lọwọ gbogbo.Alaga OGSIC ṣalaye pe apapọ ibo ti wọn di fun ipo alaga lawọn ijọba ibilẹ ogun nipinlẹ Ogun jẹ ẹgbẹrun lọna irinwo din mẹrin, ojilelẹgbẹta ati ẹyọ kan (396, 641).O ni awọn yoo fi abajade ibo awọn kansilọ naa sita tawọn ba ṣetan.O fi idunnu rẹ han si bi ibo naa ṣe lọ nirọwọ-rọsẹ, o si dupẹ lọwọ awọn eeyan ti wọn huwa ọmọluabi, ti idibo naa fi yọri si rere.Bakan naa lo dupẹ lọwọ awọn agbofinro ti wọn ṣiṣẹ aabo lasiko ibo yii, o si rọ awọn ti wọn jawe olubori lati ṣe awọn ti wọn fidi rẹmi daadaa. Ki wọn ma ṣe ri wọn bii alatako."},{"question":"Quantos ossos temos no nosso corpo?a) 126b) 206c) 18d) 300e) 200","answer":"A alternativa correcta é: b) 206.O corpo humano tem 206 ossos: 22 na cabeça, 1 no pescoço, 6 no ouvido, 44 no tórax, 7 no abdômen, 62 nos membros inferiores e 64 nos membros inferiores."},{"question":"Ny elefanta no vorona lehibe indrindra eran-tany. Marina sa diso?","answer":"Diso. Biby mampinono ny elefanta fa tsy vorona. Ny vorona lehibe indrindra dia ny aotirisy."},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி கருத்துக்களில் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை குறிப்பிடவும்.","answer":"மேற்கோள்: \\"எந்த மனிதனும் எனக்குக் கீழானவன் அல்ல, அது போலவே எவனும் எனக்கு மேலாவனும் அல்ல\\"பெரியார் என்று பரவலாக அறியப்படும் ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி சமூக சீர்திருத்தத்திற்காகவும், சாதியை அகற்றுவதற்காகவும், மூடநம்பிக்கைகளை மக்களிடமிருந்து களைவதற்காகவும், பெண் விடுதலைக்காகவும் போராடியவர். தமிழகத்தின் மிக முக்கியமான இயக்கமாகக் கருதப்படும் திராவிடர் கழகத்தினைத் தோற்றுவித்தவர்."},{"question":"Кол  - кудайдын мөөрү. Ушуну түшүндүрүп берчи.","answer":"\\"Кол  - кудайдын мөөрү\\" дегенди төмөнкүдөй кылып түшүндүрсө болот:Убаданы кол алышып бекемдөө, убаданы бузбоо деген маанини берет.Атам: «кол – кудайдын мөөрү» дечү, келе колуңду ант бузбаска, – деп ордубуздан тургандан кийин Балкыбек мага ишенбегендей карады (Мавлянов)"},{"question":"ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ මූලස්ථානය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ කොහේද?","answer":"ස්විට්සර්ලන්තයේ ජිනීවා නුවර"},{"question":"Ajụjụ: olee mgbe e bu ụzọ bipụta ọkụ nke ihe efu? ","answer":"Ọktoba 1987"},{"question":"问：《荒野大镖客2》的故事情节是什么？","answer":"答：游戏设定在1899年的美国西部，讲述了主角亚瑟·摩根（Arthur Morgan）与他所在的范德林德帮派（Van der Linde gang）的故事。随着西部边疆的逐渐消失，帮派成员们必须在这个日益现代化的世界中求生。"},{"question":"Ihe anọ gbasara Kebbi State","answer":"Ȯra Kebbi (Kebbi State) bu state no n'ime Naigeria.Emepụtara ya na 27th August 1991. Isi obodo Kebbi steeti bụ Birnin Kebbi. Ahọpụtara ya dịka steeti iri abụọ na atọ kachasị na Naịjirịa "},{"question":"وجدت هذا السؤال في موقع ثقافي: ما هي سفينة الصحراء ؟ ماهي الإجابة؟","answer":"الإجابة على السؤال:سفينة الصحراء هي: الجمل."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe Repoblika?","answer":"Ny repoblika dia endrika fitondram-panjakana tsy manana mpanjaka ho mpitondra ny firenena, fomba fandaminana ny firenena ampiasan' ny solontenam-bahoaka ny fahefana, izay amin' ny ankapobeny nofidin' ny olom-pirenena, ary ny maha filoham-panjakana dia tsy ifandovana ary tsy ny filoham-panjakana irery no mitana ny fahefana.Ny repoblika dia mifanohitra amin' ny fanjakana lovaina, saingy tsy midika foana hoe demôkrasia ny repoblika. Ny repoblika dia tokony tsy afangaro amin' ny demôkrasia: fitondran' ny lalàna ny repoblika fa ny demôkrasia kosa dia fitondran' ny daholobe. Io hevitra faran' ny teny hoe demôkrasia io dia avy amin' ny teny grika hoe demokratía izay ahitana ny hoe demos (\\"vahoaka\\") sy ny hoe kratos (\\"fanjakana\\", \\"fitondrana\\")."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. පන්ති නැති ඉස්කෝලෙ බිඳලාජීවිතේ ගැන එපා ටියුෂන්හෝඩියට ආදරේ අරගෙනආයෙමත් එනවාද දුයිෂෙන් ආයෙමත් එනවාද දුයිෂෙන් ","answer":"පන්ති නැති ඉස්කෝලෙ බිඳලාජීවිතේ ගැන එපා ටියුෂන්හෝඩියට ආදරේ අරගෙනආයෙමත් එනවාද දුයිෂෙන් ආයෙමත් එනවාද දුයිෂෙන් ගුරුතුමනි ඔබ නො එන දවසකවෘක රෑනක් ඇවිත් මෙබිමට වසන්තය ගෙන ගියා ගොදුරටඔබේ ආදර පුංචි සිසුවියබළල් පැටියා තුරුලු කරගෙන අඬනවා හැමදාම හවසටඅඬනවා හැමදාම හවසටඇගේ හිත කියවන්න දන්නේඔබම පමණයි ගුරුතුමානනිහෝඩියම දන්නැති වුණත් ඔබහෝඩියම දන්නැති වුණත් ඔබසැඳෑ සුළඟේ සැලී වැලපෙනඅතක පොප්ලර් තුරක ශෝකයකවුරු නම් හඳුනයිද ඔබ මිසමේ මහා තණ බිමේ සැඟවුන ඔබේ උත්තම නොකී ප්‍රේමයසසල කරවයි ලොවේ හදවතහිම කුණාටුව දෙබෑ කරගෙන අස්සයා නැතිනම් පයින් වත්සහතිකයි ඔබ නැවත එන වගසහතිකයි ඔබ නැවත එන වගසහතිකයි ඔබ නැවත එන වගපන්ති නැති ඉස්කෝලෙ බිඳලාජීවිතේ ගැන එපා ටියුෂන්හෝඩියට ආදරේ අරගෙනආයෙමත් එනවාද දුයිෂෙන් ආයෙමත් එනවාද දුයිෂෙන්සමන් ලෙනින් රජී වසන්ත වෙල්ගම දර්ශන රුවන් දිසානායක"},{"question":"Ndi alimi angati m'Malawi muno?","answer":"Gulu la alimi ang'onoang'ono m'Malawi muno lili ndi mabanja pafupifupi 3.1 miliyoni omwe akugawana malo okwana mahekitala 6.5 miliyoni - 69% ya malo onse a Malawi okwana mahekitala 9.4 miliyoni omwe amapezeka paulimi pansi pa chikhalidwe chawo."},{"question":"මට විවාහ මංගල්‍යයක් සැලසුම් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය වන අතර කොතැනින් ආරම්භ කළ යුතු දැයි මට අදහසක් නැත. මා කළ යුතු දේවල් කිහිපයක් ගැන කල්පනා කිරීමට ඔබ මට උදවු කරනවාද?","answer":"ඔබේ විවාහ මංගල්යය ඔබ සහ හවුල්කරුවන් ආදරය කරන උත්සවයකි. ආරම්භ කළ යුතු ස්ථානය පිළිබඳ අදහස් කිහිපයක් මෙන්න. 1. ඔබේ සහකරු සමඟ අසුන් ගන්න, සෑම කෙනෙකුම ඔබේ විවාහය සඳහා අදාළ දැක්ම, බලාපොරොත්තු සහ සිහින බෙදා ගනී. සාවධානව සවන් දී ඔබේ සහකරු පවසන දේ සටහන් කරගන්න. 2. ඔබේ විවාහ මංගල්යයේදී ඔබට අවශ්ය පුද්ගලයින්ගේ ලැයිස්තුවක් සාදන්න. එක් එක් විභව ආරාධනය ස්ථර 1,2 සහ 3 ලෙස පෙළගස්වන්න සහ ඔවුන් නියෝජනය කරන පාර්ශවය (ඔබ, ඔබේ සහකරු හෝ දෙදෙනාම). 3. ඔබට වියදම් කළ හැකි දේ මත පදනම්ව මූලික අයවැයක් හඳුනා ගන්න. 4. ප්‍රමුඛතා අනුපිළිවෙලින් (ස්ථානය, සංගීත කණ්ඩායම, මල්, ඇඳුම, ආදිය) ඔබට සහ ඔබේ සහකරුට වඩාත්ම වැදගත් දේ ලැයිස්තුවක් සාදන්න 5. ඔබේ සැලසුම් ප්‍රයත්නවලදී ඔබට සහාය වීමට මංගල සැලසුම්කරුවෙකු බඳවා ගැනීම තක්සේරු කරන්න. ඔබ මෙම උද්යෝගිමත් ක්රියාවලිය ආරම්භ කරන විට වාසනාව!"},{"question":"‘Ọlọpaa to ba tu apo eeyan wo, tabi fipa gba ẹrọ kọmputa yoo wọ gau’","answer":"Ọga ọlọpaa ni Naijiria, Muhammed Adamu ti paṣẹ wi pe ọlọpaa kankan ko gbọdọ tun gbegi dina loju popo mọ, bẹẹ ni wọn ko gbọdọ maa yẹ apo awọn eeyan wo, ẹni to ba si ṣe bẹẹ, yoo fẹnu fẹra daadaa.Ninu atẹjade ti agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa, Ọgbẹni Frank Mba, fọwọ si ni ọga agba patapata fun awọn ọlọpaa lorilẹ-ede yii ti sọrọ ọhun fawọn oniroyin.Ninu ẹ naa lo ti sọ pe, awọn mi-in tọrọ ọhun tun kan ni ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa to n gbogun ti awọn iwa janduku bii ẹgbẹ okunkun, ijinigbe atawọn iwa ọdaran mi-in to lodi sofin.Wọn lawọn ẹsọ agbofinro yii ko tun gbọdọ maa da mọto duro loju popo maa gbọn inu ẹ yẹbẹyẹbẹ mọ, bẹẹ lawọn to n le awọn ̀ọmọ yahoo kiri, ti wọn a maa tu apo ati ẹrọ kọmputa wọn naa gbọdọ sinmi.Bakan naa lo sọ pe o ti di iwa ọdaran fun ọlọpaa ti ko ba wọṣọ lati maa gbebọn kiri, tabi da mọto duro kiri ojupopo. Bẹẹ lo fi kun un pe, wahala ni yoo da fun ọlọpaa tọwọ ba tẹ pe o huwa idojutini ninu iṣẹ agbofinro.Ohun ti ALAROYE gbọ pe o mu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa gbe igbesẹ yii ni bi awọn kan ṣe n lo iṣẹ agbofinro fi huwa ti ko ba ofin mu, eyi to n ko abuku ba iṣẹ ọlọpaa.Ọga ọlọpaa ti sọ pe, agbofinro kankan ko gbọdọ maa rin kiri, tabi gbe igi dina loju popo, ti wọn yoo si maa tu foonu awọn eeyan wo, tabi tu ẹrọ kọmputa ẹnikẹni wo. O ni, iṣẹ ti ijọba ran awọn ẹsọ agbofinro ni ki wọn gbogun ti idigunjale, ijinigbe atawọn iwa ọdaran mi-in, ati pe ko sẹni to ran wọn ki wọn maa yẹ apo wo, tabi hu iwa ilọnilọwọgba fun araalu."},{"question":"Quais times do Brasileirão Série A nunca caíram para a Série B?","answer":"Os times brasileiros da Série A que nunca caíram para segunda divisão são Santos, Flamengo, São Paulo e Cuiabá até o ano de 2023."},{"question":"ഒരു ബോക്സറും ഒരു എം. എം. എ. പോരാളിയും തമ്മിൽ ആരാണ് വിജയിക്കുക?","answer":"നിയമങ്ങളില്ലാത്ത, അല്ലെങ്കിൽ എംഎംഎയിൽ പിന്തുടരുന്ന നിയമങ്ങളുമായുള്ള പോരാട്ടത്തിൽ. എം. എം. എ. പോരാളികൾക്ക് ബോക്‌സറെക്കാൾ വ്യക്തമായ നേട്ടമുണ്ടാകും, കാരണം എം. എം. എ. പോരാളികൾക്ക് വൈവിധ്യമാർന്ന കഴിവുകൾ ഉണ്ട്, ഉദാഹരണത്തിന് അവർക്ക് അവരുടെ കൈകളും കാലുകളും ഉപയോഗിക്കാം. എന്നിരുന്നാലും, ബോക്സിംഗ് നിയമങ്ങൾക്ക് കീഴിൽ, അതേ തത്ത്വം ബാധകമാകും, ഈ ക്രമീകരണത്തിൽ ഒരു ബോക്സറിന് തീർച്ചയായും മുൻതൂക്കമുണ്ടാകും. ബോക്‌സിംഗ് നിയമങ്ങൾക്ക് കീഴിലായിരുന്ന ഫ്ലോയിഡ് മെയ്‌വെതർ vs കോനോർ മക്‌ഗ്രിഗർ പോരാട്ടം ഒരു മികച്ച ഉദാഹരണമാണ്, അത് മെയ്‌വെതർ വിജയിയായി ഉയർന്നു."},{"question":"Lĩnh vực nhân số học dựa vào đâu để phân loại xu hướng tính cách con người?","answer":"Lĩnh vực nhân số học dựa vào nhiều nguồn thông tin khác nhau để phân loại và nghiên cứu xu hướng tính cách con người. Một số nguồn thông tin quan trọng bao gồm:Khảo sát và nghiên cứu khoa học: Các nhà nhân số học thường thực hiện các khảo sát và nghiên cứu để thu thập dữ liệu về các yếu tố như tính cách, tình cảm, thái độ và hành vi của con người. Những dữ liệu này có thể được sử dụng để phân tích và phân loại xu hướng tính cách.Cơ sở dữ liệu và thống kê: Các cơ sở dữ liệu về tính cách và các yếu tố nhân số khác có thể được sử dụng để tạo ra các phân loại và phân tích xu hướng tính cách.Các hệ thống phân loại và kiểm định: Có nhiều hệ thống phân loại và kiểm định tính cách khác nhau đã được phát triển bởi các nhà nhân số học và tâm lý học. Một số ví dụ bao gồm MBTI (Myers-Briggs Type Indicator), Big Five Personality Traits (Ngũ Quy), và Enneagram (Hình chữ S).Phân tích dữ liệu xã hội và trực tuyến: Mạng xã hội và các nền tảng trực tuyến khác cung cấp dữ liệu về hành vi và tương tác của con người. Những dữ liệu này có thể được sử dụng để nghiên cứu và phân tích xu hướng tính cách.Tâm lý học và nhân trắc học: Các lĩnh vực như tâm lý học và nhân trắc học (psychometrics) cung cấp các phương pháp để đo lường và đánh giá tính cách con người, từ đó có thể được sử dụng để phân loại và phân tích xu hướng.Tóm lại, lĩnh vực nhân số học dựa vào nhiều nguồn thông tin và phương pháp khác nhau để phân loại và nghiên cứu xu hướng tính cách con người, nhưng cần phải sử dụng cẩn trọng và phân tích kỹ lưỡng để đảm bảo tính chính xác và đáng tin cậy của kết quả."},{"question":"Muhammadu Buhari","answer":"Muhammadu Buhari (tí wọ́n bí ní ọjọ́ kẹtàdínlógún, oṣù Ọ̀pẹ, ọdún 1942), olóṣèlú tí ó jẹ́ Ààrẹ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà láàrin ọdún 2015 sí ọdún 2023. Ó lo sáà àkọ́kọ́ rẹ̀ láàrin ọdún 2015 sí 2019 àti ìkejì láàrin ọdún 2019 sí 2023. Buhari tí fìgbà kan jẹ́ ogágun Mejọ Gẹ́nẹ́rà àti pé ó jẹ́ olórí orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà láti ọjọ́ kọkànlélọ́gbọ̀n, oṣù Ọ̀pẹ, odún 1983 sí oṣù Ògún, odún 1985, lẹ́yìn tí ó fipá gbàjọba. A bí Muhammadu Buhari sí ìdílé Fúlàní ní ìlú Daura, ìpínlẹ̀ Katsina. Bàbá rẹ̀ ni Hardo Adamu, ẹni tí ó jẹ́ olórí Fulani, orúkọ ìyá rẹ̀ sì ni Zulaihat, ẹni tí ó jẹ́ Hausa. Òun ni ọmọ kẹtàlélógún tí bàbá rẹ̀ bí. Ìyá Buhari ni ó tọ́ọ dàgbà, bàbá rẹ̀ fi ayé s'ílẹ̀ nígbà tí ó wà ní ọmọ ọdún mẹ́rin. Buhari dara pọ̀ mọ́ Nigerian Military Training College (NMTC) ní ọdún 1962, ó jẹ́ ọmọ ọdún ọ̀kàndínlógún nígbà náà.[ Ní oṣù kejì ọdún 1964, a yí orúkọ ilé-ìwé ológun náà padà sí Nigerian Defence Academy (NDA).Ní àárín ọdún 1962 sí 1963, Buhari kọ́ nípa ìmọ̀ ogun ní Mons Officer Cadet School ní ìlú Aldershot, England. Ní oṣù kínní ọdún 1963, nígbà tí Buhari jẹ́ ọmọ ogún ọdún, wọ́n sọọ́ di lieutenant kejì."},{"question":"வினா: மருத்துவ ஆய்விற்குப் பயன்படும் குரங்கு வகை எது? ","answer":"விடை: ரீசஸ்"},{"question":" Sheeg Xayawaanka Kaliya Ee Lab Iyo Dhidig Ey Isku Eg Yihiin?","answer":"Waa Xayawaanka Loo-Yaqaano Dhurwaaga (Waraabe)"},{"question":"ටෙස්ට් ශතකයක් රැස් කළ පළමු නවසීලන්ත ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"1930 ජනවාරි මාසයේදී එංගලන්තයේ නවසීලන්ත සංචාරයේදී මෙම සන්ධිස්ථානය ලබා ගනිමින් ටෙස්ට් ශතකයක් රැස් කළ පළමු නවසීලන්ත ක්‍රීඩකයා වූයේ ස්ටීවී ඩෙම්ප්ස්ටර්ය."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'berani menjual, berani membeli'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud apa-apa yang dikerjakan (dikatakan), hendaklah ditimbang-timbang (jangan mengenai orang lain)."},{"question":"भुटानको राष्टिय खेल कुन हो ?","answer":"भुटानको राष्टिय खेल धनुषबाण हो ।"},{"question":"புதிர்:  பூவுக்குள் பூ வைத்து போர்த்திய பூ அது என்ன? ","answer":"விடை: வாழைப்பூ "},{"question":"What is a confusion matrix in machine learning?","answer":"A confusion matrix is a table used to describe the performance of a classification model on a set of test data for which the true values are known."},{"question":"Kodi ndi zinthu ziti zimene zimakhudza umbanda?","answer":"Mikhalidwe yazachuma, kuphatikiza ndalama zapakatikati, umphawi, ndi kupezeka kwa ntchito. Zikhalidwe ndi maphunziro, zosangalatsa, ndi zipembedzo. Mikhalidwe ya banja ponena za chisudzulo ndi mgwirizano wabanja."},{"question":"\\"Ny Didy Folo izay ahitana torolalana toy ny hoe 'Aza mamono olona,' sy 'Manajà ny rainao sy ny reninao', dia fitambarana fitsipika ara-moraly sy lalàna ara-pivavahana ao amin'ny Jodaisma sy ny Kristianisma.\\"Inona ny fanontaniana azo tsogaina amin'io andian-teny io?","answer":"Fanontaniana: Inona avy ireo fitsipika ara-pitondrantena ahitana ny torolalana hoe \\"Aza mamono olona\\" sy ny hoe \\"Hajao ny rainao sy ny reninao\\"?"},{"question":"Ahoana no ahafantarana fa mitantara ito angano iray ito:Ny ipaohan’ny papango ny akohoTera-dahy, hono, ity papango, indray mandeha izay, ka avy ny reniakoho hampivelona azy. Ary nony efa nifana herinandro izy dia lasa nitsangatsangana, fa nomeny hotaizain’ny akoho ny zanany. Kanjo tratra ela ny papango, ka tezitra ny akoho, fa sahirana loatra nitaiza ny zanany, dia novonoiny nataony tsy nisy niaingana ireo.Rehefa nody ny papango, ka hitany fa lany ritra ny zanany, dia tezitra loatra izy ka niady tamin’ny reniakoho; nefa notoheriny, ka ady sahala no niafarany.Nony tsy hitan’ny papango izay hatao, dia nanozona izy hoe: “Raha mety ho taranako koa hafarako hamono ny zanak’ireny reniakoho kary ireny, satria izy no namono ny zanako ”. Izany, hono, no ihinanan’ny papango ny akohokely ambaraka ndroany.","answer":"Ny ahafantarana fa mitantara io angano io dia noho izy ahitana ny teny hoe \\"hono\\"."},{"question":"Манас деген ким ?","answer":"Манас ― Манас эпосунун башкы каарманы. Кыргыз элинин эң улуу баатыры. Кыргыз урууларын бир кандыкка бириктирген баатыр. "},{"question":"90 derecelik açının adı nedir?","answer":"Dik açı 90 dereceye eşittir."},{"question":"સગપણ બાળગીત લખો.","answer":"ચોરી કરવા ચાલ્યા ચોર, સોનીપોળમાં થાતો શોરસીપાઈ  મળ્યા  સામા,   બાના  ભાઈ   તે  મામામામા લાવે  છૂકછૂક ગાડી, બાને માટે  લાવે સાડીસાડીના   રંગ   કાચા,   બાપના  ભાઈ  તે  કાકાકાકા કાકા કારેલાં,  કાકીએ વઘારેલાંકાકી પડ્યાં રોઈ, બાપની બેન તે ફોઈફોઈ ફૂલડાં લાવે છે,  ફુવાને વધાવે છેફુવા ગયા કાશી,  બાની બેન તે માસી"},{"question":"एप्पल (Apple) को बारेमा केही तथ्यहरू र यसका संस्थापक, र उपयोगकर्ता उत्पादनहरूका बारेमा केही तथ्यहरू यहाँ दिइएका छन्:","answer":"१. एप्पल एक आइटी कम्पनी हो जसको मुख्य कार्यालय कूपर्टिनो, क्यालिफोर्नियामा छ।२. एप्पलको संस्थापक स्टीव जवब्स, स्टीव वोझ्नियाक , र रोनाल्ड वेर्न हुन्।३. एप्पलले स्मार्टफोन, कम्प्यूटर, ट्याबलेट, स्मार्टवॉच, इयरपॉड्स, औद्योगिक डिजाइनहरू, आवाज बुझिलेस सिस्टम  जस्ता विभिन्न प्रोडक्टहरू निर्माण गर्दछ।४. एप्पलले  आइफोन, आइप्याड,  मैकबुक, एप्पल वाच, र एयरपॉड्स जस्ता अत्यन्त लोकप्रिय उत्पादहरू ल्याएको छ।५. एप्पलको उत्पादहरूले एक अद्वितीय डिजाइन, उच्च गुणस्तरको परफोर्मेन्स, र अप्रतिम उपयोगकर्ता अनुभव प्रदान गर्दछ।६. एप्पलको पहिलो कम्प्यूटर ले एप्पल-१ वर्ष १९७६ मा बजारमा आयो।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada rezeki\\"?","answer":"Ada peluang yang baik."},{"question":"Qual é a capital do Togo?","answer":"Lomé é a capital do Togo (país da África Ocidental) e a maior cidade do país. A cidade tem cerca de 837 437 habitantes e localiza-se na costa do Golfo da Guiné."},{"question":"څنګه په پښتو کې \\"light of stars\\" ووایاست","answer":"د ستورو رڼا"},{"question":"Балдар тууралуу кызыктуу фактылар  жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"- Даниядагы аялдардын 80% балдарынын саламаттыгы чың болушу үчүн үйлөрүндө төрөшөт."},{"question":"Wat is het antwoord op de volgende raadsel: Het leeft in de winter, gaat dood in de zomer en groeit van boven naar beneden. Wat is dat? ","answer":"Het antwoord is een ijspegel."},{"question":"GARASHADA GUUSHA!","answer":"Haddii aad u fiirsato qeexitaanadaas kor ku xusan iyo kuwa soo socdaba, giddiggood waxay ka mideysan yihiin in wax la gaaro. Sikastaba, si aan wax badan uga sii ogaado macneha guusha ayaan ka dhex baaray saddexdan qaamuus: Qaamuuska Af-Soomaaliga 1. Guul libin laga gaaro dagaal ama tartan laba qof ama laba kooxood u dhaxeeyey. 2. Cid haddadid ama xoolo aroor oo wabax ah meel; Ceelka u dhow habeen u hoyasho. Xoolo iwm dhaan isugu keenid. Tusaale “Geelii wuxuu isugu guulmay gasada.” Qaamuuska Webster’s 1.  In aad hesho ama aad gaarto hodantinimo, caannimo. 2. In aad sugto kana mirodhaliso iskudday aad jamatay. Qaamuuska Oxford 1.  In aad gaarto himilo ama ujeeddo. 2. In aad hesho caannimo, hodantinnimo ama aqoonsi bulsho. Islaamku siduu u arkaa guusha? Wuxuu u arkaa si ka duwan sida ay u arkaan dadka caadiga ah, waxa uuna ku soo koobay afar qaybood2 oo kala ah:-• Iimaan toosan. • Camal ama dhaqan suubban. • U dardaaranka xaqa ama towxiidka dadka kale. • U dardaaranka dulqaadka ama samirka dadka kale. Guusha dhabta ah ee lagu waarayo waa ku guulaysashada jannada iyo raalli gelinta Eebbe, sida uu inoogu sheegay kitaabka quraanka “Qofkii la dhaafiyo naar jannaduna hoy u noqoto kaas ayaa liibaanay.” "},{"question":"Lẹyin oṣu mẹrin ti Pele Onikoko pokunso niluu Gbọngan, ironu iku rẹ ti pa iya to bi i","answer":"Ajalu mi-in tun ti ja lu idile Ọlawale lagbegbe Ọwa-Ọpẹ, niluu Gbọngan bayii, lẹyin oṣu mẹrin ti ọkan lara awọn ogo idile naa, Festus Ọlawale, ẹni ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Pele Onikoko jade laye.Iya to bi ọmọkunrin naa la gbọ pe oun naa ki aye pe o digbooṣe nibẹrẹ ọsẹ yii.Iya naa, ẹni ti gbogbo awọn araalu mọ si iya elepo la gbọ pe o lọ sọja lati ta epo, latibẹ lo si ti bẹrẹ aisan, nigba ti yoo si fi to wakati kan, iya naa ti gbẹmi-in mi.Oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun yii, ni Pele Onikoko, ẹni ọdun mẹrinlelogoji, pokunso sinu sọọbu to ti n ta koko lagbegbe Oke-Ọla, niluu Gbọngan, ti ko si sẹni to mọ idi to fi ṣe bẹẹ.Gẹgẹ bi ẹnikan niluu Gbọngan to ba wa sọrọ, ṣugbọn to ni ka forukọ bo oun laṣiri ṣe sọ, o ni latigba ti Festus ti ku ni iya rẹ ko ti bọ sipo, o si ṣee ṣe ko jẹ ironu iku rẹ lo tete ran iya rẹ sọrun aremabọ."},{"question":"Iza no anaran'ilay tandavan-tendrombohitra any andrefan'i Arzantina?","answer":"Ny Tendrombohitra Andes dia mamakivaky ny sisin-tany andrefan'i Arzantina."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：哪个事件在19世纪末标志着美国成为世界强国？","answer":"答案：1898年的西班牙-美国战争标志着美国成为世界强国。"},{"question":"मुक्ताफलैः किं मृगपक्षिणां चमिष्टान्नपानं किमु गर्दभानाम् ।अन्धस्य दीपो बधिरस्य गीतंमूर्खस्य किं धर्मकथाप्रसंगैः ॥","answer":"जनावरांना (पशुपक्ष्यांना) मोत्याचा काय (उपयोग किंवा कौतुक)? मिष्टान्नांच्या खाद्यपेयांचे गाढवांना काय? आंधळ्याला दिव्याचे किंवा बहिऱ्याला गाण्याचे काय? त्याच प्रमाणे मूर्खाला धार्मिक कथाप्रसंगांचे काय महत्व असणार आहे?गाढवाला गुळाची चंव काय ? किंवा बंदर क्या जाने अदरक का स्वाद? अशा म्हणी यावरच आहेत."},{"question":"මිහිදු හිමියන් දෙවනපෑතිස් රජුට මුලින්ම දේශනා කල සූත්රය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"චුල්ලහත්ථිපදෝපම සුත්‍රය"},{"question":"సాధారణ దృష్టి, శాస్త్ర దృష్టి రెండూ ఒకటేనా? కాదా? ఎందుకు?","answer":"సాధారణ దృష్టి, శాస్త్ర దృష్టి ఒకటి కాదు. సాధారణ దృష్టి కలవాడు ప్రతి సంఘటనకూ వెనుక ఉన్న కారణాన్ని గూర్చి ఆలోచించడు. సూర్యుడు తూర్పు దిక్కులోనే ఎందుకు ఉదయిస్తున్నాడు ? ఆటలమ్మ ఎందుకు వచ్చింది ? అని శాస్త్ర దృష్టి కలవాడు ఆలోచిస్తాడు. వేంకటేశ్వరస్వామి కోపం వల్ల తలనొప్పి వచ్చిందంటే, శాస్త్ర దృష్టి కలవాడు అంగీకరించడు. శాస్త్ర దృష్టి కలవాడు మూఢనమ్మకాలను నమ్మడు. శాస్త్ర దృష్టితో విషయాన్ని పరీక్షించి చూచి, సత్యాన్నే నమ్ముతాడు."},{"question":"உங்கள் ஊரில் உற்பத்தியாகும் பொருள்களையும் சந்தையில் காணும் பொருள்களையும் ஒப்பிட்டு எழுதுக.","answer":"உற்பத்தியாகும் பொருள் :மனிதர்கள் நாடோடியாக, வேட்டையாடி கிடைத்த உணவை உண்டனர். பின்னாளில் நால்வகை நிலங்களில் உற்பத்தி பெருகியது. காய்கறி, கீரை, தானியம் ஆகியவற்றை உற்பத்தி செய்தனர்.சந்தையில் காணும் பொருள்:உழவர்கள் உற்பத்தி செய்த பொருள்களை விற்கவும், மாற்றுப்பொருளை வாங்கவும் முச்சந்தி, நாற்சந்தி என மக்கள் கூடும் இடங்களில் கடை விரித்துப் பொது வணிகமாக்கினர்."},{"question":"भारतातील सर्वात मोठे ऊस उत्पादक राज्य कोणते आहे?(A) पंजाब(B) तामिळनाडू(C) मध्य प्रदेश(D) उत्तर प्रदेश=> ","answer":"(D) उत्तर प्रदेश"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa noocyo cuntada ka mid ah oo kordhiya walwalka Iyo niyad Jabka ?","answer":"Dad badan oo innaga mid ah ayaa aan dhaadsanayn muhiimadda ay leedahay in la hubsado nooca cunto ee ay tahay in aynu cunno, lana kala barto cuntooyinka caafimaadka ay tahay in aynu cunno, kuwa ay tahay in la yaraysto iyo cuntooyinka aan caafimaadka u fiicnayn, oo marar badan ah kuwa aynu ugu jecelnahay cunistooda.Xaaladaha uu qofku ku jiro xanuunnada nafsiga ah, sida warwarka, walbahaarka iyo niyadjabka waxaa dhacda in uu cuno cuntooyin aad u badan ama uu isku illaawo cunista cuntada, taas oo sii kordhisa khatarta ay cuntadu ku keeni karto caafimaadkiisa nafsadeed iyo jidheed labadaba. Waxaa muhiim ah in aynu dareensanaano in ay jiraan cuntooyin badan oo laga  fisho in ay kordhiyaan xaaladahan taban ee nafsiga ah.Cilmibaadhiso ay xeeldheereyaal arrimahaas ku takhasusay sameeyeen ayaa lagu ogaaday in cuntooyinka qaarkood ay keenaan xaaladaha nafsiga ah. Waxa ay xeeldheereyaashu sheegeen in xaaladaha nafsiga ah, gaar ahaan walbahaarku aanu ahayn xaalad ku gaar ah nafsadda, ee sida oo kalana uu saamayn iyo xidhiidh ku leeyahay shaqada xubnaha, habdhisyada iyo unugyada kala duwan ee jidhka, taasna ay sababteedu tahay in hormoonnada kor u kacaya marka ay qofka xaaladahan nafsiga ahi ku yimaaddaan, ay saamayn ku yeelanayaan qaybaha kale ee jidhka. Haddaba waxaa jira cuntooyin iyaguna sii caawinaya in hormoonnadaasi kordhaan, ama hoos u dhigaya iskudhisyada kiimikaad ee dabiiciga ah, ee Alle ugu talagalay in ay yareeyaan lafalgalka taban ee ay hormoonnadaasi la falgelayaan qaybahaas jidhka.Warwarka waxaa lagu yaqaannaa in qofku uu cuntada isku illaawo oo haddana marka uu dhammaysto uu warwar kale u sii bilowdo, naftana ku canaanto sababta ay cuntada sidaas u badan u cuntay, taasina ay sii xumaynayso xaaladdiisa nafsiga ah.Cilmibaadhis kale oo ay samaysay jaamacadda Northwestern ayaa ka marag kacday in cuntooyinka qasacadaysan, iyo kuwo midabbada ama dhadhanka samayska ah lagu daraa ay sii kordhiyaan warwarka. Khamriga ayaa isaguna dhibaatadan sii kordhiya, oo muddada uu qofka ku jira inta uu illowsiiyo xaaladahan ay dad badani u qaataan in uu xalkii yahay, laakiin marka uu jidhka ka baxo ay xaaladduu gaadho meel ka sii daran meeshii hore ay u joogtay."},{"question":"حمید سوریان در مسابقات قهرمانی جهان مسکو ۲۰۱۰ چگونه ظاهر شد؟","answer":"در مسابقات قهرمانی جهان مسکو ۲۰۱۰،‌سوریان که برای بار پنجم در قهرمانی جهان شرکت می‌کرد به ترتیب محمد بوترفاسا را از الجزایر، ونلین ونکوف بلغاری، جانی هاپامیکی فنلاندی و رقیب سرسخت خود رومن آمویان آرمنی را شکست داده بود. سوریان در فینال ۵ بر ۳ در یک دیدار حساس چوی گیو-جین کره‌ای را شکست داد. سوریان با این طلا برای بار پنجم مدال طلا و قهرمانی خود را در مسابقات قهرمانی جهان تکرار کرد."},{"question":"Một ôtô đi du lịch từ thành phố A đến thành phố B với vận tốc không đổi. Biết rằng nếu ôtô tăng vận tốc thêm 20% thì chuyến đi mất ít hơn 1 tiếng so với dự định; và nếu ôtô đi với vận tốc hiện tại trong 100 km trước khi tăng lên 30% thì chuyến đi cũng mất ít hơn 1 tiếng so với dự định.Tính khoảng cách giữa hai thành phố A và B.","answer":"Nếu ôtô tăng 20% thì vận tốc bằng 120%, hay bằng 6/5 vận tốc hiện tại và thời gian tương ứng bằng 5/6 thời gian dự định.Kết hợp với dữ kiện: hai khoảng thời gian chênh lệch nhau 1 tiếng, suy ra thời gian ôtô đi với vận tốc hiện tại là 6 giờ và thời gian với vận tốc khi được tăng thêm 20% là 5 giờ.Trên cùng một quãng đường (AB -100) km, nếu vận tốc mới của ôtô bằng 130% vận tốc hiện tại thì thời gian tương ứng bằng 10/13 thời gian dự định. Do hai khoảng thời gian ôtô đi trên quãng đường (AB - 100) km chênh lệch nhau 1 tiếng, nên thời gian ôtô đi với vận tốc hiện tại là 13/3 giờ và thời gian đi khi tăng vận tốc thêm 30% là 10/3 giờ.Từ đó, ta có thời gian ôtô đi quãng đường 100 km với vận tốc hiện tại là:6 -13/3 = 5/3 (giờ) và quãng đường AB là (100 : 5/3) x 6 = 360 (km)Đáp án khoảng cách giữa hai thành phố A và B là 360 km"},{"question":"Кызыктар дүйнөсү...","answer":"Канада БУУ тарабынан 4 жыл удаа жашоого ыңгайлуу өлкө болуп аныкталган."},{"question":"Si aan hadafkeyga u gaaro maxaa sameyn karaa?","answer":"SI'AAD UGAARTO HADAFKAADA waxaa sameyn kartaa Asxaabiga jaliilka ah ee Jaabir Bin Cabdullahi hal bil oo kaamil ah ayuu usii socday magaalo loogu sheegay in uu ku sugan yahay nin hayo hal xadiith uu raadinayay.Imaam Bukhaari oo leh kitaabka ugu saxsan marka laga tago kan Qur'aanka kareemka ayaa sheegay in habeenkii uu soo toosi jiray in kabadan labaqtan jeer si uu ugaaro hadafkiisa ah in uu qoro Saxiix Bukhaari (صحيح بخاري).Imaam Nawawi labo sano oo kaamil ah dhinaciisa dhulka madhigin si uu u noqdo Imaam Nawawi, waxaana lasheegaa in labadaas sano uu ku dhaafay culimo waa wayn oo kaga horeesay barashada diinta.Adigana waad xaqiijin kartaa hadafkaada."},{"question":"Depura ahịrị okwu a n'ozuzu oke ya:E lelịa nwa ite.... ","answer":"Azịza:Ọgbọnyụọ ọkụ.Nke a pụtara na onye a na eleda anya nwere ike mee ihe dị egwu. "},{"question":"Qual é o nome do meio de Chandler na sitcom Friends?","answer":"Muriel. No episódio The One With Rachel’s Date, o nome do meio de Chandler foi revelado."},{"question":"කඳු මුදුන්වල අවිධිමත් ඉදිකිරීම් සිදුකිරීමේ අවදානම කුමක් ද?","answer":"අවිධිමත් ඉදිකිරීම් නිසා පස සෝදා පාළුවට ලක් වන අතර එමඟින් නාය යාම් සිදු වී පරිසර පද්ධතිවලට සිදුවන හානිවලට අමතරව ජීවිත හා දේපළ හානි පවා සිදු විය හැකි ය. මීට අමතරව මෙම පස් ගංගා වෙත එකතු වීමෙන් ගංගා මෙන් ම ගංගා ආශ්‍රිත පරිසර පද්ධතිවලට ද හානි ඇති වේ."},{"question":"Ndeipi tsumo inoyenderana neinotevera:Moto unopisa aubata","answer":"Mago anoruma mutokonyi"},{"question":"வினா: தமிழ்நாட்டின் கட்டிடக்கலை எந்த வகையில் தனித்துவமானது?","answer":"விடை:தமிழ்நாட்டின் கட்டிடக்கலை :தமிழர்கள் மிக நீண்ட காலமாகவே ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட நிலப்பகுதியில் நிலையாக வாழ்ந்துவருபவர்கள். தனித்துவம் வாய்ந்த ஒரு பண்பாட்டைக் கொண்டிருப்பவர்கள். மொழி, இலக்கியம், கலை போன்ற துறைகளில் கிறிஸ்துவுக்கு முந்திய நூற்றாண்டுகளிலேயே உயர்நிலை எட்டியிருந்தவர்கள். இத்தகைய பின்னணியிலே, மக்கள் வாழ்வதற்கான இல்லங்களும், அரசர்களுக்கான மாளிகைகளும், வணக்கத்தலங்களும், பொதுக் கட்டடங்கள் பலவும் உருவாக்கப் பட்டிருக்கும் என்பதில் ஐயமில்லை. இவையெல்லாம் அழிந்துபோகக்கூடிய பொருட்களால் கட்டப்பட்டதால் எதுவும் எஞ்சவில்லை.ஆறாம் நூற்றாண்டுக்குப் பின்னரே தமிழ்நாட்டில் கற்களால் கட்டடங்கள் கட்டப்பட்டன. இக் கட்டடங்களில் மிகப் பெரும்பாலானவை கோயில்களே. இவை கட்டடக்கலையின் உயர் மரபைச் சாந்தவை. ஆனாலும் இவற்றோடு இணையாகச் சாதாரண மக்களுக்கான வீடுகளையும் கட்டடங்களையும் உள்ளடக்கிய இன்னொரு கட்டடக்கலை மரபும் இருந்தது. ஆறாம் நூற்றாண்டளவில் தொடங்கிய கற்கட்டட மரபு நாயக்கர் காலம் வரை வளர்ந்து வந்தது. இந்த தமிழர் நாகரிகத்தை ஒரு சிலர் திராவிடக் கட்டடக்கலை என்று அழைத்தார்கள் . இதன் பின்னரும் தற்காலம் வரையில் ஆங்காங்கே தனித்துவமான வகைகளைச் சேர்ந்த கட்டடங்கள் இருக்கத்தான் செய்கின்றன.இத்தகைய எல்லாவகைக் கட்டடக்கலைகளினதும் கூட்டுமொத்தம் தமிழர் கட்ட்டக்கலை எனப்படலாம்.இலக்கியத்தில் தமிழர் கட்டிடக்கலை:வீடுகள் அமைப்பதில் சில முறைகள் அக்காலத்தில் இருந்தன என்று குறிப்பிடுகிறார் டாக்டர் உ. வே. சாமிநாதையர். நெடுநல்வாடையில்: \\"பெரும் பெயர் மன்னர்க் கொப்ப மனைவகுத்து\\" என்பதனால் அவரவர்களுக்கேற்றபடி மனைகள் அமைக்கும் வழக்கம் இருந்ததென்பதை அறியலாம். வீடுகள் கட்டுவதற்கு கடைக்கால் (அத்திவாரம்) போடும் காலம் நெடுநல்வாடையில் காணப்படுகிறது. கோபுரங்களும், வாயின் மாடங்களும், நிலாமுற்றங்களும், அறைகளும் அமைக்கப்பட்டன. வீடுகளின் நிலைகளிற் சித்திர வேலைகள் செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தன. மாடங்களாகவே சில வீடுகள் கட்டப்பட்டிருந்தன. காற்று ஓட்டத்திற்காக வீட்டின் சுவர்களிற் பலவகைச் சாளரங்கள் வைப்பதுண்டு. இவை காலதர் என்று கூறப்படும். கால் = காற்று, அதர் = வழி. அதாவது காற்றுப் போகும் வழி என்று பொருள்.தமிழ்நாட்டில் பல பழமையான கோயில்கள், அரண்மனைகள், கோட்டைகள் உள்ளன. தமிழ்நாட்டின் கட்டிடக்கலை தமிழ் மக்களின் கலை நுணுக்கத்தையும் கற்பனைத் திறனையும் காட்டுகிறது. தமிழ்நாட்டின் கட்டிடக்கலை உலகெங்கிலும் கவரப்பட்டு வருகிறது."},{"question":"\\"Averina foana fa tsy ho eo mandrakizay akory ny mpiaro anao, ary mbola hiverina aminao izay nataonao.\\"Inona no  fihetseham-po asehon'io fanambarana io?","answer":"Maneho fananarana, fampatsiahivana io fanambarana io."},{"question":"Inona no maha samy hafa ny fandraharahana ara-tsosialy sy ny fandraharahana nentim-paharazana?","answer":"Ny fandraharahana ara-tsosialy dia mikendry ny hamaha ny olana ara-tsosialy na ara-tontolo iainana rehefa mahazo tombony, fa ny fandraharahana nentim-paharazana dia mifantoka indrindra amin'ny tombombarotra ara-bola."},{"question":"Saan matatagpuan ang pinakamahabang tunnel sa Pilipinas?","answer":"Sa Ternate, Cavite matatagpuan ang Kaybiang Tunnel, ang pinakamahabang tunnel sa Pilipinas. May haba na 300 metro ang tunnel na ito na siyang kumukonekta sa probinsya ng Cavite at Batangas. Nagbukas ang tunnel na ito noong 2013 bilang isang alternatibong ruta papuntang Tagaytay kung galing ng Batangas, at Nasugbu kung galing ng Cavite."},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, ọmọ olorin fuji kan ku lojiji","answer":"Ninu ibanujẹ nla ni gbajumọ olorin fuji nni, Kareem Ayinde Ọsọba, ẹni tawọn eeyan tun mọ si Kabiesi Olomide wa bayii, iku ojiji lo pa ọmọ ẹ obinrin, Rachael Ọlamide Ayọka Ọsọba, lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, to kọja.Lori ẹrọ ayelujara Facebook ẹ, Kareem Ayinde Kabiesi, lo gbe ọrọ ọhun si, nibi tawọn eeyan ti n ba a kẹdun gidigidi.Ohun ti ọkunrin naa kọ nipa ọmọ ẹ yii, Rachael Ọlamide Ayọka Ọsọba ko ṣai mu ọpọ eeyan ba a kẹdun gidigidi, ti wọn si n tọrọ wi pe ki Ọlọrun foriji ọmọ naa, ko si ba a da awọn yooku si.Ohun ti Kabiesi Olomide kọ ree, “Rachael Ọlamide Ayọka Ọsọba, ala rẹ lati jẹ ojulowo ọmọ orilẹ-ede Nigeria yii ninu iṣẹ ọlọpaa ko le pada wa si imuṣẹ mọ.“Lati le di ọlọpaa to yaranti lọjọ iwaju lo mu ẹ darapọ mọ ileewe Police Force Secondary School, n’Igbo-Ọra, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, nibi to o ti ṣẹṣẹ pari ipele akọkọ ẹkọ girama laipẹ yii. Ọjọ kẹrin, oṣu yii, naa lo pari idanwo rẹ, ti o si pada waa ba wa nile.“Nigba to di Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, to kọja yii. lọwọ aarọ lo sọ pe ara n ro ẹ, loju ẹsẹ naa la si gbe ẹ lọ si ileewosan ijọba. Nigba to di Furaidee, ọjọ Ẹti, to tẹle e, funra ẹ naa lo ji, o gbadura gẹgẹ bii iṣe rẹ, bẹẹ lo bu omi sara, ti o si tun jẹ awọn eeso ti a ni nile, ṣugbọn lojiji ni gbogbo nnkan daru, ti a si sare gbe ẹ lọ si ileewosan Jẹnẹra n’Ifakọ Ijaye, nibi ti o ti mi eemi ikẹyin.“Bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn oṣiṣẹ ileewosan naa gbiyanju agbara wọn, sibẹ, a fẹ ọ ni o, ṣugbọn Ọlọrun lo fẹ ọ ju, ki Ọlọrun ba mi tẹ ọ safẹfẹ rere, nigba ti a oo tun pade lọjọ ajinde…O daarọ, Ọla mi.”Ohun ti gbajumọ olorin fuji yii, to tun jẹ ọkan pataki ninu awọn oloye ẹgbẹ PMAN, gbe sori Facebook ẹ ree, ti awọn eeyan bẹrẹ si ki i, ti wọn si n ba a kẹdun gidigidi."},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Ngày 31-7, ông Hồ Hoàng Hùng, cha của em Hồ Hoàng Anh, học sinh lớp 12 của một trường chuyên ở TP Phan Rang - Tháp Chàm, tỉnh Ninh Thuận, cho biết: Gia đình đã có đơn khiếu nại về kết quả giám định nồng độ cồn trong máu của em Anh sau khi em qua đời. Đơn khiếu nại mà gia đình nữ sinh gửi đến Bí thư tỉnh ủy, Chủ tịch UBND tỉnh Ninh Thuận và các cơ quan liên quan, đặt vấn đề: Vì sao một học sinh đến trường lúc 7 giờ sáng lại có nồng độ cồn lên đến 0,79mg/100ml máu, tương đương với người uống rượu bia thuộc loại tửu lượng cao. Gia đình cũng yêu cầu tiến hành giám định, đối chiếu mẫu máu mà Bệnh viện đa khoa tỉnh Ninh Thuận đã xét nghiệm và vì sao lấy mẫu máu mà không có sự chứng kiến của gia đình, người làm chứng, thân nhân hay Viện Kiểm sát. Đồng thời, gia đình nạn nhân cũng đề nghị tiến hành giám định nồng độ cồn của nữ sinh tại Viện Khoa học hình sự - Bộ Công an và có biện pháp xử lý, truy cứu trách nhiệm hình sự những người cố tình làm sai lệch hồ sơ vụ án (nếu có). Được biết, gia đình nhận được thông báo ngày 13-7 của Cơ quan CSĐT Công an TP Phan Rang – Tháp Chàm cho biết nồng độ cồn của em Anh là 0,79 mg/100 ml máu, do bệnh viện đa khoa tỉnh Ninh Thuận làm xét nghiệm.","answer":"Trong khi đó, theo nguồn tin của Báo Người Lao Động, nhóm bạn học của nữ sinh này đã làm cam kết và chịu trách nhiệm về bản tự khai với nội dung tối hôm trước khi xảy ra tai nạn, nhóm bạn này có học nhóm tại một quán cà phê nhưng không ai sử dụng thức uống có cồn. Riêng nữ sinh Hồ Hoàng Anh chỉ uống nước lọc tự mang theo. Ngoài những yêu cầu trên, gia đình cũng thắc mắc vì sao không tiến hành đo và công bố nồng độ cồn của ông Hoàng Văn Minh là người cầm lái ô tô gây tai nạn. Theo Châu Tỉnh (Nld.com.vn) https://nld.com.vn/thoi-su/bat-thuong-vu-nu-sinh-co-nong-do-con-cao-bi-tong-chet-o-ninh-thuan-20220731164826419.htm Trang Thông tin điện tử Docbao.vn Công ty Cổ phần Quang Minh Việt Nam Giấy phép thiết lập Trang thông tin điện tử tổng hợp trên Internet số 2372/GP-STTTT cấp ngày 29/8/2014. SĐT: 024. 666.40816 Địa chỉ: P604, Tầng 6, Tòa nhà Golden Field, Khu đô thị mới Mỹ Đình 1, phường Cầu Diễn, quận Nam Từ Liêm, Hà Nội Chịu trách nhiệm nội dung: Điều Thị Bích; ĐT: 0903.263.198; Email: docbao@kib.vn Đọc báo trực tuyến hiện tại chỉ sử dụng tên miền duy nhất là docbao.vn; độc giả lưu ý tránh nhầm lẫn. Chính sách bảo mật RSS"},{"question":"ਸ਼ੁਭ ਕੌਣ ਹਨ, ਕਿਸ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਭਾਰਤ ਦਾ ਟੂਰ ਰੱਦ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ?","answer":"ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਗਾਇਕ ਸ਼ੁਭ ਦਾ 23 ਸਤੰਬਰ ਤੋਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੰਗੀਤਕ ਟੂਰ ‘ਸਟਿਲ ਰੋਲਿਨ’ ਰੱਦ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।ਵਿਵਾਦ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਬੁੱਧਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਔਨਲਾਈਨ ਟਿਕਟਿੰਗ ਪਲੇਟਫਾਰਮ ਬੁੱਕ ਮਾਏ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਐਲਾਨ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਕੈਨੇਡਾ-ਅਧਾਰਿਤ ਗਾਇਕ-ਰੈਪਰ ਸ਼ੁਭਨੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਉਰਫ ਸ਼ੁਭ ਦੇ ਆਗਾਮੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੌਰੇ ਨੂੰ ਰੱਦ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਐਲਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਐਕਸ ਅਕਾਊਂਟ 'ਤੇ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਹੈ, \\"ਗਾਇਕ ਸ਼ੁਭਨੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਦਾ ਸਟਿਲ ਰੋਲਿਨ ਟੂਰ ਫਾਰ ਇੰਡੀਆ ਰੱਦ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਉਦੇਸ਼ ਲਈ, ਬੁੱਕ ਮਾਏ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਲਈ ਰਿਫੰਡ ਪ੍ਰਕਿਰਿਆ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਲਈ ਟਿਕਟਾਂ ਖਰੀਦੀਆਂ ਸਨ। ਰਿਫੰਡ ਦੀ ਰਕਮ ਗਾਹਕ ਦੇ ਸਰੋਤ ਖਾਤੇ ਵਿੱਚ 7-10 ਕਾਰਜਕਾਰੀ ਦਿਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆ ਜਾਵੇਗੀ।\\"ਇਸ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਵਜ੍ਹਾ \\"ਖ਼ਾਲਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਸਮਰਥਨ ਵਾਲੀ\\" ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਲੰਘੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਾਂਝੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਸੋਸ਼ਲ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਪੋਸਟ ਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਦਰਅਸਲ, ਕੁਝ ਸਮਾਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਸ਼ੁਭ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੋਸ਼ਲ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਪਲੇਟਫਾਰਮ ਇੰਸਟਾ (ਸਟੋਰੀ) 'ਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਤਸਵੀਰ ਸਾਂਝੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਦਾ 'ਗ਼ਲਤ ਨਕਸ਼ਾ' ਦਿਖਾਇਆ ਸੀ।ਇਸ ਕਾਰਨ ਸ਼ੁਭ ਦੀ ਕਾਫੀ ਆਲੋਚਨਾ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ। ਭਾਰਤੀ ਜਨਤਾ ਯੁਵਾ ਮੋਰਚਾ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਐੱਫਆਈਆਰ ਵੀ ਦਰਜ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ।16 ਸਤੰਬਰ ਨੂੰ ਖ਼ਬਰ ਏਜੰਸੀ ਏਐੱਨਆਈ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ, ਭਾਰਤੀ ਜਨਤਾ ਯੁਵਾ ਮੋਰਚਾ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਤਜਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਟਿਵਾਣਾ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ, \\"ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਏਕਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਅਖੰਡਤਾ ਦੇ ਦੁਸ਼ਮਣ ਖ਼ਾਲਿਸਤਾਨੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਇੱਥੇ ਕੋਈ ਜਗ੍ਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।\\"ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਦੇਸ਼ ਨੂੰ ਤੋੜਨ ਦੀ ਸਾਜ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਕੈਨੇਡੀਅਨ ਗਾਇਕ ਸ਼ੁਭ ਨੂੰ ਅਸੀਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ, ਛਤਰਪਤੀ ਸ਼ਿਵਾਜੀ ਦੀ ਇਸ ਪਾਵਨ ਧਰਤੀ ਮੁੰਬਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਨ ਦਿਆਂਗੇ।\\"ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ "},{"question":"请问苏轼是谁？","answer":"苏轼（1037年1月8日-1101年8月24日），世称苏东坡、苏仙，是北宋著名文学家、书法家、画家，历史治水名人。他是北宋中期文坛领袖，在诗、词、散文、书、画等方面取得很高成就。他的文书纵横恣肆；诗题材广阔，清新豪健，善用夸张比喻，独具风格，与黄庭坚并称“苏黄”；他也是词开豪放一派，与辛弃疾同是豪放派代表，并称“苏辛”；他的散文著述宏富，豪放自如，与欧阳修并称“欧苏”，也是“唐宋八大家”之一。苏轼擅长文人画，尤擅墨竹、怪石、枯木等。他与韩愈、柳宗元和欧阳修合称“千古文章四大家”。苏轼的作品有《东坡七集》《东坡易传》《东坡乐府》《潇湘竹石图卷》《古木怪石图卷》等。"},{"question":"Tunjukkan resepi untuk kuih bahulu dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan:  1 cawan (120g) tepung gandum biasa, 1 cawan (120g) gula kastor, ½ sudu kecil serbuk penaik (baking powder), 1 sudu kecil tepung beras, ¼ sudu kecil garam, 4 biji telur, ½ sudu kecil esen vanila, Minyak masak, Acuan bahulu cermai atau belimbingCara penyediaan:1. Untuk mendapatkan bahulu yang ringan, tepung yang digunakan hendaklah betul-betul kering. Tepung boleh dikeringkan dengan meratakannya di dalam loyang dan memanaskannya di dalam oven selama 2 minit. Kemudian biarkan sejuk.2. Sediakan bahan-bahan kering. Ayak tepung, garam dan serbuk penaik.Cara membuat:1. Panaskan oven kepada suhu 190°C (375°F).2. Sediakan adunan bahulu. Pukul telur dengan esen vanila di dalam mangkuk kaca hingga kembang.3. Masukkan gula dan terus memukulnya hingga campuran menjadi likat, pucat dan melekit.4. Masukkan tepung sedikit demi sedikit ke dalam campuran telur sambil mengaup balik perlahan-lahan sehingga sebati.5. Membakar bahulu. Griskan acuan bahulu dengan minyak masak dan panaskan di dalam oven selama 5 minit.6. Sudukan adunan bahulu ke dalam acuan sehingga hampir penuh.7. Masukkan ke dalam oven dan bakar selama 10-15 minit atau sehingga bahulu berwarna keemasan.8. Setelah masak, angkat bahulu dengan menggunakan pencucuk sate atau pencungkil gigi.9. Ulangi proses membakar sehingga semua adunan habis.10. Biarkan bahulu sejuk sebelum menyimpannya dalam bekas yang kedap udara"},{"question":"కాకతీయుల శాసనాలు గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"మొదటిసారిగా క్రీ.శ. 956వ సం|| నాటి తూర్పు చాళుక్య రాజు దానార్ణవుని ‘మాగల్లు శాసనం’ కాకత్య గుండ్యన పేరు ప్రస్తావించింది. ఇతడే కాకతీయవంశ మూలపురుషుడు.హనుమకొండలోని వేయిస్తంభాల గుడి శాసనము రుద్రదేవుడు స్వతంత్ర్యాన్ని ప్రకటించుకొన్న విషయాన్ని అతని విజయాలను తెలివేస్తుంది.కాకతీయ ప్రభువులు, వారి బంధువులు, సేనాపతులు వేయించినారు.బయ్యారం శాసనము దీనిని గణపతిదేవుని సోదరి మైలాంబ వేయించింది.పాలంపేట శాసనం, ద్రాక్షారామం శాసనము, చందుపట్ల శాసనము మొదలగునవి."},{"question":"nhận định về tác phẩm “Vợ nhặt” - Kim Lân","answer":"“Đói, nó vừa đắng cay, vừa đau đớn, đồng thời một mặt nào đó nó lại lóe lên một tia sáng về đạo đức, danh dự\\""},{"question":"esezingithathele lowo msebenzi?(Ujabhile) Kanti-ke akumele neze uze uzihluphe ngalowo mcabangomkami. Iqiniso elisalayo nje lisekutheni izinsuku lezi zoMdalikazefani. Ngingaphuma lisabalele lapha ekhaya kepha ngibuyeselihosha umoya obandayo ohambisana namakhaza ashubisaumnkantsha. Kanjalo futhi singehlukana ekuseni ngihleka kukuhlekunjeyaya kodwa lishone sengikhala.Yingakho nje nencwadiyomShumayeli eBhayibhelini esahlukweni sesithathu ikubeka kucacelokhu engikushoyo ngaphansi kwesihloko esithi konke kunesikhathisakho lapha phansi komthunzi welanga.(Ubukeka esekhathazekile) Ngiphuthume baba. Ngabesekwenzenjani?1. Chaza kafushane ngamaphuzu AMATHATHU ukuthi indaba eyethulwanguManqina kuMaMlanduli kulesi siqeshana iyithuthukise kanjani indikimbayalo mdlalo.","answer":"Emuva kokuba uManqina echazele uMaMlanduli ngodaba lokudilizwaemsebenzini. UMdaluli ube eseba nodlame ekhaya nasemphakathini.UMdaluli uhlukumeza uMaMlanduli uyamshaya efuna indabandaba ngenkaniuxosha nezingane. UMdaluli uthakatha uChivenga, umlalela unyendleuyamshaya ngoba ecabanga ukuthi nguyena omthathele umsebenzi ngobaengowokufika"},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 アメリカは日本やヨーロッパなどの国と一緒に、月に基地を建てることを計画しています。月の表面は、穴や坂になっている所がたくさんあります。このため、人や物を運ぶ乗り物を安全に降ろすことができる所があまりありません。東京大学などのグループは、月の表面を平らにするためのロボットを研究しています。グループは、神奈川県にあるJAXA宇宙科学研究所で、ロボットを動かす実験を行いました。5台のロボットを動かして、穴に砂を入れたり、砂の中にある物を掘り出したりしました。グループの人は「月の表面を平らにすることはとても大事です。ぜひ成功させたいです」と話していました。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。- ヨーロッパ: 1）世界の六大州の一つ。アジアの北西、アフリカの北にある。産業や文化が発達した国が多い。欧州。- 基地: 1）ものごとをおし進めるときの、よりどころとする場所。- 表面: 1）物の外側。表。2）うわべ。見せかけ。- 穴: 1）くぼんだ所。2）向こうまでつきぬけている部分。3）弱いところ。4）損。不足。- 降ろす: 1）高い所から低い所へ移す。2）下のほうに移す。3）乗り物から外へ出す。4）役目や仕事をやめさせる。- グループ: 1）仲間。集団。- 平ら: 1）でこぼこしていないようす。2）楽な姿勢ですわるようす。- ロボット: 1）電気や磁気の力で動く人形。人造人間。2）工場などで人間に代わって、作業する機械。3）（いつも）人の言いなりになって動く人。- 動かす: 1）動くようにする。2）位置を変える。3）感動させる。- 実験: 1）実際にためしてみること。- 動かし: 1）ほって、地面の下にある物を出す。2）思いがけなく、値打ちのあるものを手に入れる。- 掘り出し: 1）ものごとが思いどおりにうまくいくこと。2）高い地位や財産を得ること。"},{"question":"Ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun pohun da, o ni kawọn Kristiẹni ṣe isin aisun ọdun tuntun, ṣugbọn …","answer":"Lẹyin ọpọlọpọ ifikunlukun, ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun ti fun awọn Onigbagbọ lanfaani lati ṣe isin aisun ọdun tuntun.Ṣaaju nijọba ti kede pe ko gbọdọ si isin naa latari bi ọrọ ajakalẹ arun Koronafairọọsi ṣe n fẹ kaakiri bayii, ti iye awọn to n lugbadi rẹ si n pọ si i.Latigba naa ni agbarijọpọ ẹgbẹ awọn ọmọlẹyin Kristi, iyẹn CAN, ti n ṣepade pẹlu awọn alaṣẹ ijọba lati tun ero rẹ pa lori aṣẹ naa.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Kọmisanna feto iroyin ati ilanilọyẹ, Funkẹ Ẹgbẹmọde, fi sita nijọba ti sọ pe ki wọn ṣe isin naa, ṣugbọn ẹnikẹni ko gbọdọ ju aago kan oru lọ nita.O ni ki gbogbo isin tete pari, ki awọn ọmọ ijọ si ti wa ninu ile wọn titi aago kan oru, nitori oju arufin nijọba yoo fi wo ẹnikẹni ti ọwọ ba tẹ lẹyin aago kan oru ọjọ kin-in-ni, oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun 2021.Ijọba waa kilọ fun gbogbo awọn pasitọ lati ri i pe awọn ọmọ ijọ wọn tẹle ilana tijọba gbe kalẹ lori idena arun korona."},{"question":"Uzupełnij fragment tekstu: W okresie dwudziestolecia międzywojennego w gmachu mieściło się dowództwo 14 Dywizji Piechoty w skład której wchodziły: 55 Pułk Piechoty, 57 Pułk Piechoty, 58 Pułk Piechoty, 14 Wielkopolski Pułk Artylerii Lekkiej, 14 Dywizjon Artylerii Ciężkiej oraz 14 Batalion Saperów. W czasie II wojny światowej budynek wykorzystywała armia niemiecka. Podczas","answer":"walk o Poznań budynek został zrujnowany. Po wojnie planowano odbudowę gmachu, jednakże w 1948 roku zdecydowano się na rozbiórkę budynku i postawienie w tym miejscu nowego gmachu, przeznaczonego na siedzibę Polskiej Zjednoczonej Partii Robotniczej."},{"question":"Iza amin'ireo biby hita ao Costa Rica no iray amin'ireo maro loko indrindra eran-tany?","answer":"Ny \\"quetzal\\" , vorona manana volo maitso sy mena tsara tarehy, dia iray amin'ireo biby malaza indrindra ao Costa Rica."},{"question":" شنو هي عاصمة روسيا ؟","answer":"موسكو"},{"question":"دیے گئے منفی جملے کو مثبت جملے میں تبدیل کریں۔امی جان اکثر وقت پر دوا نہیں لیتیں۔","answer":"امی جان اکثر وقت پر دوالیتی ہیں."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 日本生産性本部は3年前から、会社などに行かないで「テレワーク」で仕事をする人について調べています。今年7月、20歳以上の1100人に働き方について聞きました。それによると、今年7月にテレワークをしている人は15.5%でした。新型コロナウイルスが広がっていた2020年5月の31.5%の半分ぐらいになりました。日本生産性本部は、法律で新型コロナの病気のレベルが下がったあと、テレワークをやめる会社が増えたと考えています。しかし働く人は、多くがこれからもテレワークを行いたいと答えています。テレワークの専門家は、会社と働く人の間で考え方が大きく違っていると考えています。新型コロナのことだけでなく生産のことも考えて、会社はテレワークをうまく利用してほしいと話しています。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。- 広がっ: 1）広くなる。2）広々と見わたせる。3）行きわたる。4）大きくなる。- レベル: 1）評価をするときの標準。水準。"},{"question":"Wolof Njaay neena ","answer":"Lëk su lekkee alom nako gërëme coy !"},{"question":"ڪيئن قدرتي چونڊ ڊرائيو ارتقاء؟","answer":"قدرتي چونڊ اهو عمل آهي جنهن جي ذريعي اهي خاصيتون آهن جيڪي ڪنهن مخصوص ماحول ۾ بقا يا پيدائشي فائدو حاصل ڪن ٿا انهن جي انهن خاصيتن کان سواءِ انهن جي ڀيٽ ۾ زنده رهڻ ۽ ٻيهر پيدا ٿيڻ جو امڪان آهي. وقت سان گڏ، اهي فائدي وارا خاصيتون آبادي ۾ وڌيڪ عام ٿي ويا آهن. اهو عمل ماحولياتي دٻاءُ، وسيلن لاءِ مقابلو، اڳڪٿي، ۽ ٻين عنصرن تي ٻڌل آهي. نتيجي طور، آبادي آهستي آهستي پنهنجي ماحول سان ٺهڪي اچي ٿي، جنهن جي نتيجي ۾ ارتقائي تبديليون اچي وڃن ٿيون. چارلس ڊارون ۽ الفريڊ رسل والس آزاديءَ سان قدرتي چونڊ جي تصور کي ارتقا لاءِ بنيادي ميکانيزم طور پيش ڪيو، ۽ اهو ارتقائي حياتيات ۾ هڪ بنيادي اصول رهي ٿو."},{"question":"नेपालीमा १ देखि २० सम्म गिन्नुहोस्","answer":"१ - एक२ - दुई३ - तीन४ - चार५ - पाँच६ - छ७ - सात८ - आठ९ - नौ१० - दश११ - एघार१२ - बाह्र१३ - तेह्र१४ - चौध१५ - पन्ध्र१६ - सोह्र१७ - सत्र१८ - अठार१९ - उन्नाइस२० - बीस"},{"question":"Inu Awolọwọ ko le dun lọrun si bi Naijiria ṣe ri loni-in- Tokunbọ Awolọwọ","answer":"Ọkan lara awọn ọmọ Oloogbe Ọbafẹmi Awolọwọ, Dokita Ọlatokunbọ Awolọwọ Dosunmu, ti sọ pe, inu baba oun ko le dun rara pẹlu bi ohun gbogbo ṣe ri ni Naijiria loni-in.Obinrin to ti figba kan jẹ aṣoju orilẹ-ede Naijiria lorilẹ-ede Netherland yii sọ pe gbogbo awọn ohun ti ijọba Awolọwọ mu ni koko iṣẹ idagbasoke pata ni ko si fawọn eeyan lasiko yii, ati pe bi orilẹ-ede yii ṣe ri loni-in, o yatọ patapata si erongba Ọbafẹmi Awolọwọ.Dosumu ni ọpọ nnkan ni inu Awolọwọ ko ni i dun si bayii, o ni, ṣe bi igbe aye awọn eeyan ṣe ri lasiko yii ni, abi bi awọn ohun amayedẹrun gbogbo ko ṣe si, ti eto iṣejọba paapaa ko dara to. O ni ẹkọ ọfẹ paapaa ko ṣe deede, bẹẹ gbogbo wa yii naa la gbadun eto ẹkọ-ọfẹ ti ijọba Awolọwọ ṣe, ati pe ayipada nla le de ba gbogbo ohun ta a ka silẹ yii, ti a ba ṣetan lati ṣe e lọna to yẹ.Ninu ọrọ ẹ naa lo ti sọ pe lara awọn eeyan to gbiyanju lati ja fun ominira orilẹ-ede yii ni Ọbafemi n ṣe, ṣugbọn lọjọ ti a n ṣẹyẹ ominira Naijiria lọdun 1960, iwa buruku gbaa ni wọn hu si Ọbafẹmi, nitori ibi ti wọn fi aga ẹ si lọjọ naa ku diẹ kaato.O ni, bo tilẹ jẹ pe oun ko ju ọmọ ọdun mọkanla lọ nigba yẹn, sibẹ, bi awọn obi oun ti ṣe n sọ ọ ninu ile, lẹyin ayẹyẹ ominira lọjọ naa fi han pe aaye awọn to ti ṣiwọ ninu iṣẹ ijọba ni wọn to baba oun si, ti iṣẹlẹ naa ko si dun mọ ẹbi atawọn eeyan ẹ ninu gẹgẹ bi olori ẹgbẹ alatako to wa. O ni, pẹlu iwa ti wọn hu yii, sibẹ, idunnu nla lo jẹ fun Ọbafẹmi pe Naijiria bọ lọwọ ijọba amunisin.Tokunbọ Awolọwọ fi kun ọrọ ẹ pe, meloo gan-an la fẹẹ ka ninu ohun rere ti ọkunrin oloṣelu naa ṣe fun ilọsiwaju Naijiria. O ni iwe nla kan wa ti ọkunrin naa kọ, ṣugbọn ede to fi kọ ọ, oun nikan lo ye daadaa, akọle iwe naa si ni, ‘Fun igbe aye rere awọn eeyan’ (For the Good of the People). Ṣugbọn ede ti Awolọwọ fi k̀ọ ọ, oun nikan lo mọ itumọ ọrọ to kọ, ko si eyikeyii ninu awọn to n tẹle e to le tumọ ẹ."},{"question":"வினா:   தொன்மை இந்தியாவின் முதுபெரும் நகரமான ஹரப்பா எனும் பகுதி அகழ்வு ஆராய்ச்சி மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட ஆண்டு எது ?1. 1919 2. 19223. 19254. 1921","answer":"விடை:4. 1921"},{"question":"A quale cattegoria appartiene questa domanda: Qual è la quarta montagna più alta del mondo?.","answer":"Questa domanda appartiene alla cattegoria geografia."},{"question":"Sheeg Xayawaanka waligii aan biyo cabin?","answer":"Waaa Guruuga. "},{"question":"निन्दन्तु नीतिनिपुणा यदि वा स्तुवन्तुलक्ष्मीः स्थिरा भवतु(समाविशतु) गच्छतु वा यथेष्टम्।अद्यैव वा मरणमस्तु युगान्तरे वान्याय्यात्पथः प्रविचलन्ति पदं न धीराः ।।","answer":"शहाणे लोक प्रशंसा करतील किंवा निंदा, लक्ष्मी टिकून राहील किंवा वाटल्यास निघून जाईल, मरण कदाचित आजच येणार असेल किंवा जगबुडीच्या वेळी, काहीही झाले तरी धीरोदात्त लोक न्यायाचा रस्ता सोडत नाहीत."},{"question":"Genera una versione più complessa di questa frase: “Molti festival cinematografici e siti web hanno ospitato film realizzati dalla sottocultura del microcinema”.","answer":"Una versione più complessa della frase è: \\"Molti festival cinematografici e siti web hanno ospitato film realizzati dalla sottocultura del microcinema e molti film stanno anche trovando maggiore spazio presso distributori indipendenti e nelle grandi catene di negozi di noleggio”."},{"question":"Given the below title and summary of an article, generate a short article or the beginning of a long article to go along with them. Title: కరోనావైరస్: ఇంటికి డబ్బు పంపించడానికి అవస్థలు పడుతున్న ప్రవాసులుnSummary: ప్రపంచ వ్యాప్తంగా కోట్లాది కుటుంబాలకు.. విదేశాల్లో పనిచేసే తమ వారు పంపించే డబ్బులే జీవనాధారం.nArticle (Max 500 characters):","answer":"ఇషాన్ గిరీశ్, గిరీశ్ సదానందన్, స్మితా గిరీశ్కానీ.. కరోనావైరస్ కారణంగా విదేశాలకు వలస వెళ్లిన వారిలో అత్యధికులు అక్కడ ఉద్యోగాలు, ఉపాధి కొనసాగించే పరిస్థితులు మృగ్యమయ్యాయి. దీంతో వేతనాలు లేక తమ ఇళ్లకు డబ్బులు పంపించలేకపోతున్నారు. వారి కుటుంబాలు ఎన్నో వెతలు పడుతున్నాయి. స్మితా గిరీష్ తన చిన్నారి కుమారుడితో కలిసి కేరళలో నివసిస్తున్నారు. ఆమె భర్త యునైటెడ్ అరబ్ ఎమిరేట్స్‌లోని దుబాయ్‌లో ఉన్నారు. ఇటీవలి వరకూ ఆయన సేల్స్ ఇంజనీర్‌గా పనిచేసేవారు. కానీ కోవిడ్-19 కారణంగా నిరుద్యోగిగా మారారు. "},{"question":"エジプトのピラミッドもこれにあたる、四角形１つと三角形4つを組み合わせてできる立体を何という？","answer":"四角錐です。"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أسباب الإرث؟","answer":"الإجابة: قرابة ، نكاح ، ولاء ، جهة الإسلام"},{"question":"问题：谁是墨西哥历史上第一任总统？","answer":"答案：墨西哥历史上的第一任总统是瓜达卢佩·维多利亚（Guadalupe Victoria）。他在1824年至1829年担任第一任墨西哥总统。他的原名为何塞·米格尔·拉蒙·阿道克托·曼努埃尔·费尔南德斯·费利克斯（José Miguel Ramón Adaucto Fernández y Félix）。"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਕਰਉ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮੁ ਸਭੁ ਜਾਨੈ ॥ਅਪਨਾ ਕੀਆ ਆਪਹਿ ਮਾਨੈ ॥ਆਪਹਿ ਆਪ ਆਪਿ ਕਰਤ ਨਿਬੇਰਾ ॥ਕਿਸੈ ਦੂਰਿ ਜਨਾਵਤ ਕਿਸੈ ਬੁਝਾਵਤ ਨੇਰਾ ॥ਉਪਾਵ ਸਿਆਨਪ ਸਗਲ ਤੇ ਰਹਤ ॥ਸਭੁ ਕਛੁ ਜਾਨੈ ਆਤਮ ਕੀ ਰਹਤ ॥ਜਿਸੁ ਭਾਵੈ ਤਿਸੁ ਲਏ ਲੜਿ ਲਾਇ ॥ਥਾਨ ਥਨੰਤਰਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਸਮਾਇ ॥ਸੋ ਸੇਵਕੁ ਜਿਸੁ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰੀ ॥ਨਿਮਖ ਨਿਮਖ ਜਪਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਹਰੀ ॥੮॥੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 269 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਜੋ ਜੋ) ਬੇਨਤੀ ਮੈਂ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਸਭ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ, ਆਪਣੇ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਜੀਵ ਨੂੰ ਉਹ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਮਾਣ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਨਿਖੇੜਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਬੁਧਿ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਸਾਡੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਜਣਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਕਿਤੇ ਦੂਰ ਹੈ ।ਸਭ ਹੀਲਿਆਂ ਤੇ ਚਤੁਰਾਈਆਂ ਤੋਂ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ਪਰੇ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਕਿਸੇ ਹੀਲੇ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰਸੰਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ) (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਹ ਜੀਵ ਦੀ) ਆਤਮਕ ਰਹਿਣੀ ਦੀ ਹਰੇਕ ਗੱਲ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਜੋ (ਜੀਵ) ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਲੜ ਲਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੈ । ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਅਸਲੀ) ਸੇਵਕ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਉਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਐਸੇ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਦਮ-ਬ-ਦਮ ਯਾਦ ਕਰ ।੮।੫।\\""},{"question":"\\"මලේ සුවඳ වාගේ\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. ","answer":"මලේ සුවඳ වාගේ මල මතම රැඳීවිලේ ජලය වාගේ විල තුළම රැඳීසඳේ සදාතන ආදර සිසිල වැදීඅපේ ආදරේ පවතී සුවඳ දිදීකල්ප කාල මං තල වල හිනා වෙවීකල්ප කාල දුර ආවා වෙනස් නොවීසෙනේ සිතින් ළඟ ඉඳගෙන කතා වෙවීපැතූ පැතුම් මල් වරුසා හෙටත් වහීහිතේ වෙලෙන ලෙන්ගතු කම කියා දිදීපෑව සිනා දුටු දා සිට පෙමින් වෙලීමහා මෙරක් සේ මා සිත නොහැර සිටීනුඹෙන් තොරව ආදරයක් සිතනු බැරීනන්දා මාලිනීරඹුකන සිද්ධාර්ථ හිමිනන්දා මාලිනී "},{"question":"வினா:வலசை போதல் பற்றி குறிப்பு வரைக ","answer":"விடை:உணவு, இருப்பிடம், தட்பவெப்பநிலை மாற்றம், இனப்பெருக்கம் இவற்றிற்காகவேபறவைகள் இடம் பெயர்கின்றன. நிலவு, விண்மீன், புவிஈர்ப்புப் புலம் ஆகியவற்றைஅடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டே பறவைகள் இடம் பெயர்கின்றன. பொதுவாக வடக்கிலிருந்து தெற்கு நோக்கியும், மேற்கிலிருந்து கிழக்கு நோக்கியும் பறவைகள் வலசை போகின்றன. ப ற வைக ள் தங்க ளு க்கென ஒ ரு வ ழித் தடத்தை  தேர்ந்தெடுத்து, அந்தப்  பாதையிலேயே பறக்கின்றன. சில பறவை இனங்கள் அதே பாதையில் தாய்நிலங்களுக்குத் திரும்புகின்றன. சில பறவை இனங்கள் போவதற்கும் வருவதற்கும் இருவேறு பாதைகளைப் பயன்படுத்துகின்றன.பயணம் செய்யும்போது சிலவகைப் ப ற வைக ள் இ ரை , ஓய்வு போன்ற தேவைகளுக்காகத் தரை இறங்கு ம் . இடையில் எங்கும் நிற்காமல் பறந்து , வாழிடம் சேரும் பறவைகளும் உண்டு.வலசையின்போது பறவையின் உடலில்ஏற்படும் மாற்றங்கள்• தலையில் சிறகு வளர்தல்• இறகுகளின் நிறம் மாறுதல்• உடலில் கற்றையாக முடி வளர்தல் ஒருவ கை ப் பற வை வே று வ கை ப் பறவையாக  உருமாறி த் தோ ன் று ம் அ ள விற்குக்கூடச் சி ல நே ர ங்களில் மாற்றங்கள் ஏற்படும்.தமிழகத்திற்கு வெளிநாட்டுப் பறவைகள் வலசை வருவது பற்றி இலக்கியங்களிலும்செய்திகள் உள்ளன. ஏறத்தாழ 1500 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு வாழ்ந்த சத்திமுத்தப்புலவர்“நாராய், நாராய், செங்கால் நாராய்” என்னும் பாடலை எழுதியுள்ளார். அப்பாடலில் உள்ள“தென்திசைக் குமரிஆடி வடதிசைக்கு ஏகுவீர் ஆயின்” என்னும் அடிகள் பறவைகள் வலசைவந்த செய்தியைக் குறிப்பிடுகின்றன.ஐரோப்பாவில் இருந்து தமிழகத்திற்குச் செங்கால் நாரைகள் வருவது தற்போதையஆய்விலும் உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டு உள்ளது. வெளிநாட்டுப் பறவைகளுக்கும் புகலிடமாகத்திகழ்கிறது தமிழ்நாடு."},{"question":"አበበ 7 ብርቱኳኖች አሉት፣ አልማዝ 3 ተጨማሪ ብርቱኳኖች ሰጠችው።ጥያቄ- አበበ በአጠቃላይ ስንት ብርቱኳኖች ይኖሩታል?","answer":" አበበ በአጠቃላይ 7+3=10 ብርቱኳኖች ይኖሩታል።"},{"question":"How has Sri Lanka been affected by climate change, particularly in terms of natural disasters and environmental challenges?","answer":"Sri Lanka, like many other countries, has been significantly affected by climate change, facing various environmental challenges and an increase in natural disasters. The impacts are wide-ranging:Increased Frequency of Extreme Weather Events: Sri Lanka has experienced more frequent and severe weather events, such as heavy rainfall, floods, and droughts. These extreme weather patterns are often attributed to climate change and have led to widespread damage to infrastructure, agriculture, and loss of life.Rising Sea Levels: Being an island nation, Sri Lanka is particularly vulnerable to rising sea levels. Coastal erosion and inundation threaten coastal communities, potentially leading to displacement, loss of livelihoods (especially for fishermen), and damage to coastal ecosystems.Impact on Agriculture: Agriculture, a key sector in Sri Lanka's economy, is highly susceptible to climate variability. Changes in rainfall patterns, increased temperatures, and extreme weather events have led to crop failures, reduced agricultural productivity, and increased vulnerability of rural communities.Water Scarcity and Quality Issues: Fluctuations in rainfall, coupled with prolonged droughts, have led to water scarcity in many regions. This not only affects agriculture but also has implications for drinking water supply and sanitation, impacting public health.Biodiversity Loss: Climate change, along with other environmental pressures, poses a threat to Sri Lanka's rich biodiversity. Changes in temperature and precipitation patterns affect the country's unique ecosystems, leading to shifts in species distribution and potential loss of species.Health Impacts: The increase in temperature and humidity, along with changing weather patterns, has created conducive environments for vector-borne diseases such as dengue fever. The population faces increased health risks due to these changing disease dynamics.Economic Impacts: The cumulative effect of these changes has significant economic implications. Agriculture, fisheries, and tourism, key sectors of the Sri Lankan economy, are all impacted by climate change, potentially leading to economic instability and increased poverty.Adaptation and Mitigation Efforts: In response, the Sri Lankan government and various organizations are implementing strategies to adapt to and mitigate the effects of climate change. These include initiatives for sustainable agriculture, water resource management, coastal conservation, and promoting renewable energy.The situation in Sri Lanka exemplifies the broader challenge faced by many countries, particularly developing nations, in addressing and adapting to the multifaceted impacts of climate change. It underscores the need for global cooperation in climate action, technological support, and financial resources to mitigate these challenges effectively."},{"question":"Conas is féidir liom a fháil amach cé mhéad gáis is féidir le mo charr a shealbhú?","answer":"Is dócha go mbeidh an t-eolas seo i lámhleabhar an úinéara do do charr, nó is féidir leat é a lorg ar an ngréasán. I lámhleabhar na úinéara d'fhéadfadh sé a bheith faoin rannán \\"Eacnamaíocht Breosla\\", nó an rannán \\"Tips\\". B'fhéidir go mbeidh ort go leor leathanaigh a flipadh chun an fhaisnéis ábhartha a fháil, áfach."},{"question":"Wanne dan wasan kwaikwayo ne ya taka Shugaban kasa a fim din 1997 'Air Force One'?","answer":"Dan wasa Harrison Ford"},{"question":"Жең ичинен сүйлөшүү деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Жашырын, башкаларга билдирбей, эки кишинин өз ара сүйлөшкөнү. Бул накыл кептин төркүнү – базарда сатылуучу малдын ээси менен алуучунун ортосундагы далдалчынын жеңдин ичине беш манжасын сойлотуп, алуучуга да, сатуучуга да бармактар менен бааны билдиргенине барып такалат. Мына ушундан улам – ар бир жашырын сүйлөшүүлөрдү – «жең ичинен сүйлөшүү» деген накыл кеп менен атай турган болгон. «Далдалчы» - арабдын жана кыргыздын сөзү. «Далдал» - «даллал» деген сөздөн өзгөргөн, «арачы», «эки ортодо мал соодасын кылуучу» деген мааниде.(Х.Карасаев)"},{"question":"Nínú Mò gbé gààrí rê, gààrí jé","answer":"òrò orúko"},{"question":"“பிழைத்தனவோ யான் அறியேன் எந்தாய்” – இடஞ்சுட்டிப் பொருள் விளக்கம் தருக.","answer":"இடம் சுட்டல்:பெரிய புராணம் திரு ஆலவாய்க் காண்டத்தில், இடைக்காடன் பிணக்குத் தீர்த்த படலத்தில் குலேச பாண்டியன் இறைவனிடம் வினவினான்.பொருள் விளக்கம்:இறைவனே, என்னால், என் படைகளால், என் பகைவரால், கள்வரால், காட்டில் உள்ள விலங்குகளால் இத்தமிழ்நாட்டில் தங்களுக்கு இடையூறு ஏற்பட்டதா? வேதங்களை பயின்றவர் நல்லொழுக்கத்தில் தவறினாரா? தவமும் தருமமும் சுருங்கியதோ? இல்லறமும் துறவறமும் தத்தம் நெறியில் இருந்து தவறினவோ? எமது தந்தையே யான் அறியனே என்று பாண்டியன் இறைவனிடம் வினவினான்.தூங்கி எழும்போது தெய்வத்தை வணங்காமல் கணவனை வணங்கி எழுகிறாள் - என்கிறார் திருவள்ளுவர். சங்கத் தமிழர் இயற்கையை வழிபட்டார்களா? தெய்வங்களையும் வழிபட்டார்களா?கீழடி அருகே தொல்லியலாளர் தோண்டிக் கண்டறிந்துள்ள நகரநாகரிகம் 2600 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் பழைமையானது.  இங்கே வழிபாட்டுப் பொருட்களோ, சமயம்சார்ந்த பொருட்களோ ஏதும் கிடைக்கவில்லை. எனவே “இந்த இடத்தில் நூற்பாலையோ தொழிற்சாலையோ இருந்திருக்கலாம், இங்கு வாழ்ந்த தமிழர் இயற்கையை வணங்கியுள்ளனர், கடவுளை வணங்கிட வில்லை” என்று பலரும் சொல்லியும் எழுதியும் வருகின்றனர்.உண்மையில் சங்கத்தமிழர் இயற்கையை மட்டுமே வணங்கியவர்களா?  கடவுளை வணங்கவில்லையா? என்று தேடிப்பார்த்தால், வியப்பிலும் வியப்பாக உள்ளது.  எட்டுத்தொகை பத்துப்பாட்டில் மட்டுமே தெய்வம் என்ற சொல் 42  இடங்களில் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளது."},{"question":"Trong các địa phương sau, địa phương nào có gần 50% thu nhập đến từ nông, lâm nghiệp?- Thái Bình- Cà Mau- Đăk Nông","answer":"Đăk Nông là địa phương duy nhất có gần 50% nguồn thu từ nông, lâm nghiệp. Cụ thể, thu nhập bình quân đầu người một tháng của Đăk Nông là 3,18 triệu đồng, trong đó 1,5 triệu từ nông, lâm nghiệp.Tỉnh này có địa hình thung lũng, cao nguyên rải rác. Đất nông nghiệp Đăk Nông chiếm 47% tổng diện tích tự nhiên, chủ yếu là đất trồng cây công nghiệp lâu năm, đem lại thu nhập cho người dân.Một số tỉnh, thành khác cũng có tỷ lệ thu nông, lâm, ngư nghiệp cao là Lâm Đồng 35%, Đăk Lăk 31%, Cà Mau và Bạc Liêu 29%."},{"question":"Ọọni bẹrẹ igbele, ko sẹni kan to le foju kan Ọba fọjọ meje","answer":"Arole Oduduwa, Ọọni Adeyẹye Ẹnitan Ogunwusi, ti bẹrẹ igbele ọlọdọọdun eleyii to maa n ṣapẹẹrẹ ibẹrẹ ọdun Ọlọjọ niluu Ileefẹ.Alẹ ana, Sannde, ni Ọọni kọja si Ile-Mọlẹ to wa ni Irẹmọ quarters ni Ileefẹ, yoo si lo ọjọ meje nibẹ lai ba ẹnikẹni sọrọ ju gbigba adura lọBi Ọọni ṣe n jade nilu Ile Oodua ti aafin rẹ wa lo sọ fun awọn oniroyin pe oun yoo lo asiko igbele naa lati ba Olodumare sọrọ lori ajakalẹ arun korona, ki ogun rẹ le ṣẹ patapata.O ni asiko naa yoo wa fun aawẹ ati adura gẹgẹ bi awọn baba-nla rẹ ṣe maa n ṣe ati lati fi ṣipẹ pe ki ajakalẹ arun tabi wahala mi-in ma ṣe tun wọnu orileede yii mọ.Lẹyin ti Ọọni ba kuro ni igbele ni oniruuru ayẹyẹ ti wọn ti la silẹ fun ọdun ọlọjọ yoo bẹrẹ, ti gbigbe ade Aare ti Ọọni yoo fi gbadura fun gbogbo orilẹ-ede yoo si kadii rẹ nilẹ.Lasiko ti Ọọni ba de ade  naa ni yoo kọja lawọn ikorita kan to ṣe pataki bii Ita Ọranfẹ, Ita Agbansala ati Ita Okemogun nibi ti adura pataki yoo ti maa waye."},{"question":"\\"أسس بيل جيتس شركة مايكروسوفت في عام 1975 وشغل منصب الرئيس التنفيذي لها حتى عام 2000.\\" لديك البيان السابق ، استخرج الكيانات وعلاقاتها ببعضها البعض:","answer":"الكيان 1: بيل جيتسالكيان 2: مايكروسوفتالعلاقة: مؤسس"},{"question":"¿Qué es el cambio climático?","answer":"El cambio climático se refiere a las alteraciones a largo plazo en los patrones climáticos de la Tierra, atribuidas en parte a las actividades humanas, como la quema de combustibles fósiles."},{"question":"Orile-ede Koria","answer":"South Korea, ni ifowosi Republic of Korea (ROK), jẹ orilẹ-ede kan ni Ila-oorun Asia. Ó jẹ́ apá gúúsù Korean Peninsula ó sì wà ní ààlà North Korea lẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ agbègbè Korean Demilitarized Zone. Òkun Yellow ló dá ààlà ìwọ̀-oòrùn orílẹ̀-èdè náà sílẹ̀, òkun Japan sì ṣàlàyé ààlà ìlà-oòrùn rẹ̀. South Korea sọ pé òun nìkan ni ìjọba tí ó tọ́ ní gbogbo ìlú náà àti àwọn erékùṣù tó wà nítòsí. Ó ní iye ènìyàn tó tó mílíọ̀nù 51.96, nínú èyí tí ó fẹ́rẹ̀ẹ́ tó ìdajì tí wọ́n ń gbé ní Seoul Capital Area, agbègbè kẹrin tí ó pọ̀ jùlọ ní àgbáyé. Àwọn ìlú ńlá mìíràn ni Incheon, Busan, àti Daegu.Wọ́n gbé Korean Peninsula ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ àkókò Lower Paleolithic. Ìjọba àkọ́kọ́ rẹ̀ ni wọ́n ṣe àkíyèsí rẹ̀ nínú àkọsílẹ̀ Chinese ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ ọ̀rúndún 7th BCE. Lẹ́yìn ìṣọ̀kan Ìjọba Mẹ́ta ti Korea sí Silla àti Balhae ní ìparí ọ̀rúndún 7th, ìjọba Goryeo (918-1392) àti ìjọba Joseon (1392-1897) àti ìjọba Joseon (1392-1897). Ìjọba Korea tí ó rọ́pò (1897-1910) ni wọ́n so pọ̀ ní 1910 sí Ìjọba Japan. Ìjọba orílẹ̀-èdè Japan parí lẹ́yìn ìfọwọ́sowọ́pọ̀ Japan ní Ogun Àgbáyé Kejì, lẹ́yìn èyí tí Wọ́n pín Korea sí àwọn agbègbè méjì: agbègbè àríwá tí Soviet Union gba, àti agbègbè gúúsù tí United States gba. Lẹ́yìn tí ìdúnàádúrà lórí ìṣọ̀kan kùnà, agbègbè gúúsù di Republic of Korea ní oṣù kẹjọ ọdún 1948, nígbà tí agbègbè àríwá di orílẹ̀-èdè Democratic People's Republic of Korea ní oṣù tó tẹ̀lé e.Ní ọdún 1950, ìkọlù North Korea bẹ̀rẹ̀ Ogun Korea, èyí tí ó rí ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ìgbésẹ̀ Àjọ Ìparapọ̀ Àwọn Orílẹ̀-èdè Amẹ́ríkà láti ṣe àtìlẹ́yìn fún Gúúsù nígbà tí China dá sí àtìlẹ́yìn fún Àríwá pẹ̀lú ìrànlọ́wọ́ Soviet. Lẹ́yìn ìparí ogun náà ní ọdún 1953, orílẹ̀-èdè náà wọ inú àjọṣepọ̀ àwọn ológun pẹ̀lú U.S., èyí tí ó ń tẹ̀síwájú títí di òní, àti pé ètò ọrọ̀ ajé rẹ̀ tí ó bàjẹ́ bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní pọ̀ sí i, tí ó ń ṣe àkọsílẹ̀ ìdàgbàsókè tí ó yára jùlọ nínú àpapọ̀ GDP fún olúkúlùkù ní àgbáyé láàárín ọdún 1980 sí 1990. Bí ó tilẹ̀ jẹ́ pé kò ní àwọn ohun àdáyébá, Orílẹ̀-èdè náà tètè dàgbà láti di ọ̀kan lára àwọn ọmọ ẹyẹ Asia Mẹ́rin tí ó dá lórí ìṣòwò àgbáyé àti ìdàgbàsókè ọrọ̀ ajé àgbáyé, tí ó ń ṣe àkójọpọ̀ ara rẹ̀ láàárín ètò ọrọ̀ ajé àgbáyé pẹ̀lú ìdàgbàsókè ilé-iṣẹ́ tí ó ní ìtọ́sọ́nà òkèèrè àti lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́ ó jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn orílẹ̀-èdè tí ó tóbi jùlọ tí wọ́n ń ta ọjà lọ sí òkèèrè ní àgbáyé, pẹ̀lú níní ọ̀kan lára àwọn ibi ìpamọ́ pàṣípààrọ̀ ilẹ̀ òkèèrè tó tóbi jùlọ ní àgbáyé. Ìjàkadì ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú Democratic Ti Oṣù Kẹfà yọrí sí òpin ìṣàkóso aláṣẹ ní ọdún 1987, orílẹ̀-èdè náà sì ti di àgbéyẹ̀wò báyìí láàrin àwọn ìjọba tiwa-n-tiwa tí ó ti gbilẹ̀ jùlọ ní Asia.South Korea jẹ́ agbára agbègbè àti orílẹ̀-èdè tí ó ti gòkè àgbà, pẹ̀lú ètò ọrọ̀ ajé rẹ̀ tí ó wà ní ipò kẹtàlá tí ó tóbi jùlọ lágbàáyé nípasẹ̀ GDP tí ó tóbi jùlọ àti èyí tí ó tóbi jùlọ nípasẹ̀ GDP (PPP). Ní àwọn ọdún àìpẹ́ yìí, orílẹ̀-èdè náà ti ń dojú kọ àwọn ènìyàn àgbàlagbà àti ìwọ̀n ìbímọ tó kéré jù ní àgbáyé. Àwọn ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè South Korea gbádùn ọ̀kan lára àwọn ìyára ìsopọ̀ ayélujára tí ó yára jùlọ lágbàáyé àti àwọn nẹ́tíwọ́ọ̀kì ọkọ̀ ojú irin tó yára jùlọ.Orílẹ̀-èdè náà ni oníṣòwò kẹsàn-án tí ó tóbi jùlọ lágbàáyé àti ẹni kẹsàn-án tí ó tóbi jùlọ tí ó ń kó wọlé. Àwọn ọmọ ogun rẹ̀ wà ní ipò gẹ́gẹ́ bí ọ̀kan lára àwọn ọmọ ogun tó lágbára jùlọ lágbàáyé, pẹ̀lú àwọn ọmọ ogun kejì tí ó tóbi jùlọ lágbàáyé láti ọwọ́ àwọn ológun àti àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ ológun.  Ní ọgọ́rùn-ún ọdún 21st, South Korea ti gbajúmọ̀ fún àṣà gbajúmọ̀ rẹ̀ kárí ayé, pàápàá jùlọ nínú orin (K-pop), àwọn eré orí ẹ̀rọ amóhùnmáwòrán (K-dramas), àti sinimá, ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ tí wọ́n ń pè ní Korean Wave. Ó jẹ́ ọmọ ẹgbẹ́ Ìgbìmọ̀ Ìrànlọ́wọ́ Ìdàgbàsókè OECD, G20, IPEF, àti Paris Club."},{"question":"Kalimah: Warung kopi ieu pikabetahuen, komo deui deukeut ti puseur kota.Patanya: Kumaha séntimén tina kalimah di luhur?","answer":"Séntimén tina kalimah di luhur nyaéta positif."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo endrika isehoan'ny rariny?","answer":"Ireto avy ireo endrika isehoan'ny rariny:- Marimaritra iraisana : Fanatsoahana hevitra iray ifanarahana izay tsy mitongilana na miandany amin’ny sokajin’olona na tombontsoan’olona iray.- Ny tandrify ny tsirairay araka ny toerana misy azy : Fahafantarana ny marina alohan’ny hamaritana ny rariny: “I Fara anie ka mbola kely… Ny ronono no sakafo sahaza ny vavoniny.” Jean NARIVONY- Lalàna ampiharina : Fifehezana ny fiarahamonina mba tsy hanaotao foana. "},{"question":" \\"Na eo aza ny vesatra ara-bola sarotra, ny fanohanana ara-pihetseham-po tsy miovaova avy amin'ny fianakaviako no loharanon'ny heriko lehibe indrindra.\\" inona ny fihetseham-po tamin'ny fanambarana teo aloha?","answer":"Ny andian-teny dia mampifangaro ny fihetseham-po tsara amin'ny fanohanana ara-pihetseham-po amin'ny fihetseham-po ratsy amin'ny vesatra ara-bola."},{"question":" \`உயிரின் ஆறு' என அழைக்கப்படுவது?","answer":"ரத்தம்."},{"question":"\\"Avatar\\" ရုပ်ရှင်ရိုက်ဖို့ ကုန်ကျငွေမူလပမာဏက ဘယ်လောက်ရှိလဲ။","answer":"Avatar (James Cameron's Avatar ဟု ဈေးကွက်တင်ထားသည်) သည် ၂၀၀၉ ခုနှစ်က ဂျိမ်းစ် ကင်မရွန်းမှ ဒါရိုက်တာ၊ ဇာတ်ညွှန်း၊ ထုတ်လုပ်၊ တွဲဖက်တည်းဖြတ်ထားသော အမေရိကန်ဇာတ်လမ်းရှည် သိပ္ပံစိတ်ကူးယဉ်ရုပ်ရှင်ဖြစ်ပြီး Sam Worthington၊ Zoe Saldana၊ Stephen Lang၊ Michelle Rodriguez နှင့် Sigourney Weaver တို့ပါဝင်သည်။ ဒီရုပ်ရှင်ဟာ ၂၂ ရာစု အလယ်မှာ ဇာတ်အိမ်တည်တယ်၊ လူသားတွေဟာ အခန်းအပူချိန် စူပါလျှပ်ကူးပစ္စည်းဖြစ်တဲ့ သတ္တု unobtanium ကို တူးဖော်ဖို့ Alpha Centauri ကြယ်စနစ်က ဓာတ်ငွေ့ကုမ္ပဏီကြီးတစ်ခုရဲ့ စိမ်းလန်းတဲ့ နေထိုင်လို့ရတဲ့ လ Pandora ကို သိမ်းပိုက်နေစဉ်ပါ။ တူးဖော်ရေး ကိုလိုနီရဲ့ တိုးချဲ့မှုဟာ ဒေသတွင်း Na'vi လူမျိုးစုရဲ့ တည်ရှိမှုကို ခြိမ်းခြောက်တယ်၊ Pandora ရဲ့ ဒေသခံ လူသားမျိုးနွယ်တစ်မျိုးပါ။ ရုပ်ရှင်၏ခေါင်းစဉ်သည် Pandora ၏ဒေသခံများနှင့်ဆက်သွယ်ရန်အသုံးပြုသောဝေးလံသောလူသားတစ်ဦး၏ဦးနှောက်မှလည်ပတ်သောဗီဇပိုင်းဆိုင်ရာအင်ဂျင်နီယာ Na'vi ခန္ဓာကိုရည်ညွှန်းသည်။ Avatar ၏ဖွံ့ဖြိုးတိုးတက်မှုသည် ၁၉၉၄ ခုနှစ်တွင်စတင်ခဲ့ပြီး Cameron သည်ရုပ်ရှင်အတွက်စာမျက်နှာ ၈၀ စာတမ်းကိုရေးသားခဲ့သည်။ ၁၉၉၉ ခုနှစ်တွင် ရုံတင်ရန် စီစဉ်ထားသော ကင်မရွန်း၏ ၁၉၉၇ ခုနှစ်တွင် ထွက်ရှိခဲ့သော Titanic ရုပ်ရှင် ပြီးစီးပြီးနောက် ရုပ်ရှင်ရိုက်ကူးရန် စီစဉ်ထားသော်လည်း ကင်မရွန်း၏ အဆိုအရ ရုပ်ရှင်၏ အမြင်ကို ရရှိရန် လိုအပ်သော နည်းပညာသည် မရှိသေးပေ။ ရုပ်ရှင်ရဲ့ ဂြိုဟ်သားတွေရဲ့ ဘာသာစကားကို ၂၀၀၅ မှာ စတင်ရေးဆွဲခဲ့ပြီး ၂၀၀၆ အစောပိုင်းမှာ Cameron ဟာ ဇာတ်ညွှန်းနဲ့ စိတ်ကူးယဉ် စကြာဝဠာကို စတင်ရေးဆွဲခဲ့တယ်။ Avatar ဟာ တရားဝင် အသုံးစရိတ် ဒေါ်လာ ၂၃၇ သန်းရှိပါတယ်။ အခြားခန့်မှန်းချက်များအရ ထုတ်လုပ်မှုအတွက် ဒေါ်လာ သန်း ၂၈၀ မှ ၃၁၀ ကြားရှိပြီး ကြော်ငြာအတွက် ဒေါ်လာ သန်း ၁၅၀ ခန့် ကုန်ကျသည်။ အဆိုပါရုပ်ရှင်သည် motion capture ရိုက်ကူးမှုနည်းပညာသစ်များကို ကျယ်ကျယ်ပြန့်ပြန့်အသုံးပြုခဲ့ပြီး အစဉ်အလာကြည့်ရှုရန်၊ 3D ကြည့်ရှုရန် (RealD 3D၊ Dolby 3D၊ XpanD 3D နှင့် IMAX 3D ပုံစံများသုံးပြီး) နှင့် တောင်ကိုရီးယားရုပ်ရှင်ရုံများတွင် \\"4D\\" အတွေ့အကြုံများအတွက် ထုတ်လွှင့်ခဲ့သည်။ ရုပ်မြင်သံကြားရုပ်ရှင်ရိုက်ကူးမှုကို ရုပ်ရှင်နည်းပညာတွင် အောင်မြင်မှုတစ်ခုအဖြစ် သတ်မှတ်ခဲ့သည်။ Avatar ကို ၂၀၀၉ ခုနှစ် ဒီဇင်ဘာလ ၁၀ ရက်နေ့တွင် လန်ဒန်တွင် ပွဲဦးထွက်ခဲ့ပြီး ဒီဇင်ဘာလ ၁၈ ရက်နေ့တွင် အမေရိကန်ပြည်ထောင်စုတွင် ပြသခဲ့ပြီး အပြုသဘောဆောင်သော သုံးသပ်ချက်များကို ရရှိခဲ့ပြီး ဝေဖန်သူများသည် ၎င်း၏ ဆန်းသစ်သော အမြင်ပိုင်းအကျိုးသက်ရောက်မှုများကို ချီးကျူးခဲ့သည်။ အဲဒီရုပ်ရှင်ဟာ ရုံတင်ပြသစဉ်အတွင်းမှာ ရုံဝင်ငွေ စံချိန်များစွာကို ချိုးဖျက်နိုင်ခဲ့ပြီး၊ အဲဒီနောက်မှာ ရုပ်ရှင်လောကမှာ အမြင့်ဆုံး ရုံဝင်ငွေကို ရယူနိုင်ခဲ့တဲ့ ရုပ်ရှင်ဖြစ်လာခဲ့ပါတယ်။  "},{"question":"هل مشاعر الجملة التالية سلبية ، إيجابية ، أم محايدة : موقع رائع من المطاعم والمقاهي. ساعود هنا مرة أخرى أوصي به لأي شخص.","answer":"مشاعر الجملة السابقة إيجابية."},{"question":"Raha jerena ireto fehezanteny roa ireto:Fehezanteny A: \\"Na dia teo aza ny fandavana miverimberina, dia nanohy ny fandefasana ny sora-tanana nataony izy, ary dia nekena izany.\\"Fehezanteny B: \\"Taorian'ny fandefasana sy fandavana marobe dia nekena tamin'ny farany ny sora-tanana.\\"Mitovy ve ny dikany?","answer":"Eny, mitovy ny dikan'ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"\\"Кудай аман\\" деген сөздүн мааниси?","answer":" 1. Өзгөрбөстөн бир калыбында, башта кандай болсо ошондой 2. өт. Эч өзгөртүү киргизилбеген, кол тийбеген, иштелбеген. Ал иш ошол бойдон, кудай аман турат колго алынбай, – деди Айнура эже"},{"question":"Gloria Grahame","answer":"Gloria Grahame je óṣèrè lóbinrin ati akọrin ilẹ america to gba Ebun Akademi bi Obinrin Osere Keji Didarajulo.Grahame ni à bisi Los Angeles. Óṣèrè lóbinrin naa ni à tọ ni ilana Methodist. Baba Gloria Reginald Michael Bloxam jẹ architect ti ilẹ èdè gẹẹsi ati ólùkọwè ṣùgbọn iya rẹ Jean McDougall jẹ óṣèrè lòbinrin ilẹ british.Grahame jẹ Democrat to ti Adlai Stevenson lẹyin lóri campaign rẹ̀ lori idibó arẹ ni ọdun 1952.Grahame fẹ ọkọ lẹẹmẹrin to si bi ọmọ mẹrim. Óṣèrè lobinrin naa ṣè Igbeyawó akọkọ pẹlu óṣèrè lọkunrin Stanley Clements ni óṣu August, ọdun 1945. Tọkọ Taya pinya ni ọdun 1948. Glori fẹ Director Nicholas Ray ti wọn si bi ọmọ ọkunrin Timothy ni óṣu November, ọdun 1948. Tọkọ Taya pinya ni ọdun 1952. Glori ṣè Igbeyawó kẹta pẹlu ólukọwè ati óludari television Cy Howard ni óṣu August, ọdun 1954 ti wọn si bi ọmọ óbinrin Marianna Paulette ni ọdun 1956. Tọkọ Taya pinya ni óṣu November, ọdun 1957. Gloria ṣè Igbèyawó kẹrin pẹlu óṣèrè lọkunrin Anthony Ray (Ọmọ ọkọ rẹ ẹlẹkèji) ni óṣu May, ọdun 1960 ti wọn si bi ọmọ ọkunrin meji; Anthony ni ọdun 1963 ati James ni ọdun 1965.Ni óṣu March, ọdun 1974 Gloria ni arun jẹjẹrẹ ti ọmu. Ni ọdun 1981, ósèrè lóbinrin naa ṣè aisan tosi yẹ ki wọn ṣiṣè abẹ fun ṣugbọn ó kọ jalẹ. Ni óṣu October, ọdun 1981 Gloria kus si Ilè iwósan St Vincent ni Manhattan, New York City. Óṣèrè lóbinrin naa ni wọn sin si Oakwood Memorial Park Cemetery ni Chatsworth, Los AngelesGrahame lọ si ilè iwe Hollywood High School lẹyin naa ni àràbinrin naa kurò nibẹ lati tẹsiwaju lóri irin ajo èrè ṣiṣèGloria gba Àmi Ẹyẹ ti Oscar ati Golden Globe.Fun ipa Óṣèrè lóbinrin naa ni motion picture industry, Gloria gba irawọ star lori Hollywood Walk of Fame ni 6522 Hollywood Boulevard"},{"question":"Midika inona ny andro Alatsinainy ho an'ny Malagasy?","answer":"Ho an'ny Malagasy, ny andro Alatsinainy dia andro mena (mafana) sy andro mafy. Andro miovaova fivezivezena sy fitsangantsanganana ary fandratoana olona tsindrian-javatra."},{"question":"Apakah maksud hati kecil? Berikan contoh ayat.","answer":"Maksudnya adalah perasaan hati yang sesungguhnya. Contoh ayat: Aida menyembunyikan hati kecil yang sebenarnya terhadap peristiwa tersebut."},{"question":"السؤال: ما اسم المشرك الذي قتله رسول الله صلّى الله عليه وسلّم؟","answer":"الجواب: أبيّ بن خلف."},{"question":"ما هو السؤال لـ: \\"الصلصة ممكن تلوينها وتذوقها بالملح (مزيج بسيط من الملح والكراميل لتلوين الأغذية) أو التسمير بالصلصة (الملح المذاب في الماء) أو يمكن استخدام مكعبات و مسحوق جاهزة كبديل للحوم الطبيعية أو المستخلصات الخضرية\\"","answer":"\\"من ماذا مصنوعة الصلصة؟\\""},{"question":"Ọmọọba ti ọlọpaa kogberegbe yinbọn lu l’Oṣogbo ti ku o","answer":"Ọmọọba Saheed Ọlabomi, ọmọkunrin ti ọlọpaa kogberegbe kan yinbọn lu lagbegbe Islahudeen, niluu Oṣogbo, lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, to kọja, ti jade laye.Ni nnkan bii aago meje aabọ alẹ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, la gbọ pe Saheed, ẹni to jẹ ọmọ ẹgbọn Aragbiji ti ilu Iragbiji, Ọba Abdulrasheed Ayọtunde Ọlabomi, mi eemi ikẹyin.Ọmọ bibi ilu Iragbiji ni Saheed, ilu Oṣogbo lo n gbe, o ni iyawo kan, o si bimọ meji. Ileewe gbogboniṣe ipinlẹ Kwara lo ti kẹkọ pari, ko too bẹrẹ ka-ra-ka-ta niluu Oṣogbo. Ọmọ ọdun mejidinlọgbọn ni ko too pade iku ojiji rẹ nirọlẹ ọjọ naa.Lasiko ti awọn ọlọpaa kogberegbe naa n kọja ninu sun-kẹrẹ-fa-kẹrẹ ọkọ lagbegbe ọhun ni ọkan lara wọn yinbọn soke, to si ba Saheed loju.Latigba naa lo ti wa nileewosan UNIOSUN pẹlu ẹnjinni ti wọn fi n mi lẹnu rẹ, ṣugbọn ti ọlọjọ de lalẹỌjọbọ.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe Alukooro ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, ASP Yẹmisi Ọpalọla, sọ pe igbẹjọ ti bẹrẹ lori ọrọ ọlọpaa naa, sibẹ, ohun ti awọn mọlẹbi Saheed n fẹ ni igbẹjọ itagbangba ati idajọ ododo."},{"question":"\\"අබරා  සිල් ගත්තා  වාගේ\\" ප්‍රස්ථාව පිරුළට පාදක වුන කතාව කුමක්ද ?","answer":"අබරා සිල් ගත්තා වාගේ - නුපුරුදු කටයුත්තක් කරන්නට ගොස් අමාරුවේ වැටීමඑක්තරා ගමක අබරා නම් මිනිසෙක් වාසය කළේය. ඔහුගේ බිරිද සෑම පොහොය දිනකදීම අටසිල් ගැනීම සදහා පන්සලට යන්ණිය. අබරාටද සිල් ගැනීම සදහා ආශාවක් ඇතිවිය. සිල් ගන්නේ කෙසේදැයි අබරා බිරිදගෙන් විමසීය. “පන්සලට ගොස් ස්වාමීන් වහන්සේ කියන කියන වචනය තමනුත් කියන්න ඕනි” යනුවෙන් ඇය පැවසුවාය. ඊලග පොහොය දිනයේදී සිල් රෙදිද ඇදගත් අබරා පන්සල වෙතට ගියේය. එවිට හාමුදුරුවෝ අබරා අමතා “ ආවේ මොකදැයි” විමසූහ. එවිට අබරාද  “ ආවේ මොකදැයි” හාමුදුරුවන්ගෙන් ඇසුවේය. “මොහුට පිස්සුදැයි” හාමුදුරුවෝ ඇසුවේය. අබරාද පෙරලා “මොහුට පිස්සුදැයි” හාමුදුරුවන්ගෙන් විමසූහ. මේ අවස්ථාවේදී හාමුදුරුවන්ට කේන්ති ගොස් “ගනු කඹයක් මූ බදින්න” යනුවෙන් ඇබිත්යන්ට පැවසූහ. මෙයද අබරා විසින් පෙරලා පැවසූහ. ටික වේලාවකට පසුව ඇබිත්තයන් විසින් අතින් පයින් අබරාට පහර දෙන්නට විය. අවසානයේදී ගුටිකෑ අබරා ඉතා අමාරුවෙන් තමාගේ නිවස වෙත දුවන්නට පටන් ගත්තේය. පහර කෑඋමෙන් වේදනාවට පත් අබරා ඉතාමත් අපහසුවෙන් නිවස දෙසට එනවා දුටු බිරිය පුදුමයෙන් මෙන් ඒ දෙස බලා සිටියේය.“ඇයි බොන නුඹල හැමදාම කොහොම සිල් ගන්නවද? මට එක දවසක් සිල් ගන්න ගිහින් සිල් ගැනීම එපාම වුණා.” යි පවසමින් තමන්ට සිදුවූ සියල්ල අබරා බිරිදට පැවසූහ. සැමියා කෙරෙහි අනුකම්පාව ඇතිවූ බිරිද සිරුරේ තෙල් බෙහෙත් ගැල්වූවාය."},{"question":"inona no toetra mampiavaka ny lahatsoratra izay literatiora amin'ny lahatsoratra tsy ara-literatiora?","answer":"Ny toetra mampiavaka ny lahatsoratra izay literatiora ary manavaka azy amin'ny lahatsoratra tsy ara-literatiora (fanaovan-gazety, dokam-barotra, siantifika, expository, argumentative, siantifika, famaritana, lahatsoratra ara-dalàna, sns.), dia ny fampitana hevitra amin'ny fomba fitandremana sy aesthetika. fomba. , ao anatin'ireo fomba maro misy."},{"question":"இந்தியா விண்வெளி யுகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்ததற்குக் காரணமாக  அமைந்தவர் யார்?  \\t1. அலிமுகமது2. ஆகா கான்3. ஏ.பி.ஜே. அப்துல் கலாம்4. சுல்தான்","answer":"3. ஏ.பி.ஜே. அப்துல் கலாம்."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Hoàng Trung, 25 tuổi, sống ở Hà Nội, đến Singapore vào đầu mùa hè. Đây là chuyến du lịch nước ngoài đầu tiên của anh sau Covid-19. Trung ghi lại cảm xúc khi đến sở thú đêm (Night Safari), sau nhiều háo hức và mong đợi. Khi tìm hiểu Singapore để có chuyến đi trọn vẹn nhất, tôi phát hiện trải nghiệm sở thú đêm. Trong tưởng tượng của tôi, sở thú đêm ắt hẳn sẽ rất thú vị và độc đáo. Tôi sẽ được chiêm ngưỡng những loài động vật sống về đêm mà sở thú ban ngày không có, và có chăng những màn hù doạ từ trong bóng tối? Đặc biệt, khi mua vé, tôi thấy quy định không được xịt nước hoa vì có thể ảnh hưởng đến động vật hoang dã, nên càng mong đợi những trải nghiệm bất ngờ và có thể được tương tác với động vật từ sở thú này. Night Safari ở cùng khu với sở thú Singapore, nằm cách biệt và rất xa trung tâm thành phố. Nếu tới đây bằng phương tiện công cộng, bạn phải trung chuyển từ tàu điện sang xe buýt. Tôi lựa chọn taxi để yên tâm hơn khi đi buổi tối, song cũng vất vả vì không quen đường Singapore, thật khó để giải thích với tài xế nơi mình đang đứng đợi. Tôi đến nơi lúc 20h, háo","answer":"hức vô cùng khi đi từ bãi đỗ xe, đi qua các biển chỉ dẫn để vào sở thú đêm. Họ phát nhạc có không khí phiêu lưu, rừng xanh, nhiều giai điệu trống và tiếng côn trùng kêu, khiến nhiều khách Tây đi cạnh tôi nhún nhảy, thậm chí chạy nhanh đến cổng soát vé vì không chờ đợi được. Sau khi lấy vé, tôi được đưa lên một chiếc tàu điện. Và mọi chuyện bắt đầu không như mong đợi từ đây. Cùng giọng đọc bằng tiếng Anh khá truyền cảm phát từ trong loa, chiếc tàu chở chúng tôi đi vòng quanh sở thú. Trải nghiệm này phụ thuộc khá nhiều vào việc bạn có biết tiếng Anh hay không vì nếu không hiểu, bạn sẽ không thể hình dung những gì đang diễn ra xung quanh vì quá tối. Theo tôi như vậy là điểm trừ vì du khách sẽ khá bị động. Bạn tôi là người không hiểu tiếng Anh, nếu không được tôi nhắc, chắc hẳn cô ấy không biết mình đã đi tới đâu và đang được xem gì. Trái ngược với mong đợi của tôi, chiếc tàu dẫn chúng tôi đi xem sư tử, hồng hạc, voi... Những con vật mà sở thú ban ngày cũng có, thay vì tôi được xem cú, trăn, hay những loại động vật săn mồi về đêm. \\"Thế này thì đi sở thú ban ngày để nhìn cho rõ còn hơn nhỉ\\", tôi nghe thấy một vị khách Đức ngồi trước mình bình luận. Nhìn được các con vật cũng là điều khá hên xui, do chỉ có ánh sáng lờ mờ và chúng hầu như đang ngủ. Tuy vậy, trong hành trình cũng có một số điểm nhấn như việc chiếc tàu điện đưa tôi đi xượt qua một con thú gì đó đang thong dong đi theo chiều ngược lại. Có lẽ tôi chỉ cách nó khoảng 10 m. Đến giờ tôi vẫn không biết đó là con vật gì, nhưng những sự bí ẩn như vậy mới là điều tôi mong đợi khi trải nghiệm sở thú đêm. Hành trình tàu điện kết thúc, chúng tôi đi xem show Những tạo vật về đêm. Tôi cũng hy vọng nhiều về show diễn này sau khi đọc quảng cáo, nghĩ rằng sẽ có những pha thót tim hoặc bất ngờ cho khán giả. Tuy nhiên, ngoài âm nhạc và hiệu ứng tắt, bật đèn không có gì ngạc nhiên, tôi chỉ được xem những con vật thông minh, như con lửng biết mở nắp hộp, hay con cú biết đậu trên tay người. Người Singapore rất biết làm du lịch, khi gợi mở được sự tò mò trong du khách, song trải nghiệm sở thú đêm thực sự không làm tôi thấy thoả mãn. Họ giỏi trong việc tạo ra không khí, nhưng như vậy chưa đủ. Sau khi trở về, tôi có đăng trên trang cá nhân trải nghiệm về sở thú này và nhiều người từng đi cũng đồng tình với tôi về cảm nhận không như mong đợi. Tuy nhiên, có thể trẻ con vẫn sẽ thích, nên nếu đi cùng gia đình, bạn vẫn nên thử, vì nó khá lạ."},{"question":"What is the purpose of a hypothesis test?","answer":"The purpose of a hypothesis test is to assess whether there is enough evidence in a sample to infer something about a population parameter."},{"question":"合法的にお酒が飲めるのは２０歳からですが、自動車の運転ができるのは何歳からでしょう？","answer":"１８歳"},{"question":"जैन साहित्याला काय म्हणतात?","answer":"जैन साहित्याला आगम म्हणतात."},{"question":"\\"Энем токуган килемди карай албадым,Атам берген пулду санай албадым\\".-табышмактын жандырмагы кандай?","answer":"Табышмактын жандырмагы -\\"КҮН, ЖЫЛДЫЗ\\"(🌞🌠)."},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Espagne","answer":"Péeyum réwum Espagne mu ngi tudu Madrid"},{"question":"Кичинеңизде асманда самолёт учуп баратса жердеги балдардын абалы кандай болгон?","answer":"Абдан кубанчубуз колубузду жайып🧍самолётко окшоп анан дагы чуркап ырдачу элек.Самолёт самолёт ✈️Кайда учуп барасыңЧөнтөгүңө салат кетКапитандын баласын. Балалык доор кайра кайтып келсе..."},{"question":"අපේ ජාතියේ පියා කවුද?","answer":"මහත්මා ගාන්ධි"},{"question":"Ọkọ tẹ awọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ meji pa n’Idanre, lawọn ẹgbẹ wọn ba fẹhonu han","answer":"Diẹ lo ku kọrọ iku awọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ meji ti wọn ku sinu ijamba ọkọ lagbegbe Idanre, nijọba ibilẹ Idanre, da rogbodiyan nla silẹ l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ to kọja.Gẹgẹ ba a ṣe gbọ, ilu Idanre lawọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ ọhun ti gbera pẹlu ọlọkada kan to gbe wọn lọjọ naa, ti wọn si mori le ọna igboro Akurẹ pẹlu ere asapajude ti ọkunrin ọlọkada yii n sa.Bo ṣe ku bii ibusọ meji pere ki wọn wọ igboro ilu Akurẹ lo ba ọkọ kan niwaju, ibi to ti n gbiyanju ati ya ọkọ yii silẹ lori are, ọkọ akoyọyọ to n ba ere bọ niwaju lo lọọ fori sọ.Loju-ẹsẹ lawọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ meji to jokoo lẹyin ọkada náà ti ku, ti ọkùnrin ọlọkada tó gbé wọn si wa lẹsẹ kan aye ẹsẹ kan ọrun títí di ba a ṣe n kọ iroyin yii lọwọ.Ko ju bii ọgbọn iṣẹju tiṣẹlẹ yii waye nigba ti ọgọọrọ awọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ kan lati ilu Idanre ya de lati fẹhonu han ta ko iku awọn ẹgbẹ wọn mejeeji.Ọkọ akoyọyọ to tẹ wọn pa ni wọn kọkọ sọ ina si ki wọn too bẹrẹ si i daamu awọn ọlọkọ atawọn eeyan to rìn si asiko ti iṣẹlẹ yii waye."},{"question":"આકાશગંગા શું છે?","answer":"આકાશગંગા એ આકાશગંગા છે જેમાં સૌરમંડળ શામેલ છે, નામ પૃથ્વી પરથી ગેલેક્સીના દેખાવનું વર્ણન કરે છે: તારાઓમાંથી રચાયેલી રાતના આકાશમાં જોવા મળતા પ્રકાશનો એક સુસ્ત બેન્ડ જે નગ્ન આંખ દ્વારા વ્યક્તિગત રૂપે અલગ કરી શકાતો નથી.આકાશગંગા શબ્દ એ લેક્ટીઆ દ્વારા લેટિનનો અનુવાદ છે, જેનો અર્થ દૂધિયું વર્તુળ છે.પૃથ્વી પરથી, આકાશગંગા બેન્ડ તરીકે દેખાય છે કારણ કે તેની ડિસ્ક-આકારની રચના અંદરથી જોવામાં આવે છે.ગેલેલીયો ગેલિલીએ પ્રથમ વખત 1610 માં તેના ટેલિસ્કોપ સાથે પ્રકાશના બેન્ડને વ્યક્તિગત તારાઓમાં ઉકેલી લીધી. 1920 ના દાયકાની શરૂઆતમાં, મોટાભાગના ખગોળશાસ્ત્રીઓએ વિચાર્યું કે આકાશગંગા બ્રહ્માંડના બધા તારાઓ ધરાવે છે.ખગોળશાસ્ત્રીઓ હાર્લો શેપલી,  એડવિન હબલ દ્વારા નિરીક્ષણોએ બતાવ્યું કે આકાશગંગા ઘણી તારાવિશ્વોમાંની એક છે."},{"question":"句子1: 然而, 大使G.麦克默特里戈德利, 和他的继任者, 威廉沙利文, 继续监督空袭在老<unk>. 第二句话: 然而,大使G.麦克默特里戈德利和他的继任者威廉沙利文继续监督在老<unk>的空袭. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"相同"},{"question":"Jubbantil mbind mii:Éy yéen way-gëm yi! Buleen di wax [sàmmoonteel ak nun], deeleen wax: \\"Xool nu\\" ; te deeleen dégg [ndigal] ! Mbugal mu metti mooy dal ca kaw way-weddi ña.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Éy yéen waygëm yi! Buléen di wàx [sàmmoonteel ak nun], deeléen wàx: \\"Xool nu\\"; te deeléen dégg [ndigal]! Mbugal mu metti moo'y dàl ca kaw wayweddi ña."},{"question":"জীববিজ্ঞান শিক্ষক তাঁর ছাত্রদের নিয়ে বিদ্যালয়ের বিভিন্ন রাজ্যের গাছগুলো পর্যবেক্ষণ করলেন। পরবর্তীতে তিনি নানা রকম গাছ (যেমন ব্যাঙের ছাতা, টেরিস, কাঠাল গাছ) দেখিয়ে একটি বিষয় সম্পর্কে আলোচনা করলেন যার জনক বিজ্ঞানী ক্যারোলাস লিনিয়াস।ছাত্রদের দেখা স্বভোজী উদ্ভিদ ২টির রাজ্যগত বৈশিষ্ট্য বর্ণনা করো।","answer":"উদ্দীপকে ছাত্রদের দেখা উদ্ভিদগুলো হলো ব্যাঙের ছাতা, টেরিস ও কাঠাল গাছ। তার মধ্যে টেরিস ও কাঠাল গাছ এই দুটি হলো স্বভোজী উদ্ভিদ, যাদের অবস্থান প্লানটি রাজ্যে। নিচে উদ্ভিদ দুটির রাজ্যগত বৈশিষ্ট্য বর্ণনা করো হলো-এরা প্রকৃত নিউক্লিয়াসযুক্ত সালোকসংশ্লেষণকারী উদ্ভিদ। এদের উন্নত টিস্যুতন্ত্র রয়েছে। এদের ভ্রূণ সৃষ্টি হয় এবং তা থেকে ডিপ্লয়েড পর্যায় শুরু হয়। এদের যৌনজনন অ্যানাইসোগ্যামাস ধরনের। এরা আর্কিগোনিয়েট ও পুষ্পক উদ্ভিদ। ক্লোরোফিল থাকায় এরা নিজেদের খাদ্য নিজেরা তৈরি করতে পারে।"},{"question":"I recommend she submit the resume in a PDF format so there will be no automatic changes in the format.is there grammatical issue?","answer":"The sentence is almost correct, but there is a minor grammatical issue. It should be:\\"I recommend that she submit the resume in PDF format so there will be no automatic changes in the formatting.\\"Here, I've added \\"that\\" after \\"recommend,\\" and I've changed \\"in a PDF format\\" to \\"in PDF format\\" for smoother phrasing. Additionally, I've modified \\"in the format\\" to \\"in the formatting\\" to make it more precise."},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Arménie","answer":"Péeyum réwum Arménie mu ngi tudu Erevan"},{"question":"Kí ni à ń pe Monday ní èdè Yorùbá?","answer":"Ọjọ́ Ajé ni."},{"question":"गन्धर्व संस्कृति जोगाउन सरकारले के गर्न सक्छ ?","answer":"गन्धर्व जातिमा मात्रै प्रचलनमा रहेको सारंगीका लोपोन्मुख राग/धुनको अनुसन्धान गरी श्रब्य, दृष्य छायांकन गरी त्यसलाई प्रकाशन समेत गरी अभिलेखीकरण गरिनु पर्दछ । यसले आम गन्धर्व जातिको बौद्धिक अमूर्त सांस्कृतिक सम्पदाको संरक्षणको सुनिश्चितता गर्दै राष्ट्रिय तथा अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय रूपमा यसलाई व्यावसायिक विकास गरिने संभावना रहेको छ । यसबाट गन्धर्व जातिको मौलिक सीप, कला, प्रविधि तथा सङ्गीत संस्कृतिको पहिचान, संरक्षण र प्रवद्र्धनमा समेत पर्याप्त योगदान पुग्नुका साथै परम्परागत अमूर्त सांस्कृतिक धरोहरहरूको संरक्षणमा नयाँ पुस्तको सहभागिता पनि बढ्ने छ"},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा सोप्या शब्दात अर्थ सांगा आलीया भोगाशी असावे सादर","answer":"कुरकुर न करता निर्माण झालेली परिस्थिती स्वीकारणे."},{"question":"සුභූති මහ රහතන් සහන්සේට ගෞතම බුදුසසුනේ හිමිවූ අග තනතුරු මොනවාද ?","answer":"සුභූති මහ රහතන් සහන්සේට ගෞතම බුදුසසුනේ හිමිවූ ​අග තනතුරු වූයේ, 1) නික්ලේශී විහාරී භික්ෂූන් අතරින් අග්‍ර සහ 2) දක්ෂිණාර්හ භික්ෂූන් අතරින් අග්‍ර යන තනතුරු වේ."},{"question":"السؤال: ما معنى الأعراف؟","answer":"الإجابة: هي إحدى سور القرآن الكريم وهي عبارة عن تلال مرتفعة تقع بين النار والجنة"},{"question":"Inona no maha samy hafa ny fiaraha-miory sy ny fiaraha-miory?","answer":"Ny fiaraha-miory dia midika hoe mahatakatra ny fihetseham-pon'ny hafa amin'ny fametrahana ny tenanao eo amin'ny toerany, fa ny fangorahana kosa dia midika fangorahana ny fihetseham-pon'ny hafa."},{"question":"නව කැලණි පාලම ඉදිකිරිම සදහා ආධාර ලබාදුන් ආයතනය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ජපානයේ ජයිකා ආයතනය නව කැලණි පාලම ඉදිකිරිම සදහා ආධාර ලබාදුන් ආයතනය වේ."},{"question":"Defina a palavra \\"dedicado,\\" de uma forma concisa,.","answer":"Dedicado significa comprometido e empenhado, em realizar uma tarefa ou alcançar um objetivo."},{"question":"要求をかなえるために労働者達が団結して仕事や作業を放棄する行為で、２００４年プロ野球でも行なわれたことをカタカナ５文字で何という？","answer":"ストライキです。"},{"question":"अ‍ॅलन ट्युरिंग हे कोण होते?","answer":"अ‍ॅलन ट्युरिंग हे ब्रिटीश गणितज्ञ, तर्कशास्त्रज्ञ आणि संगणक शास्त्रज्ञ होते ज्यांना आधुनिक संगणकीय आणि कृत्रिम बुद्धिमत्तेच्या विकासातील सर्वात प्रभावशाली व्यक्तींपैकी एक मानले जाते. त्यांचा जन्म 23 जून 1912 रोजी लंडनमधील मैदा वेल येथे झाला आणि 7 जून 1954 रोजी चेशायरच्या विल्मस्लो येथे त्यांचे दुःखद निधन झाले.ट्युरिंगने विविध क्षेत्रात महत्त्वपूर्ण योगदान दिले, यासह:1. ट्युरिंग मशिन्स: त्यांनी ट्युरिंग मशीनची संकल्पना मांडली, हे एक सैद्धांतिक उपकरण आहे जे गणनेच्या कल्पनेला औपचारिक करण्यासाठी वापरले जाते. या संकल्पनेने गणनेच्या आधुनिक सिद्धांताचा पाया घातला आणि मशीनद्वारे काय गणना केली जाऊ शकते याची मर्यादा स्थापित करण्यात मदत झाली.2. दुसर्‍या महायुद्धादरम्यान कोडब्रेकिंग: दुसऱ्या महायुद्धादरम्यान एन्क्रिप्टेड जर्मन संदेशांचा उलगडा करण्यात ट्युरिंगने महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका बजावली. जर्मन एनिग्मा कोड तोडण्यावर काम करणार्‍या संघातील तो एक प्रमुख व्यक्ती होता, ज्याचा युद्धाच्या निकालावर महत्त्वपूर्ण प्रभाव पडला.3. ट्युरिंग टेस्ट: ट्युरिंगने त्यांच्या 1950 च्या पेपर \\"कंप्युटिंग मशिनरी अँड इंटेलिजन्स\\" मध्ये \\"ट्युरिंग टेस्ट\\" म्हणून ओळखल्या जाणार्‍या गोष्टीचा प्रस्ताव मांडला. ही चाचणी मशीनची बुद्धिमान वर्तन दर्शविण्याची क्षमता निर्धारित करण्यासाठी डिझाइन केलेली आहे जी माणसाच्या वर्तनापेक्षा वेगळी आहे. कृत्रिम बुद्धिमत्तेच्या क्षेत्रात ही एक मूलभूत संकल्पना आहे.4. कृत्रिम बुद्धिमत्ता: ट्युरिंगचे ट्युरिंग चाचणीचे कार्य आणि मशीन इंटेलिजन्सच्या त्याच्या शोधामुळे कृत्रिम बुद्धिमत्तेच्या क्षेत्रासाठी मार्ग मोकळा झाला. त्याच्या कल्पनांचा एआय संशोधन आणि त्याच्या विविध उपक्षेत्रांच्या विकासावर प्रभाव पडला आहे.5. ट्युरिंगचे मॉर्फोजेनेसिस: गणित आणि संगणनामधील त्यांच्या कार्याव्यतिरिक्त, ट्युरिंगने मॉर्फोजेनेसिसचे क्षेत्र देखील शोधले, जे जैविक जीवांमध्ये नमुने आणि संरचना कशा तयार होतात याचा अभ्यास आहे. साध्या रासायनिक अभिक्रियांमधून प्राण्यांच्या आवरणांसारखे गुंतागुंतीचे नमुने कसे उद्भवू शकतात हे स्पष्ट करण्यासाठी त्यांनी गणितीय मॉडेल्सचा प्रस्ताव दिला.2009 मध्ये, त्याच्या योगदानाबद्दल आणि त्याच्यावर झालेल्या अन्यायाची मान्यता मिळवण्यासाठी दीर्घ मोहिमेनंतर, ब्रिटिश सरकारने अधिकृतपणे ट्युरिंगच्या उपचारांसाठी माफी मागितली. 2013 मध्ये, ट्युरिंगला त्याच्या दोषी ठरवल्याबद्दल मरणोत्तर शाही माफी मिळाली.अ‍ॅलन ट्युरिंगचा संगणक विज्ञान, कृत्रिम बुद्धिमत्ता आणि गणन आणि जटिलतेच्या आकलनावर त्यांच्या गहन प्रभावासाठी आजही त्यांचा वारसा साजरा केला जात आहे."},{"question":"Given the following statement, predict the tags for each word:“I like apples”","answer":"I:pronoun, like:verb, apples:noun"},{"question":"वेळेचे महत्व काय?","answer":"वेळ ही सर्वात महत्वाची गोष्ट आहे. वेळ हा कोणासाठीही थांबत नाही. तो निरंतर चालत राहतो म्हणून तर तुम्ही किती कष्ट करून किती मोठे झालात ते पक्त वेळेच्या माध्यमावर ठरवले जाते. हे आपल संपूर्ण जग वेळेचे गुलाम आहे, ते वेळेबरोबरच चालते.तुम्ही कुठेही कामाला जा तुम्ही काम तर खूप करणार पण तुम्हला मान-धन वेळेनुसारच मिळणार. मोठ्यातील मोठी कंपनी असो की गावतले छोटे दुकान सर्व वेळेनुसारच चालतात म्हणून तर सांगतात न वेळ ही संपत्ती आहे.गेलेले पैसे परत मिळवता येतात, न आवडणारी नोकरी सोडता येते पण वेळेचे तसे नाही गेलेला वेळ परत कधीच परत येत नाही, आणि वेळ कधी कोणाच्या मर्जी अनुसार हि चालत नाही. म्हणून योग्य वेळी योग्य परिश्रम केले तर तुम्हला कष्टाचे योग्य फळ मिळनाराच.हे सर्व वेळेचे महत्व सर्व थोर लोक जानतात म्हणूनच तर आपली शाळा वेळे अनुसार चालते आपण वेळेवर अभ्यास केला तर आपल्यांना चांगले गुण मिळतात. शाळाच नाही तर रेल्वे स्टेशनवर आपण पाहिले असेलच ट्रेन वेळेवर धावतात आणि ट्रेन कोणा साठी हि शनभर हि थांबत नाही वेळ चुकली तर समजा ट्रेन चुकली.वेळेचे आपल्या आयुष्या मदे खूप महत्वाचे स्थान आहे. आज जेजे जगात थोर लोक आहेत ते सर्वच वेळेचे पालन करतात आणि आपली कामे वेळेवरच करतात. ह्या एक सवइ मुलेच ते इतके यशसस्वी झाले आहेत.आपण आज पासून नाही तर याच शना पासूनच वेळेचे पालन करने सुरु केले पाहिजे. आपल्या सर्व कामाचे वेळापत्रक तयार करून ते नियोजीत पणाने पूर्ण केली पाहिजे तरच आपण आपल्या जीवनाचे स्वार्थक करू. अपयशी माणूस नेहमी आपला वेळ फालतू गोष्टी मधे वाया घालवतो, म्हणून त्यला कधीच यश मिळत नाही.आता पासून आपण वेळेचे योग्य पालन करूया आणि यशाचे हे शिखर गाठूया."},{"question":"قم بإنشاء قصيدة مدح من بحر الخفيف.","answer":"إِن عَبد الرَحمَن مَولى المَعاليوَعَديم النَظير وَالأَمثالقَد حَوى الفَضل لَم يَدعُ مِنهُ شَيئاًلِسِواهُ إِلّا خَيال الخَيالسَيد وَابن سَيد وَحَسيبمِن حَسيب مُقَدس الأَفعالإِن تَذَكرت عَنهُ تَأخير مَدحيقُلت ما قيلَ في الزَمان الخاليما تَشكَكت في الزَمان وَلَكنغَلَطي كانَ في إِختيار الرِجالإِن ذكر الكِرام ذكر جَميللَيسَ يُبلى وَكُل شَيءِ بالي"},{"question":"DISASTERChapter 2","answer":"DISASTERChapter 2Hello mum, Are you still at work? Neme askedNeme, what is it? You don't sound good. What is the problem? Her mom askedI'm not fine.Mum, mplease,e I need to talk to yo..Shee cried as Nelson snatched the phone fromher.rEnough of all these Nemes; can't you just forgive me? I said I'm sorry. Nelson beggedYou're raising your voice, right? Nelson, please give me back my phone before I do something you and I will live to regret.I'm not giving you this phone until you forgive me.You think I'll just forgive you like that? For crying out loud, Nelson, I am 2 months gone for you. You're treating me like a fool; we haven't evenJust keep quiet, Neme; haven't I paid your bride price? You are officially my wife now, wedding or no wedding. You are my wife; let's go home. Nelson told her, dragged her up, and left.What are you still doing here, Dora? Neme asked, throwing her pillows.Dora eyed her, picked up her purse, and left.I'm still sorry, Neme. Nelson beggedYou should be sorry for yourself. Nelson, don't even come closer to me.What do you want, huh? I've begged and begged, and still you don't want to listen to me. What do I owe you?Your life, she replied.Nelson raised his brow, smiled, and held Neme's hand.Hey, dog, let me be, please... Neme screamedI'm sorry, baby girl. Nelson apologizedYou're stressing me. I want to rest.But were you going to call off our wedding? He askedOf course, for cheating on me with my friend, Nelson, you're a dog. You stink.It's fine. Let me fix something for you to eat.I'm not hungry. I want to see and talk to my mom. I don't know why you brought me here. Please,  I want to go. She started crying again.Get your handbag, then let me drop you off, but I promise you won't disclose this matter to your mom. Nelson saidWhy won't I, Nelson? I'm done with this so-called marriage thing. Go ahead with Dora.Neme I don't like this; can't you forgive me? I thought you said you loved me, huh?Yes, Nelson,I have always loved you, but you keep on toiling with my heart. What for Nelson? I know you want Dora. Go for her. She repliedWhat about our baby? He askedThere's no one here; allow me to take care of him or her.What do you mean, Neme? The baby is mine... He saidPlease, I'm not dragging that with you; take me home and don't come looking for me because it is over, like I'm done with this useless thing called marriage.Neme.. He calledPlease take me out of here this moment, she said, standing on her feet.Who's the father of that thing in your womb? He asked, looking at her.Who's the father of what? What sort of question is that?You ain't leaving here if you don't tell me who the father of that thing is.Nelson, Hey, I don't understand. You are the father; who else?Neme's phone began to ring.She stared at Nelson. Nelson gave her back the stare.Pick your call, Neme...I don't feel like taking the call right now; I'm not in a good state of mind, she answered.Nelson picked up the phone and answered the call.Hello baby, aren't you coming over again? The caller asked"},{"question":"ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ‘ਤੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ?","answer":"ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ‘ਤੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਤਿੰਨ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ-1. ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ2. ਬਹੁ-ਵਿਆਹੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ3. ਸਮੂਹ ਵਿਆਹੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ।"},{"question":"Muna 1911, anochera matongo Hiram Bingham akawana kuti iguta ripi rakarasika?","answer":"Muna 1911, anochera matongo Hiram Bingham akawana guta rekare reIncan reMachu Picchu muPeru. Machu Picchu inzvimbo inoshamisa yekuchera matongo iri muAndes Mountains, inozivikanwa nematongo ayo akanyatso chengetedzwa uye ayo anokatyamadza maonero epanoramic. Inofungidzirwa kuti yakavakwa pakati pezana ramakore rechi 15 naInca Emperor Pachacuti uye yakasiiwa panguva yekukunda kweSpain. Zvakawanikwa naBingham zvakaunza kutarisisa kwenyika dzese kune ino saiti inoshamisa uye zvakabatsira pakunzwisisa kwedu budiriro yeIncan."},{"question":"كم حزب في القرآن الكريم؟ ( 50 حزبا، 40 حزبا، 30 حزبا، 60 حزبا)","answer":"الإجابة: 60 حزباً"},{"question":"ਕੱਲਰ ਜ਼ਮੀਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਧਾਰਨ ਲਈ ਲੋੜੀਂਦੀ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਦੱਸੋ ।","answer":"ਕੱਲਰ ਜ਼ਮੀਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਧਾਰਨ ਲਈ ਕੁੱਝ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰਨੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਵੇਂ :-1. ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਹੇਠਲੇ ਪਾਣੀ ਦਾ ਪੱਧਰ ।2. ਪਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਸਿੰਚਾਈ ਲਈ ਯੋਗਤਾ ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਹੈ ।3. ਨਹਿਰੀ ਪਾਣੀ ਉਪਲੱਬਧ ਹੈ ਜਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ।4. ਧਰਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਰੋੜ ਜਾਂ ਹੋਰ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਤਹਿ ਹੈ ਜਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ।5. ਵਾਧੂ ਪਾਣੀ ਕੱਢਣ ਲਈ ਖਾਲਾਂ ਦਾ ਯੋਗ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਨਹੀਂ ।6. ਕੱਲਰ ਦੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Вопрос: Столица Словении? Ответ:","answer":"Любляна"},{"question":"الجملة الأولى: 'لديك صلاحية الوصول الى الحقائق .'. الجملة الثانية: 'الحقائق متاحة لك .'. الجملتان متوافقتان، متناقضتان، أم غير ذلك؟","answer":"الجملتان السابقتان متوافقتان."},{"question":"கேள்வி : பாலைப் பதப்படுத்தும் முறையை கண்டுபிடித்தவர் யார் ? ","answer":"பதில் : லூயி பாஸ்டர்"},{"question":"¿De qué se alimentan los koalas?","answer":"Los koalas son animales herbívoros que tienen una dieta poco variada. Se alimentan principalmente de hojas de eucalipto y ocasionalmente de hojas de otras plantas. El sistema digestivo del koala es particularmente tolerante a los componentes tóxicos presentes en la hoja de eucalipto, los cuales pueden ser venenosos y mortales para la mayoría de animales."},{"question":"Phrase 1 : \\"Briggs rencontra Briggs plus tard au Festival de Monterey Pop en 1967, où Ravi Shankar se produisait également, avec Eric Burdon et The Animals.\\" Phrase 2 : \\"Briggs a rencontré Briggs plus tard au Festival de Monterey Pop de 1967, où Ravi Shankar a également joué avec Eric Burdon et The Animals.\\" Question : La phrase 1 paraphrase-t-elle la phrase 2 ?","answer":"Oui, ils ont la même sense, mais la deuxième phrase est ambiguë et pourrait laisser entendre que Ravi Shankar et Eric Burdon et The Animals ont joué ensemble, en même temps. Ils ont tous deux joué au même festival mais à des moments différents."},{"question":"అమరావతిలో అద్భుత శిల్ప సంపదను సృష్టించిన శిల్పులను అభినందిస్తూ ఒక లేఖ రాయండి.","answer":"మిత్రునకు శిల్పులను అభినందిస్తూ లేఖవిజయవాడ,x x x x xమిత్రుడు శ్రీకాంత్ కు, / మిత్రురాలు రాధకు,మిత్రమా ! శుభాకాంక్షలు. ఈ మధ్య నేను మన నవ్యాంధ్ర రాజధాని నగరం, అమరావతికి వెళ్ళి అక్కడి శిల్ప సంపదను చూసి, ఆ శిల్పాలను చెక్కిన కళా తపస్వులయిన శిల్పులకు జోహార్లు సమర్పించాను. అక్కడ బుద్ధ విగ్రహాలు, జైన మందిరము, అమరేశ్వరాలయము, స్తూపాలు అన్నీ చూశాను. ఆ శిల్పాలు చెక్కిన శిల్పులకు అభినందనలు అందించాను. ఆ శిల్పాలు ప్రపంచ శిల్ప సంపదలోనే అగ్రశ్రేణివని డా|| ఫెర్గూసన్ పొగిడాడు.జాషువా మహాకవి చెప్పినట్లు శిల్పి చేతి సుత్తె నుండి ఎన్నో దేవాలయాలు వెలిశాయి. అర్థం లేని బండరాయికి శిల్పి జీవం పోస్తాడు. రాళ్ళను దేవుళ్ళుగా మార్చి, వాటికి మనచే పూజలు చేయిస్తాడు. శిల్పి శాశ్వతుడు. రాళ్ళలో నిద్రపోయే బొమ్మల్ని ఉలి తగిలించి అతడు లేపుతాడు. శిల్పి చిరంజీవి. పుణ్యాత్ముడు. ప్రపంచ ప్రఖ్యాతిని పొందిన మహాశిల్పులకు మనం అభినందనలు అందించాలి. నీవు కూడా అమరావతి వచ్చి, మత తెలుగు శిల్పుల కళానైపుణ్యానికి జోహార్లు అందిస్తావని విశ్వసిస్తున్నాను.‘అమరావతీ నగర అపురూప శిల్పాలు’ అని మనం నిత్యం తెలుగుతల్లి పాటలో పాడుతున్నాము. ఆ శిల్పులకు జోహార్లు అందించడం మన విధి. ఉంటా.ఇట్లు,నీ మిత్రుడు, / మిత్రురాలు,శ్రీహర్ష. / రజని.చిరునామా :పి.శ్రీకాంత్, / పి.రాధ,S/o/ D/o పి.వరప్రసాద్,విశాఖపట్టణం,అక్కయ్యపాలెం, ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్."},{"question":"வினா: சிந்து சமவெளிப் பகுதிவாழ் மக்களின் மிக முக்கியத் தொழில்","answer":"விடை :  பயிர்த் தொழில்"},{"question":"Tajuk : Kawan kamu telah kehilangan duit. Dia suka menuduh orang lain tanpa usul periksa. Bagaimanakah cara kamu menasihatinya ? Tuliskan perbualan di antara kamu berdua.","answer":"( Kamu dan Azma berada di sudut kantin sekolah )Malim  :  Mengapa kamu bermuram saja, Azma ? Apakah kamu ada masalah ?Azma   :  Duit saya sebanyak sepuluh ringgit telah hilang Malim.Malim :  Macam mana boleh hilang ?Azma   :  Saya letakkan dalam beg. Balik dari rehat sahaja duit dah tak ada. Saya syak Tahir yang curi,sebab waktu rehat dia tak keluar.Malim :  Bukankah cikgu selalu menasihati agar duit jangan ditinggalkan dalam beg.  Sekarang sudah hilang, mengapa pula menuduh tanpa usul periksa ?Azma   :  Jika bukan Tahir, siapa lagi ? Saya pasti memang Tahir ! Dia dengkikan saya  !Malim :  Jangan sesekali serkap jarang. Jika bukan dia, bagaimana kita mahu tutup  muka kita ? Baik kita jumpa Cikgu Zaidi. Guru disiplin itu boleh membantu kita.Azma  :  Betul juga kata kamu, Malim. Saya berasa bangga mendapat kawan macam  kamu."},{"question":"Sani Musa Abdullahi","answer":"Sani Musa Abdullahi, tí wọ́n tún mọ̀ sí Sani Danja tàbí Danja tí wọ́n bí ní ogúnjọ́ oṣù Kẹrin ọdún 1973 jẹ́ òṣèré orí-ìtàgé, olùgbéré-jáde, alájótà àti olórin ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó kópa nínú àwùjọ Kannywood àti Nollywood. Ní oṣù Kẹ́rin ọdún 2018, tí ó jẹ́ Etsu Nupe , Yahaya Abubaka, wé láwàní fun gẹ́gẹ́ bí Zakin Arewa.Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ rẹ̀ eré ìtàgé Hausa ní ọdún 1999 nínú eré Daliba. Danja ti gbé àwọn eré ó sì ti darí àwọn eré bíi: Manakisa, Kwarya tabi Kwarya, Jaheed, Nagari, Wasiyya, Harsashi, Gidauniya, Daham, Jarida, Matashiya, àti àwọn mìíràn. Danja di ìlú-mòọ́ká ní ọdún 2012 nínú eré Daughter of the River. Àwọn àṣàyàn eré rẹ̀Sani ti kópa nínú eré , ó sì ti gbé eré jáde ó sì ti darí eré Kannywood àti Nollywood. Lárà rẹ̀ ni :ÀKỌ́LÉ ERÉ\\t- ỌDÚNYar agadez\\t2011A Cuci Maza\\t2013Albashi (The salary)\\t2002Bani Adam\\t2012Budurwa\\t2010Da Kai zan Gana\\t2013Daga Allah ne'’ (Is from the God)\\t2015Daham\\t2005Dan Magori\\t2014Duniyar nan\\t2014Fitattu\\t2013Gani Gaka\\t2012Gwanaye\\t2003Hanyar Kano\\t2014Kukan Zaki (The lion's cry)\\t2010The other side\\t2016Buri uku a duniya (Three wishes in the world)\\t2016"},{"question":"எதிர்சொல் தருக:","answer":"இளமை × முதுமைபுகழ் × இகழ்அசதி × சுறுசுறுப்புஒளி × இருள்இன்பம் × துன்பம்அமுதம் × விடம்"},{"question":"Bản tin dự báo thời tiết đưới đây cho biết nhiệt độ thấp nhất của một số ngày trong tháng 01/2020 ở Thủ đô Mát-xcơ-va (Moscow, Nga). Có những số chỉ nhiệt độ dưới 0 °C như: – 1 °C, – 2 °C, – 6 °C, – 7°C. Các số trên có gì đặc biệt?","answer":"Lời giải:Các số – 1 °C, – 2 °C, – 6 °C, – 7°C đều có đặc điểm chung là có dấu \\"–\\" (dấu trừ) trước mỗi số và các số ở sau dấu trừ thì đều là các số tự nhiên. Vậy ta thấy ngay các số ở trên đều không phải là số tự nhiên. "},{"question":"திரைப்படமான மு.வரதராசனின் கதைகள் என்னென்ன?","answer":"பெற்ற மனம் திரைப்படத்தின் கதையை மு. வரதராசன் எழுதினார். பெற்ற மனம் 1960 ஆம் ஆண்டில் வெளிவந்த இந்தியத் தமிழ்த் திரைப்படம் ஆகும். ஏ. பீம்சிங் இயக்கத்தில் நேசனல் பிக்சர்சு நிறுவனத்தினர் இதனைத் தயாரித்திருந்தனர். சிவாஜி கணேசன், புஷ்பவல்லி, எஸ். எஸ். ராஜேந்திரன், பத்மினி ஆகியோர் முக்கிய பாத்திரங்களில் நடித்தனர். இது 1953 இல் வெளிவந்த பெம்புடு கொடுக்கு என்ற தெலுங்குத் திரைப்படத்தின் தழுவல் ஆகும்.நடனங்களை கே. என். தண்டாயுதபாணி, பிள்ளை தங்கப்பன், முத்துசாமிப் பிள்ளை ஆகியோர் அமைத்திருந்தனர். பெற்ற மனமும், பெம்புடு கொடுக்கு என்ற தெலுங்குத் திரைப்படமும் ஒரே நேரத்தில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்டிருந்தாலும், தெலுங்குத் திரைப்படம் 1953 இலேயே வெளியிடப்பட்டு விட்டது. ஏழாண்டுகளின் பின்னரேயே தமிழ்த் திரைப்படம் வெளியானது."},{"question":"Bada bayani kan wannan Maudu’in: Coronavirus ta kama mutum 92 cikin sa'o'i 24 a Kano","answer":"Cutar korona tana ci gaba da mamaya  a jihar Kano da ke arewacin Najeriya inda sabbin alkaluman da hukumomi suka fitar a daren  Juma'a suka nuna cewa karin mutum 92 sun harbu da cutar cikin sa'a 24. Alkaluman da ma'aikatar lafiya ta Kano ta fitar sun ce yanzu adadin masu cutar korona a jihar ya kai 311. Sannan akwai karin mutum uku da suka mutu wanda ya kawo adadin mamata zuwa mutum 8, kuma har yanzu babu mutum ko guda da ya warke daga cutar. Jadawalin jihohin da cutar ta bulla da hukumar yaki da cututtuka masu yaduwa a Najeriya, NCDC, ta fitar ya nuna Kano ce ta biyu a yawan masu fama da cutar bayan Legas mai mutum 1006. Kashi 71 cikin 100 na wadanda aka samu dauke da cutar sun fito ne daga jihohin Legas da Kano da kuma birnin Tarayya Abuja. Wadannan alkaluman da hukumar NCDC ta fitar a daren Juma'a na wadanda suka kamu da cutar na nuni da yadda annobar ke kara yaduwa a cikin gaggawa a jihar Kano. A baya-bayan nan an rinka samun mace-mace masu yawa tsakanin jama'ar jihar ta Kano, sai dai gwamnatin jihar ta ce babu alakar karuwar mace-macen da cutar korona. Amma wasu likitoci masu zaman kansu sun alakanta mace-macen da cutar ta korona. Yanayin da jihar Kano ta tsinci kanta na zuwa ne a daidai lokacin da likitoci ke bayyana fargabar watakila a samu koma-baya a yakin da ake yi da annobar korona a Najeriya saboda rashin kayan aiki. Likitocin dai su na kukan rashin kayan kariya, lamarin da suka ce yana jefa su cikin hadarin harbuwa da cutar korona. A farkon makon nan ne dai gwamnan Kano, Abdullahi Ganduje ya yi zargin cewa an watsar da jiharsa a yakin da gwamnatin Tarayya ke yi da wannan anno Wannan dalilin ne ya sanya shugaban kasar ya sanar da dokar hana fita ta mako biyu da kuma tura wani ayarin manyan jami'an kiwon lafiya zuwa jihar domin gudanar da bincike da kuma dakile matsalolin da ke fuskata. Yanzu dai akwai mutane sama da dubu biyu da ke dauke da cutar korona a Najeriya, cikinsu 351 sun warke yayin da 68 suka  rasa rayukansu."},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:आतां श्रवण केलियाचें फळ । क्रिया पालटे तत्काळ ।तुटे संशयाचें मूळ । येकसरां ॥ २८॥अर्थ:","answer":"आता ‘हा ग्रंथ श्रवण केल्याने काय फळ मिळते ?’ या प्रश्नाचे उत्तर असे की, हा श्रवण केल्याने श्रोत्यांच्या मनातील सर्व संशय समूळ नष्ट होऊन त्यांच्या आचरणात तत्काळ फरक पडतो. (२८)"},{"question":"ਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਗੈਸ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਹੋ ਗਈ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਡਰਾਈਵਰ ਸੜਕ ’ਤੇ ਫਸਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਡਰਾਈਵਰ ਨੇ ਲਿਫਟ ਲਈ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਡਰਾਈਵਰ ਸੜਕ ’ਤੇ ਫਸਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο: Με την βοήθεια του αδελφού του (τον οποίον εμπιστευόταν ο Μανιαδάκης), ο Βασίλης Βενετσανόπουλος το 1938 ορίστηκε υποδιοικητής της Ανακτορικής Φρουράς. Δεν συμμετείχε στον Ελληνοϊταλικό πόλεμο","answer":", καθώς παρέμεινε στην Αθήνα για να φρουρεί την βασιλική οικογένεια."},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 茨城県の納豆を紹介するイベント「栄養たくさんでおいしい」","answer":"7月10日は「納豆の日」です。7を「な」10を「とう」と読むことができるためです。6月29日、納豆をたくさん作っている茨城県が、納豆を紹介するイベントを東京で行いました。タレントのなかやまきんに君が紹介しました。なかやまきんに君はボディービルダーで、納豆が好きです。納豆について「栄養がたくさんあってすばらしい食べ物だと思います。体重を減らしているときでも毎日必ず食べます」と話しました。そして「茨城の納豆だけでも40種類以上あるそうです。おいしいし健康にもいいので、たくさん食べてほしいです」と話していました。"},{"question":"Ọmọ ọdun mẹtala ni Julius ki mọlẹ l’Ayetoro, lo ba fipa ba a lo pọ","answer":"Ẹka to n ri si ifipabanilopọ ati ifiyajẹ awọn ọmọde ni ọkunrin yii, Julius Afuapẹ, ẹni ọdun mọkanlelogun, wa bayii nitori ọmọ ọdun mẹtala to fipa ba lo pọ l’Ayetoro, ni ọgbọnjọ, oṣu kẹsan-an, to pari yii.Ọgbọn buruku ni Julius lo fun ọmọdebinrin naa to fi ba a lo pọ, to si gba ibale rẹ.Gẹgẹ bi ọmọdebinrin ti wọn forukọ bo laṣiiri naa ṣe ṣalaye, o ni inu ile loun wa lọsan-an ọjọ naa, ni nnkan bii aago kan aabọ ọsan, nigba naa ni Julius tawọn jọ n gbe laduugbo waa kan ilẹkun, to si ni aunti oun (anti ọmọbinrin yii) lo ni koun waa tun jẹnẹretọ ti wọn n lo ṣe.Aunti ọmọ naa ko si nile lasiko ti Julius wa, iyẹn lo jẹ kọmọbinrin naa ro pe ẹgbọn oun toun n gbe lọdọ ẹ naa lo ni ko waa tun jẹnẹretọ ṣe loootọ, n lo ba jẹ ko wọle.Ṣugbọn bi Julius ṣe wọle tan, ko fọwọ kan jẹnẹretọ, ọmọbinrin naa lo fipa wọ lọ si yara, to si fipa ba a lo pọ, to gba ibale rẹ. Bo si ṣe ṣere egele naa tan lo sa lọ.Nigba ti ẹgbọn ọmọ naa de to ba a nipo inira lo beere ohun to ṣẹlẹ, biyẹn si ṣe ṣalaye ni ẹgbọn rẹ mu ẹjọ naa lọ si teṣan ọlọpaa Ayetoro.DPO teṣan naa, CSP Mobọlaji Jimọh, ni kawọn ọmọọṣẹ rẹ lọọ wa afurasi naa wa, ni wọn ba bẹrẹ si i wa Julius kiri.Ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ti i ṣe ọjọ keji, oṣu kẹwaa, ni wọn ri Julius mu nibi to n fara pamọ si, o si jẹwọ pe loootọ loun fipa ba ọmọdebinrin naa lo pọ.Bi wọn ti mu ọmọbinrin naa lọ sileewosan ti wọn ṣe ayẹwo fun un ni wọn fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ibale abẹ ẹ ti sọnu sọwọ Julius to fipa ṣe kinni fun un.DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ọkunrin to fipa baayan sun yii ti wa lẹka to n ri si lilo ọmọde nilokulo, gẹgẹ bi CP Edward Ajogun, kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ yii ṣe paṣẹ"},{"question":"Berikan rumusan ringkas tentang TV2 di Malaysia.","answer":"TV2 (televisyen ini dikenali sebagai Rangkaian Kedua) (secara rasmi ditanda panggil sebagai Rangkaian Kedua) ialah saluran televisyen terestrial tertua di Malaysia. Saluran itu secara rasminya memulakan siaran pada 17 November 1969 jam 9:00 malam dengan bersiaran 1 jam dan 47 minit sehari bermula dari jam 9:00 malam sehingga 10:47 malam sebagai Rangkaian Kedua. TV2 utamanya ialah di Wisma TV, Angkasapuri, Kuala Lumpur. Kecuali set studio untuk siaran berita TV2 kini bersiaran dari Wisma Berita RTM, Angkasapuri, Kuala Lumpur. TV2 ialah stesen TV kedua dan kedua tertua di Malaysia. "},{"question":"What is a polarimeter?","answer":"An instrument to determine optical rotation."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഭാഗം വായിച്ച് ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ഭാഗം: ഇന്ത്യയിലെ ആഗ്രയിൽ സ്ഥിതി ചെയ്യുന്ന ലോകപ്രശസ്ത ശവകുടീരമാണ് താജ്മഹൽ. പതിനേഴാം നൂറ്റാണ്ടിൽ മുഗൾ ചക്രവർത്തിയായ ഷാജഹാൻ പണികഴിപ്പിച്ച ഇത് അദ്ദേഹത്തിന്റെ ഭാര്യ മുംതാസ് മഹലിന് സമർപ്പിച്ചതാണ്. പേർഷ്യൻ, ഇസ്ലാമിക്, ഇന്ത്യൻ സ്വാധീനങ്ങൾ സമന്വയിപ്പിച്ച് മുഗൾ വാസ്തുവിദ്യയുടെ ഏറ്റവും മികച്ച ഉദാഹരണങ്ങളിലൊന്നാണ് താജ്മഹൽ. അതിമനോഹരമായ വെളുത്ത മാർബിൾ മുഖവും സങ്കീർണ്ണമായ കൊത്തുപണികളും മനോഹരമായ പൂന്തോട്ടങ്ങളും ഇതിനെ യുനെസ്കോയുടെ ലോക പൈതൃക സ്ഥലവും സ്നേഹത്തിന്റെയും ഭക്തിയുടെയും പ്രതീകമാക്കുന്നു. അതിമനോഹരമായ സൗന്ദര്യത്തെ അഭിനന്ദിക്കാനും ചരിത്രപരമായ പ്രാധാന്യത്തെക്കുറിച്ച് അറിയാനും വരുന്ന ദശലക്ഷക്കണക്കിന് സന്ദർശകരെ ഇത് ആകർഷിക്കുന്നു.ചോദ്യം: ഈ ഭാഗം എന്തിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഈ ഭാഗം ഇന്ത്യയിലെ ആഗ്രയിലെ താജ്മഹലിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്. ഷാജഹാൻ ചക്രവർത്തി തന്റെ ഭാര്യയോടുള്ള ആദരസൂചകമായി ഇതിന്റെ നിർമ്മാണം നടത്തി. ഇത് യുനെസ്കോയുടെ ലോക പൈതൃക സൈറ്റായി കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്നു. താജ്മഹൽ സ്നേഹത്തിന്റെയും ഭക്തിയുടെയും പ്രതിനിധാനമാണ്. മുകളിലുള്ള ഖണ്ഡിക ഈ കാര്യങ്ങളെക്കുറിച്ചെല്ലാം സംസാരിക്കുന്നു. "},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Muddada Uu Uurka Ku Sido Nibiriga Ilmihiisa?","answer":"Jawaab: Nibiriga Wuxu Ilmihiisa Caloosha Ku Sidaa 365 Maalmood (Hal Sano)."},{"question":"Qui est l'auteur de \\"la Critique de la raison pure\\" ?","answer":"\\"La Critique de la raison pure\\"  a été écrit par Emmanuel Kant en 1781."},{"question":"வினா: சூரிய ஒளி பூமியை வந்தடைய எடுத்துக்கொள்ளும் நேரம்?","answer":"விடை: 8 நிமிடங்கள்"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਕਿਵ ਸਚਿਆਰਾ ਹੋਈਐ ਕਿਵ ਕੂੜੈ ਤੁਟੈ ਪਾਲਿ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 1 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦਾ ਪਰਕਾਸ਼ ਹੋਣ ਲਈ ਯੋਗ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਬਣ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ (ਅਤੇ ਸਾਡੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਦਾ) ਕੂੜ ਦਾ ਪਰਦਾ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਟੁੱਟ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ?\\""},{"question":"中国的国鸟是什么？","answer":"中国的国鸟是丹顶鹤。"},{"question":"لدينا السؤال التالي: ما هي البحيرة التي تتدفق منها تيار التغذية الرئيسي لبحيرة كايوتا ؟. أجب عليه بإستخدام النص التالي: ترتبط البحيرة بنهر سسكويهانا عن طريق كايوتا كريك، الذي يتدفق من الطرف الجنوبي للبحيرة. تيار التغذية الرئيسي لبحيرة كايوتا هو خليج بحيرة كايوتا وهو الذي يدخل البحيرة من خلال منطقة المستنقعات من الطرف الشمالي ويقع جزء كبير من هذا الشاطئ الشمالي للبحيرة بداخل محمية تسمى محمية ألين..","answer":"لقد قمت بقراءة النص. الإجابة هي كايوتا كريك."},{"question":"مضمون جو خلاصو:  هڪ ماءُ پنهنجي خوفناڪ ڌيءَ کي هڪ هيڊ لاڪ ۾ جهليندي ڏسي رهي آهي جڏهن ته ننڍڙي ڇوڪريءَ جي ڪنن کي سوراخ ڪيو پيو وڃي. شڪاگو، ايليينوس ۾ ٺهيل فوٽيج ۾، ننڍڙو ٻار خوف کان روئيندي نظر اچي ٿو جڏهن هڪ مرد هڪ سوراخ ڪندڙ اوزار سان ويجهو اچي ٿو. هڪ نقطي تي ، ڇوڪري کي رڙ ڪندي ٻڌو وڃي ٿو 'مهرباني ڪري نه ، مهرباني ڪري نه ڪريو' جئين هوءَ ڪرسي ۾ ويهي رهي ٿي جڏهن ته هڪ مرد ڪئميرا کان پري خوفزده نوجوان تي الزام لڳائي ٿو ته 'هڪ نن babyڙي ٻار وانگر ڪم ڪري رهيو آهي'. فوٽيج ۾ ٻار کي روئيندي ڏيکاريو ويو آهي جڏهن ته هڪ مرد (کاٻي پاسي) ڪن ۾ سوراخ ڪرڻ واري اوزار سان اچي ٿو. ٿوري دير کان پوءِ ڊڄي ويل ڇوڪريءَ کي سندس ماءُ (ساڄي پاسي) جي هٿان سر تي بند ڪيو ويو. آخرڪار، هڪ عورت جنهن کي سندس ماءُ سمجهيو ويندو آهي، روئڻ واري ڇوڪريءَ کي هن عمل جي دوران قيد ۾ رکي ٿي. موبائل فون تي ٺهيل فلم سوشل ميڊيا جي ويب سائيٽن تي ڪاوڙ جو سبب بڻيو آهي ۽ ڪجهه ماڻهن ماءُ تي الزام هنيو آهي ته هوءَ حد کان وڌي وئي آهي. هڪ يوٽيوب صارف، والري جونز لکيو: 'هي خوفناڪ آهي - ڪنهن ٻار جي التجا ڪيئن ٻڌي ۽ ان کي نظرانداز ڪري سگهي ٿو؟' هڪ ٻي، شيلي ڪيري فوٽ، چيو: 'ڏسو ته اهو غريب ٻار پنهنجي اکين سان ان مرد کي التجا ڪري رهيو آهي. ڪهڙي بي عزتي آهي. ۽ ويڊيو ڏسڻ کان پوءِ ، ايڊرين ڊوائيٽ لکيو: 'مان يقين نه ٿو ڪري سگهان جيڪو مون صرف ڏٺو آهي.' ڇوڪريءَ کي رڙ ڪندي ٻڌو وڃي ٿو 'مهرباني ڪري نه ڪريو، مهرباني ڪري نه ڪريو' جيئن هوءَ ڪرسيءَ ۾ ويهي رهي ۽ هٿن کي مٿي رکڻ جي ڪوشش ڪري ٿي ته جيئن سوراخ ٿيڻ کان روڪي سگهجي. ويڊيو جي شروعات هڪ ڇوڪريءَ سان ڪرسيءَ تي ويٺي آهي جنهن سان هڪ مرد سندس ڪن کي سوراخ ڪرڻ جي تياري ڪري رهيو آهي. پر هوءَ بار بار پنهنجا هٿ مٿي ڪندي رهي ٿي ۽ چوڌاري بيٺل بالغن کان التجا ڪندي رهي ٿي ته اهو نه ٿيڻ ڏيو ۽ روئيندي رهي ٿي: \\"پر اهو ڏک ٿيندو\\". هڪ نقطي تي ، ماءُ چوي ٿي ته هوءَ پنجن تائين ڳڻڻ واري آهي نوجوان کي حڪم ڏيڻ لاءِ ته 'خاموش ٿي وڃو' ، 'مضبوطيءَ سان پڪڙڻ' ۽ ڇوڪري کي مزاحمت ڪرڻ کان روڪڻ جو حڪم ڏيڻ. پر هيستري وارو ٻار بار بار رڙ ڪري ٿو 'مهرباني ڪري نه ڪريو، مهرباني ڪري نه ڪريو' ۽ بي قابو ٿي روئي ٿو جيئن هن جي ماءُ هن کي پائن ڪري ٿي. ويڊيو ۾ نينگر کي پوئتي هٽندي ڏيکاريو ويو آهي (کاٻي پاسي) جڏهن هڪ مرد هن جي ڪن کي سوراخ ڪرڻ جي ڪوشش ڪري ٿو ان کان اڳ هن جي ماءُ هن جو سر هيٺ رکي ٿي (سا ساڄي پاسي) نوجوان کي 'سڪون' ۽ 'مضبوطي سان' رکڻ لاءِ چئي ٿي ان کان پوءِ ، ماءُ ٿي سگهي ٿي.","answer":"فوٽيج ۾ ڏيکاريل آهي ته هڪ شخص شڪاگو، ايليينوس ۾ هڪ نوجوان ڇوڪريءَ جي ڪن کي سوراخ ڪرڻ جي تياري ڪري رهيو آهي. ڊڄي ٻار بار بار روئيندو آهي ته جيئن عمل کي روڪي سگهجي. هڪ عورت جنهن کي هن جي ماءُ سمجهيو ويندو آهي ته پوءِ هن جوان کي سر تي رکندي آهي. ڇوڪريءَ کي ٻُڌڻ ۾ اچي ٿو ته هوءَ رڙ ڪري ٿي \\" مهرباني ڪري نه ڪر \\" کان اڳ ئي سندس ڪن ۾ سوراخ ٿي ويو آهي. ويڊيو ڪجهه ماڻهن جي برانڊنگ سان ناراضگي پيدا ڪئي آهي جيڪي ملوث آهن 'هڪ شرم'"},{"question":"একটি বাগান সম্পর্কে একটি সংক্ষিপ্ত বিবরণ লিখুন","answer":"একটি বাগান হল একটি বারান্দায় বা বাড়ির সামনে একটি উত্সর্গীকৃত স্থান যা গাছপালা চাষের জন্য উত্সর্গীকৃত। বাগানে চারা, ফুল ও ভেষজ গাছ রয়েছে। বাগানগুলি নিয়মিতভাবে পাতা ছাঁটাই করে, সমৃদ্ধ উদ্ভিদ বৃদ্ধির জন্য কম্পোস্ট তৈরি করে। শীতকালে, বাগানগুলি ফুলে ফুলে পরিপূর্ণ, একটি খুব সুন্দর দৃশ্য তৈরি করে। উদ্যানগুলি শহরের কংক্রিটের জঙ্গলের মধ্যে তাজা বাতাসের ছোট নিঃশ্বাস।"},{"question":"O que envolve a 'Sentença de Procedência'?","answer":"A 'Sentença de Procedência' é uma decisão final do juiz que julga a ação procedente, ou seja, favorável ao autor da ação."},{"question":"올림픽의 성화는 어디에서 시작되나요? 이유까지도 알려주세요ㅎㅎ","answer":"성화 봉송은 그리스의 올림피아에서 태양열로 점화하여 시작합니다. 그리스 올림피아에서 시작하는 이유는 고대 올림픽 개최지이기 때문입니다. 그리고 불이 꺼지지 않은 채로 올림픽 개최지까지 릴레이로 성화가 전달됩니다."},{"question":"வினா : இந்தியாவில் வடகிழக்கில் அமைந்துள்ள மலைத்தொடரின் பெயர்?","answer":" விடை :  இந்தியாவில் வடகிழக்கில் அமைந்துள்ள மலைத்தொடரின் பெயர் பூர்வாஞ்சல் ஆகும்.பூர்வாஞ்சல்வட இந்தியாவின் கிழக்கு உத்திரப் பிரதேச மாநிலத்தின் நிலவியல் அமைப்பை குறிப்பதாகும். பூர்வாஞ்சல் பகுதியில் அதிகம் பேசப்படும் மொழிகள் இந்தி, போஜ்புரி, உருது மற்றும் அவதி ஆகும்.எல்லைகள்: பூர்வாஞ்சலின் வடக்கில் நேபாளம், கிழக்கில் பிகார், தெற்கில் மத்தியப் பிரதேசம் மற்றும் மேற்கில் உத்திரப் பிரதேசத்தின் அவத் பிராந்தியம் மற்றும் கீழ் தோவாப் பிராந்தியங்கள் எல்லைகளாகக் கொண்டது.பூர்வாஞ்சல் பகுதியில் போஜ்புரி, அவதி மொழி, இந்தி, மற்றும் உருது மொழிகள் பேசப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"Orin ti Áfríkà","answer":"Fun titobi ti Orílẹ̀ Afirika, orin rẹ yatọ, pẹlu awọn agbegbe ati awọn orilẹ-ede ti o ni ọpọlọpọ awọn aṣa orin ọtọtọ. Orin Áfíríkà ni oríṣi bí amapiano, Jùjú, Fuji, Afrobeat, Highlife, Makossa, Kizomba, àti àwọn mìíràn. Orin Áfíríkà tún máa ń lo oríṣiríṣi ohun èlò jákèjádò àgbáyé. Orin ati ijó ti awọn ilu Afirika, ti a ṣẹda si awọn ipele tí o yatọ lori awọn aṣa orin orin Afirika, pẹlu orin Amẹrika bi Dixieland jazz, blues, jazz, ati ọpọlọpọ awọn oriṣi Caribbean, gẹgẹbi calypso ati soca . Awọn oriṣi orin Latin Amẹ́ríkà bi cumbia, orin salsa, rumba, conga, bomba, samba ati zouk ni a sẹ̀dá nípa se orin ti awọn ọmọ Afirika tí wọ́n kó lẹ́rú, ti o si ti ni ipa lori orin ti o gbajumo ni Afirika lóde òní .Bii orin ti Esia, India ati Aarin Ila-oorun, o jẹ orin alarinrin. Awọn ilana rhythmic ti o nipọn nigbagbogbo pẹlu ohun orin kan ti a ṣe lodi si omiiran lati ṣẹda orin miran latii ara rẹ.\\"Irisi iyatọ miiran ti orin Afirika ni ẹda ipe-ati-idahun rẹ: ohun kan tabi ohun elo kan ṣe gbolohun ọrọ aladun kukuru kan, ati pe gbolohun naa jẹ atunwi nipasẹ ohun tabi ohun elo miiran. Ipe-ati-idahun iseda gbooro si awọn ilu, ibi ti ọkan ilu yoo mu ohùn, ti ilù miiran yio dun kanna bi ti ilu alaákọ̀kọ́. Orin Afirika tun jẹ imudara gaan.Orin ibile ni pupọ julọ ní orílẹ̀ naa ni wọ́n n n kọ́ nílànà ọrọ̀ sísọ tí kò sì ni àkọ́sílẹ̀ lati iran kan si òmínràn. Orin ṣe pataki si ẹsin ni Afirika, nibiti awọn aṣa ati awọn ayẹyẹ ẹsin má nlo orin lati sọ itan lati irandiran ati lati kọrin ati ijó si. Ni afikun, orin ṣe pataki si àṣà ni apapọ, kii ṣe gẹgẹ bi ọna ti ẹsin ati ikosile ti ara ẹni nikan, ṣugbọn gẹgẹbi ọna ibaraẹnisọrọ lati sọ nipa awọn eniyan pataki, iṣelu, o nti o n sẹlẹ̀ nilu, awọn iwa àti ìtọ́nisọ́nà.Ọpọlọpọ awọn aṣa miiran ti ṣe iwadi orin Afirika, nitorinaa ipa pupọ ti o ti ni lori awọn àṣà miiran. Fun apẹẹrẹ, ni Oṣu kejila ọdun 2002, Ẹgbẹ Swiss fun Ethnomusicology ṣe awọn apejọ ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ni igbiyanju lati ṣe iwadi orin Ghana . Awọn onimọ-jinlẹ wọnyi ti wọ́n n kopa ninu iwadii wo lati kọ ẹkọ awọn ẹya itan nipasẹ orin, pẹlu awọn aṣa. Ni afikun, diẹ ninu awọn onímọ̀-jinle bi John Collins se iwadi diẹ sii kan nipa orin awon ara Ghana, iru orin yi ni àwọn ami Kristiẹniti ti gbajumo ninu orin àwọn ara orílẹ̀-èdè Ghana.Orin Afirika ni ibatan ti o jinlẹ pẹlu agbegbe. Orin Afirika ni a ṣe fun igbadun gbogbo eniyan ati ikopa ti gbogbo eniyan; eyiti o jẹ ki orin Afirika wa labẹ ẹka ti Orin Agbègbè, nibiti o si ti jẹ́ iwuri fun àwọn ara agbegbe naa lati kópa.Arìwá Afirika ati Iwọ̀ AfirikaAriwa Afirika jẹ ijoko ti Egipti atijọ ati Carthage, ọlaju pẹlu awọn asopọ to lagbara si Ila-oorun Itosi atijọ ati eyiti o ni ipa lori awọn aṣa Greek ati awọn aṣa Romu atijọ. Níkẹyìn, Íjíbítì wa lábẹ́ ìṣàkóso Páṣíà tí Gíríìkì àti ti Róòmù tẹ̀ lé e, nígbà tí Carthage ti wá jọba lẹ́yìn náà nípasẹ̀ àwọn ará Róòmù àti Vandals . Awọn Larubawa padà ṣẹgun Ariwa Afirika, ti wọ́n sì ṣẹda agbegbe naa gẹgẹbi Maghreb ti agbaye Arab.Awọn ilu ti a lo ninu orin ibile Afirika pẹlu ni ilu gángan, bougarabou ati djembe ni Iwọ-oorun Afirika, awọn ilu omi ni Central ati West Africa, ati awọn oriṣiriṣi awọn ilu ngoma ni àrin-gbòngbò ati Gusu Afirika . Awọn ohun elo orin miiran pẹlu ọpọlọpọ ni awọn gbigbọn, bi kosika (kashaka), ọpá ojo, agogo ati awọn igi . Ni, Afirika ni ọpọlọpọ awọn iru ilu miiran, ati ọpọlọpọ awọn fèrè ati okun ati awọn ohun elo afẹfẹ.Ọpọlọpọ awọn ede ti a sọ ni Afirika jẹ awọn ede ohún, ti o yori si asopọ ti o sunmọ laarin orin ati ede ni diẹ ninu awọn aṣa agbegbe. Awọn agbegbe ni pato ma nlo awọn ohun ati awọn agbeka pẹlu orin wọn pẹlu. Ninu orin kikọ, apẹrẹ ohùn tabi ọrọ nfi idiwọ si awọn ilana aladun. Ní ònà kejì ẹ̀wẹ̀, nínú orin ohun èlò ìkọrin, olùbánisọ̀rọ̀ ìbílẹ̀ ti èdè lè sábà máa ń róye ọ̀rọ̀ tàbí ọ̀rọ̀ inú orin náà. Ipa yii tun jẹ ipilẹ ti awọn èdè ìlù (awọn ilu ti n sọrọ).Ni itan-akọọlẹ, ọpọlọpọ awọn nnkan ni ipa lori orin ibile ti Afirika . Nipasẹ ede, agbegbe, ọpọlọpọ awọn aṣa, iṣelu, ati igbiyanju olugbe, gbogbo eyiti o wa ni idapo. Ẹgbẹ kọọkan ti Afirika wa ni agbegbe ti o yatọ ti òrílẹ̀ naa, eyiti o tumọ si pe wọn n jẹ awọn ounjẹ oriṣiriṣi, wọ́n dojuko awọn oju ojo oriṣiriṣi, ti wọn si se alabapade awọn ẹgbẹ oriṣiriṣi ju awọn awujọ miiran lọ.Ẹgbẹ kọọkan gbe ni awọn oṣuwọn oriṣiriṣi, si awọn ààyè oriṣiriṣi ju awọn miiran lọ, ati nitorinaa kọọkan nipasẹ awọn eniyan ati awọn ìsẹ̀lẹ̀ oriṣiriṣi.Ní àfikún, kogbondandan ki awujọ kọọkan ṣiṣẹ labẹ ijọba kanna, eyiti o tun ni ipa ni pataki awọn aṣa orin wọn.Orin ti o gbajumọ ni Afirika, bii orin ibile Afirika, pọ̀ jọjọ ti o si jẹ orísirísi. Ọpọlọpọ awọn oriṣi ti orin olokiki, bí blues, jazz ati rumba, wa ni awọn iwọn oriṣiriṣi lati awọn aṣa orin lati Afirika, ti a mu lọ si Amẹrika nipasẹ awọn ọmọ Afirika ti o jẹ ẹrú. Awọn ohun ti ni imudara lẹhinna nipasẹ awọn iru orin tuntun bii orin ẹmi, ati ilu ati blues .Ni Iwo-oorun Afirika, Fela Kuti ati Tony Allen ṣe orin Afrobeat. Femi Kuti ati Seun Kuti tẹle baba wọn Fẹla Kuti . Ọkan ninu awọn akọrin ọdun 20 ti o ṣe pataki julọ ti orin olokiki South Africa ni Miriam Makeba, ti o ko ipa pataki kan, ni awọn ọdun 60. Zenzile Miriam Makeba ni itàn sọ pe o jẹ ọkan ninu awọn olokiki julọ ati olokiki akọrin ni Afirika, nibẹrẹ awọn ọdun 1950. O jẹ apakan ti awọn ẹgbẹ mẹta, pẹlu ẹgbẹ gbogbo obinrin kan ati awọn meji miiran. Ó ṣe oríṣiríṣi orin jazz, orin ìbílẹ̀ Áfíríkà, àti orin tó gbajúmọ̀ ní Ìwọ̀ Oòrùn Áfíríkà nígbà yẹn. Miriamu ṣe pupọ ninu awọn orin rẹ ni irisi “ mbube ”, eyiti o jẹ “ara ti isokan ohun ti o fa lori jazz Amẹrika, ragtime, ati awọn orin orin-ijọ Anglican, ati awọn aṣa orin abinibi.” Lẹhin ti o lọ si AMẸRIKA, awọn iṣoro pẹlu iwe irinna Makeba waye ti o si mu duro si Amẹrika, wọn sọ pe o fi afikun ohun Amẹrika si pupọ julọ awọn orin Afirika rẹ."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: പസഫിക് സമുദ്രം ആഗോള കാലാവസ്ഥയെ എങ്ങനെ സ്വാധീനിക്കുന്നു?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ആഗോള കാലാവസ്ഥ രൂപപ്പെടുത്തുന്നതിൽ പസഫിക് സമുദ്രം നിർണായക പങ്ക് വഹിക്കുന്നു. നോർത്ത് പസഫിക് കറന്റ്, കാലിഫോർണിയ കറന്റ് തുടങ്ങിയ പസഫിക് സമുദ്രത്തിലെ പ്രവാഹങ്ങൾ കാലാവസ്ഥാ സംവിധാനങ്ങളെയും സമുദ്ര താപനിലയെയും സ്വാധീനിക്കുന്നു, ഇത് എൽ നിനോ, ലാ നിന തുടങ്ങിയ പ്രതിഭാസങ്ങൾ ഉൾപ്പെടെയുള്ള ആഗോള കാലാവസ്ഥയെ സ്വാധീനിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"¿Durante qué años estuvo Charles Darwin en Chile?","answer":"El renombrado científico británico marcó su huella en nuestro país entre 1832 y 1835, cuando recorrió el territorio nacional desde Tierra del Fuego a Copiapó, realizando observaciones geológicas, botánicas, zoológicas y antropológicas."},{"question":" Sheeg Magacii Hore Ee Loo-Yaqaana Sacuudiga Boqortooyada Kahor","answer":"Jawab , Waxaa Loo-Yaqaanay Xijaas."},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து வேர்க்கடலை சுண்டல் செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:1 கப் வேர்க்கடலை அரை உப்பு போட்டு வேகவைத்தது1/4 டீஸ்பூன் மஞ்சள் தூள்தேவைகேற்ப உப்பு2 டீஸ்பூன் தேங்காய் துருவல்","answer":"செய்முறை:1. போடி செய்ய குடுத்த பொருட்கள் அனைத்தையும் வறுத்து பொடி செய்து கொள்ளவும்.2. கடாயில் எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி காய்ந்ததும் கடுகு, காய்ந்த மிளகாய், கரிவேபில்லை போட்டு தாளிக்கவும்.3. பிறகு, அதில் வேகவைத்த வேர்க்கடலை, மஞ்சள் தூள், உப்பு, தேங்காய் துருவல் சேர்த்து மூன்று நிமிடம் கிளறவும்.4. பின், பொடி சேர்த்து நன்கு கிளறவும்5. வெர்கடலை சுந்தலை பரிமாறும் கிண்ணத்திற்கு மாற்றி பரிமாறவும்."},{"question":"Zer da arkeologian fosila, eta nola ulertzen du izaki bizidunen aztarna antzinakoak?","answer":"Fosila da izaki bizidunen aztarna antzinako bat, lurpean gordetzen dena. Fosilak ulertzen ditu izaki bizidunen eboluzioa eta historia geologikoa."},{"question":"كم تبلغ مساحة سلطنة عمان ؟","answer":"220 ألف كم مربع"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheg Meeshay Eheed Meeshii Ay Aayada Quraanka Ugu Horeesay Ku Soo Degtay?","answer":"Jawaab: Meeshii Ugu Horeesay Ay Aayada Quraanka Ku Soo Degto Waxay Eheed Xiraa."},{"question":"Zein da Euskadiko hiriburua? A) Bilbo B) Donostia C) Gasteiz D) Iruñea","answer":"C) Gasteiz"},{"question":"من القائل:وهيفاء تحكي الرمح لونا وقامة * لها مهجتي مبذولة وفؤادي؟","answer":"البهاء زهير "},{"question":"السؤال: ما هى السورة التى يبلغ عدد آياتها ١١ آية فقط؟","answer":"الإجابة: سورة الجمعة."},{"question":"வினா: கார் மின்கலன்கள் மற்றும் பல சேர்மங்களைத் தயாரிப்பதில் பயன்படுவது?","answer":"விடை: கந்தக அமிலம்"},{"question":"નીચેના રૂઢિપ્રયોગ નો અર્થ આપો:પરસેવો પાડવો ","answer":"ખૂબ મહેનત કરવી "},{"question":"17 වැනි සියවසේදී ගාල්ල පුළුල් ලෙස ශක්තිමත් කළේ කුමන යුරෝපීය යටත් විජිත බලයද?","answer":"1649 සිට ආරම්භ වූ 17 වන සියවසේදී ලන්දේසීන් විසින් නගරය පුළුල් ලෙස ශක්තිමත් කරන ලදී."},{"question":"Quốc hoa Campuchia có màu đặc trưng là gì?","answer":"Rumdul, loài hoa có màu vàng đặc trưng, là quốc hoa của Campuchia.Năm 2005, Rumdul chính thức trở thành quốc hoa của Campuchia và là biểu tượng bảo vệ môi trường của chính phủ. Loài hoa này phổ biến tại Campuchia, tượng trưng cho bản chất lương thiện, tích cực của người dân.Cây Rumdul có thể cao từ 8 đến 12 m, đường kính thân 20-30 cm, lá đơn mọc so le. Mùi thơm của hoa rumdul có thể ngửi thấy từ xa, nên có thể tạo sáp thơm. Trong y học cổ truyền, hoa rumdul được dùng để chữa chóng mặt, có ích cho tim mạch, huyết áp."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bulan madu'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud pergi ke sesuatu tempat untuk berhibur sesudah berkahwin. Contoh ayat: Pengantin baru itu bercadang untuk berbulan madu di Langkawi."},{"question":"請完成以下句子:  1941年12月，同為軸心國的大日本帝國為了能夠在亞洲及太平洋地區獲得領導地位，陸續襲擊位在太平洋的美國統轄地區和座落於與中南半島的泰國亦被逼加入日本一方，很快地於西太平洋和東亞戰區獲得了主導權。1942年時日本開始在一系列的海戰中戰敗，位於歐洲的軸心國也陸續於北非戰役以及史達林格勒戰役中節節敗退，這些都迫使軸心國停下進攻的腳步。1943年時法西斯義大利在","answer":"西西里島戰役中面對同盟國部隊嚴重失利，另一方面德軍在庫斯克會戰戰敗後失去對東歐的領導地位，同時美軍也在太平洋戰區中獲得了一連串的勝利，1943年9月義大利投降，自此軸心國集團逐漸失去主導權並開始嘗試將佈署於各地的前線部隊進行戰略性的撤退。"},{"question":"नेवार सभ्यताले छिमेकी सभ्यताहरूसँगको अन्तरक्रियालाई कसरी नेभिगेट गर्यो र काठमाडौं उपत्यकामा कस्तो सांस्कृतिक आदानप्रदान भयो?","answer":"नेवार सभ्यता तिब्बत, भारत र चीन लगायतका छिमेकी सभ्यताहरूसँग व्यापक सांस्कृतिक आदानप्रदानमा संलग्न छ। यी अन्तरक्रियाहरूले कला, धर्म र व्यापारलाई प्रभाव पारे, जसले काठमाडौं उपत्यकाको विश्वव्यापी प्रकृतिमा योगदान पुर्‍यायो।"},{"question":"Дүйнөдөгү эң жаш банкнот кайсы?","answer":"Банкноттордун эң жашы бул - Евро. Ал 2002-жылдан бери Европа Борбордук Банкы тарабынан басылып колдонууга берилип келет. Ал \\"Евроаймакка\\" кирген, 19 өлкөнүн расмий жана 9 өлкөнүн улуттук акчасы катары колдонулат."},{"question":"Nei uchifanira kuva akatendeseka?","answer":"Nekuti haufanirwe kubiridzira chero munhu uye izvo zvinokupa hupenyu hwakanaka"},{"question":"What are the primary functions of the roots of a plant?","answer":"The roots of a plant have several primary functions:Anchorage: Roots anchor the plant to the ground, providing stability and support.Absorption: Roots absorb water and minerals from the soil, which are essential for the plant’s growth and development.Storage: Some roots, such as those of carrots and beets, also serve as storage organs for nutrients and energy reserves.Transport: Roots transport absorbed water and minerals to other parts of the plant through the vascular system.Hormone Production: Roots often produce hormones, such as auxins, which play a role in plant growth and development."},{"question":"问题：如何选择适合自己的护手霜？","answer":"回答：选择护手霜时可以根据自己的肤质和需求，选择保湿、修护、抗老化等功能的产品。"},{"question":"Inona no fivavahana ahitana mpino betsaka indrindra eto Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny Kristianisma no fivavahana ahitana mpino betsaka indrindra eto Madagasikara."},{"question":"Doc to summarize: ਮਾਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਬੁੱਧਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਕੈਪਟਨ ਅਮਰਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਵਿਧਾਨ ਸਭਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਤੋਂ ਹੋਈ।ਕੈਪਟਨ ਅਮਰਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, 'ਸ਼ਹੀਦ ਹੋ ਜਾਵਾਂਗੇ ਪਰ ਪਾਣੀ ਸੂਬੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਣ ਦਿਆਂਗੇ।'ਪੰਜਾਬ ਵਿਧਾਨ ਸਭਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਾਜਪਾਲ ਦੇ ਭਾਸ਼ਣ 'ਤੇ ਧੰਨਵਾਦ ਮਤੇ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਕੋਲ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਸੂਬੇ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਣ ਲਈ ਪਾਣੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ। ਕਾਰਨ ਕਿ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਦਰਿਆਵਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾਣੀ ਘੱਟ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਉਹ 17.1 ਮਿਲੀਅਨ ਏਕੜ ਫੀਟ (M.A.F.) ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਕੇ 13.1 ਮਿਲੀਅਨ ਏਕੜ ਫੀਟ ਰਹਿ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਇਸੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਨੂੰ ਪਾਣੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇ ਸਕਦਾ।ਇਸ 'ਤੇ ਪਲਟਵਾਰ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਮਨੋਹਰ ਲਾਲ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ, 'ਕਿਸੇ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਹੀਦ ਹੋਣ ਦਾ ਤਾਂ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਰ ਐੱਸਵਾਈਐੱਲ ਦੇ ਪਾਣੀ ਉੱਤੇ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਦਾ ਹੱਕ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਰੋਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੇ।'ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਹੁਣ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਨੇ ਕਰਨਾ ਹੈ। ਉਸ 'ਤੇ ਹੀ ਸਭ ਦੀਆਂ ਨਜ਼ਰਾਂ ਹਨ। ਪਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਦੇ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਸਾਥ ਮਿਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਸਾਬਕਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਭੁਪਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਹੁੱਡਾ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਅਸੀਂ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਤੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਭੀਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਮੰਗ ਰਹੇ ਬਲਕਿ ਆਪਣਾ ਹੱਕ ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।ਕੀ ਹੈ ਸਤਲੁਜ ਯਮੁਨਾ ਲਿੰਕ ਨਹਿਰ : ਸਤਲੁਜ ਯਮੁਨਾ ਲਿੰਕ ਨਹਿਰ ਭਾਖੜਾ ਡੈਮ ਦਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਦੀ ਯਮੁਨਾ ਨਦੀ ਤੱਕ ਪਹੁੰਚਣ ਲਈ ਬਣਾਈ ਗਈ ਸੀ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਨਹਿਰ ਪੂਰੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਇਹ ਸਿਆਸਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਲਝੀ ਗਈ। ਇਸ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਨਹਿਰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਪਾਣੀ ਲਈ ਪਿਆਸੀ ਹੋ ਗਈ।ਸਤਲੁਜ ਯਮੁਨਾ ਨਹਿਰ ਦੀ ਕੁੱਲ ਲੰਬਾਈ 214 ਕਿੱਲੋਮੀਟਰ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ 122 ਕਿੱਲੋਮੀਟਰ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਨੇ ਕਰਨਾ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ 92 ਕਿੱਲੋਮੀਟਰ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਨੇ ਕਰਨਾ ਸੀ। ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿੱਸੇ ਦੀ ਨਹਿਰ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕਰ ਚੁੱਕਾ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂ ਕਿ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਅਧੂਰੀ ਹੈ।ਸਤਲੁਜ ਤੇ ਯਮੁਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਜੋੜਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਇਹ ਨਹਿਰ ਜਦੋਂ ਦੀ ਬਣਨੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਤੋਂ ਹੀ ਵਿਵਾਦਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹੀ ਹੈਪੰਜਾਬ ਦਾ ਰੁੱਖ।ਐੱਸਵਾਈਐੱਲ ਦੀ ਉਸਾਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਡਾ ਝਟਕਾ 14 ਮਾਰਚ 2016 ਨੂੰ ਲੱਗਿਆ। ਤਤਕਾਲੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਪਰਕਾਸ਼ ਸਿੰਘ ਬਾਦਲ ਨੇ ਨਹਿਰ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਐਕਵਾਇਰ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਕਿਸਾਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵਾਪਸ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਬਿੱਲ ਪਾਸ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਕਿਸਾਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਤੁਰੰਤ ਹੀ ਨਹਿਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਿੱਟੀ ਭਰ ਕੇ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਉੱਤੇ ਕਬਜ਼ਾ ਵੀ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ। ਨਹਿਰ ਦਾ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ : 1955 ਵਿੱਚ ਰਾਵੀ ਅਤੇ ਬਿਆਸ ਨਦੀ ਵਿਚ 15.85 ਐੱਮ.ਏ.ਐਫ. ਪਾਣੀ ਸੀ। ਕੇਂਦਰ ਨੇ ਰਾਵੀ ਦਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਤਿੰਨਾਂ ਸੂਬਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡ ਦਿੱਤਾ:ਸਤਲੁਜ ਯਮੁਨਾ ਨਹਿਰ ਦਾ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਸਮਝਣ ਦੇ ਲਈ 54 ਸਾਲ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਜਾਣਾ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ। ਇਸ ਨਹਿਰ ਦੀ ਨੀਂਹ 1966 ਰੱਖੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ। ਜਦੋਂ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੀ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਦੇ ਅਧਾਰ 'ਤੇ ਵੰਡ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਅਤੇ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਸਤਲੁਜ ਯਮਨਾ ਲਿੰਕ ਨਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਦੇ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਇੱਕ ਵਾਰ ਫਿਰ ਤੋਂ ਸਿਆਸਤ ਗਰਮਾ ਗਈ ਗਈ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Inona no zava-nitranga ara-tantara nanomboka tamin’ny 28 Jona 1914 tamin’ny namonoana an’i Archduke Franz Ferdinand avy any Aotrisy?","answer":"Ny famonoana an’i Archduke Franz Ferdinand avy any Aotrisy no nanamarika ny fiandohan’ny Ady Lehibe Voalohany."},{"question":"رگسی کباب بنانے کی ترکیب","answer":"انڈوں کو ابال کر لمبائی کے رخ پر درمیان سے کاٹیں اور احتیاط سے زردی نکال لیں۔مٹر اور گاجر کو ابال کر ہلکا سا میش کر لیں اور اس میں نمک،ایک باریک کٹی ہوئی ہری مرچ اور ایک کھانے کا چمچ ہرا دھنیا ملا لیں۔ قیمے میں ایک پیاز،ایک چائے کا چمچ ادرک لہسن،انڈے کی زردیاں،ہری مرچیں اور ہرا دھنیا ملا کر باریک پیس لیں۔ کٹے ہوئے انڈوں کے درمیان میں سبزیوں کا مکسچر بھر کر اچھی طرح دبا کر بند کر دیں،پھر اس پر پسا ہوا قیمہ لپیٹ دیں۔ پین میں تین سے چار کھانے کے چمچ کوکنگ آئل میں پیاز کو سنہری فرائی کریں اور اس میں نمک،ادرک لہسن،لال مرچیں،ہلدی،دھنیا،زیرہ اور دہی ڈال کر اچھی طرح بھونیں۔ جب تیل علیحدہ ہو جائے تو اچھی طرح بھون کر اس میں تیار کئے ہوئے کباب ڈال کر آدھی پیالی پانی ڈال دیں۔ جب کبابوں کی رنگت تبدیل ہو جائے تو اس کو ہلکا سا بھون کر ہرا دھنیا چھڑک کر دم پر رکھ دیں۔ خوبصورت سے پلیٹر میں نکال کر اس کو گرم گرم نان یا چپاتی کے ساتھ شروع کریں۔"},{"question":"Responda à pergunta: o que é o encantamento Capacious Extremis na saga de Harry Potter?","answer":"É um encantamento usado para expandir o interior de um objeto aparentemente pequeno, sem que afete sua aparência exterior."},{"question":"Tilmaamida Hogaamiye/Hogaamiso.","answer":" Tilmaamid Hogaamiye/HogaamisoMarkaad aragtay:  Aqoonta iyo Waaya aragnimadiisaMarkaad Tixgelisay:  Kartida iyo Dadnimada uu leeyahay/ay leedahayMarkaad garwaaqsaday:   Sumcada iyo Xushmada uu Bulshada ku dhex leeyahayWaxaad Xeerisay:1. In aad u garatay Hebel ………. Ama Heblaayo ……… oo Asxaabtaada ka mid ah in uu leeyahay/leedahay sifooyinki Hogaamiyenimo, mustaqbalka dhowna uu noqon karo Madax meel sare gaaraXeerkani waxa uu dhaqangelayaa marka aad halkan ku mention-gareyso (ku xusto) qofkaa Mahadsanidiin."},{"question":"NumPy අරාවකින්  5ට වඩා  වැඩි ඉලක්කම් තෝරන්න.","answer":"import numpy as nparray = np.array([1, 2, 3, 6, 7, 8])selected_elements = array[array > 5]"},{"question":"এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :সৈয়দ হক তার বাবা মারা যাবার পর অর্থকষ্টে পড়লে চলচ্চিত্রের জন্য চিত্রনাট্য লেখা শুরু করেন। ১৯৫৯ খ্রিষ্টাব্দে তিনি মাটির পাহাড় চলচ্চিত্রের চিত্রনাট্য লিখেন। পরে \\"তোমার আমার\\", \\"শীত বিকেল\\", কাঁচ কাটা হীরে, ক খ গ ঘ ঙ, বড় ভাল লোক ছিল, পুরস্কারসহ আরও বেশ কিছু চলচ্চিত্রের কাহিনী, চিত্রনাট্য ও সংলাপ লিখেন। বড় ভাল লোক ছিল ও পুরস্কার নামে দুটি চলচ্চিত্রের জন্য তিনি শ্রেষ্ঠ চিত্রনাট্যকার বিভাগে জাতীয় চলচ্চিত্র পুরস্কার অর্জন করেন। ১৯৭১ খ্রিষ্টাব্দের নভেম্বর মাসে বাংলাদেশ ত্যাগ করে লন্ডন চলে যান এবং সেখানে বিবিসির বাংলা খবর পাঠক হিসেবে চাকুরি গ্রহণ করেন। তিনি ১৯৭১ খ্রিষ্টাব্দের ১৬ ডিসেম্বর","answer":"পাকিস্তান সেনাবাহিনীর আত্মসর্মপণের খবরটি পাঠ করেছিলেন। পরে ১৯৭২ খ্রিষ্টাব্দ থেকে ১৯৭৮ খ্রিষ্টাব্দ পর্যন্ত বিবিসি বাংলার প্রযোজক হিসেবে দায়িত্ব পালন করেন। তার দৃঢ়কণ্ঠ সাবলীল উচ্চারণের জন্য তিনি জনসাধারণ্যে পরিচিতি লাভ করেন।"},{"question":"Oración 1: Nació en New Westminster y trabajó en la popa del río Fraser y el río Fraser antes de llegar al río Yukon superior a principios del siglo XX.Oración 2: Nació en New Westminster y trabajó en los ciclistas estelares del bajo río Fraser y Yukon antes de llegar al río Fraser superior a principios del siglo XX.Pregunta :¿la oración 1 parafrasea la oración 2?. ","answer":"No, la parafrasea. "},{"question":"Ampute etmek ne demek?","answer":"Ampute etmek, tamir edilemeyecek düzeyde hasarlanmış bir UZVU (kol, bacak, el, ayak, parmak...) ameliyat sırasında uzvun kemiği ile beraber keserek vücuttan ayırma işlemidir. "},{"question":"Zer da klima aldaketa, eta nola eragiten du itsas mailaren igoera?","answer":"Klima aldaketa da atmosferaren tenperatura batez bestekoaren aldaketa. Itsas mailaren igoeran, klima aldaketak eragiten du izotzaren urratzea eta itsas uraren dilatazio termikoa, horrek itsas maila igoarazten du."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యంకి ప్రతిపదార్థాలు రాయండి.అనుచున్ జేవుజు మీ జు కన్నుఁగవతో నాస్పందితోష్ణంబుతోఘన హుంకారముతో నటద్భుకుటితో గర్జిల్లు నా భోసలేశునిఁ జూదన్ బుయిలోడెఁ గొల్వు శివుఁడీసున్ గుత్తుకన్ మ్రింగి, బోరన నవ్వారల బంధ మూడ్చి గొని తేరన్ బంచె సోన్ దేవునిన్","answer":"అనుచున్ = శివాజీ అలా హెచ్చరిస్తూ (ఆ విధంగా చెపుతూ)జేవుఱుమీటు = జేగురు రంగును (ఎరుపు రంగును) అతిశయించే (జేగురు రంగు కంటే ఎఱ్ఱగా నున్న)కన్నుఁగవతోన్ = కనుల జంటతోఆస్పందదోష్ఠంబుతోన్; ఆస్పందత్ = కొలదిగా కదులుతున్నఓష్ఠంబుతోన్ = పెదవితోఘనహుంకారముతోన్ = గొప్ప హుంకార ధ్వనితోనటద్ర్భుకుటితోన్; నటత్ = నాట్యము చేయుచున్న (బాగా కదలి ఆడుచున్న)భ్రుకుటీతోన్ = కనుబొమల ముడితోగర్జీల్లు = గర్జిస్తున్నఆ ఫోన్సలేశునిన్ (ఆ ఫోన్సల + ఈశునిన్) = ఆభోంసల వంశ ప్రభువైన శివాజీనిచూడన్ = చూడ్డానికికొల్వు = రాజసభపుయిలోడెన్ = జంకింది (భయపడింది.) (నిశ్చేష్టులయ్యారు)శివుడు = శివాజీఈసున్ = (తన) కోపాన్నికుత్తుకన్ = గొంతుకలోమ్రింగి = అణచుకొనిబోరనన్ = శీఘ్రముగా (ఇది ‘బోరునన్’) అని ఉండాలి.)అవ్వారల = వారి యొక్క (కళ్యాణి సర్దారు యొక్క ఆతని అంతఃపురకాంత యొక్కబంధమూడ్చి (బంధము + ఊడ్చి) – సంకెలలు తొలగించి,కొనితేరన్ = తీసికొనిరావడానికి (సభలోకి తీసుకురావడానికి)సోన్ దేవునిన్ = (తన సైన్యాధిపతియైన, వారిని బంధించి తెచ్చిన) సోన్ దేవుడినిపంచెన్ = ఆజ్ఞాపించెను."},{"question":"Buatlah tiga paragraf cerita pendek berdasarkan judul atau topik yang diberikan, dengan melanjutkan penggalan teks di bawah ini.Judul: Keledai dan Penjual Garam.Alkisah, hiduplah seorang penjual garam yang menggunakan keledai untuk membawa garamnya. Garam diwadahi dalam sebuah ...","answer":"kantong tas, yang kemudian diletakkan di atas punggung si keledai. Banyaknya garam yang dibawa membuat keledai merasa keberatan. Hingga pada suatu ketika keledai membawa banyak garam pada punggungnya dengan cuaca yang panas. Keledai membawa garam dengan melewati sungai, tanpa sengaja, tas garam yang dibawanya jatuh ke sungai, sehingga hampir setengah garam menjadi larut ke air sungai. Kemudian sang keledai mengambil dan meletakkan tas pada punggungnya kembali. Si keledai, kaget merasakan tasnya menjadi sangat ringan.Akhirnya keledai melakukan trik tersebut ketika disuruh oleh si penjual garam. Penjual garam yang mengerti hal tersebut merasa rugi karena garam yang dibawanya menjadi berkurang dalam jumlah yang banyak dan menjadi tersisa sedikit. Karena merasa dirugikan akhirnya penjual garam memainkan trik agar keledai tidak lagi menipunya.Keesokan harinya, penjual garam memasukkan tas katun yang tebal ke dalam kantong yang dibawa oleh keledai. Tanpa merasa curiga, keledai pun berjalan melewati sungai. Saat itu keledai juga melakukan hal yang sama, ia kembali masuk ke dalam air untuk memperingan beban yang ia bawa. Karena di dalam kantongnya berupa tas katun, akhirnya air pun terserap oleh tas katun yang dibawanya. Bukannya bertambah ringan, beban yang dibawa oleh keledai malah bertambah berat, dan keledai merasa sangat lelah. Akhirnya untuk hari berikutnya karena takut menjadi berat, akhirnya keledai tidak pernah memainkan trik yang sama. Penjual garam pun menjadi senang karena ia tidak lagi mengalami kerugian garam."},{"question":"Ireto misy fanambarana :“Matory eo ambony fandriana ilay saka.” sy \\"Ny seza dia fandriana ho an'ny saka.\\"Mifanindran-teny ve ireo ?","answer":"Eny,  samy mamaritra ny toerana atorizan'ny saka."},{"question":"Dime a qué categoría corresponde la siguiente pregunta: ¿Cuántos paquetes de expansión tiene The Sims 4?","answer":"La categoría es videojuegos. "},{"question":"Atsakykite į šį sudėtingą klausimą: Kokią kampaniją vykdo ir \\"Tiesa moksle\\", ir \\"Rasti atradimai\\"?","answer":"\\"Teach the controversy\\" kampanija"},{"question":"Inona ny anaran'ilay boky James Bond voalohany ? ","answer":"Ny anaran'ilay boky James Bond voalohany dia Casino Royal."},{"question":" A wani Hadisi Manzon Allah Sallallahu Alaihi Wa Sallama Ya yi bayanii girman kai. Ya ce: Girman kai shine: ","answer":"(a) Rowa da jiji da kai (b) Watsi da gaskiya da kuma raina mutane (c) Takama da alfahari"},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de pregunta de trivia en esta categoría: deportes. ","answer":"¿En qué año se retiró el jugador de fútbol americano Franco Harris? Respuesta: en el año 1984."},{"question":"I am traveling to Thailand next week. What are the some things that I should do in Bangkok? ","answer":"That sounds like an exciting trip! Bangkok, the capital of Thailand, is a vibrant and bustling city with a rich cultural heritage. There are numerous things to do and see in Bangkok. Here are some must-visit places and activities to consider during your trip:1) Grand Palace and Wat Phra Kaew: The Grand Palace is a stunning complex of royal buildings and temples, and Wat Phra Kaew (Temple of the Emerald Buddha) is one of the most important and sacred temples in Thailand. The intricate architecture and historical significance make this a must-visit site.2) Wat Arun: The Temple of Dawn is another beautiful temple on the banks of the Chao Phraya River. Climbing the central prang offers a breathtaking view of the city.3) Chao Phraya River Cruise: Take a cruise along the Chao Phraya River to see some of Bangkok's most famous landmarks from the water, and enjoy the city's skyline and vibrant atmosphere.4) Khao San Road: This bustling street is famous for its nightlife, street food, shopping, and entertainment. It's a popular spot for backpackers and travelers looking for a lively atmosphere.5) Street Food: Bangkok is famous for its delicious street food. Don't miss trying local favorites such as Pad Thai, Som Tum (green papaya salad), Mango Sticky Rice, and various grilled skewers.6) Visit a rooftop bar: Bangkok has some incredible rooftop bars that offer stunning views of the city skyline. It's a great way to unwind after a day of exploring.Take a Tuk-Tuk Ride: Tuk-tuks are a fun and iconic way to get around the city, especially for short distances.Enjoy your trip to Bangkok!"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Leo thác chụp ảnh, hai thanh niên tử vong. Nội dung chính của đoạn văn kể về một sự cố tai nạn xảy ra tại đập Bình Nin, xã Xuân Bình, thị xã Sông Cầu vào chiều 31/7. Trong khi một nhóm thanh niên đến đây để chụp ảnh, một trong họ bất ngờ té xuống vực suối. Hai người khác trong nhóm cũng đã nhảy xuống cứu họ, nhưng cả ba đều đuối nước. Người dân trong khu vực đã đến cứu họ, nhưng chỉ kịp cứu một người trong nhóm. Hai người còn lại đã không qua khỏi. Đập Bình Nin là một điểm du lịch nổi tiếng, nhưng nó đã trở thành nơi diễn ra một bi kịch đau lòng trong ngày hôm đó.","answer":"Sáng 31/7, UBND thị xã Sông Cầu cho biết chiều qua nhóm thanh niên ở huyện Chư Sê, Gia Lai, đến khu vui chơi đập Bình Nin, xã Xuân Bình (thị xã Sông Cầu). Trong lúc chụp ảnh tại khu vực bờ đá đập nước, một thanh niên bị trượt chân té xuống vực suối. Hai người đi cùng nhảy xuống hỗ trợ cũng đuối nước. Thấy hô hoán, người dân trong khu vực đến cứu, vớt lên, hô hấp nhân tạo nhưng chỉ cứu được một người, nam thanh niên chụp ảnh và người bạn trong nhóm không qua khỏi. Hai thi thể được địa phương bàn giao gia đình trong sáng nay. Đập Bình Nin là điểm du lịch cách quốc lộ 1 khoảng 9 km, gồm 5 tầng với nhiều tảng đá lớn, nước chảy quanh năm, phía dưới thác là vực suối sâu."},{"question":"السؤال: شنو كان مضمون وعد بلفور ؟","answer":"الإجابة: “أن حكومة صاحب الجلالة كات شوف بعين العطف لإقامة وطن قومي ففلسطين للشعب اليهودي، و غادي تبذل جهدها كل باش تسهل تحقيق هاذ الغاية”"},{"question":"வினா: அசோக சக்கரத்தை வென்ற முதல் இந்தியப் பெண் யார்?","answer":"விடை: நீர்ஜா பானோட்"},{"question":" Sheeg magaca caalimkii muslinka ahaa ee loo yaqiinay aabihii cilmiga Kimistiriga (Chemistry)?","answer":"Wuxu ahaa Jaabir Bin Xayaan."},{"question":"Dokończ następujący akapit:  W maju 1980 ustanowił rekord świata w dziesięcioboju w Götzis w Austrii wynikiem 8648 pkt (w czerwcu tego roku stracił go na rzecz Guido Kratschmera). Zdobył złoty medal w tej konkurencji na igrzyskach olimpijskich w 1980 w Moskwie. W maju 1982 w Götzis odzyskał rekord świata uzyskując 8730 pkt, ale w sierpniu ponownie go utracił; tym razem nowym rekordzistą został Jürgen Hingsen z RFN. We wrześniu 1982 Thompson zdobył złoty medal na","answer":"mistrzostwach Europy w Atenach i jednocześnie poprawił rekord świata na 8774 pkt. Zwyciężył również w igrzyskach Wspólnoty Narodów w 1982 w Brisbane."},{"question":"Tỉnh nào nằm ở ngã ba Đông Dương?","answer":"Kon Tum là tỉnh nằm ở phía bắc Tây Nguyên, có diện tích tự nhiên 9.676 km2, chiếm 3,1% diện tích toàn quốc, phía bắc giáp tỉnh Quảng Nam (chiều dài ranh giới 142 km); phía nam giáp tỉnh Gia Lai (203 km), phía đông giáp Quảng Ngãi (74 km), phía tây giáp hai nước Lào và Campuchia (có chung đường biên giới dài 280,7 km).Đây là tỉnh duy nhất cả nước có đường biên giới chung với Lào và Campuchia, được gọi là ngã ba Đông Dương. Câu chuyện một con gà gáy, cả ba nước cùng nghe xuất phát từ đây."},{"question":"What does transparent means?","answer":"\\"Transparent\\" refers to a material or substance that allows light to pass through it in such a way that objects on the other side can be distinctly seen. In other words, a transparent material does not obstruct the view through it. Common examples of transparent materials include clear glass and some plastics. The term can also be used metaphorically to describe an entity or process that is open, clear, and free from deceit or secrecy, such as in the phrase \\"transparent government policies.\\" This metaphorical use implies easy visibility or understanding of inner workings or information."},{"question":"સબમરીન વિષે માહિતી આપો.","answer":"સબમરીન એ પાણીની સપાટી પર તેમ જ ઊંડા પાણીના તળિયે જઈને પણ રસ્તો કાપી શકે તેવું વાહન છે. આ વાહન જહાજના આકારની જ મોટી હવાચુસ્ત પેટી જેવું હોય છે. દરિયાના તળભાગમાં પાણીનું દબાણ અત્યંત વધી જતું હોઈ સબમરીનની સપાટી મજબૂત ધાતુની બનાવવામાં આવે છે. આ વાહન પેટ્રોલ, ડીઝલ જેવાં બળતણથી અથવા અણુશક્તિથી ચલાવવામાં આવે છે.સબમરીનની શોધમાં ઘણા વૈજ્ઞાનિકોનો હિસ્સો છે. ઈ. સ. ૧૬૨૦ના વર્ષમાં કૉર્નેલીસ ડ્રેબલ નામના વિજ્ઞાનીએ લાકડાની ઈંડા આકારની પ્રથમ સબમરીન બનાવી હતી. છેલ્લે હાલમાં વપરાય છે તેવી જેટ એંજિનવાળી સબમરીનની ડીઝાઈન જહોન ફિલિપ હોલેન્ડ નામના સંશોધકે કરી હતી."},{"question":"নিচের বক্তব্যের সারাংশ লেখ:কুসংসর্গও চরিত্রহীনতার অন্যতম কারণ। সঙ্গদোষে মানুষ পশুরও অধম হয়ে থাকে। এ জগতে যত লোকের অধঃপতন হয়েছে, অসৎ সংসর্গই তার কারণ। মানুষ সতর্ক থাকলেও কুসংসর্গে পড়ে নিজের অজ্ঞাতে পাপের পথে পরিচালিত হয়। কুসংসর্গ বলতে কেবল কুলোকের সংসর্গ নহে, কুচিন্তা, কদর্য পুস্তকাদি পাঠ এসকলকেও কুসংসর্গ বলা হয়। যদি সচ্চরিত্র হয়ে জীবন যাপন করা তোমার অভিপ্রায় হয়, তবে হীন চরিত্র লোকের সঙ্গ, থিয়েটার, সিনেমা ও আমোদে উত্তেজিত হওয়া, কুরুচিপূর্ণ সঙ্গীত, কবিতা ও পুস্তক পাঠ এবং কুচিন্তা প্রভৃতি সযত্নে পরিত্যাগ করবে।","answer":"বক্তব্যটির সারাংশ হলো:সৎসঙ্গ মানুষকে যেমন উচুঁতে নিয়ে যায় তেমনি অসৎ সঙ্গ মানুষকে চরম অধ:পতিত করে। অসৎ সঙ্গ পরিত্যাগ করাই হল উন্নত জীবনের স্বরূপ। খারাপ সঙ্গ জীবনকে কদর্যপূর্ণ ও পশুর ন্যায় বিবেকহীন করে তোলে। "},{"question":"  அம்பை இயற்றிய நூல்கள் யாவை ?","answer":"1.அந்தி மாலை (புதினம்)2.ஒரு கறுப்புச் சிலந்தியுடன் (1988)3.அந்தேரி மேம்பாலத்தில் ஒரு சந்திப்பு (2014)4.சிறகுகள் முறியும் (1976) - (முதலாவது தொகுதி - ஓர் பெண்ணின் வாழ்வில் ஏற்படும் பலவிதமான 5.சம்பவங்களை சம்பிரதாயங்களை பேசும் கதைகள்)6.வீட்டின் மூலையில் ஓர் சமையல் அறை (1988)7.காட்டில் ஒரு மான் (2000)8.சக்கர நாற்காலி9.ஸஞ்சாரி10.தண்ணியடிக்க11.வற்றும் ஏரியின் மீன்கள் (2007)12.பயணப்படாத பாதைகள் (ஓவியம், நாடகம், பாரம்பரிய நடனத்துறைகளில் ஈடுபட்ட பெண்கள். 13.வாய்மொழி வரலாற்றுப்பதிவு)14.சொல்லாத கதைகள் (சுதந்திரப் போராட்டத்தில் பங்குபற்றிய பெண்கள், தலித்எழுத்தாளர்கள் ஆகியவர்களின் வாய்மொழி வரலாற்றுப்   பதிவுகள்) "},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning till detta stycke - Tyskarnas blixtkrig körde fast under andra hälften av andra världskriget.","answer":"Slaget vid Kursk 1943 är ett tydligt exempel där Röda armén hade utvecklat metoder, bland annat försvar på djupet med många pansarvärnsvapen samt en stor rörlig mekaniserad reservstyrka, som lyckades stoppa tyskarnas blixtkrig. De metoder i krigföringen som Röda armén och de allierade använde sig av mot tyskarna 1944–1945 påminde om och var delvis en kopia av blixtkrig."},{"question":"வினா : மணியம்மையார்  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினைத் தருக .","answer":"விடை : மணியம்மையார்  மேற்கோள் 'நம்மைப் பிறவி இழிவுள்ள மக்களாக ஆக்கி வைத்திருக்கின்ற ஜாதி முறையினை ஒழிப்பதுதான் திராவிடர் கழகத்தின் குறிக்கோள்.'"},{"question":"Tôi thường đau đầu khi làm việc, ăn rau củ quả nhiều màu sắc có giúp ngăn ngừa tình trạng này không?","answer":"Các loại rau củ quả có nhiều màu sắc giàu dưỡng chất và chất chống oxy hóa - những hợp chất giúp ngăn chặn các gốc tự do nguy hiểm. Ăn chúng thường xuyên có thể giúp nâng cao sức khỏe tổng thể, tăng lưu lượng máu lên não, hạn chế tình trạng đau đầu, nhất là đau đầu do thiếu máu não cục bộ nhẹ.Beta-caroten: Beta-caroten có trong các loại rau củ quả màu cam như bí ngô, đu đủ, cà rốt... giúp tăng cường hệ miễn dịch, tốt cho thị giác, giảm các phản ứng viêm, trong đó, có viêm ở não.Folate: Folate có trong các loại rau màu xanh thẫm như rau ngót, rau muống, rau cải... Vitamin nhóm B này hỗ trợ ngăn ngừa chứng thiếu máu, tăng cung cấp máu cho não, cải thiện tâm trạng.Indole và lutein: Các chất này có vai trò hỗ trợ nâng cao hệ miễn dịch, cải thiện thị giác, tăng cường hoạt động của các hormone nội tiết, xoa dịu tâm trạng... Mọi người có thể bổ sung indole và lutein qua các thực phẩm như súp lơ trắng, cải thảo...Vitamin C và flavonoid: Chúng góp phần chống lão hóa tế bào não và tế bào nói chung, tăng cường hệ miễn dịch, cải thiện thị giác. Vitamin V và flavonoid có nhiều trong rau củ quả màu vàng như ớt chuông, cam, chanh.Anthocyanin: Anthocyanin có trong các loại rau, trái cây màu tím như quả việt quất, nho, cà tím... Chúng góp phần chống lão hóa, tăng cường sức khỏe não bộ.Resveratrol: Resveratrol có nhiều trong các loại quả màu hồng như thanh long, mâm xôi... giúp tăng cường miễn dịch, nâng cao hoạt động của các hormone nội tiết tố cải thiện tâm trạng, giảm viêm.Dinh dưỡng góp phần hỗ trợ ngăn chặn hoặc giảm đau đầu. Bạn cần kết hợp nghỉ ngơi, làm việc điều độ, hạn chế các chất kích thích như bia rượu, thuốc lá, thức khuya... Nếu tình trạng đau đầu tăng nặng, xuất hiện thường xuyên hay có biểu hiện bất thường thì bạn nên đi khám ở những bệnh viện có chuyên khoa thần kinh. Ở đó, bác sĩ có thể xác định đúng nguyên nhân gây đau đầu và có phác đồ điều trị phù hợp."},{"question":"Ity fanambarana manaraka ity dia amin'ny teny frantsay, adikao amin'ny teny malagasy :\\"J'aime faire de la promenade\\"","answer":"Izaho dia tia mandendeha."},{"question":"ಈ ಪ್ರಶ್ನೆಯನ್ನು ಉತ್ತರಿಸಿರಿ : ಯಾವ ಕಾದಂಬರಿಯು 1884 ರಲ್ಲಿ ಮೊದಲ ಬಾರಿಗೆ ಪ್ರಕಟವಾದ ಮಾರ್ಕ್ ಟ್ವೈನ್ ಅವರ ಕಾದಂಬರಿಯ ಆಧಾರದ ಮೇಲೆ ಒಂದು ಪಾತ್ರದ ನಿಜವಾದ ಕಥೆಯನ್ನು ಕಲ್ಪಿಸುತ್ತದೆ?","answer":"ಶೋಹೋಲಾ ಜಲಪಾತ"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిబఠానీ మొక్కలో ఆకర్షణ పత్రాలు ఏ విధంగా అమరి ఉంటాయి? అటువంటి అమరికను ఏమంటారు?","answer":"1. బఠానీ పుష్పంలో ఐదు ఆకర్షణ పత్రాలు ఉంటాయి. అతిపెద్ద ఆకర్షణపత్రము రెండు పార్శ్వ ఆకర్షణపత్రాలను కప్పి ఉంచుతుంది. ఈ పార్శ్వ పత్రాలు పూర్వాంతంలో ఉన్న రెండు అతి చిన్నవైన ఆకర్షణ పత్రాలు కప్పి ఉంచుతాయి.2. ఈ రకపు అమరికను ‘వెక్సిల్లరీ’ లేదా ‘పాపిలియోనేషియస్’ పుష్పరచన అంటారు."},{"question":"கீழே உள்ள பகுதியை பார்க்கவும், பின்னர் அதே மொழியில் கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கவும் :\\"  யு யாங்கி (பிறப்புஃ ஜூன் 8, 1994) ஒரு சீன செஸ் கிராண்ட் மாஸ்டர் ஆவார். 2009 ஆம் ஆண்டில் 14 வயது, 11 மாதங்கள் மற்றும் 23 நாட்களில் கிராண்ட் மாஸ்டர் பட்டத்திற்கு அவர் தகுதி பெற்றார்.  கேள்வி: யு யங் யி எந்த சாக்கர் பட்டத்தை வென்றார்?","answer":"யு யங் யி  செஸ் கிராண்ட் மாஸ்டர் பட்டத்தை வென்றார்."},{"question":"Koks yra klausimas: \\"Salamandros tigras (Ambystoma tigrinum) yra molių salamandros rūšis\\" Tema yra \\"Tiger Salamander\\".","answer":"\\"Koks yra Rytų salamandros tigro mokslinis pavadinimas?\\""},{"question":"Abẹ́rẹ́ mẹ́ta ọ̀tọ̀tọ̀ tí nọ́ọ̀sì fún Mohbad ló jẹ́ kí ikú rẹ̀ yá – Ọlọ́pàá","answer":"Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko ti kede pe oun ti pari iwadii oun lori ohun to ṣokunfa iku olorin takasufe, Ilerioluwa Aloba ‘Mohbad.’Kọmiṣona ọlopaa ipinlẹ Eko, Idowu Owohunwa, lo fi ọrọ naa lede nibi ipade awọn akọroyin kan to waye lọjọ Ẹti.Idowu ni eredi iwadii ileeṣẹ naa ko ṣẹyin ati mọ ohun gan to ṣokunfa iku oloogbe naa ati lati mọ awọn to lọwọ ninu iṣẹlẹ naa.Owohunwa ni lati mọ kulẹkulẹ ọrọ ọhun, awọn ṣe iwadii Azeez Adeshina Fashola ‘Naira Marley’ ati Samson Balogun ‘Sam Larry.’Yatọ si awọn meji yii, o ni awọn tun ṣe iwadii ipa ti ajọ to n gbogun ti oogun oloro, NDLEA ko ninu iku rẹ.\\"Eeyan mẹrindinlọgbọn ni a fọrọ wa lẹnu wo lori iku Mohbad\\"Ọwohunwa sọ pe eeyan mẹrindinlọgbọn ni awọn ti gba ọrọ silẹ lẹnu wọn, lara wọn ni baba oloogbe, iya oloogbe, ẹgbọn oloogbe ọkunrin ati obinrin, to fi mọ iyawo rẹ atawọn mii.Ọlọpaa tun gba ọrọ lẹnu Zlatan, ẹni to ni ọkọ ti wọn fi gbe Mohbad lọ sile iwosan lọjọ to ku, ayaworan oloogbe, oluranlọwọ rẹ, awakọ to gbe lọ si gbade ere to lọ kẹyin, ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ.O fikun pe awọn se ayẹwo iwadii Autopsy nipa iku oloogbe naa, ti awọn si n reti ayẹwo naa bayii lati mọ ohun to pa Mohbad.\\"Nọọsi jẹwọ pe awọn abẹrẹ ti oun fun Mohbad lo pada yọri si iku rẹ\\"O wohunwa wa fikun pe abajade ileesẹ ọlọpaa lori iku Mohbad ni awọn n kede rẹ lonii.“Lọwọ yii, awọn afurasi marun un ni a ti mu, ti wọn si ti wa ni ahamọ wa bayii lori iku oloogbe naa.”Lara awọn to ti wa ni atimọle ni “nọọsi to fun ni abẹrẹ mẹta ọtọtọ, eyii ti o wa lara nnkan to gbẹmi rẹ.”“Nọoṣi naa gan ni ojulowo afurasi wa.”“O jẹwọ pe awọn abẹrẹ ti oun fun oloogbe naa lo fa nnkan to pada yọri si iku Mohbad.”Ọlọpaa ni nọosi ọhun wọ gau latari pe ko koju oṣuwọn, ko si ni iwe ẹri ijọba lati fun alaisan kankan ni abẹrẹ ati pe ibi to ti fun un ni abẹrẹ kii ṣe ile iwosan tabi ibi to yẹ ki wọn ti tọju alaisan.“Ọgbẹni Ayobami Siduq ti wọn n pe ni ‘Spending,’ oun lo lọ pe nọọsi to fun Mohbad labẹrẹ, a fura si pe o gbimọpọ lọwọ ninu iku rẹ nitori ko pe ojulowo nọọsi.”“Ibrahim Oluwatosin Owoduni ti apẹle rẹ n jẹ ‘Cryboy’... oun ati Mohbad ja, a ri oun naa gẹgẹ bii afurasi.”O fi kun pe awọn mu Sam Larry ati Naira Marley nitori pe wọn lọwọ ninu ilu bara ti wọn na oloogbe naa gẹgẹ bii awọn fidio to wa lori ayelujara ti oloogbe ọhun ṣe ṣaaju iku rẹ, wọn si ti wa ni ahamọ.\\"Ọgbẹ ti Mohbad gba lapa nibi ija oun ati ọrẹ rẹ, eyi to ti n wu, lo gbe lọ sile iwosan, ki Nọọsi to fun ni abẹrẹ to pa a\\"Ọlọpaa ṣalaye pe ija kan waye laarin Mohbad ati ọrẹ rẹ kan nibi ode ere to lọ kẹyin, nibi to ti fi ọwọ ṣeṣe lasiko to fẹ fun ọrẹ rẹ naa ni ikuku.Amọ ikuku naa ba gilasi ọkọ Prado ti wọn gbe lọ sibẹ, eyii to mu ko ṣeṣe.Gẹgẹ ohun to sọ, awọn ọrẹ oloogbe mii to wa nibẹ sọ fun pe ko lọ sile iwosan nitori ọwọ ọhun ti bẹrẹ si wu.Amọ Mohbad kọ jalẹ, o si sọ pe oun yoo pe nọosi oun to maa n tọju oun tẹlẹ.Nọọsi naa ni ọlọpaa ni o fun oloogbe ọhun labẹrẹ mẹta ọtọtọ, eyii to ṣokunfa bi iku rẹ ṣe waye gẹgẹ bi wọn ṣe ni o jẹwọ ni agọ awọn."},{"question":"හිම්බා ගෝත්‍රික කාන්තාවෝ  ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න.","answer":"හිම්බා (Himba) යනු අප්‍රිකානු ආදිවාසී ජන කොට්ඨාශයක් වන අතර ඇස්තමේන්තුගත ජනගහනය 50,000 ක් පමණ වෙයි. උතුරු නැමීබියාවේ ක්‍යුනේන (Kunene) ප්‍රදේශයේ සහ ක්‍යුනේන ගංගාවේ අනෙක් පසින් පිහිටි ඇංගෝලාවේ ජීවත් වෙති.වඩාත්ම කැපී පෙනෙන හිම්බා ගති ලක්ෂණවලින් එකක් නම් කාන්තාවන්ට සේදීම සඳහා ජලය භාවිතා කිරීමට අවසර නොමැතිවීමයි. මෙයින් අදහස් කරනු ලබන්නේ තමන්ගේ සිරුර මෙන්ම ඔවුන්ගේ ඇඳුම් පැළඳුම් සෝදා පවිත්‍ර කිරීම වෙයි. ගෝත්‍රික වැඩිහිටියන්ට අනුව මෙය සම්ප්‍රදාය ඈත අතීතයේ පැවති ජලය ඉතා හිඟ වූ මහා නියං කාලයක් දක්වා දිවෙන අතර සේදීමේ කටයුතු සඳහා පිරිමින්ට පමණක් ජලය භාවිතා කල හැකි වෙයි.ඔවුන් ජීවත්වන උණුසුම්, අර්ධ ශුෂ්ක කලාපීය දේශගුණයෙන් ආරක්ෂා වීම සඳහා හිම්බා ගෝත්‍රිකයෝ ඔවුන්ගේ සම සහ හිසකෙස් මත රතු පැහැති වර්ණකයක් අඩංගු මැටි විශේෂයක් මෝරු සමග මිශ්‍ර කර සාදාගන්නා ඔජීස් (Otjize) නමින් හැඳින්වෙන ආලේපයක් භාවිතා කරති. ඊට අමතරව කාන්තාවෝ පෞද්ගලික සනීපාරක්ෂාව පවත්වා ගැනීම සඳහා දිනපතා දුම් ස්නානය කරති. බඳුනක ඇති ගිනියම් වූ ගල් අඟුරු මතට ඖෂධීය ශාක පත්‍ර සහ අතු කැබලි හා අගිල් දමා ඉන් පැනනගින දුම සිරුරට වැදීමට සලස්වයි. බඳුනෙන් පිටවන අධික උෂ්ණත්වය නිසා සිරුරෙන් දහඩිය වැගිරීමට පටන්ගන්නා අතර එය දුම් නෑම වෙයි.  සම්පූර්ණ සිරුර සේදීම සඳහා සමහර අවස්ථා වලදී පොරෝනාවක් මගින් සිරුර ආවරණය කිරීමද සිදුකරයි. එමගින් සියොළඟ පුරා දහඩිය වැගිරීමට පටන්ගනී."},{"question":"පීකි බ්ලයින්ඩර්ස් කතා මාලාවේ ටොමී ෂෙල්බිගේ චරිතයට පණ පොවන්නේ කවුද?","answer":"කිලියන් මර්ෆි"},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :АКШ да үйсүз адамдарга караганда эч ким жашабай койгон үйлөр көп."},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত বাক্যাংশটি সম্পূর্ণ করুন;তিব্বতে রুশ নাগরিক হিসেবে তার উপস্থিতি ভারতে অবস্থিত ব্রিটিশদের মধ্যে প্রাচ্যে রুশ সাম্রাজ্যের সম্প্রসারণ সম্বন্ধে আশঙ্কার সৃষ্টি করে, যা পরবর্তীতে","answer":"ব্রিটিশদের দ্বারা তিব্বতে সামরিক অভিযানে পর্যবসিত হয়। এই আক্রমণের সময় ত্রয়োদশ দলাই লামা মঙ্গোলিয়ার উর্গা শহরে পালিয়ে বেশ কিছু রুশ প্রতিনিধিদের সঙ্গে সাক্ষাত করেন। এই সমস্ত সাক্ষাতকারে গোম্বোজাব দোভাষীর ভূমিকা পালন করেন। তিব্বতে তার অভিযানের অভিজ্ঞতা তিনি লিপিবদ্ধ করা ছাড়াও ত্সোং-খা-পা-ব্লো-ব্জাং-গ্রাগ্স-পা রচিত লাম-রিম-ছেন-মো গ্রন্থের অনুবাদ শুরু করেন। পরবর্তীকালে তিনি রাশিয়া ফিরে এলে ভ্লাদিভস্তক বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়ে তিব্বতী ভাষা সম্বন্ধে শিক্ষা প্রদান করেন।"},{"question":"नेपालको पर्यटकीय गन्तव्यको रूपमा \\"नगरकोट\\" पहाडी स्टेशनको महत्त्व व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"नगरकोटले हिमालयको मनोरम दृश्यहरू प्रदान गर्दछ र एक लोकप्रिय हिल स्टेशन हो जुन यसको प्राकृतिक सौन्दर्य र सूर्योदय दृश्यहरूको लागि परिचित छ।"},{"question":"Ebee ka Delta State dị","answer":"Delta State bu state no n'ime Naigeria.Emepụtara Delta State na 27 Ọgọst 1991. Isi obodo ya na-bụ Asaba. Ahọpụtara ya dịka steeti iri na abụọ kacha nwee mmadụ na Naịjirịa."},{"question":"Awọn eleyii n fẹwọn ṣere, irin reluwee ni wọn lọọ ji ko n’Ijọra","answer":"Ibi tọkanjuwa ẹni ba so si leeyan ti n ka a loootọ, ṣugbọn ni bebe ẹwọn Fọlọrunṣọ Adeṣina ati Victor Akpan ti lọọ ka tiwọn o, irin reluwee tijọba ko jọ lawọn lọọ ji ko, wọn fẹẹ maa sa lọ lawọn agbofinro mu wọn.Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, Ọgbẹni Olumuyiwa Adejọbi, to fiṣẹlẹ yii to ALAROYE leti ninu atẹjade kan sọ pe nnkan bii aago mẹrin irọlẹ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde to lọ yii, lọwọ ba awọn afurasi mejeeji, ẹni ọdun mọkanlelogun ni wọn pe Victor, oun ni wọn lo wa mọto ti wọn gbe waa jale. Ojule kẹrindinlogoji, Opopona Biefield, l’Apapa, ni wọn ni Fọlọrunṣọ n gbe ni tiẹ, wọn o sọ pato ọjọ-ori ẹ.Awọn kan ti wọn fura si wọn bi wọn ṣe n ko awọn irin ọhun sinu mọto wọn ni wọn woye pe awọn araabi yii ki i ṣe oṣiṣẹ reluwee, awọn o si ri ami pe wọn gbawe aṣẹ lati ko nnkan ti wọn n ko yii, ni wọn ba tẹ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa laago, oju-ẹsẹ si lawọn agbofinro lati Eria E, ni Festac, ti kan wọn lara.Nigba ti wọn bi wọn leere pe pe bawo ni ti irin reluwee ti wọn n ko sinu mọto ṣe jẹ, wọn ni Victor loun o mọ nnkan kan nipa ẹ ni toun, Fọlọrunṣọ lo haaya oun pe koun waa ba oun fi mọto ko irin lọ sibi kan ni Apapa. Wọn ni Fọlọrunṣọ ko fesi kan ju pe ki wọn ṣaanu oun, ki wọn fori ji oun lọ, n lawọn ọlọpaa ba ko ṣẹkẹṣẹkẹ si wọn lọwọ, wọn si fi pampẹ ofin gbe wọn.Wọn ni kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa Eko, Hakeem Odumosu, ti gbọ siṣẹlẹ ọhun, o si ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn fawọn afurasi naa ṣọwọ si Panti, ni Yaba, nibi tawọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ aa ti ṣe iwadii to gbopọn nipa ẹ, ki wọn too foju wọn ba ile-ẹjọ pẹlu ẹsibiiti mọto wọn."},{"question":"Алиппе китеби качан басылып чыккан жана автору ким?","answer":"Кыргыз-казак балдарына арналган \\"Алифба йаки төте окуу\\" аттуу окуу китепти атактуу кыргыз агартуучусу Эшенаалы Арабай уулу Уфада окуп жүргөн кезинде казак студенти Хафис Сарсекеев менен биргеликте даярдаган. Китеп 1911-жылы 15-февралда “Шарк” басмаканасынан кыргыз-казак тилинде араб жазмасында жарык көргөн."},{"question":"Qual dessas aves não voa?a) Pinguimb) Galinhac) Cegonhad) Patoe) Peru","answer":"A resposta correta é letra A: Pinguim. O pinguim, apesar de ser uma ave, não voa. Isso deve-se ao fato da adaptação que esses animais sofreram ao longo dos anos. Cientistas acreditam que eles foram aos poucos deixando de voar e se tornaram exímios nadadores."},{"question":"ஐ.நா. சபையின் தலைமையகம் எங்கு அமைந்துள்ளது?","answer":"ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் தலைமையகம் ஜெனிவாவில் உள்ளது. "},{"question":"පෘථිවියේ වාසය කරන විශාලතම සත්වයා  කවුද?","answer":"පෘථිවියේ ජීවත් වන විශාලතම සත්වයා නිල් තල්මසා (Balaenoptera musculus) වේ. නිල් තල්මසුන් යනු දැනට ජීවත් වන විශාලතම සතුන් පමණක් නොව, පෘථිවියේ මෙතෙක් පැවති විශාලතම සතුන් ද වේ. මෙම සාගර ක්ෂීරපායින් අඩි 100 (මීටර් 30) දක්වා දිගට ළඟා විය හැකි අතර බර ටොන් 200 ක් හෝ ඊට වැඩි ය. ඔවුන්ගේ හදවත පමණක් කුඩා මෝටර් රථයක් තරම් බර විය හැකි අතර, ඔවුන් සාගරයේ සැබෑ යෝධයන් බවට පත් කරයි."},{"question":"Complete o seguinte extrato: Esses são os resultados do","answer":"Campeonato da NACAC Sub-23 de Atletismo de 2014 que ocorreram de 8 a 10 de agosto de 2014 no Estádio Hillsid, em Kamloops, no Canadá. Contou com a presença de 197 atletas de 19 nacionalidades distribuídos em 44 provas."},{"question":"ታክሲው አልመጣም?","answer":"ታክሲው መጥቷል።"},{"question":"Бир эрди менен көктү, бир эрди менен жерди шыпырган","answer":"Жаактууга жай бербеген, ээ-жаа бербей албууттанып сүйлөнгөн, сөзгө алдырбаган бей-жай, кара-жаак.Митингге адатынча бир эрди менен көктү, бир эрди менен жерди шыпырган аялдар да кошулушту."},{"question":"Кыргызстандын Ош шаарындагы Сулайман-Тоосунун чокуларынын аталышы?","answer":"Сулайман-Тоодо 5 чоку бар: 1) Баара-Таг же Сулайман тоо. Мында Бабурдун үйү (музейи жайгашкан). 2) Шор-Таг (“Ак туздуу чоку” дегенди түшүндүрөт). 3) Рушан-Таг (“Эң бийик”, “эң жарык” деген маанини берет). 4) Ээр-Таг (“Ээрге окшош тоо”). Чокунун түндүк капталы көрүнүшүнө жараша Каттама-Таш деп аталат. 5) Кекилик-Учар."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fahendrena?","answer":"Endriky ny fitondran-tena takian’ny fiarahamonina ny fahendrena.Ho an’ny ankizy ny manoa ray aman-dreny, ny tsy mandainga, tsy mangalatra. Ho an'ny tanora kosa dia ny madio fitondran-tena, tsy manandrakandram-poana, mahay mifehy tena amin’ny rendrarendra. Ho an'ny olon-dehibe dia ny mahalala sy mahay mandanjalanja ny atao, mahay mitady sy mitandrina ny marina, manam-panahy, mitondra sy miantoka ny ankohonany."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và trả lời câu hỏi bên dưới:Câu hỏi: \\"Truyện cổ tích cho trẻ em và truyện kể trong nhà\\" tập 2 có bao nhiêu câu truyện cổ tích?Hai anh em Grimm bắt đầu sưu tầm các truyện kể dân gian từ khoảng năm 1807 khi nhu cầu tìm hiểu truyện dân gian ở Đức bắt đầu phát triển. Với 86 truyện sưu tầm và hiệu đính kỹ lưỡng, năm 1812, Jacob Grimm và Wilhelm Grimm đã cho xuất bản tập đầu tiên của bộ truyện mang tựa đề Truyện cổ tích cho trẻ em và truyện kể trong nhà.Bốn năm sau, họ cho xuất bản tập thứ hai với 70 truyện cổ tích, nâng số truyện trong bộ sưu tập lên con số 156. Từ năm 1819 đến năm 1822, bộ truyện được tái bản lần thứ hai với số truyện được họ sưu tầm, biên soạn lên 170 truyện. Từ đó cho đến khi Jacob Grimm mất (năm 1863), số truyện mà họ sưu tầm, biên soạn đã lên tới con số 211 truyện.Bộ sưu tập truyện cổ tích của anh em nhà Grimm cũng nhận không ít chỉ trích bởi nhiều nội dung không thích hợp với trẻ em. Họ đã cầu thị, tôn trọng độc giả khi đã nhiều lần chỉnh sửa theo hướng bớt đi những tình tiết mang yếu tố bạo lực, tục tĩu trong những lần tái bản.Mặc dù rất thành công trong việc sưu tầm truyện dân gian nhưng công việc chính của hai anh em nhà Grimm là nghiên cứu ngôn ngữ học, đặc biệt là xác định những tính chất của ngôn ngữ và văn hóa của nước Đức mới được hình thành.Hai người đã soạn bộ từ điển tiếng Đức Deutsches Wörterbuch, tác phẩm lớn đầu tiên trong việc chuẩn hóa tiếng Đức kể từ khi Martin Luther dịch Kinh Thánh ra tiếng Đức. Đây là một bộ sách rất đồ sộ với 33 tập, nặng tới 84 kg và cho đến nay vẫn được coi là một tác phẩm tham khảo quan trọng của từ nguyên học Đức.","answer":"\\"Truyện cổ tích cho trẻ em và truyện kể trong nhà\\" tập 2 có 70 câu truyện cổ tích được xuất bản vào năm năm 1816, nâng số truyện trong bộ sưu tập lên con số 156."},{"question":"Ndiani akanyora Northanger Abbey?    ","answer":"Kungwara kwekunyora kwaJane Austen kunopenya kuburikidza mukugadzira kwake bhuku rinonakidza \\"Northanger Abbey.\\" Basa raAusten rinopa vaverengi fafitera pamusoro pemaomero emagariro uye zverudo zvenguva yacho."},{"question":"Atsakyk į šį klausimą. Vienoje vietoje gyvenantys gyventojai sudaro, ką?. Galimi variantai: a) bendruomenę; b) sistema; c) buveinę; d) rūšį;","answer":"Atsakymas: a) bendruomenė"},{"question":"Zer dira hezurketa fosilak?","answer":"Hezurdura fosilak geologiako harri-geruzetan dauden organismoen edo haien jardueren aztarnak dira."},{"question":"බිනර පසළොස්වක පොහොය දින සිද්ධීන් නම් කරන්න.","answer":"බිනර පසළොස්වක පොහොය දින සිද්ධීන් පහත දැක්වේ.මෙහෙනි සස්නේ ආරම්භය.බුදුරදුන් විශාලා මහනුවර කූටාගාර ශාලාවේ වැඩ වෙසෙන සමයේ මහා ප්‍රජාපතී ගෝතමී දේවිය රෝහිනී නදී තීරයේදී පැවිදි වූ කුමරුවන්ගේ භාර්යාවන් 500 දෙනා සමඟ කෙස් සිඳ, කසාවත් හැඳ කිඹුල්වත් පුරයේ සිට පා ගමනින්ම විශාලා මහනුවරට පැමිණියාය.අනඳ හිමියන්ගේ මාර්ගයෙන් කාන්තාවන්ට සසුන් පැවිද්ද දෙනලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියහ.අනඳ හිමි බුදුරදුන්ට මේ බව සැලකලද උන්වහන්සේ තෙවරක්ම එම ඉල්ලීම ප්‍රතික්‍ෂේප කළහ.පසුව අනඳ හිමිගේ බලවත් උත්සාහය මත කරුණු පහදා දී මහා ප්‍රජාපතී ගෝතමිය ප්‍රධාන කාන්තාවන්ට සසුන් දොර විවෘත විය.පැවිද්ද අවශ්‍යනම් අෂ්ඨගරු ධර්ම පිළිගත යුතුය,එයම ඇයට පැවිද්ද හා උපසම්පදාව වන්නේයි බුදුරදුන් ප්‍රකාශ කලහ.එය පිළිගෙන එවලෙහිම පැවිද්ද හා උපසම්පදාව ලැබීය."},{"question":"Gentille Assih","answer":"Gentille Menguizani Assih (tí wọ́n bí ní 2 Oṣù Kẹẹ̀rin, Ọdún 1979) jẹ́ olùdarí eré àti agbéréjáde ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Tógò.Wọ́n bí Assih ní ìlú Kpalimé, orílẹ̀-èdè Tógò ní ọdún 1979. Ó fẹ́ràn ṣíṣe iṣẹ́ sinimá láti ìgbà kékeré rẹ̀. Ní ọdún 2001, ó kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ìmọ̀-ẹ̀rọ kọ̀mpútà àti fọ́tòyíyà. Ní ọdún 2006, Assih tún kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ìtàn-eré kíkọ ní orílẹ̀-èdè Sẹ̀nẹ̀gàl. Nígbà yìí kan náà ni ó gba oyè-ẹ̀kọ́ nínu ìmọ̀ ìbáraẹnisọ̀rọ̀ láti ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga African Institute of Commercial Studies Ní ọdún 2009, Assih gba oyè-ẹ̀kọ́ nínu ìmọ̀ ìṣàkóso àwọn òṣìṣẹ́.Assih ṣiṣẹ́ ní ilé-iṣẹ́ kan tó n rísí bíbáraẹnisọ̀rọ̀ fún ọdún méjì ṣáájú kí ó tó dá ilé-iṣẹ́ tirẹ̀ sílẹ̀ tí ó pe orúkọ rẹ̀ ní “World Films”. Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ rẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bi olùdarí eré ní ọdún 2004 pẹ̀lú ṣíṣe àwọn fíìmù oníṣókí kan tí àkọ́lé wọ́n jẹ́ Le prix du velo àti La vendeuse contaminee. Ní ọdún 2008, ó ṣe adarí eré Itchombi.Ní ọdún tí ó tẹ̀le, Assih ṣe adarí àti agbéréjáde fún fíìmù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Bidenam, l’espoir d’un village ní ìlú Johannesburg, pẹ̀lú ìrànlọ́wọ́ ẹgbẹ́ Goethe Institute. Fíìmù náà dá lóri ayé Bidenam, ẹnití ó padà sí abúlé rẹ̀ lẹ́hìn ọdún mẹ́fà tí ó ti wà láárè, tó sì pinnu láti kọ́ àwọn ẹbí rẹ̀ bí wọ́n ti ń ṣe ètò ọ̀gbìn ní ìlànà ìbomirin. Àbúrò rẹ̀ obìnrin tí ó lọ kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ní orílẹ̀-èdè Mòrókò ni ó mú àbá ìtàn eré náà wá. Ní ọdún 2012, Assih ṣe adarí eré ìrírí gígùn kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Le Rite, la Folle et moi."},{"question":"Inona ary izao : \\"Teraka izay zanizeny, teraka iray zenizeny, faralahy lava indrindra.\\"","answer":"Valiny : ravitaretra. Ny mitsiry farany indray no lava indrindra."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన కవికి కవి పరిచయం రాయండి: శ్రీనాథుడు","answer":"కవి పేరు : శ్రీనాథుడు.ఉద్యోగం : పెదకోమటి వేమారెడ్డి ఆస్థానంలో విద్యాధికారిగా ఉండేవాడు.బిరుదులు : కవిసార్వభౌముడు.రచనలు :మరుత్తరాట్చరిత్ర, శృంగార నైషధం, కాశీఖండం, హరవిలాసం, పల్నాటి వీరచరిత్రం, క్రీడాభిరామం మొదలైనవి.ప్రత్యేకతలు : ఆయన రచించిన చాటు పద్యాలు చాలా ప్రఖ్యాతిని పొందాయి."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe hitsiny ara-piarahamonina?","answer":"Ny hitsiny dia lalana mahitsy, mazava, tsy maintsy arahin’ny rehetra; na koa fefy tsy azo ihoarana. Ny hitsiny dia sori-dalana na fitsipi-piainana feno fahamarinana, manoritra ny fitsipi-pitondran-tena, tokony harahin’ny rehetra mba tsy ho diso."},{"question":"असा कोणता प्राणी आहे जो एकाच वेळेला दोन वेगवेगळ्या दिशेला बघू शकतो?A. बेडूकB. सरडा C. सापD. पाल","answer":"B. सरडा "},{"question":"Zita remhuka ipi rinoturikirwa kuti bhiza remvura?","answer":"Mhuka ine zita rinoturikira kuti \\"bhiza remvura\\" ndiyo \\"mvuu.\\" Shoko rokuti \\"mvuu\\" rinobva pashoko rechiGiriki rokuti \\"mvuu\\" (rinoreva \\"bhiza\\") uye \\"potamos\\" (rinoreva \\"rwizi\\"). Pasinei nezita racho, mvuu haina ukama hwepedyo nemabhiza; imhuka hombe, inogara mumvura inoyamwisa kuAfrica uye inozivikanwa nehukuru hwayo, muviri wakaita sembiru, uye mararamiro emumvura."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. සළෙල පහසින් කිළිටි වූ රෑයහන වැතිරුණ දුක් සුසුම්දයාවේ නෙතු ඉමෙන් වැළහීඅම්බපාලිය මිදුණු මළ පුඩුවේ බැඳුනිදෝකිකිළියේරන් කිකිළියේ","answer":"සළෙල පහසින් කිළිටි වූ රෑයහන වැතිරුණ දුක් සුසුම්දයාවේ නෙතු ඉමෙන් වැළහීඅම්බපාලිය මිදුණු මළ පුඩුවේ බැඳුනිදෝකිකිළියේරන් කිකිළියේසිනා පඬු ගෑ දෙතොල සිර කළඉවුරු බිඳ හල කඳුළු මහ වැහිගොදුරු ලොබ බැඳ සරන මුව වැදිමළ පුඩුව මත් නිදි වරාදෝනෙත පුරා රත ගෑවුණේකිකිළියේරන් කිකිළියේපිණිදියෙන් මුව දොවා මල්කැන්නියත විවරණ ලබන උදයකපර මලක්දෝ රෑ කුමාරීමල් වැලින් බිම වැටී වැළපෙනජීවිතේ රොන් සුවඳ ඉහිරීකිකිළියේරන් කිකිළියේ"},{"question":"ਰਾਜ ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਰਾਜ ਸੋਚ-ਸਮਝ ਕੇ ਚੇਤਨ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂਕਿ ਰਾਜਨੀਤਿਕ ਉਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਲਈ ਇਸਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਯੋਗ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕੇ ।"},{"question":"Unsa ang imong mga responsibilidad sa trabaho?","answer":"Ako nagahimo ug nagamentinar ug application sa akong trabaho."},{"question":"Em đang điều trị tiểu đường tuýp 1 được 9 năm, đã tiêm 3 mũi vaccine, tuy nhiên vẫn bị nhiễm 2 lần Covid-19, lần nào cũng mệt nhiều, lần 2 được chỉ định uống kháng virus Molnu 400mg. Vậy em có nên tiêm kháng thể đơn dòng không ạ?","answer":"Kháng thể đơn dòng ngừa Covid-19 được chỉ định dự phòng trước phơi nhiễm cho những người bị suy giảm miễn dịch từ mức độ trung bình đến nặng và không đáp ứng miễn dịch đầy đủ sau tiêm vaccine. Trường hợp của bạn bị đái tháo đường type 1 là thuộc nhóm có suy giảm miễn dịch và thực tế bạn đã tiêm 3 mũi vaccine mà vẫn bị Covid-19 tới 2 lần càng chứng minh điều đó. Vì vậy bạn vẫn có thể sử dụng kháng thể đơn dòng dự phòng Covid-19."},{"question":"આઇએમઓ નંબર એટલે શું?","answer":"આંતરરાષ્ટ્રીય દરિયાઇ સંગઠનની આઇએમઓ સંખ્યા એ સામાન્ય શબ્દ છે જે બે અલગ અર્થોને આવરી લે છે.આઇએમઓ શિપ ઓળખ નંબર એક અનન્ય શિપ ઓળખકર્તા છે;આઇએમઓ કંપની અને નોંધાયેલ માલિક ઓળખ નંબરનો ઉપયોગ દરેક કંપની અને/અથવા નોંધાયેલા માલિકને ઓછામાં ઓછા 100 ગ્રોસ ટન  ના સંચાલિત જહાજોને ઓળખવા માટે થાય છે.યોજનાઓનું સંચાલન સમાંતરમાં કરવામાં આવે છે, પરંતુ આઇએમઓ કંપની/માલિકની સંખ્યા આઇએમઓ શિપ નંબરો ન ધરાવતા જહાજોના મેનેજરો દ્વારા પણ મેળવી શકાય છે.આઇએમઓ નંબરો દરિયાઇ સલામતીમાં સુધારો કરવા અને છેતરપિંડી અને પ્રદૂષણને ઘટાડવા માટે રજૂ કરવામાં આવ્યા હતા, આંતરરાષ્ટ્રીય સંમેલન ફોર લાઇફ એટ લાઇફ એટ સી હેઠળ."},{"question":"रेग्युलेटिंग ॲक्टमधील उणीवा दूर करण्यासाठी दुसरा कोणता सुधारित कायदा झाला ?","answer":"रेग्युलेटिंग ॲक्टमधील उणीवा दूर करण्यासाठी पिट्स इंडिया ॲक्ट सुधारित कायदा झाला."},{"question":"Qual o significado de \\"Confundir alhos com bugalhos?\\"","answer":"Significa fazer confusão entre coisas."},{"question":"வினா:கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து சிக்கன் மலாய் டிக்கா செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:500 கிராம்  எலும்பு நீக்கிய சிக்கன்¾ கெட்டி தயிர்½ கப் ஃப்ரெஷ் க்ரீம்1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சோள மாவு8 to 10 பாதாம் பருப்பு3 பல் பூண்டு1 துண்டு இஞ்சி1 எலுமிச்சம் பழம்1 பச்சை மிளகாய்2 மேஜைக்கரண்டி கரம் மசாலா2 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சாட் மசாலா1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி கசூரி மேத்தி¼ மேஜைக்கரண்டி கருப்பு மிளகு தூள்¼ மேஜைக்கரண்டி வெள்ளை மிளகு தூள்தேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்தேவையான அளவு நெய்தேவையான அளவு உப்புசிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லி","answer":"விடை:செய்முறை விளக்கம் :1. முதலில் சிக்கனை நன்கு கழுவி சுத்தம் செய்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து பின்பு இஞ்சி பூண்டை பேஸ்ட் ஆக்கி, கொத்தமல்லியை பொடியாக நறுக்கி, மற்றும் எலுமிச்சம் பழத்தை பிழிந்து சாறை எடுத்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. இப்பொழுது ஒரு கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் சிறிதளவு தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி அதில் பாதாமை போட்டு சுமார் 20 லிருந்து 25 நிமிடம் வரை அதை ஊற விடவும்.3. அடுத்து நாம் சுத்தம் செய்து கழுவி வைத்திருக்கும் சிக்கனை ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் போட்டு அதில் நாம் அரைத்து வைத்திருக்கும் இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட், கருப்பு மிளகு தூள், மற்றும் தேவையான அளவு உப்பு போட்டு அதை நன்கு கலந்து விட்டு சுமார் 10 லிருந்து 20 நிமிடம் வரை ஊற விடவும்.4. பின்பு ஒரு மிக்ஸி ஜாரை எடுத்து அதில் நாம் ஊற வைத்திருக்கும் பாதாமை போட்டு அதை நன்கு அரைத்து எடுத்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.5. பிறகு அதில் பச்சை மிளகாயை நறுக்கி போட்டு அதையும் நன்கு அரைத்து பேஸ்ட் ஆக்கி ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.6. இப்பொழுது ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை எடுத்து அதில் நாம் அரைத்து வைத்திருக்கும் பாதாம் பேஸ்ட், பச்சை மிளகாய் பேஸ்ட், தயிர், ஃப்ரெஷ் கிரீம், கரம் மசாலா, கசூரி மேத்தி, வெள்ளை மிளகு தூள், நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் கொத்தமல்லி, மற்றும் தேவையான அளவு உப்பை போட்டு அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.7. பின்னர் அதில் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு சோள மாவை போட்டு அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.8. அடுத்து அதில் நாம் ஊற வைத்திருக்கும் சிக்கனை போட்டு அது நன்கு மசாலாவோடு சேருமாறு அதை கிளறி விட்டு சுமார் 5 லிருந்து 10 நிமிடம் வரை ஊற விடவும்.9. 10 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு ஒரு குச்சியை எடுத்து அதில் இந்த சிக்கன் துண்டுகளை ஒவ்வொன்றாக சொருகி வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.10. பின்பு இவ்வாறு மற்ற குச்சியின் அளவிற்கேற்ப சிக்கன் துண்டுகளை சொருகி அதை ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.11. குச்சியைப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கு முன் சுமார் அரை மணி நேரத்திலிருந்து ஒரு மணி நேரம் வரை தண்ணீரில் ஊற வைத்து எடுத்து கொள்ளவும்.12. இப்பொழுது ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் சுமார் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய் மற்றும் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு நெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.13. எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் அதில் நாம் சிக்கன் துண்டுகளை சொருகி வைத்திருக்கும் குச்சியை எடுத்து பாத்திரத்தின் அளவிற்கேற்ப அதில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.14. குச்சியை தொடர்ச்சியாக திருப்பி விட்டு கொண்டே இருக்க வேண்டும் அப்பொழுது தான் சிக்கன் துண்டுகள் அனைத்து புறமும் சமமாக வெந்து இருக்கும்.15. இதை அவனில் செய்வதாக இருந்தால் அவனில் சுமார் 450 டிகிரி பாரன்ஹீட்க்கு சூடு செய்து இந்த சிக்கன் துண்டுகளோடு இருக்கும் குச்சிகளை ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து அதை அவனில் வைத்து சுமார் 10 நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும்.16. 10 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அவனில் இருந்து அந்த தட்டை கவனமாக எடுத்து குச்சியைத் திருப்பி வைத்து மீண்டும் அதே அவனில் வைத்து சுமார் 12 லிருந்து 15 நிமிடம் வரை அதை வேக விட்டு வெளியே எடுக்கவும்.17. பின்பு இதை ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து அதில் நாம் பிழிந்து வைத்திருக்கும் எலுமிச்சை சாறை ஊற்றி பின்பு அதன் மீது ஃப்ரெஷ் கிரீம்மை ஊற்றி, அதனுடன் கேரட், வெங்காயம், மற்றும் வெள்ளரிக்காய் துண்டுகளை நறுக்கி வைத்து அதை சுட சுட பரிமாறவும்.18. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் சுவையான சிக்கன் மலாய் டிக்கா தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து சுவைத்து மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"كمل الفقرة:وفي خطوة فاجأت المستثمرين، خفضت \\"فيتش\\" أمس الثلاثاء تصنيف الولايات المتحدة من \\"إيه إيه إيه\\" (AAA) إلى \\"إيه إيه بلس\\" (AA+)، وأرجعت هذا إلى","answer":"التدهور المالي المتوقع على مدى السنوات الثلاث المقبلة، وتكرار مفاوضات سقف الدين الحكومي التي تهدد قدرة الإدارة على سداد التزاماتها."},{"question":"Tại sao máy bay trực thăng hay dono (thiết bị bay cất cánh thẳng đứng) luôn có số hệ thống cánh là số chẵn: 2, 4, 6...?A. Để máy bay trực thăng và dono không bị xoayB. Để chuyển hướng được dễ dàng hơnC. Để khi thiết kế có thể xác định tâm đối xứng dễ dàng hơn","answer":"A. Để máy bay trực thăng và dono không bị xoayMáy bay trực thăng, dono là những thiết bị bay cất cánh theo phương thẳng đứng nhờ lực nâng do chênh lệch áp suất của dòng khí phía trên và dưới cánh máy bay (cơ chế về lực nâng tương tự như máy bay cánh cố định). Chúng có thể di chuyển linh hoạt mà không cần đến động cơ phản lực (như ở máy bay chiến đấu) hay động cơ phản lực cánh quạt (như ở máy bay dân sự).Do có trục linh hoạt nên cánh của máy bay trực thăng có thể nghiêng về phía trước, khi đó, lực do chênh lệch áp suất ở phía trên và dưới cánh máy bay, ngoài tác dụng nâng còn đẩy máy bay về phía trước, làm nó di chuyển.Với máy bay trực thăng một cánh chính, trục của cánh đi qua trọng tâm của máy bay: Khi cánh quay, theo định luật bảo toàn mô men động lượng, thân máy bay phải quay theo chiều ngược lại (tương tự như định luật bảo toàn động lượng trong chuyển động thẳng). Do đó, người ta phải bố trí thêm một cánh quạt nhỏ ở phía đuôi có trục quay nằm ngang sao cho mô men lực do nó sinh ra cân bằng với mô men lực làm quay máy bay, giúp thân máy bay ổn định, không bị quay. Như vậy, chúng có hai hệ thống cánh.Máy bay trực thăng hai hệ thống cánh chính, thường có hai loại: loại hai cánh đồng trục và hai cánh trên hai trục song song. Khi đó, hai cánh này luôn quay cùng tốc độ nhưng ngược chiều để triệt tiêu chuyển động quay của thân.Với thiết bị bay dono: tương tự như máy bay trực thăng khi cần có số cánh là số chẵn: 2, 4, 6... được bố trí đồng trục và theo các trục song song, đối xứng với nhau qua trọng tâm của dono. Trong đó, mỗi một nửa quay theo hai chiều khác nhau để mô men động lượng của thân dono bị triệt tiêu. Nếu bố trí cặp cánh trên một trục thì hai cánh phải quay ngược chiều để triệt tiêu chuyển động quay của thân ngay trên mỗi cặp."},{"question":"とりの市の名物で幸運をかき集めると言われる縁起物といえば何？","answer":"くまでです。"},{"question":"📚 Манас эпосундагы Манастын апасы Чыйырды эмнеге талгак болду?а) Жолборстун жүрөгүнө, шердин тилинеб) Жолборс менен жылкынын жүрөгүнөв) Жолборстун жүрөгүнөг) Жолборстун жүрөгүнө, ажыдаардын этине","answer":"а) Жолборстун жүрөгүнө, шердин тилине"},{"question":"कोणत्या तहाने मराठ्यांचे स्वातंत्र्य संपुष्टात आले ?","answer":"वसईच्या तहाने"},{"question":"එක්සත් ජනපද ජනාධිපති ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ වයස්ගතම පුද්ගලයා  කවුද, සහ ඔවුන් තනතුරු භාර ගත්තේ කුමන වයසේදීද?","answer":"එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ වයස්ගතම පුද්ගලයා  ජෝ බයිඩන් වන අතර ඔහු තේරී පත්වන විට 77 හැවිරිදි වියේ පසුවිය. ඉන්පසු ඔහු 2021 ජනවාරි මාසයේදී වයස අවුරුදු 78 දී දිවුරුම් දුන් අතර, ඔහු එක්සත් ජනපද ඉතිහාසයේ වයස්ගතම ජනාධිපතිවරයා  බවට පත්විය."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 来年の春に卒業する高校生が仕事をさがす活動が、7月から始まりました。積水ハウスは、来年高校と専門学校を卒業して、家を建てる仕事をする人を95人入れる計画です。今年の２倍以上に増やします。高校を卒業した人が最初にもらう給料は19万5000円に上げます。会社は「建物を建てる仕事をする若い人が少なくなっています。来年、働く時間の規則が厳しくなるため、人を増やす必要があります」と話しています。キリンビバレッジは、高校を卒業した人を初めて入れます。大学を卒業した人だけでは、必要な数の人を入れることが難しくなっているためです。高校を卒業した人は、1年以内に仕事をやめた人の割合が高くなっています。このためファンケルは、長く働いてもらう方法を考えています。今までは新しい人を1人ずつ工場に入れていましたが、来年からは2人以上にしてコミュニケーションがしやすいようにします。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。- 活動: 1）元気よく動いたり、働いたりすること。- 専門学校: 1）高等学校を卒業した人に、職業に必要な能力を育てる専門の学校。- 増やし: 1）多くする。- 給料: 1）やとい主が、働いた人にはらうお金。給与。サラリー。- 増やす: 1）一つ、二つ、三つなどと数えた物の数量。すう。2）いくつもあること。たくさん。3）数え上げる値打ちのあるもの。仲間。- 数: 1）勤めや役目から退く。- やめ: 1）物と物との関係を、数で表したもの。割。率。歩合。2）思いのほか。比較的。- 割合: 1）ものごとを行うやり方。しかた。- 方法: 1）言葉や文字などによって、たがいに気持ちや考えを伝え合うこと。"},{"question":"கேள்வி :  முப்படைகளின் கமாண்டர்களின் மாநாடு எங்கு நடைபெற உள்ளது?","answer":"பதில் : ராணுவ தளபதிகள் மாநாடு 2023 அக்டோபர் 16 முதல் 20 வரை புது தில்லியில் நடைபெற உள்ளது."},{"question":"టుగాగమ సంధి గురించి వివరించి ఉదాహరణలు ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"టుగాగమ సంధిi) కర్మధారయములందుత్తునకు అచ్చు పరంబగు నపుడు టుగాగమంబగు.ఉదా :నిగ్గు + అద్దము – నిగ్గుటద్దముకఱకు + అమ్ము – కఱకుటమ్ముసరసపు + అలుక – సరసపుటలుకకర్మధారయములందు అనుటచే ఉకారములేని వాటికి కూడా కొన్ని చోట్ల టుగాగమంబు వచ్చును.దుక్కి + ఎద్దు – దుక్కిటెద్దుపల్లె + ఊరు – పల్లెటూరుii) కర్మధారయమునందు పేర్వాది శబ్దములకు అచ్చు పరంబగునపుడు టుగాగమంబు విభాషనగు.ఉదా :పేరు + ఉరము – పేరుటురము , పేరుమపొదరు + ఇల్లు – పొదరుటిల్లు, పొదరిల్లు"},{"question":"Sử dụng tiêu đề và tóm tắt sau để viết một bài báo tối đa 500 chữ.Tiêu đề: Người dân đổ ra biển nhặt sò tímTóm tắt: Người dân huyện Cẩm Xuyên đổ ra biển Cẩm Nhượng nhặt sò tím dạt bờ, bắt được hàng tạ đem về làm thực phẩm và bán cho thương lái.","answer":"Sáng 16/9, dọc bờ biển hơn một km đoạn qua thôn Chùa, xã Cẩm Nhượng, hàng tấn sò tím (dân địa phương gọi là sò trạng) bị sóng lớn đánh dạt bờ. Sò đa phần đã chết, miệng hở, nhiều con bung ruột chất thành đống nhỏ, dày 2-5 cm.Cầm bì tải cỡ lớn đi dọc bờ biển, ông Nguyễn Văn Tâm, 57 tuổi, trú xã Cẩm Lĩnh, cứ vài giây lại cúi xuống nhặt các con sò nằm chất đống hoặc lẫn trong cát. \\"Sò tím sống cách bờ biển khoảng 10 hải lý, thường xuất hiện vào đầu và giữa năm. Mấy hôm nay thời tiết xấu, có thể ngoài khơi biển động, thủy triều đổi dòng cuốn sò dạt vào\\", ông Tâm nói.Cách vị trí ông Tâm đứng 50 m, một số thanh niên, đàn ông trung niên ngâm mình dưới vùng biển sâu hơn nửa mét, dùng vợt lưới cán dài gần hai mét, liên tục khua vợt giữa những đợt sóng để bắt sò. Cứ 5-10 phút, họ kéo được một mẻ.Trung bình từ sáng đến trưa một người nhặt được khoảng 30 kg sò. Một số gia đình đông nhân lực bắt được gần một tạ. Mọi người xem đây là \\"lộc biển\\" nên gọi tất cả thành viên ra biển nhặt và đánh bắt gần bờ để kiếm thêm thu nhập.Sò tím bán bán 20.000 đồng một kg. Ngoài nhập cho thương lái ngay tại bờ biển, nhiều người đưa về cất làm thực phẩm hoặc sơ chế, lấy ruột đem ra các chợ trên địa bàn bán lẻ. Loại hải sản này có thể hấp, nấu cháo, xào sả, nướng mỡ hành...\\"Trong buổi sáng tôi thu về hơn 500.000 đồng tiền bán sò. Một số gia đình khác bắt được hơn 100 kg thì lời tiền triệu, ai cũng phấn khởi\\", bà Nguyễn Thị Phượng, 55 tuổi, trú xã Cẩm Nhượng cho hay.Theo ông Nguyễn Văn Hùng, Chủ tịch xã Cẩm Nhượng, sò tím dạt bờ là hiện tượng hiếm, gần đây xuất hiện trên địa bàn hai lần, vào tuần trước và hôm nay. Sò dạt ước tính hàng tấn, trung bình mỗi người bắt được khoảng 40 kg, về lựa lại còn 10-20 kg. Đến chiều nay, sò không còn dạt, chỉ còn vài người đi nhặt.\\"Trước đây, mỗi đợt biển động hoặc sau bão thường chỉ ghi nhận sò lông dạt bờ, sò tím là lần đầu. Sò tím ngoài sống trong tự nhiên thì một số người dân trong huyện cũng nuôi\\", ông Hùng nói.Cơ quan chuyên môn nhận định, sau các đợt bão lũ, áp thấp, thường ghi nhận nhiều loài hải sản dạt bờ... Ba hôm nay Hà Tĩnh xảy mưa lớn, riêng vùng biển huyện Cẩm Xuyên thời tiết xấu, sóng lớn, gió giật cấp 7."},{"question":"በሴኔጋል ፓርላማ ውስጥ ካሉት ምክር ቤቶች አንዱ የብሔራዊ ስብስብ ምን ያህል መቀመጫዎች አሉት?","answer":"፻፳(120) መቀመጫዎች አሉት።"},{"question":"በዚህ ምድብ ውስጥ አንድ ምሳሌ ስጠኝ: ስፖርት","answer":"ሌከርስ የ2021 የኤንቢኤ ሻምፒዮናውን አሸንፏል።"},{"question":"...અલગ થઈ ગઈ. બે વર્ષ બાદ મતલબ કે મે 2013 માં એક વખત સામાન્ય ચૂંટણી થઈ. આ સમયે તેમની પાર્ટી ચૂંટણી જીતી અને નવાઝ શરીફ ત્રીજી વખત વડા પ્રધાન બન્યા. હાલમાં તેમનો મુકાબલો ક્રિકેટરથી રાજનેતા બનેલા ઇમરાન ખાન સાથે છે. ઇમરાન ખાને, નવાઝ શરીફ પર ચૂંટણી દરમિયાન છેતરપિંડીના આરોપ લગાવ્યા. વર્ષ 2014 માં ઇમરાન ખાને ઇસ્લામાબાદમાં મહિનાઓ સુધી ધરણા પ્રદર્શન કર્યા હતા. આ બધાની વચ્ચે ભારતના વડા પ્રધાન નરેન્દ્ર મોદીના શપથ ગ્રહણ કાર્યક્રમમાં નવાઝ શરીફે ભાગ લીધો હતો. એટલું જ નહીં વર્ષ 2015 માં તેમણે લાહોરમાં નરેન્દ્ર... બાકીનો લેખ લખો - ","answer":"રાખવાનો પણ આરોપ લાગ્યો હતો.તમે અમને ફેસબુક, ઇન્સ્ટાગ્રામ, યુટ્યૂબ અને ટ્વિટર પર ફોલો કરી શકો છો"},{"question":"Zuretzat, zer da lana eta familiaren arteko oreka egokitena lortzeko gako bat?","answer":"Niretzat, denbora kudeaketaren gaitasuna da lana eta familiaren arteko oreka egokitena lortzeko gako bat. Honen bitartez, beharrezkoak diren eginkizunak egiteko denbora aurkitu ahal izango dugu, baina denbora kalitatezkoak pasatzeko ere izango dugu."},{"question":"ਏਸ਼ਿਆਈ ਖੇਡਾਂ ਕਦੋਂ ਅਤੇ ਕਿੱਥੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋਈਆਂ ? ","answer":"ਪਹਿਲੀਆਂ ਏਸ਼ਿਆਈ ਖੇਡਾਂ 1951 ਨੂੰ ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੇ ਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਸਟੇਡੀਅਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੋਈਆਂ ।ਏਸ਼ੀਆਈ ਖੇਡਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਏਸ਼ਿਆਡ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਨਾਲ ਵੀ ਜਾਣਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਚਾਰ ਸਾਲ ਬਾਅਦ ਆਯੋਜਿਤ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਬਹੁ-ਖੇਡ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਯੋਗਤਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੇਵਲ ਏਸ਼ੀਆ ਦੇ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਦੇ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਭਾਗ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ।ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਖੇਡਾਂ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਏਸ਼ਿਆਈ ਓਲੰਪਿਕ ਪਰਿਸ਼ਦ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਅੰਤਰਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਓਲੰਪਿਕ ਪਰਿਸ਼ਦ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਰਾਨੀ ਹੇਠ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਹਰ ਇੱਕ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਸਥਾਨ ਲਈ ਸੋਨਾ, ਦੂਜੇ ਲਈ ਚਾਂਦੀ, ਅਤੇ ਤੀਸਰੇ ਲਈ ਕਾਂਸੀ ਦੇ ਤਮਗੇ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ। ਇਸ ਪਰੰਪਰਾ ਦਾ ਆਰੰਭ 1951 ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ।ਪਹਿਲੀਆਂ ਏਸ਼ਿਆਈ ਖੇਡਾਂ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਦਿੱਲੀ, ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Tirana moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Tirana moy péeyu réwum Albanie"},{"question":"Bakit ipinagbabawal sa relihiyong Islam ang pagkain ng baboy?","answer":"Ipinagbabawal sa Quran, ang banal na aklat ng Islam, ang pagkain ng karne ng baboy dahil itinuturing na marumi ito. Kilala ang mga baboy sa pagkain nila nang kahit anuman, kasama na ang mga insekto at kahit ang dumi ng ibang hayop. Mahilig ding magtampisaw sa putikan ang mga baboy upang magpalamig. Maaring dahilan ang mga ito kung bakit itinuturing na marumi ang baboy sa Islam."},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai. Isteri nelayan menjemur ikan di atas __ yang dibina di halaman rumahnya. Pilihan:  A) papan-papanB) para-paraC) ruang-ruangD) rak-rak","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C) ruang-ruang"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය ගයනා  කරන්නේ කව්ද ?වස්තුව ඉල්ලන කාශ්‍යප පුතුනේඇයි හදවත රිදවන්නේඇස් දෙක වාගෙයි මුගලන් සහ නුඹපිය රජු සෙවනේ උන්නේබලන්න දෙටු පුත මේ දිය තලයමකෙත් වතු සාර කරන්නේමට ඇති වස්තුව මත ඇති සම්පතමේ නිල් දිය කඳ වන්නේහිටුවා පස් ගස්වා මා මැරුමටකවුරුද පුතු සිත බින්දේමා මළ පසු පුත මිහිදන් කළ මැනකලා වැවේ වැව් කන්දේමගේ කලා වැව සදා රකිනු මැනඅවුකන පිළිම සමින්දේ","answer":"ඇන්ටන් රුද්‍රිගු"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هى السور التى تسمى بمواقيت الصلاة؟","answer":"الإجابة: الفجر والعصر."},{"question":"පහත නාම පදයට අදාළ පුරුෂ ලිංග නාම පාදක කුමක්ද? නෑනා ","answer":"මස්සිනා"},{"question":"Podaj przykład zagadki z kategorii: polityka.","answer":"Kto był senatorem Stanów Zjednoczonych i był członkiem obsady w Saturday Night Live? Al Franken"},{"question":"Sobre que evento importante é este texto: Em 25 de março de 2009, Aubameyang foi selecionado para a Seleção do Gabão  e fez sua estréia na equipe. Ele marcou seu primeiro gol em uma vitória por 3 a 2 sobre o Marrocos, depois marcou um gol em amistosos contra Benin, Togo, Argélia e Senegal, no ano seguinde, disputou a Copa das Nações Africanas de 2010. Aubameyang foi um membro importante da sua Seleção que chegou às quartas de final da e Copa das Nações Africanas de 2012 como co-anfitriões da competição. Ele marcou três gols no total, terminando o torneio como um dos artilheiros.","answer":"O evento é a Copa das Nações Africanas de 2012."},{"question":"Ичтен чыккан ийри жылан","answer":"Курсактан чыккан бала, тууган балам деген маанидеги накыл кеп. Бул накыл кептин төркүнү байыркы замандан бери кыргыз элинин айтып келе жаткан жомогуна барып такалат. Анын жөнү мындай: илгери бир аял жылан төрөйт. Эл мындай укмуштан коркуп, түлөө кылып, Кудайга жалынып, көчө качышат. Төрөлгөн жыланды коломтого таштап кетишет. Энеси аттанып жөнөйт. Бир аз баргандан кийин: «Ий! Ичтен чыккан ийри жылан!» - деп боору ачып, кайта бурулуп келип, коломтодогу жыланды карайт. Жылан тууса да ошого боору ачып, кете албай кылчактайт. Мына ушундан улам, бала канча жаман болсо да, азар кылса да, азап тарттырса да, эне баарын чыдап, «ичимен чыккан» деп аяп, «ичтен чыккан ийри жылан» деп накыл кеп чыгарган. Бул накыл кеп жалгыз гана балага карата айтылат. Ушул накыл кеп менен гана эненин жүрөгүн, ченемсиз сүйүүсүн билдирүүгө болот."},{"question":"මිතුරනි, 'සුරත් සුවය' යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"සුරතාන්ත සුවය"},{"question":"इ.स. 8 व्या शतकात जगप्रसिध्द विक्रमशिला विद्यापीठाची स्थापना कोणी केली ?","answer":"इ.स. 8 व्या शतकात जगप्रसिध्द विक्रमशिला विद्यापीठाची स्थापना राजा धर्मपालने केली."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو اسم الملك الذي يقف خازناً على جهنم؟","answer":"الإجابة: مالك."},{"question":"Nganong gipatay si Jesus sa krus?","answer":"Aron makaluwas sa mga sala sa katawhan pinaagi sa iyang kamatayon."},{"question":"Ilang crates ang kailangan mo kung mayroon kang 304 na pares ng sapatos at ang bawat crate ay maaaring maglaman ng 19 na sapatos?","answer":"Mayroon kang 608 sapatos dahil mayroon kang 304 na pares ng sapatos, at may 2 sapatos sa bawat isang pares. Kung maaaring maglaman ng 19 na sapatos ang isang crate, kailangan mo ng 608 ÷ 19 = 32 na crates."},{"question":"팔팔 끓는 물일수록 온도가 높은 것은 아니라고 하는데 그러면 물이 팔팔 끓거나 덜 끓거나를 결정하는 건 무엇인가요?","answer":"물에 용해된(들어있는) 기체의 양에 따라 결정됩니다."},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: Kiedy w 1773 roku nastąpiła kasata zakonu Jezuitów rząd austriacki przejął kolegium i utworzył w jego miejsce sześcioletnie gimnazjum (jedno z sześciu szkół średnich jakie pozostawiono w Galicji). Eksjezuitom pozwolono uczyć w szkole do roku 1787, a rok później wprowadzono język niemiecki jako wykładowy. Od tego czasu w gimnazjum uczyli nauczyciele świeccy, na których czele stał prefekt. W listopadzie 1819 roku utworzono przy gimnazjum dwuletni zakład filozoficzny, którego ukończenie pozwalało na podjęcie studiów uniwersyteckich. Uczniowie gimnazjum uczestniczyli we wszystkich najważniejszych wydarzeniach 1. i 2. połowy XIX w.: walczyli w kampaniach napoleońskich, o niepodległość Grecji, w","answer":"Powstaniu Listopadowym, wchodzili w skład organizacji spiskowych lat 30., brali udział w Wiośnie Ludów nie tylko na terenach polskich, ale i węgierskich, walczyli w Powstaniu Styczniowym. W roku szkolnym 1849/1850, w wyniku reformy oświaty, połączono sześcioletnie gimnazjum z dwuletnim zakładem filozoficznym w jeden ośmioletni zakład. Nauka w gimnazjum kończyła się maturą umożliwiającą podjęcie studiów uniwersyteckich. Od roku szkolnego 1867/1868 językiem wykładowym ustanowiono język polski. 3 września 1895 roku uroczyście poświęcono nowy budynek szkolny przy ówczesnej ul. Dobromilskiej, który służy szkole do dziś. Koniec ery autonomicznej związany jest z wieloma wydarzeniami w historii szkoły. To z niej w 1895 roku wyłoniono gimnazjum ukraińskie, a w 1906 roku – gimnazjum zasańskie. Szkoła – w okresie rozbudzonych uczuć narodowych – była \\"almae matris\\" dla wielu wybitnych działaczy niepodległościowych polskich, ukraińskich, a także żydowskich. To w murach Gimnazjum w 1907 roku zawiązano zalążki dzisiejszego Klubu Sportowego „Polonia”. Prężnie rozwijały się inicjatywy teatralne, harcerskie oraz ruch turystyczny."},{"question":"Ọwọ ti ba ‘Stubborn’, ogbologboo ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun n’Ilaro","answer":"O pẹ tawọn ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun ti n wa Dare Ojugbele tawọn eeyan n pe ni ‘Stubborn’, n’Ilaro. Koda, orukọ ẹ ti wa ninu iwe awọn ọdaran tijọba n wa, ko too di pe o bọ sọwọ awọn agbofinro logunjọ, oṣu kẹjọ yii.Ni nnkan bii aago mejila ọsan ọjọ naa ni DPO Ilaro, CSP Ọlayẹmi Jacob, ẹni to n wọde pẹlu awọn ikọ rẹ lọna Idọgọ, ṣadeede ri Stubborn ti wọn ti n wa tipẹ lori ọkada, bi wọn ṣe da ọkada naa duro niyẹn.Wọn yẹ ara ẹ wo loju-ẹsẹ, ibọn ilewọ kan lawọn ọlọpaa sọ pe awọn ri lapo ẹ pẹlu ọta ibọn ti wọn ko ti i yin, awọn nnkan ija mi-in pẹlu awọn oogun to fi n ṣagbara naa si tun wa lapo ẹ gẹgẹ bi wọn ṣe wi.Dare Ojugbele ti wọn ni agbegbe Itawaya, n’Ilaro, lo ti wa, jẹwọ fawọn ọlọpaa pe ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun Ẹiyẹ loun. Wọn lo jẹwọ pe gbogbo rogbodiyan ẹgbẹ okunkun to n waye n’Ilaro ati agbegbe rẹ ko ṣẹyin oun atawọn ẹgbẹ oun.Nigba to n paṣẹ pe ki wọn gbe Stubborn lọ sẹka itọpinpin lọdọ awọn ọlọpaa, CP Edward Ajogun tun sọ pe aaye ṣi wa fun ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun yoowu to ba fẹẹ kọ ẹgbẹ naa silẹ lati wa bayii, nitori ijọba yoo ṣe aforiji fun wọn, wọn yoo sọ wọn di ọmọ gidi. Ṣugbọn ẹni to ba kọ lati ṣe bẹẹ yoo da ara rẹ lẹbi tọwọ ba pada tẹ ẹ, nitori tọhun yoo jiya bii ẹran oriso pẹlu ofin ni."},{"question":"Beqil ma mbind mii:[Fàttalikuleen] Ba ngeen reyee bakkan te ngeen jiiñante ko!... Te Yàlla génne la ngeen doon nëbb.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:[Fàttlikuléen] Ba ngéen rayee bakkan te ngéen jiiñante ko!... Te Yàlla génne la ngéen doon nëbb."},{"question":"Sallar asuba raka'a nawa ce","answer":"(a)data(b)biyu(c)uku"},{"question":"Shin batun me ake magana a wannan mai zuwa? \\"yan keke NAPEPE sun fara yajin aikin gama-gari a Jihar Adamawa\\":(a) Lafiya(b) Afirka(c) Najeriya(d) Siyasa(e) Duniya","answer":"Jumlar : \\"yan keke NAPEPE sun fara yajin aikin gama-gari a Jihar Adamawa\\" na batu ne a kan najeria."},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?[Fàttalikuleen], ba Nu dëelanteek Muusaa ñeen-fukki guddi! Te ngeen jaamu yëkk wa ginnaawam, ngeen di way-tooñ.","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:[Fàttlikuleen], ba Nu dëhalantee'k Muusaa ñent fukk i guddi! Te ngéen jaamu yëkk wa ginnaawam, ngéen di waytooñ."},{"question":"સુરેશ દલાલ ની \\"દરિયા સાથે દોસ્તી\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"દરિયા સાથે દોસ્તી મારી, નદીઓ સાથે નાતો,છલાંગ મારતા ઝરણા સાથે, હું તો ગીતો ગાતો..હું તો ગીતો ગાતો.. દરિયા સાથે..લીલાંછમ વૃક્ષો વ્હાલા, પહાડો મારા ભેરુ,વ્હાલું મને લાગે કેવું નાનું અમથું દેરું,આસુંઓની પાછળ જઈને ક્યારેક હું છુપાતો..હું તો ગીતો ગાતો.. દરિયા સાથે..ફૂલ ને ઝાકળ, દળ-વાદળ ને હર્યુંભર્યું આ ઘાસ,મારો સૌની સાથે કેવો સહજ મળે છે પ્રાસ,સરોવરનાં આ હંસકમળની સાથે કરતો વાતો..હું તો ગીતો ગાતો.. દરિયા સાથે.."},{"question":"What are the key challenges in software maintenance, and how can they be addressed?","answer":"Challenges in software maintenance include bug fixes, updates, and adapting to changing environments. Effective documentation, version control, and automated testing help address these challenges."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"Akoholahy maneno alina ka _.\\"","answer":"\\"Akoholahy maneno alina : lozain' ny vavany.\\""},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 東京都によると、9月10日までの1週間にインフルエンザになった人は、今年がいちばん多くなっています。東京都は21日、これからインフルエンザになる人が増えると考えて、注意報を出しました。インフルエンザは普通、秋の終わりから冬に広がります。今年は今まででいちばん早く注意報が出ました。インフルエンザが原因でクラスなどが休みになっている幼稚園や学校もあります。9月17日までの2週間で、207の学校などが休みになりました。インフルエンザの注意報は、埼玉県と千葉県などにも出ています。東京都などは、よく手を洗って、部屋に新しい空気を入れて、インフルエンザがうつらないように気をつけてほしいと言っています。↑インフルエンザのデータはこちらから見ることができます。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。- インフルエンザ: 1）のどや気管などが、ウイルスによってただれる病気。かぜに似ているが、高い熱が出て、うつりやすい。流行性感冒。流感。- 注意報: 1）災害のおそれがあるとき、注意を呼びかける知らせ。- 広がり: 1）広くなる。2）広々と見わたせる。3）行きわたる。4）大きくなる。- 幼稚園: 1）小学校に入る前の子どもに、集団生活に慣れさせるため、いろいろのことを教える所。"},{"question":"క్రింది గద్యాన్ని చదివి అందలి ఐదు కీలకమైన పదాలను గుర్తించి రాయండి. పత్రికలలో దినపత్రికలకు ఒక ప్రత్యేక స్థానం ఉన్నది. ఈనాడు, వార్త, ఆంధ్రజ్యోతి, నమస్తే తెలంగాణ, నవతెలంగాణ, సాక్షి వంటి దినపత్రికలు నేడు బహుళ ప్రచారంలో ఉన్నవి. ప్రభుత్వానికి, ప్రజలకు మధ్య పత్రికలు వారధిలా పనిచేస్తాయి. ప్రభుత్వం చేపట్టిన కార్యక్రమాలు, ప్రకటనలను పత్రికలు ప్రజలకు తెలియజేస్తాయి. వాటిని గురించి ప్రజల స్పందన ఎట్లా ఉన్నదో వివరించే బాధ్యత కూడా పత్రికలపైన ఉన్నది. పత్రికలు సమాజాన్ని మేల్కొలిపే వైతాళికుల లాంటివి. అందుకే విద్యార్థులు పత్రికా పఠనాన్ని ఒక అనివార్య విషయంగా భావించి దాని సాధనకు తప్పనిసరిగా సమయం కేటాయించుకోవాలి.","answer":"కీలక పదాలు :దినపత్రికలువారధిప్రజలస్పందనవైతాళికులుపత్రికా పఠనం"},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 歌手のブラザー・コーンさんが、乳がんになったことがわかったとSNSに書きました。 ブラザー・コーンさんは男性で67歳です。SNSによると、左の胸にしこりができたため、病院で調べてもらったら、乳がんが見つかりました。医者からは、早く見つかったので亡くなる心配はないと言われました。","answer":"ブラザー・コーンさんは「男性の乳がんは珍しいようで、驚きました」と書いています。 専門家によると、日本で乳がんが見つかる人は1年に約10万人います。この中で男性は1％より少ない約600人です。60歳から79歳ぐらいで見つかる男性が多くなっています。 専門家は「胸や脇を触ってしこりがあるときや、乳首から血が出るときなどは、すぐ病院に行ってください」と話しています。"},{"question":"Tôi đang sinh sống tại TP HCM, thu nhập hàng tháng 30-35 triệu đồng, vốn tự có 1,4 tỷ đồng, chưa lập gia đình. Hàng tháng tôi có thể tiết kiệm được ít nhất 40% thu nhập. Tôi đang muốn mua căn hộ hoặc nhà để chuẩn bị lập gia đình sau này. Tuy nhiên, tôi băn khoăn nên mua căn hộ 2 phòng ngủ, 2 vệ sinh giá khoảng 2-2,4 tỷ đồng hay mua nhà đất diện tích nền 20-30 m2 ở khu vực quận 7, quận 8, huyện Nhà Bè, giá 2,5 tỷ đồng.Tôi vẫn thích sở hữu nhà đất hơn là căn hộ chung cư. Mong được các chuyên gia và độc giả tư vấn!","answer":"Với số vốn sẵn có 1,4 tỷ đồng cùng với thu nhập cố định và khoản tiết kiệm hàng tháng, bạn có thể vay thêm một khoản tương đương 800 triệu đồng đến 1 tỷ đồng, thời hạn 15 năm. Như vậy, ngân sách để mua nhà của bạn tối đa là 2,4 tỷ đồng.Tại khu Nam Sài Gòn bạn nhắm đến, ngân sách trên có thể mua căn hộ chuyển nhượng diện tích 55-70 m2 ở quận 7, quận 8 hoặc diện tích 60-80 m2 ở huyện Nhà Bè. Tuy nhiên, nếu mua nhà đất, với ngân sách này chỉ có thể tìm được những căn nhà trong hẻm nhỏ diện tích dưới 25 m2 ở quận 7, dưới 40 m2 ở quận 8 hoặc 60 m2 tại những khu dân lâu đời ở huyện Nhà Bè.Để lựa chọn phân khúc bất động sản phù hợp, bạn cần xem xét mục tiêu mua bất động sản để dành là ở thực hay tích sản, chống trượt giá.Với mục tiêu mua để ở, chung cư là lựa chọn tốt hơn nhà đất. Bởi với ngân sách sẵn có và vị trí tương đương, bạn sẽ dễ dàng tìm được một căn chung cư phù hợp với nhu cầu của mình hơn nhà đất. Nguồn cung căn hộ tại khu Nam hiện nay khá dồi dào, đem đến cho bạn nhiều lựa chọn. Mỗi dự án cung cấp hàng trăm căn hộ diện tích đa dạng, tương đồng về môi trường sống, thiết kế, tiện ích. Đối tượng ở đa số là các gia đình trẻ, thích thay đổi trải nghiệm, dễ thích nghi với các môi trường sống mới.Cũng ngân sách này, nếu mua nhà đất, bạn chỉ có thể lựa chọn những căn nhà sâu trong ngõ hẻm hay tại khu dân cư lâu đời. Để tìm nhà đất phù hợp với nhu cầu sẽ khó hơn do mỗi căn nhà là một sản phẩm riêng biệt với nhiều điểm khác nhau. Bạn cần phải cân nhắc đến nhiều yếu tố hơn như quy hoạch, sổ đỏ, khu dân cư xung quanh.Nếu chưa ở ngay, bạn có thể khai thác cho thuê căn hộ với lợi suất cho thuê cao hơn nhà trong ngõ hẻm. Ví dụ, căn hộ tầm giá 2,4 tỷ đồng ở khu Nam có thể cho thuê được khoảng 7-9 triệu đồng mỗi tháng. Trong khi nhà ở ngõ hẻm nhỏ, tuy cùng giá trị 2,4 tỷ đồng nhưng chỉ có thể cho thuê 6-7 triệu đồng mỗi tháng.Với mục tiêu tích sản, chống trượt giá, nhà đất là lựa chọn tốt hơn chung cư. Bởi giá trị đất trong cơ cấu giá tạo nên chung cư thường rất nhỏ so với giá trị đất trong cơ cấu giá của nhà liền thổ. Ví dụ, giá trị nhà mặt đất thường bao gồm 75% giá trị đất, 25% giá trị nhà. Còn chung cư chỉ khoảng 55% giá trị nhà sử dụng riêng, 45% giá trị đất sử dụng chung (tiện ích, khuôn viên dự án).Trong khi đó, giá trị đất luôn tăng nhanh hơn giá trị nhà. Do đó, khi giá trị đất tăng lên nhờ sự phát triển của hạ tầng khu vực, tổng giá trị của chung cư vẫn tăng ít hơn nhiều nhà đất.Về hiệu quả của mục tiêu mua nhà để dành, tổng tiền lãi gửi tiết kiệm 5% mỗi năm của 1,4 tỷ đồng và tiền lãi vay 11% mỗi năm của 1 tỷ đồng (bỏ qua lãi kép tiền gửi và tiền lãi giảm dần theo dư nợ) là 180 triệu đồng mỗi năm. Trừ đi thu nhập từ tiền cho thuê khoảng 80 triệu đồng (nếu khai thác cho thuê 6 triệu đồng mỗi tháng), chi phí sử dụng vốn của 2,4 tỷ đồng vào khoảng 100 triệu đồng mỗi năm.Giả sử 5 năm sau bạn lấy lại nhà để ở, tổng vốn bỏ vào tài sản này lúc này khoảng 3 tỷ đồng (gồm giá trị căn nhà và chi phí sử dụng vốn). Nếu giá trị căn nhà của bạn khi đó chưa đến 3 tỷ đồng, mục tiêu mua để dành, chống trượt giá của bạn thất bại. Do đó, bạn cần ưu tiên loại bất động sản có khả năng tăng giá tốt hơn, trường hợp này nhà đất trong ngõ hẻm có ưu thế hơn chung cư.Nhìn chung lại, bạn muốn mua căn hộ hoặc nhà để dành sau này lập gia đình, nghĩa là chưa có nhu cầu sử dụng ngay. Trong cùng một vị trí và mức giá tương đồng, môi trường sống và giá cho thuê chung cư phần lớn sẽ tốt hơn nhà đất. Ngược lại, nhà đất có lợi thế về mức độ tăng giá chống lạm phát hơn chung cư đã bàn giao. Bạn nên xem xét mục tiêu lớn nhất khi mua bất động sản để dành là gì để đưa ra lựa chọn phù hợp."},{"question":"२० औं शताब्दीको उत्तरार्धमा नेपाली चलचित्र उद्योगमा विश्वव्यापीकरणको प्रभावको चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"२० औं शताब्दीको उत्तरार्धमा विश्वव्यापीकरणले नेपाली चलचित्र उद्योगलाई अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय प्रचलनहरूमा पर्दाफास गरेर र विदेशी फिल्म निर्माताहरूसँगको सहकार्य बढाएर प्रभाव पारेको थियो। यस अवधिले फरक नेपाली कथा कथनको साथ विश्वव्यापी सिनेमाई प्रभावहरूको संयोजन देख्यो।"},{"question":"அன்றாட உணவில் சகஜமாக பயன்படுத்தப்படும் பொருட்களில் ஒன்று வெங்காயம். காரத்தன்மை கொண்ட வெங்காயம் பச்சையாக சமைக்காமல் சாப்பிடும்போது உடலில் பல மாற்றங்களை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது. வெங்காயத்தை பச்சையாக சாப்பிடுவது நல்லதா?","answer":"• பச்சை வெங்காயம் வைட்டமின் சி இன் சிறந்த மூலமாகும். இது உடலின் நோய் எதிர்ப்பு சக்தியை அதிகரிக்க உதவுகிறது.• வெங்காயத்தில் குர்செடின் போன்ற உயிர் வளியேற்ற எதிர்ப்பொருள்கள் நிறைந்துள்ளன. இது உடலில் உள்ள கெட்ட கொழுப்பின் அளவைக் குறைக்க உதவுகிறது.• பச்சை வெங்காயத்தில் நார்ச்சத்து உள்ளது. இது செரிமானத்திற்கும் உடலில் இருந்து கழிவுகளை வெளியேற்றுவதற்கும் முக்கியமானது.• குவெர்செடின் நிறைந்த பச்சை வெங்காயத்தில் அழற்சி எதிர்ப்பு பண்புகள் உள்ளன. அவை உடலில் ஏற்படும் அழற்சியின் அளவைக் குறைக்க உதவுகின்றன.• வெங்காயம் கந்தகம் நிறைந்த கலவைகளின் சிறந்த மூலமாகும். இது எலும்பு ஆரோக்கியத்தை மேம்படுத்த பங்களிக்கிறது.• பச்சை வெங்காயத்தில் கந்தகம் நிறைந்த கலவைகள் மற்றும் உயிர் வளியேற்ற எதிர்ப்பொருள்கள் உள்ளன. அவை புற்றுநோயைத் தடுக்க உதவுகின்றன. • பச்சை வெங்காயத்தை உட்கொள்வது தோல் சுருக்கங்கள், புள்ளிகள் மற்றும் நிறமி அளவைக் குறைக்க உதவுகிறது.• பச்சை வெங்காயத்தில் நீலிரும்பு உள்ளது, இது இரத்த சர்க்கரை அளவைக் கட்டுப்படுத்துவதில் முக்கியமான ஒரு தாதுப்பொருளாகும்."},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Equateur nékk","answer":"Réwum Equateur mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Amerique"},{"question":"Oje Nasıl Bozulur?","answer":"Oje saklamanın püf noktaları:Ağzı iyi kapanmayan ojeler hava alır ve kısa sürede ojenin yapısı yoğunlaşır ve katılaşır. 2) Oje yapısını bozan bir diğer unsur ise ojenin aşırı sıcak ya da aşırı soğukta bırakılmasıdır. Ojeleri saklarken en ideal ısı oda sıcaklığıdır. 3) Ojeleri güneş ışığı altında da bırakmamak gerekir."},{"question":"Rumor has it that వరి, మినుము, మొక్కజొన్to జెర్రిగొండి గ్రామంలో ప్రధాన పంట ఏంటి?","answer":"వరి, మినుము, మొక్కజొన్న"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe motera efa-dingana?","answer":"Ny maotera efa-dingana dia mamita dingana efatra (fidirana, fanerena, fandoroana, setroka) mba hamitana tsingerina iray."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Sau những màn chào sân ấn tượng từ tập 1, tập 2 Sàn Đấu Vũ Đạo 2022 là màn đối đầu với chủ đề \\"Hip-hop never die\\" của 6 đội thi đầu tiên bao gồm Mai Ngô - Shin Trúc Anh, Ciin - Duy Tân, Dương Domic - Hải 2D, Gin Tuấn Kiệt - Trần Tú, Mai Âm Nhạc - Song Linh, Denis Đặng cùng bộ đôi biên đạo Quang Hiệp - Kiên Cường. Đồng hành cùng 2 giám khảo cố định Minh Hằng và John Huy Trần trong tập phát sóng tuần này chính là giám khảo khách mời: diễn viên Diệp Lâm Anh. Đây là gương mặt quen thuộc trong giới Hip-hop. Thuở xưa, cô cũng từng là thành viên của nhóm nhảy đình đám Hà Nội - Big Toe từ năm 15 tuổi. Ngoài ra, người đẹp cũng lọt top 4 khi tham gia Bước Nhảy Hoàn Vũ 2015. Tham gia chương trình lần này, Diệp Lâm Anh cho biết cô muốn sống lại khoảng thời gian Hip-hop cách đây hơn 10 năm. Bên cạnh dàn giám khảo ngồi \\"ghế nóng\\" còn có sự xuất hiện của hội đồng bình chọn bao gồm khán giả, đại diện biên đạo và đại diện truyền thông. Ciin tiếp tục dựng tiết mục hoành tráng đáp trả antifan vì danh xưng \\"Lisa Việt Nam\\" Sân khấu mà Ciin và biên đạo Duy Tân chuẩn bị trong tuần thi thứ 2 gây chú ý khi màn hình xuất hiện hàng loạt bình luận tiêu cực từ antifan. Tham gia Sàn Đấu Vũ Đạo mùa 2, Ciin được dịp trải lòng về những tháng ngày bị \\"ném đá\\" vì danh xưng \\"Lisa Việt Nam\\". Nữ vũ công giãi bày thoạt đầu rất thích khi được đặt biệt danh so sánh với thần tượng là thành viên BLACKPINK nhưng giờ đây lại sợ nghe mọi người gọi cô bằng danh xưng này. \\"Qua Sàn Đấu Vũ Đạo, mình muốn chứng minh bản thân còn có thể làm nhiều thứ khác, mong mọi người đón nhận hình ảnh của Ciin vì Ciin là chính mình\\", Ciin khẳng định. Chia sẻ về cách dàn dựng tiết mục của mình, biên đạo Duy Tân nghẹn ngào trên sân khấu: \\"Thời gian qua, Ciin đã chịu áp lực rất lớn vì bị gán ghép danh xưng không đúng. Để Ciin từ từ mở lòng hơn, em muốn Ciin đi từng bước chứ không vội vàng. Là người ở chung phòng trọ với Ciin, em chứng kiến hết, em cảm nhận được sự tiêu cực trong Ciin và muốn bạn mở lòng với xã hội nhiều hơn. Đây là mục tiêu đầu tiên mà em đến tham gia chương trình\\". Bài thi Hip-hop của Ciin - Duy Tân bị các giám khảo nhận xét là quá an toàn. Biên đạo John Huy Trần chia sẻ: \\"Anh muốn các em khám phá kỹ thuật, động tác khó hơn. Đây là bài thi kiểu Hip-hop thị trường những năm 1980, cần cập nhật đổi mới hiện đại hơn\\". Ciin thừa nhận Hip-hop là điểm yếu của mình vì đã không tập thể loại này 7 năm. Kết quả, đội Ciin - Duy Tân nhận được số điểm lần lượt là: 7,5 điểm từ biên đạo John Huy, 8 điểm từ giám khảo Minh Hằng và 8,75 điểm từ giám khảo Diệp Lâm Anh. Mai Ngô tạo cypher Hip-hop, Diệp Lâm Anh phấn khích tham gia \\"ke đầu\\" Với chủ đề Hip-hop tuần này, Mai Ngô đã tạo cả trận cypher với rất nhiều thể loại nhảy \\"chất phát ngất\\", mang đậm tinh thần nhảy đường phố từ trekking, C-walk, X-game, toprock, footwork,... Đặc biệt, phần hỗ trợ của beatboxer và DJ càng khiến tiết mục của Mai Ngô - Shin Trúc Anh thêm phần sôi động. ","answer":"Tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn trên có thể là: \\"Sàn Đấu Vũ Đạo 2022: Cuộc đọ sức sôi động với chủ đề 'Hip-hop never die'\\""},{"question":"Var i världen visas Leonardo da Vincis Mona Lisa?","answer":"Louvren, Paris, Frankrike."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'nanti-nantian bagai berlakikan raja'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud perihal orang yang berhajat kepada seseorang yang tidak sangat berkehendak kepadanya"},{"question":"السؤال: من هم المغضوب عليهم عند الله تعالى؟","answer":"الإجابة:  اليهود."},{"question":"Sino si Lea Salonga?","answer":"Si Lea Salonga ay isang mang-aawit at aktres mula sa Pilipinas na kilala sa larangan ng musika at entablado. Kilala si Salonga sa kanyang pagganap sa ilang musikal, katulad ng pagganap niya bilang Kim sa \\"Miss Saigon\\" at Eponine sa \\"Les Miserables\\". Siya rin ang nagboses sa ilang prinsesa ng Disney, katulad nina Princess Jasmine sa \\"Aladdin\\" at Mulan sa \\"Mulan\\". Marami nang napanalunan na award si Salonga dahil sa kanyang boses at talento, kabilang ang Tony Award bilang \\"Best Actress in a Musical\\" para sa \\"Miss Saigon\\". "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਲੋਕੁ ॥ਦਾਸਹ ਏਕੁ ਨਿਹਾਰਿਆ ਸਭੁ ਕਛੁ ਦੇਵਨਹਾਰ ॥ਸਾਸਿ ਸਾਸਿ ਸਿਮਰਤ ਰਹਹਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਦਰਸ ਅਧਾਰ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 257 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਸੇਵਕਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਵੇਖ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ (ਇਹ ਨਿਸਚਾ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ) ਕਿ ਹਰੇਕ ਦਾਤਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ (ਇਸ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਉਹ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਟੇਕ ਰੱਖਣ ਦੇ ਥਾਂ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਦੀਦਾਰ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦਾ) ਆਸਰਾ ਬਣਾ ਕੇ ਸੁਆਸ ਸੁਆਸ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਯਾਦ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।\\""},{"question":"Mengapakah kita perlu memelihara warisan bangsa Kesultanan Melayu Melaka. ","answer":"-Untuk dlijadikan sebagai warisan.- Rujukan generasi akan datang.- Sebagai sumber Sejarah.- Generasi muda dapat melihat mengetahui identiti asal negara.-Menimbulkan rasa bangga kerana lambang kebangaan tamadun bangsa.-Meningkatkan semangat patriotisme dalam kalangan genera"},{"question":"එක්සත් ජනපදය ගැන කෙටි විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය නොහොත් එක්සත් ජනපදය මෙන් ම, US නමින් ද, USA නමින් ද ඇමරිකාව නමින්ද හැඳින්වෙන්නේ ප්‍රාන්ත පනහකින් සහ ෆෙඩරල් දිස්ත්‍රික්කයකින් සමන්විත වූ ෆෙඩරල් ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක ජනරජයකි. මෙහි බහුතර භූමිය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ උතුරු මැද ඇමරිකාවේය, එහි ප්‍රත්‍යාසන්න ප්‍රාන්ත 48 ක් සහ අගනුවර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය වන වොෂිංන්ටන් ඩී.සී. ද පිහිටා ඇත්තේ පැසිෆික් සහ අත්ලාන්තික් සාගර අතර ය. උතුරු මායිමේ පිහිටන්නේ කැනඩාව ය. දකුණු මායිමේ පිහිටන්නේ මෙක්සිකෝව ය. ඇලස්කා ප්‍රාන්තය වයඹින් පිහිටා ඇති අතර එහි නැගෙනහිර මායිම් වෙන්නේ කැනඩාවෙනි. එය බටහිරින් මායිම් වෙන්නේ බේරින් සානුව එපිටින් පිහිටන රුසියාවයි. හවායි ප්‍රාන්තය පැසිෆික් සාගරය මධ්‍යයේ පිහිටි ‍කොදෙව් දූපත් සමූහයකින් සෑදෙන්නකි. මෙම රටට කැරිබියන් හා පැසිෆික්හි භෞමික ප්‍රදේශයන් කිහිපයක් අයිති වෙයි. වර්ග සැතපුම් මිලියන 3.79 ක් (වර්ග කිලෝමීටර් මිලියන 9.83) යුතු මෙම රටෙහි ජනගහනය මිලියන 314 කට වඩා අධික ය. රටට අයත් සම්පූර්ණ ප්‍රමාණය සැලකිල්ලට ගැනීමේ දී එය ජනගහණයෙන් හා භූමි ප්‍රමාණයෙන් යන දෙකින් ම ලොව තුන්වන හෝ හතරවන විශාලතම රට වෙයි. ලෝකයේ විවිධ රටවල් වලින් විශාල සංඛ්‍යාවක් සංක්‍රමණිකයන් පැමිණීම හේතුවෙන් ලෝකයේ වඩාත් ම විවිධ වූ ජනවාර්ගික නියෝජනයෙන් යුක්ත හා බහුසංස්කෘතික වූ රටක් වෙයි.අද ඇමරිකාව යැයි සැලකෙන මහා භූමි ප්‍රමාණයට වසර 15,000 කට පමණ පෙර ආසියාවෙන් පේලියෝඉන්දියානුවන් සංක්‍රමණය වූවා යැයි සැලකේ. ස්වදේශී ඇමෙරිකන් ජනගහණය ඔවුන් වෙතින් පැවත එන්නන් සේ සැලකෙන අතර ක්‍රමයෙන් ජනගහණය අඩු වී යන්නේ පළමුව යුරෝපීයයන් ගේ පැමිණීමත් සමඟ ඔවුන් හා සබඳතා පැවැත්වීමේ දී බෝවෙන ලෙඩ රෝග වැළඳීමත් අනතුරුව ඒ තත්වය යුරෝපීය යටත්විජිත පටන් ගැනීමේ දී වැඩියෙන් පැතිර යාමත් නිසා ය. අත්ලාන්තික වෙරළබඩ පළාත් හි වූ බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය යටත්විජිත උපනිවේෂ දහතුනකින් ඇමෙරිකාව මුලින් සෑදෙන ලදි. 1776 ජූලි 04 වැනිදා මහාද්වීප කොංග්‍රසයට සහභාගී වූ උපනිවේෂ නියෝජිතයන් විසින් නිදහස් ප්‍රකාශනයක් නිකුත් කරන ලද්දහ. එයින් කියා සිටියේ ඔවුනට ස්වෛරීභාවයට සහ ස්වාධීන රාජ්‍යයක් පිහිටුවන්නට අයිතියක් ඇතැයි කියාය. බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අධිරාජ්‍යය පරාජය කරමින් විප්ලවිය ප්‍රාන්ත විසින් ඇමෙරිකානු විප්ලවීය අරගලය ජයගන්නට සමත් වූහ. එය යටත්විජිතයක් ස්වාධීනත්වය දිනාගත් ප්‍රථම සාර්ථක යුද්ධයයි. වර්තමාන ඇමරිකන් එක්සත් ජනපද ව්‍යවස්ථාව පිහිටුවා ගන්නේ 1787 සැප්තැම්බර් 17 වැනිදා ය. එහි අපරානුමත කිරීම් ඊ ළඟ වසරේ දී සිද්ධ වෙන්නේ සියළු ප්‍රාන්ත එකතු වෙමින් ඒකීය ජනරජයක් හා ශක්තිමත් මධ්‍යම ආණ්ඩුවක් නිර්මාණයෙනි. ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිසංශෝධන දහයකින් මූලික සිවිල් අයිතීන් හා නිදහස තහවුරු කරන අයිතීන්ගේ ව්‍යවස්ථා කෙටුම් පනත අපරානුමතය සිදු වෙන්නේ 1791 දී ය.[2]19 වන ශත වර්ෂය පුරා එක්සත් ජනපදය රට ව්‍යාප්ත කරන සීඝ්‍ර මෙහෙයුමක් උතුරු ඇමෙරිකාව තුල පටන් ගනියි. එයින් ස්වදේශී ගෝත්‍රික ජනතාවට පදිංචි වී හිටි තැන් අහිමි වූහ. 1803 දී ප්‍රංශයෙන් ලුයිසියානා භෞමික ප්‍රදේශය මිල දී ගන්නා ලදි.[3] 1845 දී ටෙක්සාස් ජනරජය ඈඳා ගන්නා ලදි. එයින් ඇරඹුනු යුද්ධයෙන් මෙක්සිකෝවෙන් බාගයක් පමණ අල්ලා ගන්නට හැකිවිය. 1867 දී රුසියාවෙන් ඇලස්කාව මිල දී ගන්නා ලදි. මුල් කාලීන භෞමික ව්‍යාප්ත මෙහෙයුම් නිසා වහල් අයිතිය හිමි කෘෂිකාර්මික දකුණු පළාත් අතරත් වහල් සේවයෙන් නිදහස්-භූමියෙන් යුතු කාර්මික උතුරු පළාත් අතර ත් සුවිශේෂී අරගල ඇති වී ඇමෙරිකන් සිවිල් යුද්ධය පටන් ගන්නට හේතු සාධක විය. උතුරේ ජයග්‍රහණය නැවතත් රට එක්සත් කරන ලදි. එක්සත් ජනපදයේ සියළු ම ප්‍රාන්ත වල වහල් සේවයට මිනිසුන් යෙදවීම එයින් අවසන් බව නීතිගත කෙරෙන ඇමෙරිකන් ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ දහතුන් වැනි ප්‍රතිසංශෝධනය අපරානුමත කරන්නට යුද ජයග්‍රහණයෙන් පසු හැකිවුණි. මිටියාවත් ඉන්දියන් යුද්ධ නිසා ඉතිරි වී සිටි ගෝත්‍රිකයන් සංරක්ෂක භූමි වලට ඇතුල් කරන ලදි. කොංග්‍රසයේ අභියෝජනාවක් මඟින් හවායි ජනරජය ඈඳා ගන්නා ලදි. ස්පාඤ්ඤ-ඇමෙරිකන් යුද්ධය අවසන් කරමින් පුවෙර්තො රීකෝ සහ ගුවාම් උත්ත්‍යක්ත ප්‍රදේශයන් බවට පත්විය. 19 වැනි ශ. ව. අවසානයේ දී එහි ජාතික ආර්ථික ලෝකයේ විශාලතම වූවයි.ස්පාඤ්ඤ-ඇමෙරිකන් යුද්ධය සහ පළමුවැනි ලෝක යුද්ධය රට ගෝලීය හමුදා බලයෙන් යුතු වූවක් බව තහවුරු කරන ලදි. දෙවැනි ලෝක යුද්ධයෙන් පසු පරමාණු අවි ඇති ප්‍රථම රට එක්සත් ජනපදය වෙයි. එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලයේ ස්ථිර සාමාජිකත්වය ලබයි. සීතල යුද්ධය අවසානය සහ සෝවියට් යුනියනය විසුරුවා හැරීමත් සමඟ එක්සත් ජනපදය සුපිරි බලයෙන් වූ එකම රට වෙයි. එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ආර්ථිකය ලොව විශාලතම ජාතික ආර්ථිකයයි. 2011 දී එහි දළ ජාතික නිෂ්පාදිතය ඩොලර් ට්‍රිලියන 15.1 ක් විය. එහි ප්‍රතිශ්‍රීර්ෂ ආදායම ලෝකයේ හය වැනි ඉහළ ස්ථානය ගනියි. ගෝලීය හමුදා වැයෙන් 41% ක් වියදම් දරන්නේ මේ රටයි. එසේම එය ලෝකයේ ආර්ථික, දේශපාලන සහ සංස්කෘතික යනාදියේ ප්‍රමුඛත්වය ගන්නකි."},{"question":"Ọkada mẹrindinlaaadọrun-un tun ha sọdọ awọn agbofinro l’Ekoo","answer":"Ọkada bii mẹrindinlaaadọrun-un nijọba gba nidii awọn to n gun wọn lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, kaakiri awọn agbegbe ipinlẹ Eko, wọn lawọn ọlọkada naa ya eleti ikun, awọn ọna tijọba ti ka leewọ fun wọn ni wọn n gba.Awọn ikọ amuṣẹya tijọba ipinlẹ Eko gbe kalẹ ta ko awọn to n rufin irinna nipinlẹ ọhun (Lagos State Environmental and Special Offences Unit Taskforce), eyi ti CSP Ṣọla Jẹjẹloye ṣe alaga rẹ ni wọn mu awọn ọkada naa.Awọn agbegbe bii Ikẹja, Ọba Akran, Yaba, Oyingbo, Surulere, Allen Avenue ati awọn opopona mi-in ni wọn lawọn ti mu wọn.Jẹjẹloye ni niṣe lọpọ awọn to n gun ọkada naa maa n fi ọkada wọn silẹ, ti wọn aa si fẹsẹ fẹ ẹ, kawọn agbofinro ma baa fi pampẹ ofin gbe wọn. Mọto gagara kan ni wọn fi n loodu awọn ọkada naa lọ sahaamọ wọn n’Ikẹja.Wọn ni niṣe lawọn maa lu awọn ọkada naa ni gbajo laipẹ tile-ẹjọ ba ti fọwọ si i, gẹgẹ bo ṣe wa ninu iwe ofin irinna ipinlẹ naa."},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية:ومحمد هو الطفل الثالث في عائلة مكوّنة من 5 أبناء، إذ تسبقه الأختان صفية وسعاد، فيما أنجبت والدته أخويه صلاح وعلي في عامي 1931 و1933، ثم توفيت بعد","answer":"إنجاب الأخير بوقت قليل. ويرى توم أن جزءا كبيرا من تكوين الفايد يعود إلى صدمة اليُتم وغياب والدته في سن صغيرة، في مقابل وجود أب حازم يعشق الانضباط ويتبع نمطا صارما في تربية أبنائه."},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.කඩෙන් ගත්තොත් භාණ්ඩයක්  දියෙන් ගත්තොත් මාංශයක්     ","answer":"ඉබ්බා "},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa Kuwii Islaamka ugu horeeyey ee muhaajiriin ah ?","answer":" Waxay Kala Ahaayeen,1- Hooyo Khadiijo Bintu Khuweylad Rc,2- Cali Bin Abii Daalib Rc,3- Abuu-Bakar Rc,4- Sayid Binu Thaabit Rc,5- Cusmaan Bin Cafaan Rc,6- Subeyr Bin Cawaam Rc,7- Cabdi Raxmaan Bin Cowf Rc,8- Sacad Bin Abii Waqaas Rc,9- Dalxa Bin Cubeydillah Rc"},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"கடவுள் இல்லை என்று கூற ஒரு அறிவாளியால் மட்டுமே முடியும்."},{"question":"পৃথিবীর কিছু জল ভূগর্ভস্থ স্থলভাগে জলাধার নামে পরিচিত ছিদ্রযুক্ত শিলা গঠনে সংরক্ষণ করা হয়। এর মধ্যে কোনটি ভূগর্ভস্থ জল ব্যবহার করতে পারে? বিকল্প: A) ওজার্কস-এ প্রচুর বৃষ্টিপাত খ) কুয়ো থেকে অতিরিক্ত পাম্পিং সি) নিম্ন মিসিসিপিতে বাঁধ D) কমিউনিটি ওয়াটার কনজারভেশন","answer":"(খ)কুয়ো থেকে অতিরিক্ত পাম্পিং"},{"question":"Unsa ang tawag sa pagsugod sa pagbalik-balik sa mga Judio gikan sa pagkabihag sa Babilonia?","answer":"Ang kini tawag sa pagbalik-balik mao ang \\"Exodus.”"},{"question":"पोलोमा गोलको गोल गर्ने नियम के के हुन्छ?","answer":"पोलोमा गोल गर्न खेलाडीले नियमनबमा बोल्नुपर्दछ, त्यसलाई नियमनबमा भन्दै प्रतिद्वन्द्वीको नेटमा डाल्नुपर्दछ। खेलाडीले नियमहरूको पालना गर्दै बोल अवस्थामा गोल गर्ने बित्तिकै गोल गर्छ।"},{"question":"1 torba hazır şap kaç m2 yer yapar?","answer":"1 Torba akıllı şap kaç m2 yer yapar, 1 mm kalınlık için ortalama 1,7 kg malzeme gider. Örneğin 5 mm kalınlığında bir tesviye için 5x1,7 kg = 8,5 kg/ m2 malzeme gider 1 torba 25 kg olduğu için 25 kg akıllı şap ne kadar yer kaplar? 1 torba ile 3 m2 alan yapılır diyoruz."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أنواع الربا ؟","answer":"الإجابة: ربا الفضل، ربا النسيئة، ربا اليد"},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"பிரார்த்தனை என்பதற்கு வேறு பெயர் பேராசை. பேராசை என்றால் தகுதிக்கு மேல் விரும்புவது, வேலை செய்யாமல் கூலி பெறுவது என்பதே ஆகும்."},{"question":"A ∩ B = Φ అయిన క్రింది వానిలో ఏది సత్యం ?A) A, B లు వియుక్త సమితులుB) A ≠ Φ మరియు B = ΦC) A = Φ మరియు B ≠ ΦD) పైవన్నీ","answer":"D) పైవన్నీ"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai dakwat dengan kertas\\"?","answer":"Perhubungan yang sangat rapat."},{"question":"هل يمكنك أن تزودني ببعض السياق للجملة التالية: ما الذي صمّم الراهب اللامي على القيام به؟ على ما يبدو ،  ولادته ذهنياً من جديد. ","answer":"يلقّب معلّمو الشريعة البوذية التبتية بالرهبان اللاميين. ويسمّى الراهب الذي يمر بمرحلتي الفاوا والسدذي ويصمّم على ولادته ذهنياً من جديد عديد المرات في أحيان كثيرة للوفاء بنذره البوذيساتفي، بالتولكو."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਬਹੁਤੁ ਸਿਆਣਪ ਜਮ ਕਾ ਭਉ ਬਿਆਪੈ ॥ਅਨਿਕ ਜਤਨ ਕਰਿ ਤ੍ਰਿਸਨ ਨਾ ਧ੍ਰਾਪੈ ॥ਭੇਖ ਅਨੇਕ ਅਗਨਿ ਨਹੀ ਬੁਝੈ ॥ਕੋਟਿ ਉਪਾਵ ਦਰਗਹ ਨਹੀ ਸਿਝੈ ॥ਛੂਟਸਿ ਨਾਹੀ ਊਭ ਪਇਆਲਿ ॥ਮੋਹਿ ਬਿਆਪਹਿ ਮਾਇਆ ਜਾਲਿ ॥ਅਵਰ ਕਰਤੂਤਿ ਸਗਲੀ ਜਮੁ ਡਾਨੈ ॥ਗੋਵਿੰਦ ਭਜਨ ਬਿਨੁ ਤਿਲੁ ਨਹੀ ਮਾਨੈ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪਤ ਦੁਖੁ ਜਾਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਬੋਲੈ ਸਹਜਿ ਸੁਭਾਇ ॥੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 265 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਜੀਵ ਦੀ) ਬਹੁਤੀ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ (ਦੇ ਕਾਰਣ) ਜਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਡਰ (ਜੀਵ ਨੂੰ) ਆ ਦਬਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ਦੇ) ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਜਤਨ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ) ਤ੍ਰਿਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਮੁੱਕਦੀ । ਅਨੇਕਾਂ (ਧਾਰਮਿਕ) ਭੇਖ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ (ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੀ) ਅੱਗ ਨਹੀਂ ਬੁੱਝਦੀ, (ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹੇ) ਕੋ੍ਰੜਾਂ ਤਰੀਕੇ (ਵਰਤਿਆਂ ਭੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ) ਦਰਗਾਹ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਰਖ਼ਰੂ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਈਦਾ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਜਤਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ) ਜੀਵ ਚਾਹੇ ਅਕਾਸ਼ ਤੇ ਚੜ੍ਹ ਜਾਏ, ਚਾਹੇ ਪਤਾਲ ਵਿਚ ਲੁਕ ਜਾਏ (ਮਾਇਆ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ, (ਸਗੋਂ) ਜੀਵ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਜਾਲ ਵਿਚ ਤੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸਦੇ ਹਨ । (ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ) ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਕਰਤੂਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜਮਰਾਜ ਡੰਨ ਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਭਜਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਰਤਾ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਤੀਜਦਾ । ਉਸ ਦਾ ਦੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਦਿਆਂ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਨਾਲ (ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ) ਉਚਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ।੪।\\""},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phù hợp với nội dung: Theo Page Six, chỉ ít giờ sau khi Will Smith xuất hiện trên mạng xã hội để xin lỗi vì tát Chris Rock tại Oscar 2022, nam danh hài đã lên tiếng châm biếm. Rock so sánh Will Smith với Suge Knight - cựu Giám đốc điều hành Death Row Records, người đang bị giam giữ vì tội hình sự. \\"Ai cũng đều tự biến họ thành nạn nhân. Nếu chỉ khăng khăng nghĩ mình là nạn nhân, họ sẽ không biết được ai là nạn nhân thực sự. Ngay cả khi bị 'Suge Smith' tát, tôi vẫn cố gắng đi làm vào hôm sau. Bất cứ ai nói lời tổn thương đều chưa bao giờ bị đấm vào mặt\\", Chris Rock nói. Chris Rock đang thực hiện chuyến lưu diễn vòng quanh thế giới, gần đây là New Jersey và New York. Qua nhiều tháng xảy ra cái tát chấn động trên sóng truyền hình, nam danh hài hiện chưa tha lỗi cho Will Smith. Theo nguồn tin của Page Six, lý do Chris Rock không muốn nhận lời xin lỗi của Will Smith sau sự cố tại Oscar là nó quá thiếu chân thành và muộn màng. \\"Will Smith không làm điều này vì sự tử tế của mình. Will nhận thấy anh ấy không còn nổi tiếng như trước. Hậu quả của cú tát để lại quá lớn\\", nguồn tin nói. Ngoài ra, người này cho rằng tài tử Aladdin xin lỗi do anh nhận thấy cú tát đã gây tổn hại lâu dài cho sự nghiệp của mình. \\"Mọi người đừng quên rằng Will hành hung người khác ngay trên sóng truyền hình quốc gia, sau đó ăn uống như ngôi sao nhạc rock tại tiệc của Vanity Fair\\", nguồn tin nói thêm. Trước đó, Will Smith gây chú ý khi đăng video xin lỗi vì những chuyện đã qua. \\"Tôi đã liên hệ với Chris và được biết anh ấy chưa sẵn sàng nói chuyện. Nếu muốn, anh ấy sẽ chủ động. Nhưng tại đây, tôi muốn nói là tôi xin lỗi anh. Hành vi của tôi không thể chấp nhận được. Tôi sẵn sàng ra gặp mặt và xin lỗi anh khi anh sẵn sàng\\", sao phim King Richard nói trong video. Will Smith nói anh bị sang chấn tâm lý khi làm khán giả thất vọng. Tài tử King Richard không ngừng xấu hổ và ăn năn. \\"Tôi cũng là con người và phạm sai lầm. Tôi đang cố gắng không nghĩ bản thân là cặn bã\\", anh nói.","answer":"Tiêu đề: Chris Rock so sánh Will Smith với tội phạm"},{"question":"பன்னாட்டு எழுத்தறிவு ஆண்டாக ஐ.நா. வினால் அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட ஆண்டு எது?","answer":"1990-ம் ஆண்டு 'அறிவுர்விற்கான சர்வதேச ஆண்டாக' அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது. சர்வதேச எழுத்தறிவு ஆண்டில், கேரளாவை நூறு சதவீதம் கல்வியறிவு கொண்ட மாநிலமாக மாற்ற மாநில அரசு தீர்மானித்துள்ளது. அதன்படி, இந்தியாவிலேயே நூறு சதவீதம் கல்வியறிவு பெற்ற முதல் மாநிலமாக கேரளா ஆனது."},{"question":"పటాల తయారీలో చిహ్నాల ఆవశ్యకతను వివరించండి.","answer":"పటంలో భవనాలు, రహదారులు, వంతెనలు, చెట్లు, రైలుమార్గాలు బావులు మొదలైనటువంటి వివిధ అంశాలను వాటి వాస్తవ పరిమాణం మరియు ఆకారంలో చూపలేం. కాబట్టి వాటిని కొన్ని అక్షరాలు, రంగులు, చిత్రాలు, గీతలు చిహ్నాలతో సూచిస్తారు. ఇవి తక్కువ స్థలంలో ఎక్కువ సమాచారాన్ని ఇస్తాయి. పటాలు గీయడం, చదవడం సులభమవుతుంది."},{"question":"Inis dom faoin teanga Gaeilge. ","answer":"Tá Gaeilge uaireanta ar a dtugtar Gaeilge na hÉireann . Is ceann de na teangacha Ceilteacha í an Ghaeilge, agus ceann de na trí cinn de theangacha Ceilteacha ar a dtugtar na teangacha Gaelacha (Gaeilge, Gaeilge Mhanann agus Gaeilge na hAlban) go háirithe. Labhraítear in Éirinn go príomha í, ach tá cainteoirí Gaeilge ina gcónaí in áiteanna eile ar fud an domhain.Is í an teanga náisiúnta nó dhúchais agus an phríomhtheanga oifigiúil i bPoblacht na hÉireann í an Ghaeilge. Tá an Béarla luaite sa Bhunreacht mar theanga oifigiúil eile. "},{"question":"Tìm ý và lập dàn ý cho Bài tập: Nhiều người cho rằng nên có các con vật nuôi trong nhà. Em có ý kiến như thế nào về vấn đề này?","answer":"- Tìm ý:+ Những con vật nuôi đã được thuần hóa từ động vật hoang dã.+ Em biết những con vật nuôi như mèo, chó, chuột lang,… Nhà em có nuôi một chú mèo.+ Ưu điểm của vật nuôi là một người bạn tâm tình, cùng vui chơi, giúp em phát triển bản thân… Hạn chế của vật nuôi là lông rụng, cần không gian để vui đùa,…+ Nên có vật nuôi trong nhà.- Lập dàn ý:+ Mở bài: Nên có vật nuôi trong nhà.+ Thân bài:  Vui chơi và luyện tập: đi dạo cùng chó, chơi ném bóng với chó,… Phát triển ý thức trách nhiệm: chăm sóc, cho ăn, tắm rửa, dọn dẹp vệ sinh, huấn luyện,… Nếu không chăm sóc thì dẫn đến những hậu quả xấu. Giảm stress: vuốt ve, âu yếm,… làm giảm căng thẳng.+ Kết bài: Vật nuôi trong nhà giống như một thành viên của gia đình. Và khi có vật nuôi trong nhà, chúng ta cần có tránh nhiệm với nó."},{"question":"நவீன வேதியியலின் தந்தை என்று அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார்?","answer":"இராபர்ட் வில்லியம் பாயில் 'நவீன வேதியியலின் தந்தை' என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறார்."},{"question":"வினா:சிவயோக சுவாமியின் மேற்கோள் சிலவற்றை தரவும்.","answer":"விடை:செருப்பைப்போல் தேகத்தைப் பாவிக்க வேண்டும்.எப்பவோ முடிந்த காரியம்நாம் அறியோம்ஒரு பொல்லாப்பும் இல்லைமுழுதும் உண்மை"},{"question":"Ijanba ina ba dukia jẹ l’Ebute-mẹta","answer":"Ninu ibanujẹ nla lawọn olugbe atawọn to ni ṣọọbu laduugbo Kano Street, l’Ebute-Mẹta, Eko, wa bayii lori ijanba ina to ṣẹlẹ to si ba gbogbo dukia wọn jẹ.Lọwọ irọlẹ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ni wọn sọ pe ina ọhun bẹrẹ, ina ijọba ti waya ẹ kan ara wọn ni wọn sọ pe o fa a, ki wọn si too ṣe ohunkohun si i, ina nla ti sọ, bẹẹ lọpọ dukia atawọn ọja pako lagbegbe naa si ṣe bẹẹ jona guruguru.ALAROYE gbọ pe ohun to tubọ mu ina ọhun fẹju ni bi gaasi, iyẹn afẹfẹ idana tawọn eeyan kan fi n dana lagbegbe ọhun naa ṣe dun gbamu, to si mu iṣelẹ naa fẹju si i.Ohun tawọn to ni sọọbu lagbegbe naa n bẹbẹ fun bayii ni bi ijọba ko ṣe ni gba agbegbe naa lọwọ wọn, ti wọn yoo fun wọn lanfaani lati tun ibẹ kọ pada, pẹlu owo iranwọ lati ọdọ ijọba, ki iṣoro ina yii ma maa da nnkan ru fun wọn ju bayii lọ.Ileeṣẹ panapana to wa ni Iganmu ati Ilupeju l’Ekoo la gbọ pe o waa ba wọn pana ọhun lẹyin to ti jo fun bii wakati mẹfa.Adele fun ileeṣẹ panapana l’Ekoo, Arabinrin Margaret Adeṣẹyẹ, sọ pe ninu ira lawọn eeyan ọhun kọ ile wọn si, bẹẹ lo ṣoro fun ileeṣẹ panapana lati tete ri ibẹ wọ, ṣugbọn awọn ileeṣẹ panapana to wa lati Ilupeju ati Iganmu gbiyanju daadaa, wọn si pada ri ina ọhun pa patapata ni nnkan bii aago mjeila abọ oru.Pupọ ninu awọn ti wọn n taja nibẹ ti ọja wọn ba iṣẹlẹ ina ọhun lọ ni wọn n bẹ ijoba bayii ko ṣeto iranwọ owo, ki iṣẹlẹ ọhun ma baa sọ wọn di ẹdun arinlẹ"},{"question":"Колониялык башкарууда жерлерди ким башкарат? ","answer":"Империализм менен колониализмдин экөө тең саясий жана экономикалык артыкчылыкты жер жана алар көзөмөлдөгөн түпкүлүктүү калктын үстүнөн көрсөтөт, бирок окумуштуулар кээде экөөнүн ортосундагы айырманы көрсөтүү кыйынга турат. Империализм жана колониализм бири-бирин басууга багытталса да, колониализм бир өлкөнүн башка бир өлкөнү физикалык жактан көзөмөлгө алуу процессине карата колдонулса, империализм саясий жана акча-кредит үстөмдүгүнө карата колдонулат, расмий же расмий эмес түрдө. Колониялык башкаруунун архитектору катары каралат, ал эми империализмди баскынчылыктын идеясын колониялык кызматташтык менен түзүү катары караса болот. Колониялык башкаруу - бул кайсы бир империялык мамлекет кайсы бир аймакты басып ала баштаганда жана анан ал аймактарды башкаруу мүмкүнчүлүгүнө ээ болгондо, ал мурдагы империялык мамлекет болгон. Колониализмдин негизги мааниси - бул багындырылган элдин баалуу мүлкүн жана ресурстарын пайдалануу жана багындыруучу эл согуштан алган олжосунан пайда алуу. Империализмдин мааниси - бул башка мамлекеттердин жерлерин басып алуу жана ошону менен өзүнүн үстөмдүгүн күчөтүү жолу менен империя түзүү. Колониялык башкаруу - бул чет өлкөлүк калктын аймактагы колониялык ээлигин куруу жана сактоо. Колониялык башкаруу аймактагы социалдык түзүлүштү, физикалык түзүлүштү жана экономиканы толугу менен өзгөртө алат."},{"question":" \\"Manao mofomamy aho amin'ny fitsingerenan'ny andro nahaterahan'ny namako. Nanaraka tsara ny fomba fanamboarana aho. Na izany aza, teo am-pikarakarana ny sakafo dia tsapako fa tsy nanana atody intsony aho.\\" Inona no tokony hataoko?","answer":" \\"Mba hamita ny fanomanana ny mofomamy dia azonao atao ny manandrana manolo ny atody  amin'ny akondro na yaourt.\\""},{"question":"كم سنة حكم الإستعمار الفرنسي الجزائر ؟","answer":"132 سنة"},{"question":"1800 ගණන්වල මැද භාගයේ හයිඩ්‍රොලික් සෝපානවල ඇති ප්‍රධාන අවාසිය කුමක්ද සහ ඒවා උස් ගොඩනැගිලි සඳහා ප්‍රායෝගික නොවන ලෙස සැලකුවේ ඇයි?","answer":"හයිඩ්‍රොලික් සෝපානවල ඇති ප්‍රධාන අවාසිය නම්, ගොඩනැගිලිවලට පිස්ටන් සවි කිරීම සඳහා සෝපාන පතුවළට පහළින් වලවල් අවශ්‍ය වීමයි. ගොඩනැගිල්ල උස වන තරමට වළ ගැඹුරු විය යුතු අතර, උස් ගොඩනැගිලි සඳහා මෙම සෝපාන වර්ගය ප්‍රායෝගික නොවේ."},{"question":"Туулган күнгө карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы  ?","answer":"Өзгөчө күнүңүздө сүйүү океанын жиберип жатам, жаным! Туулган күнүңүз дагы сиздей салкын жана шайыр болсун!"},{"question":"Apakah yang dimaksudkan  'cari makan'? Beri satu contoh ayat yang sesuai.","answer":"Ia bermaksud bekerja atau mencari rezeki. Contoh ayat: Kebanyakan para nelayan menghadapi kesukaran untuk mencari makan kerana masalah pencemaran pantai yang semakin menjadi-jadi kebelakangan ini."},{"question":"Vraag: Welk energielabel moet een kantoorgebouw in Nederlands vanaf 1 januari 2023 verplicht hebben?","answer":"Antwoord: Energielabel C."},{"question":"Viết một bài văn với chủ đề: Tả lại một trận bóng đá mà em đã chứng kiến.","answer":"Bóng đá – môn thể thao vua luôn nhận được sự quan tâm của rất nhiều người. Trong các trận bóng đá em đã từng xem trên truyền hình, có lẽ trận đấu bán kết giải bóng đá U23 châu Á giữa Việt Nam và Quatar vào ngày 23/01/2018 để lại trong em và cả trong lòng người dân Việt Nam những kỷ niệm và nhiều cảm xúc sâu sắc nhất.Trận bóng được diễn ra tại sân bóng Thường Châu, Trung Quốc. Sân bóng lớn hình chữ nhật có các đường kẻ trắng lớn ngang dọc phù hợp với luật chơi. Dưới sân là lớp cỏ xanh mướt giúp các cầu thủ khi chạy trên sân được an toàn hơn. Trên khán đống nghịt dù thời tiết có lạnh những vẫn vang tiếng hò hét, cổ vũ. Tiếng kèn khai mạc trận đấu vang lên, cầu thủ Việt Nam mặc áo trắng và cầu thủ Quatar mặc áo đỏ tiến vào sân. Tiếng reo hò lại vang thật to thật rõ khi các cầu thủ xuất hiện. Lần lượt hai đội chào cờ, các cầu thủ đặt tay lên ngực mình nhẩm theo bài quốc ca hùng tráng đang vang lên. Tiếng còi của trọng tài báo hiệu trận đấu bắt đầu. Người chuyền đường bóng đầu tiên chính là cầu thủ Xuân Trường – đội trưởng đội bóng U23 Việt Nam. Bóng được chuyền đi, 22 cầu thủ trên sân bắt đầu di chuyển theo chiến thuật của riêng đội mình giành bóng, kiến tạo những đường bóng để ghi bàn. Các cầu thủ U23 có quả đá phạt từ cự ly 11m nên nhanh chóng ghi bàn mở đầu tỷ số 1 – 0 nghiêng về Quatar. Nhưng rất nhanh chóng sau đó, cầu thủ Quang Hải của Việt Nam ghi bàn bằng một cú sút ấn tượng san bằng 1 đều. Không chỉ trên khán đài tại trận đấu tiếng hò reo cũng như cờ Việt Nam được tung bay, ngồi trước màn hình vô tuyến em và bố em cũng reo hò ầm ĩ cổ vũ cho đội tuyển Việt Nam.Chẳng bao lâu, các cầu thủ Quatar lại ghi thêm bàn thắng, nhưng cũng chỉ sau 2 phút, cầu thủ Quang Hải lại lập chiến công ghi bàn lần nữa. Kết thúc trận đấu với tỉ số hòa nên hai đội tuyển bước vào đấu hiệp phụ. Hai hiệp phụ trôi qua trong không khí đầy ganh đua và quyết liệt nhưng cũng không phân thắng bại nên bắt buộc phải đá luân lưu để tìm ra đội vào chung kết. Những lượt đá luân lưu vô cùng căng thẳng diễn ra. Không chỉ những người sút bóng, thủ môn mà thậm chí khán giả cũng hồi hộp, theo dõi từng phút giây. Và cuối cùng cầu thủ Vũ Văn Thanh đứng trước quả sút cuối cùng quyết định chiến thắng của Việt Nam. Cả đất nước như vỡ òa khi cầu thủ Văn Thanh đã hoàn thành tốt nhiệm vụ, Việt Nam tiến thẳng vào chung kết đầy oai phong.Đến bây giờ, em vẫn không thể quên sự kịch tích và thú vị của trận đấu ngày hôm đó. Em thật sự tự hào khi đội tuyển U23 Việt Nam đã giành chiến thắng trước đối thủ mạnh là đội tuyển U23 Quatar."}]`),I={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:S},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:M,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},x={class:"search-container"},B={class:"card-container"},O=["disabled"],K={key:0},P={key:1};function D(e,a,s,m,o,r){const k=y("PoemCard");return i(),t("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",x,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),b(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=u=>o.searchQuery=u),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[c,o.searchQuery]])]),n("div",B,[(i(!0),t(w,null,p(r.filteredPoems,(u,d)=>(i(),f(k,{key:d,poem:u},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),r.hasMorePoems?(i(),t("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:o.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...u)=>r.loadMore&&r.loadMore(...u))},[o.isLoading?(i(),t("span",P,"Loading...")):(i(),t("span",K,"See more"))],8,O)):j("",!0)])}const H=g(I,[["render",D],["__scopeId","data-v-3aa2f697"]]),G=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/35.md","filePath":"chatai/35.md"}'),L={name:"chatai/35.md"},R=Object.assign(L,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),t("div",null,[v(H)]))}});export{G as __pageData,R as default};
